All right.
I think this is
the last of the
sevens. We've had
a great run of
eight weeks of
seven, which is, I
wish it was seven
weeks of seven.
But we're on the
28th. So here we are.
This has been a
pretty big week. Lots
going on. It's
almost like I can't
keep track of like the
major announcements
that happened two
days ago because
there's a new
announcement that's
even more exciting
than the previous.
But I think that
we're seeing like
this dramatic increase
in capability,
both in these
models. like the new
Gemini model that
came out, 2.5, crazy,
awesome, free.
Oh, it's only, what
would you say, Rob,
only five requests for
a minute? For minute.
Yeah.
Just enough to
wet your whistle.
Yeah, so luckily
I've got like
10 Google accounts,
so maybe I'll
do some kind of
load balancer.
Maybe that, oh no,
I'm going to have to get
my bot to build that now.
Yeah, that's right.
You've got to
set it up and as
a standalone
API call, like,
like Requesti
or OpenRotter.
Yeah, well, maybe
we can get the
guys from Requesti
to create some kind
of like load
balancer that allows
us to get more
than five requests,
something like
that. And that could
be a side product
of the Requesti
guys that we'll
have on who we
have coming up here
shortly, right?
We do, yeah.
So today we've got Daniel,
Daniel, I'm talking
about from Requestie,
and he's going to
be showing us not just
the platform, but also
custom prompt that
further enhances the
token savings so that's
great daniel looking
forward to that thank
you and then uh as well
we've got joseph uh dr
joe uh joseph sonny's
um going to be sharing
his obsidian mcp set
up which is very timely
should be good and
i just want to give
a shout out uh review
and i were talking before
we got started here
we had uh splix dorian
and chris from splix
on there last week and
uh wanted to give a
congratulations sandy
dunners their new c-so
officer that's a great
great hire for the
team there and wonderful
to see for somebody
from the community
and then splix closed
their seven million
dollar seed round so
great news for those
guys they've been working
hard it's nice that
they built out that
open source component
i think it's called
agent radar which is
wonderful and then also
guy beber uh last minute
ad he's got uh he's
got a little tool
he came across that
gives you unlimited
three point five sonnet
three point five for
four bucks a month so
that'll be the third
the third lightning so
should be good okay
I'm excited to hear
about that yeah I'm
here I'm trying to save
a buck every way I can
you know four dollars
is great my my bill
this week is down
dramatically thanks
to someone will have
on here in a minute
I want to I don't
spoil their their
thunder too much but yeah
that the the their
system seems to work
at the requesties so
be exciting to see
what they have I you
know there's so much
to show I'm not even
sure where to start.
So the biggest
topic is probably,
you know, one, the
images that are
being created
probably in chat GPT.
And, you know, for
those who haven't
seen it, it works
particularly well.
It's a major upgrade,
a little slow. I think
some, I think Altman
said that their servers
are melting. Is that
what I heard Robert?
Yes.
All right.
So here's an example.
Here's me,
I guess. My legs are a
little longer in that,
I guess. but I do, I
should have wore that
shirt instead of my
tropical shirt today.
That's the stern look,
the stern really.
A little, a
little creepy.
Here we go, this is me in
the middle ages, I guess.
My legs haven't
gotten any longer.
Here's the, I'm like,
make it look
more like me.
And like, it sometimes
goes into various,
you know, designs. What
else do I got here?
I, it's, it's,
here, I've been playing.
play or the cyber
one i did last night
turned out pretty cool
if you guys yeah i
saw that that's great
yeah here we can look
at how i create those
so and i just created a
picture myself nothing
nothing and then i
said there make me
into a cyborg of a
metallic skin a little too
gray for me then it
then it went and looked
up some other designs
which was kind of
an interesting approach
so basically it's
trying to figure out
what i want then it gave
me this design and i
said no make it look
like more like me and
give it sunglasses and
then i and then i
veered into the sort of
the world of like just
different styles like
this one i said more
steampunk which is
it's kind of kind of
steampunky more japanese
bahito basito kind of
this is actually kind
of my favorite i think
i really like that
and apparently i don't
speak japanese but
according to my wife
who grew up in Tokyo,
she says that the
latest model actually
does kanji and
she could read it.
So there you go.
I didn't realize
that in the pre,
apparently the
previous version,
the kanji was
just gibberish.
Now,
the other thing
to show this week,
there's been some
major upgrades to IDEO.
I did bring up
with three. And if
you think that the
model that this model,
this model, I was
showing you if it
would use good,
this is even better.
So this is how I
created my models this
morning, if you're
curious. But what's
really cool about this,
if you go in here,
I can actually mix, I
can mix and match. So
here I define my color
scheme. So you can
see here I've got pink
and gray and so on.
Then I can use another
image to give it
the style. So I can
actually create one image,
then pass it along
and use it. So for
example, so this is
the reference image. So
this was an image I
created previous but
then I wanted this
new image to be Klein
Rules right so I go in
here and I give it my
my prompt which was a
close-up monochromatic
retro UI 8-bit LED
display and it says
you know Klein Rules
which it does and and
then I want to change
up the color scheme so
I can go here and I
can use different color
schemes so and what
this is what's great
about this is I've got
a lot more capability
in terms of size.
So I can define the,
I'm not only
defining the general
capabilities like
we saw in chat to
BT, I can go in
there and say,
well, what size do
I want it, right?
So I can, I can make
it. So if you're
using it for
LinkedIn, for example,
you probably want
a four by five
ratio, which
fits perfectly in
the sort of max
size image area.
So I'll choose
that. Then if I want
to change the model,
I get different
models. There's
really no model better
in three. This
is, in my opinion,
the best model
going at the moment.
Then you've got magic
prompt. I'm not really
sure what the magic
prompt is. I usually
leave it on. So we've
got different styles.
So auto is pretty
good. Realistic is
obviously realistic.
Design is for like graphic
design style. And
this is really great
text. General. I'm
not really sure what
General does when random
is pretty obvious.
You can you can track
style code. So if you've
previously designed
something like here.
I can go in here
and use the seed
right here. I think
that's what it is.
I should probably
do a better
job of reading
the documentation.
But you can pop that in
here and reuse the style.
And then I can say
create a billboard that
says AI hacker space
live. Oh, I get
space twice. there we
go and what's unlike
the um the chat chibi
t this is substantially
faster so chat t
bt takes forever
to to to render now
i'm going to get four
images here in roughly
about 20 seconds
thing see i chose
i chose i chose
i didn't give it
a whole lot of
guidance just
because whatever but
um i didn't give it
any text either but it
looks like it's it's
lying to me on the text
the text the work out
so great this time
but generally it works
pretty good and see
here i i fool around
with different images
like here's here's 3d
images and isometric
this this image turned
out pretty good i
was playing with
different agenetics logo
ideas just to see so i
i i basically give it
a logo and then i give
it a reference and
then it gives that kind
of you know metallic
kind of look to it
which is cool so i can
fool around with it
anyway if you're in
the graphic design this
is in my opinion the
best yeah um as you're
a place that you look
and like kind of get
inspiration or clarity
on like what kind
of prompt or how to
prompt in on the image
side do you use like
prompt libraries to
to learn are there any
resources like that
you can share with us
I've created 350,000
images I just got a feel
for it at this point
you can check on my
Instagram I got tons
of stuff on there if
for those who are more
into into that sort
of thing it's art I'm
at RUV on Instagram.
I share a lot of my
prompts there as well.
Is it going to make
me log in? I'm not
going to log in
right now, whatever.
But, yeah,
I'm Instagram, RV.
But I use a lot of
descriptive text,
like, you know,
points of view,
you know,
style,
design,
perspective.
I got,
you know, different
types of, you know, I
guess just like lenses,
things like that.
Another thing we're
doing, just as an FYI,
we're looking to
launch an ambassador
program. This was
Sinal's idea yesterday.
We have bots to build
our stuff quickly.
So we're looking
to launch an
ambassador program.
So if you're
interested in being
an ambassador,
really only requirement
is your paying
member, which is
like 10 bucks anyway.
And that will give you
the ability to sort
of build chapters in
your local area. these
place are currently
placeholders so I need
three people who are
willing to be an ambassador
mostly because I need
to update the website
with something that
isn't a placeholder
and and your avatar or
image or whatever you
want to slap in there
also guy here okay so
slap your name or text
me text me your image
and your location and
some one sentence line
description of who
you are and what's
what's interesting um
we get eligibility you
just need to be on the
call today apparently
so and responsibilities
we want to throw vents
like we want to get
the stuff going we've
got all these locations
and we're i think
we're constrained mostly
by the fact that it
just i'm probably taken
on too much at this
point but uh but luckily
we've got an army of
people who are willing
to help so i'm going
to take you guys up
on your offers to help
and uh yeah so this
this is the site it's
not linked anywhere
you'd have to go slash
ambassador currently
i'll link it somewhere
later um also just
as an FYI i there's
a minor well maybe
a major error in the
in the sign up process
on the site which
i which i need to
call super base to fix
so i've disabled the
register with your
username and password
unfortunately right
now you're just going
to have to log in a
register with your
github or google account
uh Apparently, there's
a trigger that I
set that I can't undo
in SuperBase. So if
anyone knows how to
undo off base triggers,
let me know because
currently the off
base triggers failing,
which means it only
works if you register
with Google or OA,
which kind of *****.
Anyway,
let's do the
last jump. Last
thing, this is a
part that people
are really excited
about earlier.
Earlier this week, I
created a, I created
a ton of stuff this
week, but actually
one last thing I
want to show you.
Check this out. The
guys that request
you are going to be
on here in a minute.
My bill last
week was $1,200,
which is,
you know, pretty
decent for a week.
So since, so almost
exactly a week,
we're looking at
$200. I spent $265
on my, on my
various usage. We'll
see what models
I use. And I use
3.7 in deep seek
predominantly.
And that is, I
don't know what the
percentage is, but it's
down $1,000. So that's
something. like, what,
90% or something?
So my cost is
substantially lower.
Well, we're going
to let request
you tell you
exactly how they
managed to drop
my bill by $1,000.
I'm not going to
lie, I'm curious.
But I built a crazy
amount of stuff this
week. So the fact
that it only cost me
$265 is even crazier.
So just to give you
a quick view, I built
Spark. So for those
that are familiar,
this is my sort of
second generation of
my autonomous coding
system. It does a ton
of stuff. Basically,
it allows you to
monitor your every
transaction within
your coding system
using vectors on a
multi-dimensional
structure, both in
terms of time and
sort of what it does,
sort of context.
So here's an example.
I'm running it.
I'm hearing in GPT4.
I have different
models and modes. I
can run it sequentially
or in parallel
or in concurrent
modes. So as various
things happen,
I'm creating vector
contextual vectors.
In this case,
it started.
Then I've run another
vector saying, you
know, whether this is
a brand new repository.
I'm using unified dip
structure, similar
to the diff structure
in Rue, to do a
comparison of the code
that's being created.
Then I guess so the
system can automatically
go back and look
at any code that's
been previously
created and say, did it
work? Did it fail?
And if they want, if
the system wants to
use it. All it needs to
do is grab the diff
and immediately apply
it, which means it's
cheaper, faster,
and doesn't require
the LLM to even go and
make an LLM request,
which is kind of nice.
So you can see
here, I'm running
it here, it's
analyzing code.
I'm using a EB2 code
interpreter to actually
run the code. So that
means I'm running the
code independently of
my code environment,
which is cool.
So it means I can
concurrently run multiple
agents that swarm
and build an Apple
know,
kind of like an ant
colony building a,
I don't know, an
ant colony, I guess.
So you can use
different types
of concurrent
parallel processes.
I can build
things in like
a hundred times of speed.
Now, it's also a
hundred times more
expensive, and that's
why I was looking at
things like Gemini 2
.5, and Gemini 2.5 is
essentially free at
the moment. So if you
use Gemini 2.5,
there's another way for
you to save some
money there. I'm going
to save you a bunch
of money in a minute.
Oh,
and guys got an
even better hack
for, I think,
for $4, which
I'm very excited
to hear about.
Last thing, last
thing, okay.
So I did a post
this morning because
everyone's asking. How
do I do my autonomous?
So a couple of
things to look at.
I'm moving fast
here. So you'll have
to watch the playback
of the recording.
So I'm running,
you can see here
I'm running my
Spark system here.
I did a query,
analyze the command
implementation, and
then I see a response.
So this is querying
the vector.
So essentially,
you'll see
here a similarity score.
The closer you get the
one, the more perfect
the similarity
matches when you look
at vectors, right?
So 0.74 is basically
saying, is the code
somewhat related? Well,
according to the
similarity search,
there's a 75%
relationship to it.
So I'm able to
essentially create
a sort of agentic,
rag-based,
multidimensional,
temporal,
distributed coding
system with MCP,
all integrated into
my client. So Klein
acts as a kind of
orchestrator for
multiple agents. Each
one of those agents
is being run as an
independent process
using the OpenAAI
agent SDK and API.
It's fast, it's cheap,
and it's infinitely
scalable. I was able to
do thousands of these
agents all running
concurrently doing different
things, and the price
was like 25 cents.
So you can also replace
the GPT-40 model
with any other model
you want. So if you want
it to do the actual
logic using, let's say,
Gemini or Sonnet 3.7,
you can just do that.
This entire code base,
which is, I think,
close to 100,000
lines of originally,
original code
built in an afternoon
on the weekend,
you know, was,
I think the overall cost
was something like $75.
and completely
functional.
It was built using
this methodology
that uses testing
and sort of iterative
feedback, basically
on autopilot.
I think I've got to
the point where I can
literally just point
these dots at my code
and say, go build
me this crazy thing,
go and I go
have dinner, I
come back and it's built.
I think we have reached
the age of a completely
autonomous building
of applications with
basically nothing more
than a decent plan.
and a test-driven
development environment.
All right, last
thing I want to show
you guys is the
Rue Kline rules.
When you're in
your Rue or Klein,
and I think cursor has
something called cursor
rules, which is almost
exactly the same,
you can put a file
called dot-cline rules.
This ends up being one
of the most important
parts of any automated
component. It tells
the system how to
sort of automate the
parts. So last week I
was showing you guys
this idea, when you go
into Rue and you can
sort of set up these
automated, you know,
execution commands.
So that's important,
but this actually allows
you to sort of tell
it what your preferences
are, how, you
know, which linter,
you know, what testing
and all, you know, how
to execute the MCPs.
Without this,
it's a wild mess. The
MCPs fail half the time.
This seems to be
the magic piece
to make a lot
of this stuff
work. Check out
the LinkedIn,
post it this
morning if you
want to copy
me. paste it,
I can, I'll
publish this to
the repo here a
bit and you got
to do a little
more testing.
But you can see here's
fire file triggers.
Here are the terminal
commands. Here
are the commands
I don't want it to
run. Here's my MCP
related commands.
You see my analyze,
my modify and
search and pass for
uploading files.
Everything, all the
settings here. The great
thing is I can actually
get Rue or Klein
to actually create this
file for me or even
optimize it based on
the particulars of
the thing I'm building.
So I change it up for
every project based
on the requirements
of that project. But if
100,000 lines of code
completely functional
is any indication,
it works pretty good.
All right. I'm done.
Do you still use a normal
prompt in incline
or root code?
I use plans.
Yeah. So I
create a detailed
plans step by
step and those
plans. guides
guide the system.
So let me, actually,
if you guys want
one more minute. I was
trying to end early
today, but let me
just show you quick.
So you see here,
I've built a few
different things. The
benchmark system is
probably the best
example I've built
using this. So the
first thing I did
is I create the
spark system, right?
It's substantial.
There's a lot of, there's
a lot of stuff in
here, right? I got
CLIs and dips and
sandboxes and vectors,
all of which is organized
nice and cleanly.
Again, in the agent
structures and all
that. that sort of
stuff. So again, huge,
huge project.
But I need a
benchmark it, right?
So to create a
benchmark, what I
did is I went and
created a plan.
So before I built
anything, I basically,
I switched to thinking
mode in Sonnet 3.7
thinking medium because
it's a nice balance
between being too
expensive and too
long. Then I tell it
to basically create a
detailed implementation
plan that I can
implement phase by
phase. So this is the
overview, you know,
current implementation
and it uses a metrics
collector and various
things and then I
guide it through it.
And then that creates
the entire system.
And again, this was,
what you're looking at is
completely autonomous
development.
Like other than
the plan, which I'm
basically using
ChatGVT or Sonnet 3
.7 to create based
on the other code,
I set it and I go
off and do something
else for a few hours.
And I come back.
This benchmarking tool,
which is
substantial as well,
is, was built,
let's see here,
which read me am I
looking at. Yeah,
this was built for under
five bucks and took
about an hour or so,
and I had very, very
little involvement for
me. So it's a C-L-I,
it can do all the
benchmarking to prove that
my system works and
I can test different
types of step-marks.
I can integrate it
with various types of
evaluation frameworks,
you know,
swee bench and stuff
like that anyway
set and forget
that's that's the
that's the that's
my buzzword for
day are you using
are using cowboy mode
like is that is that
essentially what you
do you go straight up
like when you leave
for dinner uh no
yeah well it's it's
it's cowboy mode but
now I'm using a roof
for it and and spark
2.0 I I don't I'm
not I'm not calling
it cowboy mode anymore
because the the guys
at RA were not happy
with me using their
cowboy mode term.
Gotcha.
Okay.
If that's a problem,
I will call it cowboy
mode. I'll call it
cowgirl mode. How's that?
I don't know why
they were really
upset when I called
it cowboy mode.
I gave them credit.
I don't know why
they got so upset
about that, but anyway.
Hey, a quick question
about the code
basis. Like,
which kind of
programming languages
have you tried
this against?
I used, I tried it
using Python, Rust,
TypeScript, JavaScript,
and Java,
straight up Java,
and funny, it works
great for Java.
I had a rant yesterday,
which I'm going
to repeat just briefly,
anyone that was
on the call for the
live coding session.
Python's one of
the worst freaking
languages for
automated coding.
And one of the reasons
why is, you know,
the indents and the
blank space within,
and Python counts
as tokens and usage.
And it's always the
thing that breaks.
So when you're using
an automated system
and using dips, you're
always running into
the same general
problems with Python.
It's the fact that
those indents aren't
quite right. There's
an extra space. There's
an extra indent
somewhere that is too
much or too little.
And then it breaks
and you have to do
the whole thing again.
When you use
languages that
aren't indented
like Python,
it's cheaper,
you're not paying
for blank
space. Remember,
blank space and LLM
input and output costs,
right? It counts towards
your token usage.
So if you're paying for
something, it
isn't even there,
and it's a thing that
breaks. So if you are
building things
autonomously, the reason why
you see me building
a lot more using
TypeScript and languages
that don't use indents
is that reason, right?
It's more efficient.
I have less breakage,
and I get from zero
to functional more
quickly. Now, there's
always reasons to use
Python, but for the most
part, if you're building
something net new
and there's no module
that you need to
import that happens to
be explicitly Python,
avoid Python.
It's also slow
and cumbersome.
There, my rant's over.
So do you prefer
Dino for the
backend like a CPA
currently doing?
So I like Dino, but
there's the drawback to
Dino. So the best part
of Dino is the explicit
nature of the security
and the rules and
how it's, you know,
has how it's executed.
So you have to
explicitly allow for file
operations or network
access or whatever,
which is great for an
agent, right? Because
the agent acts as
a self-contained
sandbox, right? So if
you don't want it to
have access to the
file system, you
literally just don't
run it with file system
access and it inherently
doesn't get it.
Now,
that's great for
security, but
the problem is
the AI doesn't
quite. understand
how Dino works.
So there's often an
issue where you have to
kind of repeatedly tell
it how to explicitly
allow the agent to
actually gain access
to things like the
network or dot EMB file.
So the the drawback
the Dino is you're
going to have to do some
more prompt engineering
to tell it how it
needs to use Dino.
Because it just
isn't it's changed.
Dino's changed how it
how its permissions
work over the last
couple of versions.
So whatever the
sort of versions
of Gemini and GPT4
and Sonnet were
trained on, they
were apparently
trained on older
versions of it,
which causes some
problems. But once
you get beyond that,
it's, in my opinion,
the best place
and mechanism to
create serverless
functions or agents.
It's by far the
fastest. I can create a
Dino agent that starts
in 30 milliseconds.
That same agent that
I built in Python
takes, you know,
sometimes. times one or
two seconds, and that's
if I've optimized
the server to not
load anything else.
And if it isn't
optimized, a cold
start could be like
10 to 15 seconds.
So we're talking 10 to 15
seconds, no optimization,
versus 30 milliseconds
with no optimization.
Would you consider a
rust with the bottom
edge as a method
of building agents?
The problem is rust,
you have to compile it.
So once you've
compiled it, it's fast.
It's probably as
fast as type script.
the compilation process,
20 minutes.
In 20 minutes, I could
have built the ****
thing five times over
and I'm still waiting
for it to compile just
to discover there's
an error and then I've
got to wait another
20 minutes to fix
that error. So the
time it takes to compile
a Rust application
defeats the purpose
of the speed that
you get for actually
operating it. So I
need both the
compilation time to be
fast and the execution
time to be fast.
Plus, great
for execution,
abysmal a compilation.
Hey, Roof, but what
about just optimizing
after you've done
developing? Just tell
the model to like
convert the code to rest.
Well, yeah, you can get,
that's a good point.
So you could use a
test-driven development
approach where you're
not doing the comp,
directly doing the
compilation, but you're doing
the tests and running
against the tests,
and then doing a
final compilation
once the tests all pass.
That is a logic. That's
a pretty good way
to do it, too. And
maybe even better way
is just don't convert
the entire agent
to Rust, but just like
run the profiler and
use the output and
identify the slow
pieces and then convert
just those to Rust.
Or you could just
use TypeScript and
it just does that
without any fuss.
Maybe.
You know, it's, I
like this, I'm lazy.
I like simple and
easy and cheap.
And Rust isn't,
is not, is not
necessarily
simple or easy.
It's cheap and it's
fast once it's compiled.
Just my opinion,
I'm sure. I mean, if
someone else has a
different opinion, I'm
willing, I'm certainly
willing to hear it.
That's been my
experience with it.
And just to give
a firm room, we're
going to, if we're
going to fire up
Spark 2.0, we need
an EB2 account.
You let's, if we're
using the analogy,
I've been using
the sort of, you
know, karate analogy
lately. and I'm
not saying I'm Mr.
Miyagi or anything.
But that is black belt.
If you're starting out,
Spark 2 right
now is alpha,
and it's super
complicated.
Now, it's
complicated in terms
of what it does,
and I probably
need to simplify
its interface.
So if you're just
getting going, it's not
ready for novice users
yet. This is meant
to be like the art of
the possible. Like,
what's the most complex,
you know, difficult
thing I could possibly
build for coding?
That's why I was
attempting to build.
Now I need to try
to make an interface
for it to make it
simpler and easier.
If you do decide
to give it a spin,
you're going to
need an EB2 API key.
Start with the
scripts examples
folder. I created
a bunch of scripts
that just run
independently of MCP.
That's probably
the quickest way
to get up and
running with it.
And there's a
CLI, which is also
probably another
easy. way to get up
and running with
it. But again, it's
not, it's not simple,
unfortunately.
I will. I'll work on
making it more simple.
And I posted
the link to the
fungibility article
on the optimization
of the Rue and
the Klein Rules.
It's in the chat there.
Yeah, that's where you
want to, that's where
you want to focus.
That I think, I think,
I think if you guys
can optimize and create
self-creating,
you know, loops in
Rue, there's nothing
you can't build.
Literally,
I don't think,
you know, I'm...
Between that
and requestee,
we're on fire.
Yeah, I think the key
here, again, tests.
If there's anything,
if there's anything
I can suggest
for you guys is
create a detail
plan and create
tests, unit tests.
And those tests
feedback into
Russ, or sorry,
Russ, Roo,
and then every failure
or problem, and
there's always going
to be problems, get
automatically fixed,
and then as they're
fixed, it moves on
to the next test.
And by the time
the tests are all
100% coverage,
your app works.
It's effectively
the reward
function for
reinforcement learning.
Yeah.
All right. Well,
this sounds
like a great
transfer guy.
Good to see you.
And for those who
don't know, Guy and I
work together at
Citrix in the R&D lab.
And what was our job
basically to dream
up the future? and
I think we did,
except it was actually
successfully used
by every other company
other than ours.
That's pretty close.
Yeah.
Take it away, Guy.
Are you on a new show?
Okay.
Yeah,
I'm super excited
about this. I've been
trying to do local AI
and it works okay. But
using the bigger models
as all is a better
deal. So let me share
my screen real quick.
so I can find it.
So I did a little article
on this, but basically,
at a high level,
if you use root
code, co-pilot,
GitHub co-pilot,
and visual code,
you get access
to all of these
models for four
bucks a month.
That's Cloud 3.5 Sonet,
Gemini 2.0 Flash,
GPT40, 01,03 Mini,
354O and 4. It's
huge, huge cost
-saving. So you
just have to
enable it in your
BS code setup.
So as an example
in my RU code
setup, if you
just go in here,
oops,
why this is in my way.
Basically,
there's this API
provider called
VSCode LM API.
And if you
select that, what
that does is it
gives you access
to everything
in co-pilot.
Other than, I will
say, the 3.7 models
don't work. tried
all of the models,
and I can use
them locally.
So I set up a
coding co-pilot one,
and I set up a
planning co-pilot
one, which uses
Gemini Flash.
And this gives
you 5,000 API
calls per hour for
the $4 license.
You can't beat this
anywhere. That's
not tokens.
That's API calls.
And if you actually
buy the enterprise
version, you get 15
,000 API calls per hour,
and it doesn't train
on your code. So pretty
amazing. So, you know,
I can use this code
mode, et cetera, and
do whatever I want.
Like, you know.
And guy, just as an FYI,
there was a
report about three
weeks ago on our
subreddit that when
you use that
particular setting
in like a fully
autonomous mode,
accounts for
being banned.
So be careful They've
got some kind of like
Tripwire or something
for like Autonomous Use
And once And it'll
like literally ban your
GitHub account And
then you get to go
through a whole Rigomer
roll to get it unbanned
There's a whole
bunch of people That
went and did it And
when I did that post on
What was it? Yeah,
Reddit It was about a
month ago So yeah And
they were all like We're
really ****** And they
thought that I'm the
one that made them do
it So just be careful
I'll be careful.
I haven't
hit a hit a
limit on it yet.
And it seems
fine when you're
just going
back and forth.
But the problem
is when you
have it like
running, you know,
autonomously for an hour.
Yeah, they think
it's like they think
it you're up to no
good or whatever.
So wait, Guy, where did
you sign up for this?
This was just a GitHub
co-pilot account.
You pay for a
GitHub co-pilot
account. I think
if you do the free
account, they will
bring you. Yeah.
But if you pay for the
$4 a month account,
I don't think
you get banned.
But these guys
were paid accounts.
So it's a pro version.
Yeah, just be careful.
Yeah, and so I've built
tools with
this, obviously.
So, you know, Proji
is for me to help
me switch between
projects because,
like, Rue, I have way
too many projects.
But the cool part about
this is I can say, hey,
I want to go
code my defense.
filter project.
And that'll actually,
if I have an instance
of Visual Code Studio
open with that open,
it'll find it and
switch me to it.
So I can switch
contacts like that.
I can create a new
repo, et cetera.
And it's pretty
handy that way.
But that's all
I wanted to
show today.
That's awesome.
How did you do the
switching thing?
I basically use the
API for visual code to
find which one had the
project. So I really,
I pointed AI
out and said,
hey, figure this out.
It also will
switch between
coding windows.
So if I go and do,
that's my AI server.
Sorry,
if I say I want to
work in my financial
project, so I can say
Project C.V. Finney.
Now, if there's an
X-term window open,
it'll find it and
open it. If there's
not, it'll open it for
me in that directory.
And then it uses
something called
during and V to switch
the environment.
Anytime you see the
end of the directory,
it actually does a
Python environment
switch. And
so it's set up
to code in either
Node or Python,
apparently.
But super cool,
super useful.
The next step I
want to do is have
it actually organize
all my windows.
So if I have supporting
materials and open
in browsers, et cetera,
that it switches that
context for me as I
switch between all
these projects and, you
know, cool things like
I can if I forgot to
sync my projects I
can basically go hey
you know sync all my
projects or check my
projects you know our
notes I think one cool
thing which we could do
on top of this is just
like branching let's
say like we have a
dev branch and another
branch usually in
large projects there'll
be a significant diff
this would be really
super cool on projects
that you can link the
divs accurately and
the LLM has context on
the different brands.
I mean, I usually
just copy-paste it,
but this would be
an amazing thing.
Looks awesome.
So this just tells
me this one has,
I've been working on
this one, it needs
to be committed. If
I hit sync, it would
actually do the
GitHub repo push to
the master repo and
stuff. So anyways,
thanks for the
time. Hopefully
save you guys some money.
You publish your
project code anywhere?
I can.
Right now it's pretty
selfish about it
and just had it designed
to work on MacOS.
So people want
to extend it.
Oh, yeah.
I'm sure we can
vibe code our way
into a Windows and
a Linux version.
You know, and
you bring up an
interesting point.
And I've been getting
some pushback and
some of the stuff
that literally
only works for me.
And this is something
I want to mention.
Like the stuff
that I share is
literally only
built for me, right?
And the same way that
you just described
that when you
built that for you.
And I share it
because I can, but
it's not built
necessarily for others.
And it's built.
And that's something
that I think
some folks need to
sort of understand
when it comes
to open source.
You know,
I just build because I
can. I'm not building
for any other
reason, just to learn
something new and whether
it works for someone
else is sometimes
a kind of secondary
thought for me. Maybe
that's because I'm
selfish in some weird
way, but I don't know.
But if you think back
when the decision
was, hey, I wish I
could automate that, but
it would take too long
to automate it. And
now the price model
or the effort required
to do that is inverted.
So making custom
tools is extremely
inexpensive. concept.
And so everyone should
be doing that for,
you know, their
personal work processes
to accelerate
development. Like I have
this problem where
I had, you know, 30
terminals open and
30 visual code studio
things open and I
couldn't find them.
And so that
that just fixed
my own problem, right?
It kind of reminds me
of like the computer
clubs back in like
when I was a kid in the
80s. And when you
wanted software, there
were, you know, there
was basically two ways
to do it. You had,
well, three ways. You
could buy it. I had
no money. I was a kid.
You could get shareware,
which were these
discs that you got in
the mail, and you can
install software that
other people created
to solve their own
problems, and they
were, you know, hacked
together. And then
there were these,
like, computer clubs of
geeks that would get
together and hack together
software just for
their own purposes.
And, you know, back
in, like, for me,
is 1988, so I was
10 years old. And I
created a BBS. And
the reason I created
the BBS and took
up my parents and,
you know, modem and
whatnot was literally,
because I didn't
have any money to
create software for
my tandy computer.
So I used the BBS
to connect to other
geeks in the town
that I lived in.
And we would
collaborate on creating
software, which we
basically stole from the
shareware discs that
we were being sent
in the back of the
PC World magazine.
But it feels a
little bit like
that again, if
I'm going back
in time and
showing my age.
Awesome.
Anyway,
thanks for guys.
thanks guy it brings a
thought no like the
greatest games in this world
came from pirated because
gamers are pirating
games and doing
amazing stuff it's just
yeah we're sharing
ideas and knowledge this
people just has to take
the idea from an idea
perspective and just
be happy and innovate
on top of it because I
think people this age
takes too much too
many things granted so
I like your I like
the way you think you
know let's tell that's
Metallica so they
don't sue me again but
anyway who you turn it
back the clock again
roof I know I still
freaking I was on a
podcast the other day
and the guys like you're
basically the forest
gump of tech if you
look someone in the
background you were
there you were never
in the foreground I think
that was a compliment
possibly i don't
know who my jenny is
my i guess my wife
anyway we have a little
switch up so it's
tibble one of the co
-founders from requesty
is going to be doing
the demo for us today
hey tibble how are you
good how's everyone
great yeah i'm excited
to see what what you
know i've been using
you guys for a week
you see the earlier
my little uh my little
demo there um you guys
have cut my cost by
$1,000,000 dollars.
And give or take,
I put out close
to 250,000 lines
of code this week.
Wow. Just shy.
Yeah.
So
I want to know
how you did it.
Amazing.
Let me share my screen.
Can everyone
see my screen?
Today's demo is about
the root code integration
we have that you've
mentioned. We've
added a really cool
quick button. So if you
install rule code for
the first time you just
can click on requestee
boom it gets you
redirected um we have
a little surprise we've
done a whole new platform
does does everyone
want to see that or
yeah let's go to the new
this is the new the
new platform so if
everything goes wrong
that's fine it's the new
platform but basically
use oaf to authenticate
one click and it
should just authorize
code I click that, it's
authorizing, and it
should bring me back
to Visual Studio codes.
There we go.
All seamless so far.
What I'm going to
do is just say, hey,
code me a snake
game in one
Python file just
for the test.
Hope it works.
And it seems to be
working. So the integration
is very quick and
easy, as you can see.
The benefit of using
request here with
code is that you
can just come here.
here and you'll
see all of the
different models that
we serve. So if you
want to use the
latest Gemini model,
you can just use
it straight away
from the list with
about 200 models.
And you can play
around with that
while RU code is
coding for you,
which is the
best part of it.
If I go back to
the platform,
we still
need to click a
button here, but
this is a new
platform, by the way.
Let's see what you
guys think about
it. But we've
just spent seven
cents on that one
request. We can see
the latency, the
request volume.
We can see the
actual logs, but I'm
going to go into
the API keys. So you
can see the rule
code API key here.
And what's really
cool is that
you have this
configure button.
You can create both
fallback policies
because, you know,
Atropic can be down.
So an idea of a
fallback policy could be
I want to use, I want
to use Anthropic 3
.7 as my model. and I
want to add another
model and let's do
3.5 and basically if
you create this
this policy it will
basically go to the
first model if we get an
error it will straight
away go to the
second one so that you're
always online always
getting a response
now for how we can
actually save cost
is we enforce caching
but we also have other
really cool features
such as the root
code custom prompt.
So GOSU Coder,
it's another coder,
I'm very active
on root code.
He made a custom
prompt that you can
enable yourself,
just by click here,
but you can also
set your own custom
prompt. And what
will happen is
WordPressi will
override the prompt,
system prompt from
root code for you.
So you don't have to
put that in rules,
you just configure
that in the UI.
Now, we saw here 7
cents on the first
request. So if we
can go back here,
in book code. We have our
Python game
here in Python,
our snake game. I'm just
going to delete that.
And I wonder what's
going to happen with,
let me see here,
what's going to
happen with a new
prompt that we
just instructed.
So we had seven
cents before.
Let's see what
happened now.
Oh, it wants
to do a Friday
demo. Let's
approve 0.042.
And it is writing code.
amazing and let us go
back to requestee and
the benefit of request
is that everything
is in the logs you
can turn off the logs
for privacy reasons
if you don't want to
send them to us but
let's just see if he's
still coding or not
he is still coding we
can go to the first
requests that we did
was about seven cents
as we can see 12 000
tokens 10 000 input
tokens and 1,900 output
tokens if i refresh
here what do we see
four sets so 3,600
tokens a lot more output
tokens but the input
tokens dramatically
changed so we went from
10,000 input tokens
to a thousand hundred
input tokens with
a new prompt so that's
the benefit of being
able to customize and
configure your system
prompt with root
code is that you can
dramatically impact
those amount of tokens
and that should reflect
in your analytics.
And we've added
a new pool
dashboard, which
is the savings,
which is basically
what you're
saving if you're
using caching.
We're not caching
yet because
I wanted to do
the request.
So if I do
improve the code,
it should use caching.
And if we see
the cache here,
maybe it was not quick
enough to use the cache.
But you get our point.
And the main
goal is reducing
your costs while
you aren't coded.
Any questions?
Feedback.
It works.
Like,
it totally works.
There's one thing
that you probably
need to do to
improve it further.
I created a symbolic
caching system, like,
or optimization thing
called Simplang.
I added that.
And I was able,
I'm able to get it
up to 95% savings
using that now.
And you should add
something like, you
should just add
my Simplang. It'll
dramatically improve
that even further.
And I went into
your prompt options,
and I just added my
prompt that basically
said, use symbolism
for sort of hyper
-optimization of
the code structure.
And it's just
magically worked,
which is amazing.
So, yeah.
Where can we
find out prompt?
Well, you can go to my
synth laying project.
I actually
attempted to create
a proxy a while
back. So you
can see my proxy
implementation,
but you should
totally use it.
Here's the, I'm going
to put it in the chat.
You can see my
optimization
and it works really well.
And so I, that's
how I was able
to get your
system up from.
Initially it was
about 50% reduction in
cost. I was able to
get up to about 90,
90% reduction in cost.
Crazy.
Like really well done.
You guys are, you
guys are going to be,
if the company we
had last week just
announced a $7
million funding round.
70 million, way more,
way more valuable.
Sorry,
sorry, sorry, we,
I like those other
guys too, but you
guys, you guys just
saved me a thousand
bucks in a week. So
what, what more?
Best friends forever.
Yes,
exactly.
Would you expect the,
what do you think of the,
sorry,
would you expect
the model providers
to eventually provide
cashing because,
you know, they do.
But the, the caching
provide, like, Open
AI currently offers
direct caching, right?
And you You don't
have to enable it.
Sonnet 3 point, sonnet
or clod, you have
to enable the flag
to get the caching.
But it doesn't
benefit the amount of
tokens being sent
as part of the
system prompt and
the initial request.
So what these guys
have done, and I'm
talking for you guys
momentarily here, but you
guys have taken that
and made it magic.
It just kind of
works without me
having to worry
about why or how.
So, Martin,
we enforce the
Anthropic caching
manually behind
the scenes, so
you don't have to
worry about it.
Anthropic, you
need to specify
what you want to
cash and when,
and we just do
it based on your
usage, based on
your behavior.
So we try to optimize
that message possible.
We get to 80 or
83%, not yet 90,
so we're going
to use your
prompts and try to
get it up to 90.
You're more than welcome
to take the whole thing.
You know,
obviously, I just
build this stuff because.
You know,
and for those that
are interested, you
can check that
link and there's a
playground or a translate
section, and you
can see how I
translate a 1,200 token
prompt down to
like, I don't know,
it's it's like 100
tokens or something.
So how do you currently
use it with a request
date before they're
having the credit in?
Oh, okay. Here
let me show you.
Again, this is
this is what I did.
So here, let me share
my screen quick.
So this is the
UI I create just
to show how the
thing works.
So quickly,
I go in here, I'm
creating a prompt. This
prompt is essentially
creating a Node.js app.
So you can see the
original tokens.
I'm going to let that
run for a minute.
And then there's
a system prompt.
This is it.
So I'm basically
converting, I'm converting
the text into a logo
graphic structure.
you know, using, I
do go crazy. I kept
it pretty simple. I
don't want to make
it more verbose
than it need to be.
We can, then we
can go in here. You
can optimize it
further if you want to
use different
characters. You know,
if you want Mandarin
or Japanese or
Arabic or whatever
language you want,
you can use super
optimizations and
choose what
characters you want.
But generally,
the default's
probably the
best. This is what
I get the best
results from.
And then just to
see it here, it's
still, I'm using a
cheap model here,
but I'm going
to just go ahead
and hopefully
it's almost, done.
And so you see it's
its entire app,
right? And I can
then translate this
entire application
into this structure.
I'm not sure why it's
going so slow today,
but let's just
go and let's hit
translate now and
see what happens.
All right, so
I'm taking this
entire, this entire
1,200 tokens or
whatever it is,
and then I've
condensed it down
to this structure.
So I'm encapsulating
the information,
but I'm encapsulating
it in symbolism.
Now,
this is an 87% reduction
in this particular
example.
Now to prove
that that works,
all we needed,
and I actually
did it before
it was done, but
we can go here
to chat GPT.
And without me
giving it any prompt
at all, it'll
recognize the
structure and we'll
go, Let's use just
a fast model
UTP4. I'll put it.
It recognizes
it inherently.
Crazy, right?
This is what you
call an emergent
capability of a
language model.
I can't tell you
why that works.
I love to tell
you why it works.
I have absolutely no
idea, but it does.
Can you take databases
or entire files
and have it converted
like that too?
So when you're
using a vector,
it's just like
it's spoken, right?
Yeah.
When you're
using a vector,
you can encapsulate
your vector information
in the SynthLang
format and you take
what's verbose and,
you know, huge, and you
can get, in some
cases, down in 98%
reduction in the
overall size. It works
particularly well for
vectors for exactly that.
And the similarity
aspect of the vectors
maintains. So when
you're searching
report, even though
it's not in English,
it still figures out
what it's needed.
Anyway, I
copied that into
Requesti's prompt option.
Actually, I'm
going to let...
Which LAMS does
this work with?
Like, you used it now?
All of them, yeah.
So actually, just as
a quick example here,
if you go in, I
used OpenRouter, but
I'm going to switch
this if I have time.
this to Requesti.
But if you go here
to the settings,
you can see
that different
models. I just ran
that in Sonic 3
.7, but here's
all the models,
every model that's
on OpenRouter.
And you can choose what
your default model is.
You can, you know,
I've got playground.
If you want to
test it further,
you can play
around with it.
Yeah.
And you can just
try it, boom.
And this actually,
it'll self-validate.
So this acts as a
validation of the, so
this is the original
one, this is the
output, and then this
translates it back.
So I'm basically
kind of like
Google Translate
for symbolic,
neuro-symbolic reasoning.
It also lets you hack
any LLM, by the way,
but don't do anything
stupid with that.
It bypasses pretty
much every guardrail.
Guard rails are built
usually in natural
language, right? So
symbolic reasoning
bypasses the natural
language guardrails.
So how do you
use it yourself?
Like,
do you use your own
interface on the
webble or like do
you use it directly
from common by this
an automated process
like when you're
doing? I put it
in my prompt. I put
it in the prompt.
So in,
oh, up until request
he showed up, I
would put it in my
root code prompt
and then it would
basically, you know,
reformulate its
internal thinking
process using my
compressions. question.
And that works. I
don't know why it
worked. It just works.
And so when the request
you guys showed
up, I saw a little
button that said, use
your own, use your
own prompt. I just
popped it in there.
Very neat. We've got
just enough time, Rove,
to have, have Joseph
for his lightning
talk, and then we can
go to the open format.
Krasman, is that
okay if we hold on to
your question and saw
the open format part?
Awesome. Okay.
Joseph, you all set?
Yep.
Hey, hey,
hey,
everyone.
My name's Joe.
I'm from Synaptic Labs.
I am a vibe coder like
probably most of you
and a proselytizer
of Obsidian, which is
a note-taking app that
is amazing and allows
you to pull from a lot
of community plugins
that, you know,
there's sort of base
functionality in
Obsidian, but then there's
all these nice little
plugins you can get
that do fun things.
and I would highly
recommend if you are a
vibe coder like myself,
start in Obsidian,
make your own
plugins, because
it's actually
fairly simple and
straightforward.
There's pretty
good documentation,
and especially
if you don't want
to deal with like
front end stuff
or really even
back end stuff,
like everything's kind of
built for you
to already use.
So along those lines,
you know, I also
want to proselytize
MCPs, as I know this
group has been doing
for a few weeks now.
People still don't
really understand how
incredible this thing is,
and I think it's super
important that we are
all hopping on this
bandwagon because I
don't know about you
all, I'm so sick of
everyone coming up with
their own standard for
all this agent stuff.
Like, let's all
agree on one
thing that's
interoperable.
So I absolutely
love the MCP.
And one of the things
I really wanted to do
was create an MCP that's
accessible to people
who have no idea how
to code or use any
of this stuff by just
turning into a plugin.
So this is literally
something right that
you're going to
stick in, you know,
the folder, your
obsidian folder, folder,
and we're going
to see it gives
you this quick
little setup.
You go to show
configuration,
you copy this,
you open that,
and there you go.
It's going to be
ready and logged
in for you to have
your tools to control
your obsidian.
Now one thing I want
to mention is I think
we're starting to
actually move towards
actual like natural
language programming, like
we're slowly getting
there where we can
abstract away the actual
code. And one way,
you know, I think is
really important to show
is how do we sort
of have this notes
database, right, where
the note itself can act
as a prompt or guide
for the LLM to do
actions rather than me
having to code the action
by using an MCP with
sort of those atomic
tools that it can
string together, right?
So as an example
of this, we have
just these normal
tools, you know,
it can edit a
note, read a note,
it can generate
text, it can,
search your vault. It
can move things around.
Those are the
atomic tools, right,
that we use. And then
I have this little
project manager,
which I'm hoping
it'll work when I
show you guys, the
idea being similar
to like the plan mode
in Klein or Rue or
whatever, right?
You know, have it
planned something first
and then also have
a checkpoint tool
within this toolbox
so that it doesn't
like just keep going
and going and going
and doing like more
stuff than you asked
it to do. So it can
plan out, hit that
checkpoint and kind
of check in with you.
So one of the first
things I have this
do in its prompt,
which I can bring
up in a second, is
I wanted to find
this file and read
it first of all.
And the idea is
you have this map
of contents
file, which tells
you a little bit
about whomever.
It has this to,
you know, help you
navigate the vaults.
You can have the
plugins that it has
access to and any
sort of instruction.
So for example,
I think I have,
you know, project
management.
Whenever I ask you
to start a project,
right, I want you to
follow these rules.
And then you
have all these
templates, for example.
Templates, for example.
So if I wanted to make a
map of content
for a folder,
this is just a
prompt, right?
That it goes
and fills in. If
I wanted to
create a project,
it's just a prompt
that it fills in.
So we can do something as
simple as like
create a project
for my coding efforts
on something called,
Claud Cidion that
is a plugin for
Obsidian to use
an MCP server.
Let's see if this
actually works. One of
the things I've been
working really hard on
is like how vague
can you be with this
thing and it still do
what you wanted to do.
And of course, Claude
is going to crash
when I'm trying to
show you guys this.
So let's... Guaranteed
in the demo.
vagueness is my
problem. Like it,
I struggle with a
consistent mechanism
to execute or
invoke the MCP.
Yes. And prompting is
the key. And again,
like the navigation
of the note so
it can prompt itself
is like super key.
So you'll see here
I actually have a
project that is
specific to the vault.
And again, the
first that pretty
much all the
prompt says is
like, go look at
this file first.
Okay, let's see
if this works
again. Create a project.
for an obsidian
plugin that connects
to an MCP server.
I'm also hoping
I don't actually
have this project
in here already,
but let's see.
Okay, so you guys
have probably all seen
this before, but it's
listening, right?
It's going and reading
my map of contents.
It found the
project template.
It's looking at
the project demo.
So it's also
looking at, oh, is
there already
a project here?
It's searching to see
if there's anything,
any information
about MCP servers.
It is finding
the documentation
I have for MCP servers.
Now it's going
to go, you know,
do all of its
research and stuff.
See, this is my issue
with MCP, right?
It's like, why
did it need to do
so much freaking
research when it
could have just
executed the **** thing
in the first step?
Yeah, totally.
Right? It's an
overachiever.
It's like, I don't
want you to do. I
don't want to burn
$2 just to discover
that it needs to run
the certain command
that I told it to do
in the first place.
But these tools
aren't incentivized
financially to reduce
that request time,
right? They make
money per request.
But not in this
case, right?
Because I'm just using
the cloud desktop
app. So I'm not
getting charged
additional for running
this right now.
I think is this
more on APIs for
production
applications? Like,
this is a really good,
cool use case for
personal people in
the given context.
But if we want to
build it for customers,
this is a very
expensive operation.
It would probably
cost us probably a
buck or two and do
it a thousand times.
It's broke.
Well,
not if you're using the
client rules or
cursor rules.
That sort of solves
that problem.
So, but if you're
building an agent for
a customer, you
don't need. need MCP.
You've got direct
API access anyway.
So this is like this
kind of intermediary
use case, right? That's
what's weird about MCP.
I like the fact that
you've got the sort
of, you know, HTTP
protocol as well as the
output of the terminal
that you can use.
I get a question
for you, are
you using any
of the new SSE
capabilities that
came out recently?
No, is that the
parallelization?
It's exactly what
it is. And it came
out, I think last
one. week. And
it's something I've
been playing with
a lot. So when
you're using the MCP,
one of the challenges
you have, especially
with sort of long running
processes, is it's
got a really short timeout
on it. And sometimes
these things take,
you know, minutes to
execute, right? Deep
research, for example.
If you, if you
invoke the SSE
capability, what that
does, it allows for
an incremental
reporting of what's
happening back to
the chat client.
So you could do a
stepped response.
You know,
I started at the process,
which it stops that
timeout from happening.
And then 30 seconds
later, it says, I'm
still working on it.
And then two minutes
later, it might say
I've completed. Or it
could just be like a
CLI style output that
gives you a step by
step along the way.
But it's a really
nice, easy way to
solve some of the
timeout issues.
Yes, I haven't been
able to look into
it yet, but I was
very excited to see
that because even
this, right, is too
sequential. Like
it could have been
doing all that
research, for example,
and it doesn't,
I have to get it
to use this tool
more. There's a
batch read tool
where it just like
reads everything
at once, right?
It doesn't need
to be doing all
this sequentially.
It could be doing
multiple things
at the same time.
Yeah, and that's
kind of what I was
trying to do with
my Spark example was
the idea of concurrency
and parallelism
within the
structure of an MCP.
So you're making,
so the UI, like
what you're
showing, acts as
the kind of central
orchestrator.
then it can sort of
spawn sub threads,
if you will, that
execute independently
and then report back
when they're done.
This is awesome,
by the way.
I love this.
Yeah.
And one of the things,
like, we're all
in it again,
so we're like,
this is so cool,
like, and so
easy to, like,
throw these
things together.
Like, no one outside this
group really
understands, like,
that we're here,
that we've, like,
arrived at this stage.
like even me showing
this to people they
still can't like
quite wrap their head
around it this is
another issue since
it's so verbose right it
always like runs out
of its uh its time
oh that's that's
use the vector that
solves that problem
so the vector acts as
the short term and
long term memory and
then you can just
basically clear your
uh your cache with
the and the if use
the open a i SDK it
takes you like two
minutes to get that
that up and running
Yeah,
I will definitely
look into
that in the
parallelization.
But again, the
idea is like people
can't access
this stuff yet.
Like, it's super easy
for us, but I really
want people to like
start using this stuff
and understand and
be able to actually
kind of just program
in natural language
because that's where
we're moving. It's a
lot more accessible
than it ever has been
if you're just given
sort of the right
tools. So the next
phase of this project is
I'm actually trying
to build out an out.
application that is
sort of the Omni MCP,
where you can
call into it from
anywhere just through
a function call.
And then you
just add all your
APIs, your web
hooks, your
databases, whatever
it might be,
right into an interface.
And then you just
have your one-stop
shop. You can
kind of access it
from anywhere as
long as, you know,
you have the password.
So I'm starting
deploying AI
inside corporation.
What worked is
I did a half
-day training session on,
you know, what is AI
and what are the limits
of the models and
inference and all that
kind of stuff and then
give them a half day
to do a coding hackathon
and then that tool
that i point gtreev
that does a code count
and looks at the time
that it would take it
or the cost and that
seems to open people's
eyes and go hey we can
actually use this to
get real work done
but without actually
experiencing it and kind
of understanding the
rough edges people
dismiss it pretty quickly.
Just quickly, I
saw a question in
the chat. So how
to use templates?
You treat them like
a prompt, right?
So I said, I want
you to make a memory.
And it knows, based
on another prompt I
had, I need to find
the memory template.
I need to fill out
a memory, and then I
need to stick it in
my memories folder.
And the idea here is
to actually support
in the future fine
-tuning a model,
right? So I'm trying
to format sort
of the conversation
in a reduced way,
showing the human,
the assistant, and the
tool use to help eventually
fine-tune a model
so that we don't even
need to run it on this
stuff, right? You
just get a pretty good
$12 billion parameter
model, just run it
locally. It can do 90%
of what you need to do.
You know what
you should do.
Use the DeSpy library
and make it JSONL.
And then the benefit
to that is it'll
run locally, but you
can also take the
JSONL and then fine
-tune any model. They
all use JSONL, right,
for fine-tuning.
you're good to go yeah
so actually i have
another obsidian plug
-in that is a synthetic
data generator and
that's exactly what
it does is like after
it's done you can
press a button it
converts everything into
a jason l so you can
easily just you know
upload it to hugging
face or whatever do
some unsloth have your
way with yeah yeah
that's cool yeah you're
killing you're you're
you're tell you Dr.
Dre. I mean, doctor
for nothing. I'm not
even a doctor, guys.
This is, this is
Professor Synaps
over here. He's
our AI avatar.
And so he's the doctor.
You're a doctor to me.
If Dr. Dre can
be a doctor,
then you can be a doctor.
Well, thanks all for
your time. I'm going
to, so you guys can
use this right now.
I'm going to stick
the GitHub in here.
It's literally just you
create like a folder
in your obsidian
vaults under plugins
called CloudSity and
the files in there and
it'll just it'll just
work hopefully now we
now i know maybe
someone else on the call
might know if the clod
desktop client supports
server send events
yet i'm going to go
on a limit and say it
probably doesn't but
maybe um but the uh the
rube definitely does
so that that's cool so
you're you're testing
this all just in the
desktop client yes
for now um but again
And the idea is like,
I want you to
be able to just
essentially, it's
a tool itself.
Like, it's just
a question tool.
And it sends it off,
right, to wherever you
want to send it from
wherever you're sending
it into a central
location. And it can
do all the things.
That's cool.
There's so many things
we could do with it.
I'm struggling for
enterprise use cases like
Guy mentioned. You
know, it's like there,
sometimes the simpler
solution might be the
better solution when it
comes to enterprises.
Like the MCP seems
useful for things
where you're technical
and you want a nice
clean abstraction. But
I'd say for like 90
% of use cases, especially
with Enterprise,
just build the function
hooked directly
into whatever app
you've already built.
What difference
does it make?
So I think it's named
weird, right? Because
I think what their
intent was with MCP
model context protocol
was to allow you to
access your private
data in an LLM that
doesn't, really hasn't
trained on your private
data yet people are
using it for full
use because it really
invokes a method and
returns something
and so it's it's got
this weird i don't know
birthright or whatever
i find that the
tools built into like
root line or root
code um are sufficient
right it can web browse
and i can use the
command prompt i can
do everything else from
that well you know
what else you could do
and this is something
i don't know if we
still have the guys
from from Requestion.
But we could induce
the same function
by basically having
sort of like a
parser. So let's
say we use a hashtag
or something, something
that's unique.
And as part of the
request, all we really
need to do if we
want to invoke an MCP
on the proxy, let's
say that the guys at
request, do you
want to have an MCP
proxy? We'd put in
something like hashtag,
analyze, underscore code.
When that is passed
to the proxy, it sees
that commitment.
and then could
potentially execute the
MCP request directly
on the proxy, skipping
any of the requirement
for that discovery
phase that we
were seeing from Joe
a second ago, right?
And that solves a
lot of the, you know,
verbosity issue that
we have where it takes
five minutes for the
thing to figure out how
to execute the thing
that it should have
done in the first step,
right? So it's kind
of like a slash command
on Discord or Slack,
right? It's just a
command that needs to
be picked up. And that
would be way faster.
You could bypass
the LLM altogether.
A lot of these
requests don't even
need to hit an
LLM. They just
need to hit a
vector or some other
API service and
give you a result.
And that would also
save your money.
Yeah. So actually,
I think we talked about
it when we met for
the first time. And
I think that's the
direction of MCP tools
should go to. As in,
there's no reason for
people to handle all
those crazy animations
on their local hosts.
So we're definitely
looking into ways
of integrating a
lot of different MCP
tools into the
proxy and using some
directives, just
like you mentioned.
If anyone here is
interested in collaborating
in that or has an
idea how it can be
useful in an organization,
we're more than
happy to try and
figure out of it. Well,
I've got a rudimentary
implementation you
can steal or borrow
if you're interested.
I attempted,
I'm not going to lie,
you guys inspired
me last week.
week. I'm like, oh,
geez, these guys are
killing that. How
in the world are
they doing it? But
it's nowhere near
as elegant as yours.
I'm not going to lie.
But basically what
I was trying to do
is I created a proxy.
And then I basically am
executing the commands.
And you can arbitrarily
define the commands
as long as they're
not something that
exists commonly in the
code or things that you're
passing to the proxy.
And then basically
it grabs that and then
it sort of hijacks the
request. So when when
it sees that you're
requesting a certain
hashtag or slash, it'll
then redirect to a
different tool and then
give you the result of
that redirection versus
the selection of Sonnet
3.7 or something.
Yeah. Yeah. So I
actually took a look
at the code. So
I guess I think
the tricky part is
like the parsing.
If you only base
like if you base,
if you use the hashtag
convention, then
it's It might be tricky
to pass arguments,
but that's
definitely like a
direction that
we're exploring,
trying to figure
out how to do that.
So I think I have
a solution. The
hashtag thing is
problematic because, you
know, hashtags
exist in Markdown
frequently. So you
can't use a hashtag
because it'll confuse
it with headers.
You can't use slashes
because any kind
of, you know, Jason
is going to break.
So what I was
thinking, and this is
you guys can tell
me if I'm crazy,
the back to the
synth laying I
was showing
you earlier, we
could use arbitrary,
unusually.
symbolic references.
And when you look at
the synth-lang examples
that I ended up choosing,
those are arbitrary
and uncommonly used.
I wasn't going and
using Mandarin characters
that were common,
like China or something,
that would be used
frequently, but I
was using things that
were the most unusual
of the characters that
would show up infrequently.
And then I would
add a secondary sort
of command that along
with the unusual
command or symbol would
mean it's pretty much
never going to happen.
So the two sort of
allow it to be found
and not interfere with
common slashes or,
you know, pound hash
mark kind of things.
That I hope that
makes sense.
Yeah, yeah,
that's, of course.
Yeah,
so I think we've had
a great, this has been
a particularly
interesting session today.
Anyone have any comments?
I got some real.
In SIFLang,
did you try to
feed back into
the input of it,
the previous output?
Yeah, well,
you talk about
the translation,
I think. Yes.
And the translation is
the most important part.
What you want
is the output
to be the same as you,
semantically the same
as the original input.
Now, it's not
going to be exactly
the same. It's
a translation.
So, but the meaning has
to remain, right? So,
and the way that I
went about testing it
was I did a similarity
-based sort of
search, I guess
you'd say, on that
information. And then
I used DSPI to optimize
it to a point where I
got sort of coherence
in both the input
and the response.
And when I got to
about 90%, it basically
didn't make any
difference. So even though
it was different,
like the input wasn't
exactly the same or the
output wasn't exactly
the same as the original
input, the meaning
remained. Like when
I showed you guys the
example earlier, the
folder structure was
still the same folder
structure, the instructions
were still the same
instructions. They
were just described
slightly differently,
but not enough to
directly affect
the implementation
of the code or
whatever it is I
was doing with it.
We're in crazy
land, I think,
at this point,
but anyway.
Can I show you
something, cool, Roof?
Sure.
What do you showed
you like what I was
working on but I made
it like way cooler
now all right so
we got to where
we're going to plot
on Neo 4j so I'm going
to run the analyzer
and it's going
to plot the entire
code base and the Neo
4j and I got the
cross functional um
thing working
one second let me
just get it so it
plots on the graph
Goddains?
Yeah.
The more vibe, the
better if you ask me.
And while we're
waiting, just want to
give a shout out to
Requesti. I think it
was our first
foundation purchase. So
we are customers.
Okay. So it's
analyzing all the
files and then it's
plotting them. It's
also creating
embeddings and a
whole bunch of cool
stuff like that.
So what exactly you're
doing like you're
creating embeddings
for what purpose um
all of the uh the
functions the files the
methods are getting
embedded for my semantic
search tools i built
a whole tool set
um for utilizing
this new neo 4j graph
see here all right so
we've got everything
the entire code
base here let's say,
plotted in the
Neo4J, right?
And then we can use the
tools that I created
to query this for
whatever purpose we
need. And I kind
of built a set of
instructions so that it
uses these tools in a
way that humans would
use to solve complex
problems. But some
of the tools it has
available to it is it
can look for circular
dependencies. It can
pull entire dependency
trees. can look
for the nodes that
have most connected
modes. It can find complex
files, find fan in
and fan out nodes.
And then the big
thing is, is that
it can pull context
on nodes. So,
like, when I want to go
edit a file or a node,
I can say,
see,
there's like a
file here. We'll
just run the node
context tool on.
parser.tser.ts file.
I'm surprised you haven't
added an MCP
interface to this.
I'm still like working
on it, but it should
run the tool on this.
And then it'll give
you a complete context.
It'll tell you everything
that is connected
to this file's node.
And then everything
too hops out
from it too is
what it was doing.
I changed it around
and it seems to have
an error. because it
was like playing with
it but and then there's
also like a code
overbase tool that
gives me a complete
readout of like an
overview of the entire
code but essentially
it's taken the neo
4j graph and I've
just built a bunch of
tools and like you
can see these are like
files functions
variables the green are
the variables the
blue are the functions
the yellow or the pink
are the files brown
are the directories
and you can see it
how everything is
connected and how it's
connected cross file
wise with each other.
And then I just
built a bunch
of tools that use
this information
to give you.
This is Python?
No, this is
TypeScript right now.
Okay. Is what it's
set up as. Did
you publish this
on a Git somewhere?
No, but I'm going
to, but it's like, I
want to make it so it
works a lot better.
So other people can
easily just use it.
I've been
refining it. I've
been working on
it. It's just
some few things
that are fixed.
Yeah.
It's like I just put
it out there, you know,
and then people complain
and I fix it up.
Well, maybe I
should do that.
I'll just do that today.
You know,
it's never, if it's
full, if it's fully
baked, I, I spend
too much time on it.
Okay.
I think what you built
would actually be a
great addition to
some of the stuff I've
been building lately.
The, The one thing that
would be interesting,
rather than Neo4J,
I've been looking
at using the
Network X library
from Python,
which is basically
what Neo4J is
built on, as far
as I can tell.
And that would give you
a **** of a lot more
options, and you get
direct graph access.
Well, like this
thing here, it
gives me all
the embeddings.
And for the files,
like, it even tells it,
like, if it's async or
not, and it's, like,
got embeddings. They
can search through
embeddings and find
semantically similar code.
It can do a whole
bunch of stuff.
It's got pretty
robust details in the
nodes themselves
and the classes and
everything. And
how many dimensions
are you running in
your embeddings,
15,
67 or whatever
the number is?
I don't know. I just
use like a mini model
to embed. And then it
also like, like when
you document like a
function or a code,
it embeds that
documentation
too into it also.
So it can use that for
part of the search.
Has anyone tried weviate
for this problem?
because they also have
like a lightweight
graph system and
combined with the vector.
The weird thing
here, the word
thing here is
this is kind
of the poor man
to neural net.
You know, and if
the data set that
you're training on
is so much smaller,
like the number of
tokens that go in,
is it feasible
to train your
private data into
a very small model
that a large
model talks to?
Yes.
And I think I
understand. I think
what you're saying
is using one model
to train another
model or optimize the
model. Is that
what you're asking?
No, I'm saying
take your private
data set that the
public model, large
model, was never
able to access.
It's trying a
very small large
language model using
LLM techniques.
And is the cost of
that low enough that
then you can interface
the large language
model to that? Like if
it has questions about
your local data, it
fits that model. because
everything else like
vector databases,
the Neo4J, these are all
approximations
of a neural net.
And we already know how
to build a neural net.
So are you basically
saying that's
turning your code
base into a lower
adapter into a language
model and then do
everything. Small
language model. So
maybe it's not a
large, it's an SMM.
Yeah, but that's
exactly what Despi does,
right?
Inherently, you're
essentially creating
a secondary, you
know, hyper-optimized
prompt that allows
you to, you know,
create a kind of
secondary model that
gets hit before
the primary model,
right? Is it a
proper model that has
all the characteristics
of an LLM?
Yeah, well,
it's made, well,
proper is as in a
compiled, you know,
neural net? No, proper
as in like, does it
act like the, the, a
neural net? Yes. I guess
it depends on how
you describe proper.
I think that we've
become acclimatized to
high torch and the
compilation process
of sort of traditional
mixture of experts'
models and that whole
sort of approach
to fine-tuning and
training using GPUs.
But as you point
out, most of these
models don't require
that level of
sophistication. And
that's why I like
DeSpy. It acts as a
kind of, you know,
abstraction that
still uses, you know,
PyTorps approach, but
allows you to basically
just have a JSONL
file that acts as
a that sort of sits
in between the two.
But my point
being is that,
you know, they're
training these large
models on trillions
of tokens of data.
And like any corporate's
private data
model is probably,
you know,
one, one
millionth of that
in size, right? and
so it actually might
be affordable to use
the same technique
we use for large
language models for a
small language model
and have that private
because that's the
big tension I think is
yeah the neural net
knows a lot about general
things but it knows
nothing about my
specific business from
an enterprise standpoint
yeah that that is a
that is a good point
there's so many
opportunities in the space
right now I think that
we're in the the sort
of wild early days of
whatever this phenomenon
is that we found
ourselves in the midst
of and it's one of
those rare moments that
a random vibe coder
like chris or whomever
can go out and literally
invent something
that's never been done
before by following
some random rabbit hole
and seeing where it
leads and that's what's
kind of exciting one
thing that i did work
on just like a week
and a half ago was
building i built a program,
I put on my GitHub,
I put a link in the
chat to allowing the LLMs
to self-conceptualize
themselves using a
few biologic functions
about like how
antibodies and genes work
and like how homeoplasticity
works so that
the AIs just think on
its own concepts and
then just build out the
graph automatically.
So it basically plots
a whole knowledge
graph with its own
knowledge automatically.
And then if you have
all of the knowledge
from an LLM,
right, plot it on a
knowledge graph, then
you can separate the
reasoner from the
knowledge and then just
have a bunch. Isn't
that like a thing?
Yeah, it's
already a thing.
That is the inherent
structure of a reasoning
language model, right?
So that's basically
what you're doing
when you're using
thinking in test time
sort of optimization.
So what you're
doing is essentially
explicitly defining the
neural structure,
hypothetically,
but that's going
to induce all kinds
of latency in the
model, most likely,
right? So what I
think the guys that,
like, Dispo and
others have done is
they've done it in
a way that doesn't
require that level
of sort of, you know,
analysis of the
inherent structure.
It kind of just
automatically does it
without having to
think about why.
Yours is going to
probably take a process
that took 20 seconds
and make it 20 minutes.
well i was thinking
that we just had like
one knowledge graph
with all the knowledge
and then like just
have reasoners that are
like a lot smaller
that could go on like
phones and things and
they could all just
connect one big knowledge
that's deep that's
g spo that's exactly
what gspo does yeah
look up gspo that you
you you've uh you've
discovered deep gspo
without even knowing it
that's literally the
purpose of that algorithm
and if you ever use
deep seek that was
their big aha, right?
They basically took
the previous model and
applied GSPO to it.
It's exciting to
discover the things that
are being discovered
independently for sure.
Yeah, that was on.
So you say Dispo,
like, do you mean
that this pilot you
mentioned earlier?
No, no, GSPO, I think
it's GSPO, I think
is the acronym.
I don't remember
exactly what it stands
for. GSPO, okay.
Yeah, and so GSPO
is essentially
the reinforcement
algorithm
that was used,
in, I think,
Gwen QWQ back
in December.
And that was the
guys in China at
Alibaba that came
up with Gwen.
Then the guys at DC
basically took that and
ran with it and trained
it on a whole bunch
more data. And then
DeepSeek was launched.
Now,
back in September,
I created something
called Strawberry Pie.
I don't know if you
guys remember that
project, but basically
Strawberry, Strawberry,
Pi was a rudimentary
implementation
of GSPO on the newly
released O1 model.
So what I did is I
took 2,500 reasoning
steps and I put it
in a JSONL model,
and then I trained
Lama 3.2 on it, and
then Lama 3.2 became
a reasoning model.
And I used Phi,
the Phi 3 at the
time, I think
it was called,
from Microsoft.
And essentially
that's what it did. It
created the ability
for it to do test
time-based thinking.
So when it made the
request, it could
sort of reflect on
why and what it was
doing inherently in
the neural net versus
a secondary agentic
process, which you
see frequently.
So the neural net
itself was doing
the sort of reasoning
and multi-step
process versus
secondary requests
to the neural net
or language model.
So we're all kind
of doing the same
stuff. apparently
the deep seek
guy guys were just
better at marketing
what we'd been
doing for months
just saying
hey thanks for that
inside very good yeah
it's exciting times
you know and I'm sure
that the GSPO stuff
was probably vibe coded
on a random you know
exploration of 01
let's be honest like
none of these guys
that are inventing stuff
are are super geniuses
that that are inventing
a vacuum they're
probably doing the
same stuff we're
doing they're just
they're just putting it in
the form of an academic
paper where i'm
just publishing it
randomly on a tuesday
afternoon for a linked
in post right i guess
i spend more time
doing academic papers
is it's like why why
generating academic
papers the next thing
like after wipe quoting
or that's already a
thing i think what
you know paper code
paper vibing or vibe
papering or something
like that all right
we're on we're at time
here this this was
a good one i think
i i really and oh we
had one more presentation
we skipped uh we
yeah i i don't have
a call 1 30 today so
yeah we can we
can do the next
next week are we
do next week if you
prefer we're kind
of out of time
um but yeah next
week all right
Yeah, for those are
interested, again,
we're doing the
ambassador program.
So I think Guy you
mentioned, you're
interested. I'm sure
we got a few others.
I'm looking for
three people who want
to get a little exposure
on the ambassador
page so I don't
have placeholders.
And I'd like you
to actually do the
actual work as
well. But, you know,
basically that's
what I'm looking for.
A little diversity
if we can.
We need to get more women
involved in our crew.
I don't know. we're
too many dudes
I don't have a
solution to that
problem other than
to say we need more
diversity so invite
invite some diversity
if you know someone
that might be interested
i'm pretty confident
as soon as we move out
from the bs code
environments like the
amount of women will
start increasing but as
long as all the demos
are happening like the
through code inside
a bs code environment
i think it's going to
be doers mostly you're
saying that we're
dudes love nerdy stuff
more than women
absolutely like as soon as
you're bringing in some
design user interface
and other things like
like instantly more
options okay yeah i
i i apologize i'm a
i'm a nerd i i like
hard complicated things
and i don't that's just
we're uncomfortable
and rube there's a
couple of women that i'm
aware of that you
know you might be able
to reach out to on
LinkedIn that probably
follow you already that
could potentially create
some more exposure
for that side of the
of the audience yeah
okay well we'll give
it we'll give it a
we'll try to solve that
and yeah I guess we
didn't have a chance to
do any any real agentic
foundation updates
tons of interest what
can I say agentics
is really hot right
now so let's let's see
where this goes all
right thanks everyone
that's it for today
I was particularly
chatty I guess we
blew through more time
than I was expecting
but appreciate you
all and if you need
anything ping me on
WhatsApp or Discord and
Martin I'm gonna take
you up on your offer
to help with some
of the Discord stuff
so and if anyone else
wants to collaborate
create content do
whatever just let us
know we're looking
for volunteer we're
all volunteers here so
next time.
Thank you.
Thanks guys. Bye.