all right here we
are the April 4th the
what did the Americans
call yesterday like
Liberation Day or
something yeah but I won't
get in the tariffs
although I did build
a tariff app but which
I won't share apparently
it's it's too
inflammatory according
to my wife so we we
won't go go there all
right so for me this
week has been it's been
really about the
automation of a lot of
Who do we got on
tap for today?
We've got a, so
we have a couple
lightning talks.
We've got Ocean. He's
going to be
covering some of the
stuff he's been
doing with rust micro
kernels and then
some vibe coding,
how he goes about it.
And then Benzzi,
Benz's going
to be joining
us closer to the
bottom of the
air around 1230.
And he's got a new
designer mode for Roo code
that I'm excited to
see. that should be
really good all kinds
of modes exploding you
know uh into the realm
right now awesome yeah
and that's the hot
topic of the week you
know there's obviously
a lot a lot of interest
in agentic development
like it's it's the
thing and there's
almost like a dichotomy
and i i'm probably too
honest in my assessment
of a you know agents
and agentics but i'm
that's how i that's
all you can really be.
The worst the economy
does, the more phone
calls and opportunities
I seem to get.
And there seems to be
a direct correlation
between the
market tanking and
companies saying, you
know what, we need
more agents in agent,
agentic systems.
And the reality is
that is not necessary,
it's a dark reality.
The reality is that's
probably an easy, quick
way to replace the people
they're either going
to lay off or in the
process of laying off.
And I don't know how
to necessarily
reconcile that part of
Agenetics. And it's the
part of Agenics that I
really don't like. Like,
I don't like the fact
that this technology
can be used to, to, I
want to empower people,
not replace people,
but that is part of
the same sort of,
I guess the flip
side of a coin. I
don't know what the,
what the analogy
is. But it's something.
that I think we
have to be cognizant
of and address,
and that's all like
we can really do.
So they're rant over.
But what I really want
to show you this week
is the new features
that came out in Rue
Code, I think it was
Saturday of last week,
which seems
like ages ago,
where they came out
with something called
Boomerang, which
allows you to kind of
orchestrate multiple
modes within Rue.
And what I did is I
took the work that some
of you might be
familiar with around the
Spark protocol and
methodology, which allows
you to create a
specification, pseudocode,
architecture,
refinement,
and completion,
and apply that directly
within the sort
of automated fashion
of using Root. Yes.
It works really,
really, really well for
just set and forget
kind of development, as
long as you give it
a really good plan.
And so what I want
to do is walk some
of the folks today
through how that works
because it works
particularly well.
And Brad,
remind me to give a Jetix
Foundation
update as well.
I'm told I don't
do enough self
-promotion, which is crazy
because I think I
do way too much.
But anyway,
here we are.
I'll let Brad, Nick,
and others handle
the self-promotion
part. I just want to
show you the cool
stuff that you can do.
So let's start there.
All right. So I'm
going to show you
guys some of the
modes, and I'll show
you how to get set
up. If anyone is
following along, feel
free to open up your
BS code and copy
and paste some of
the stuff that I'm
about to show you.
All right.
So,
again, this is technical,
but it's less technical.
You've got to
use BS code.
I'm looking at
ways to automate it
so you don't have
to use VS code, but
that's a problem
for another day.
So the first and
most important part
here is a file called
Rue modes. Too bad
I can't call it Rube
modes. But anyway,
by adding the... modes,
you gain access to
all these different
things, these custom modes
that you can sort of
create. In this case,
you'll see there I've
got things like auto
-coder and debugger
and security reviewer.
So the Spark Orchestrator
basically is a
mode that orchestrates
other modes. So
as you run, it can
then say, well, I need
to code or I need to
do a specification
or I need to secure
it. I need to deploy
it to the cloud or
whatever. And it
can do everything
you define it to do
automatically without
you having to sit there
and babysit it,
which is particularly
exciting.
So in this case, what
I did is I created
this file last weekend
when it came out,
and basically you can
see here that I've
got options here for
like which files it
can edit, you know,
so you can do regular
expressions. So you
can say only edit MDs
if you're in a spec
mode or only edit
certain files for certain
modes, and you can
give limitations to
commands it can run.
So it's pretty cool
from that point
of view. So you
can see, Here,
in the spec mode,
I have the ability
for it to run and
read and edit.
In the architect mode, it
only has the
ability to read.
In the code mode,
it can read, edit,
browse, use MCPs.
By the way,
this particular
ability to define
modes actually works
great because you
can define modes
that only do MCP.
And one of the
drawbacks to a lot of
the MCPs is this
kind of recurring
reading and editing
and looking at
files. And once an
MCP is deployed,
I don't want it to
go and discover the
MCP. I just want it
to execute the MCP.
So for an MCP mode, you
could literally just say,
only run the MCP, and
it really makes it
run more efficiently,
which is pretty
cool. So you see all
the different modes.
All right. So I'm
like, okay, so I
built this system
that can sort of
automatically run, it
can test, it can edit.
And by the way, the
testing is actually
the most important
part. It can
iteratively test until
the thing's done.
But I'm like, can
I create a startup,
like from soup to
nuts or whatever
the expression
is overnight?
So that's what I tried
to do last night.
So in this case, I
went in and I said
a, I want to create
a dynamic phone
agent. So what I
wanted to do was
create a fake
startup. This isn't
real. This is just
me messing around.
That would create an
environment that would
allow you to basically
CC a call agent.
and have that agent
call into your Zoom or
your Google Hangout
or whatever and then
sort of be allow you
to interact with it so
I could say things
like hey call agent go
schedule me a you
know a burrito or CRM
or whatever it is it
want to do so so this
basically was built
overnight it can it can
call I'm not going to
do it if I'm on but
it trust me it uses
bland. So it's basically
just dialing into
the phone number I
give it. I can, it
can auto schedule so I
can schedule it. It can
parse the attachment.
So if you're, if you
invite it as part
of your calendar
invite, you can use an
email service. So you
could basically just
send an email to agent
at your website.com.
It's it's like a
cool little big
startup kind of thing,
but it all works.
So it created a little
web page. It created
the, you know, the
analytics dashboards.
it's got all you know
the actions this was
a hundred percent
created without me doing
anything basically just
saying you know here
here's a here's a guide
so let me show you
what that that process
looks like all right
so add the root code
to your to your your
uh root folder here
and then you'll see
here you have so i'll
show you the file so
lots of stuff here
you'll see that there's a
folder here or file
called rue modes you're
going to want to do
the same thing then
what i did is i created
a read-me file, which
it might have actually
overwritten, but
we'll take a look at
what it looks like now.
So this this
read-me file is
basically saying
how I want to
deploy the actual
application.
So it includes a
combination of spec and
sort of structure.
So I want it to use
resend to send emails.
I want to use Cloudflare
for pages to it's
cheap than want to
pay for it. And I want
to use Blended AI.
There's some
features, there's some
project structure.
This basically guides
the system into what
plans is to create.
Then the first step was
to create the plans.
So these plans
are essentially
what guides the
development.
So when I go in here
and I want it to
be developed, I'm
basically going in here
and saying, go do
this or go do that.
Now I've already gone
ahead and
developed it. So,
but basically
what you're going
in is going in
here to room
and you're going to
select the orchestrator.
Now, a couple of things
to note. it works
i cannot get the the
thing to work with
gemini pro it just
doesn't seem to want
to work and it all
it basically seems to
only really work with
sonnet 3.7 thinking or
sonnet 3.7 so it's
important that you go
in here and create and
use basically sonnet
for now i'm sure that'll
be able to figure
out how to get other
models to work i
haven't had any time
to do that so make sure
you you add different
models if you're
curious how to add
models there's a plus
button here, so you can
add different models,
and you can select
what models. One of
the quirks, though, I
will say of Requesti,
you notice that in for
my Sonnet 3.7 thinking,
I actually am using the
Anthropic API directly.
I don't see an
option in Requesti
for using the
Sonnet 3.7 thinking,
which is kind
of a let down.
But you can also choose
different models here.
For example, I can choose
different locations.
So in this case, I'm
using 3.7. because i was
having trouble with
three point sorry three
point five because
i was having trouble
with three point seven
the benefit to three
point five is you can
choose locations which
speeds up the process
in this case i'm running
this at a u s east
on amazon which is a
really nice feature of
requestee as well in this
case i'm going to
switch back to sonnet 3
.7 i don't uh i guess
wait where is it sonnet
3.7 latest so you can
see here that if you
don't line 3.5. There's
other options. And
3.5 is a bit cheaper
as well, which is nice.
So we can go in there.
I'm going to save that.
And we can go in here.
Now,
for the orchestrator,
I'm going to switch
to a new, a new,
I'm not going
to run on Maine
because I'm probably
going to break
it. So we'll call
it AI Hacker,
Hacker,
Space, Live,
April 4.
Create a new branch.
And I'm just going
to use the copilot.
to create me a
commit message
actually i'm going
to bother doing
that i'm just going
to put an update
we'll pop that can
push all right so now
i break it it's not
going to be a big
deal again and if
you ever do break
something get graph
quick way to roll back
it's not you know
probably later when after
i go i'll probably
just roll back to
wherever i was now
but in this case i'm
going to choose
orchestrator now when you
use the orchestrator
you know there's
a few things you're
going to want to do
what you want to build.
Now, I might want to say,
update the application
to include a dashboard,
a dashboard UI in
slash dashboard.
I guess, spell
it, not that I'd,
you know, dashboard.
This should be
both desktop and,
mobile friendly and
again I'm giving a
guidance the more
guidance you give it the
better but it's get
the general idea and
I've created a local
mode here so I'm just
going to remind it
what the local mode is
so I'm gonna say you
know run you know
and make sure it runs
in the local mode so
you know this basically
allows me to get
you know the I've got
different modes for
the operation of this
app like I've got
the API and I've got
other ways to interact
with. So this is
basically the web UI.
And then one of
the things I do a
lot of here,
because it still
sometimes doesn't,
doesn't flew in.
I'm just reminding it.
Use new underscore
task for each
activity, I
guess, activity.
And I'm going to say
create a
detailed plan in,
plans slash dashboard
now i'm not i'm not
giving a lot of
guidance here because we
don't have a lot of
time so i just want
to we just want to see
what the orchestrator
does i'm going to
switch back to the
uh 3.7 thinking and
i'm going to close the
terminal for now i don't
don't even see that
and let's let's hope
the demo gods smile
on me all right so
now what we're doing
is we're using this
spark orchestrator
again the orchestrator
just orchestrator
different modes.
So I like the thinking
mode here because I
like it to do the
thinking up front and then
I use other models for
the implementation.
So it's taking a look.
I didn't give it a
whole lot of guidance.
I didn't really
tell it what the dashboard
should do or what
I needed on the
dashboard. I'm vibe coding
this at the moment.
This is pretty, but
it's got a starting
point because it knows
this application
because it's already
built and working. Now
I just want a way to
manage it, which so
I didn't create any
kind of admin tool for
it. So in this case,
The things you want
to keep a look out
here is the bottom
left hand corner, the
Spark Orchestrator,
when it switches modes.
If all is working well,
it should switch to
different modes to
create the plans or the
implement the code or
do security checks.
And this will literally
run for hours. Like
I set this before I
go to bed, wake up in
the morning, and I had
this startup built.
Literally that's
all it's involved.
Alright, so now it
wants to switch. So
now it's a switch.
So now it created a
subtask. So this is
a task that spawned
from the original
orchestrator. You
see that it created
its own guidance for
that task. I didn't
create this. It
actually did that
automatically for me.
And it's saying it's
going to create detailed
requirements, including
responsive design
of both desktop and
mobile, user stories,
blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah.
Lots of stuff, right?
And so now these,
so it's in the
specification writer mode.
The specs are the
sort of secret
to making this
work really well.
Without specs, you're
vibe coding
into oblivion.
The specs keeps it off
point, keeps it guided.
You can use things like
Klein Rules as well.
I think I've got
Klein Rules in
this one. Let's
take a little quick.
Maybe I don't.
No, I guess I didn't
put client rules.
Depending on what
I'm doing, sometimes
I'll use Klein
Rules, which helps
guide it even
further. In this
case, I'm not using
the Klein Rules.
For a lot of them,
I actually do
use Klein Rules,
which gives it
sort of how to
code for guidance.
In this case, it's
already built,
so it doesn't
matter that much.
But it's doing its
initial investigation.
It looks like still
using Sonnet 3.7.
I probably should.
Oh,
for spec writing,
I actually
like thinking models.
For implementation,
it should switch to
the other mode. You'll
notice here that
you've got the ability
to change modes.
So for example,
when I have the auto
coder mode uses
the default option,
which is basically
taught at 3.7 or
was 3.5 earlier if
I switched to 3.7.
All right, now it's
creating the
dashboard spec,
saying what it
needs to do.
Again, I didn't
give it a whole
lot of guidance
because I'm kind of
just building for
the **** of it.
And this isn't a real
startup. This is a
fake startup to show
that you can build a
real startup by just
asking kind of thing.
But it's pretty cool.
It'll run.
Now, what I might
do here is I
might just let
it run for the
length of our
AI hacker space.
in an hour or so.
I'll come back
to it and see
what it's done,
what the dashboard
looks like.
But this will literally
be running the entire
time that we're on the
call. So it's pretty
cool. If you're
interested in where and
how to get this, you
can go, I probably need
to do a dedicated
GitHub, but you can grab
my rules file here
and the Rue mode. I've
got a tutorial on
LinkedIn that you can also
see if you're curious.
But basically, all
you need to do is go
into my my gist grab
the uh rue codes file
here i it's not lose
the jason i've only did
that because it needed
to render the jason
but it's it's rue
modes or dot rue modes
no jason just f y click
raw copy and paste it
you can just grab the
whole thing and let's
do a quick little
update on requestee
because it seems to be
great um save my cost
savings is yesterday was
$159 and I spent $69
it I'm not going to
lie I'm a huge fan of
requestee it seems to
you know I'm sitting
at 72% cost savings so
that's that's something
so it's pretty cool
I'm getting quite a
bit of latency today
I'm not sure what what's
up with that yeah so
for for if you're using
it I would suggest
using requestee the
only drawback for
requestee and maybe I'm
just not finding it is
I'm not sure how to
use the thinking model.
I don't think they have
it. Let's just
check here.
So it's a shame
because thinking
model is kind of
the most interesting
part of using
Sonnet. No, they
don't have any
thinking options.
I'm going to
have to reach out
to our friends
that request you
and say add the
thinking model.
All right.
I'm under time today.
I want to go fast
today. I don't want
to slap too much. but
it's pretty powerful,
pretty exciting,
and it totally works.
A question about how you
set up the groups, Roof.
Is that self-defining
when you, an
orchestrator,
when you lay out groups,
or is there another
layer of configuration?
Modes or the...
In the modes.
Yeah,
so those modes,
the label in the
modes defines
the title that
displays in the
RU code system.
I added the
emojis because it
just makes it
easier for me to
see it quickly
because I'm lazy.
And yeah, so the
modes have two parts.
The mode defines
both the role
definition and the
custom instructions.
I think the role
definition is kind
of like a system
prompt, and the custom
instructions is
kind of like the
assistant instructions,
right, if you're
familiar with
prompt engineering.
Don't overdo it.
I find for those,
less is more when
it comes to those,
especially when
it comes to the
custom instructions.
If you need really
detailed guidance, use
either the plans or
the Klein.orgul's
or cursor. Rules if
you're on in cursor.
And those will
work pretty well.
Again, if you're
using rule, you
need client rules.
But as far as set
and forget sort
of, coding goes,
this is the best
that I've been
able to come
up with so far.
It, you know,
it works better
than Manus as far
as my test go.
It does more
complex systems.
And it's, it's
particularly, it works
particularly well. Now,
if you want to use guys,
you know, hack
for VS code,
make sure to set the
rate limiting to a higher
number. The, you can
use it for free with
VS code. If you have
the $4 account. the
guy gave a demo last
week I had to do that,
but make sure that you
set the rate limiting.
The VS code free,
they give you 3.5 for
free and 01, a few
others, but it's heavily
rate limited, and this
is really intense.
So I think you
set it to about,
you know, five
or plus requests
per minute, you
should be okay.
I'm currently running
at like 20 requests
a minute, which is
too much for VS code.
So I have a quick
question on the work
you do before you
even get to Roo.
How big are those
specs and how much time
do you spend on them
in the plans document?
Because that
sounds like that's
where most of the
work goes, right?
Yeah, it is.
Let me show you a quick
thing I did this morning.
This was like a
client project.
And I'm multitasking.
Like while we're
working, while I'm
talking to you right now,
I've got two other
code and code spaces
running fully on client
projects that I'm
working on. So I'm
able to multitask quite
well. I still like
perplexity for this.
I tried using Googles
and Open AI, but for
the most part, for the
types of work I do,
I'm using this. Then
this is actually maybe
next week's demo as
well, but I'll give you
a little sneak peek.
So a lot of what my
customers are coming
to me and asking me is
they're creating services,
right? And the biggest
cost of a lot of
these agentic services
that I'm setting up,
especially for startups,
is the use of
LLMs and metering.
So what they want
to do is they want
to have a kind
of credit system.
And so I'm like, okay,
what if I created a
credit system using the
new meter capabilities
from Stripe? So
Stripe allows you to
meter and build based
on usage, which is the
number. So once I saw
that, I'm like, well,
what if I created a
proxy to other LLMs
and then automatically
have that interact
with the, you know, the
strike cost systems?
So I can see here,
I give it a pretty
simple little
instructions. Using stripe
metering and open AI
chat to be proxy in
typescript and Deno,
give me a complex
architecture and
implementation, include
file folder structure
and so on. And then
I used their deep
research capability.
This took probably
about 10 minutes.
So then it created
a file structure.
It gave me, you
know, various
implementation details.
This is what I fed
the Spark protocol.
Then Spark, which
this actually might be
building it as we speak.
Let's just jump to,
yeah, this has
been running
for a couple
hours, actually.
We can get a little
sneak peek of what that
looks like. So it
went in here and
created, you know, a
whole lot of code, it
would seem. Here's all
the tests. It's currently
working through the
test components.
But you can see
here that it's
basically building
every, you
know, all my, all
my components.
We've got services
and, you know, lots
of stuff that it's
building for me.
But basically all I
fed it was this read
me, you know, create,
you know, create,
I can't show you
because it's coding it.
But yeah, it's building,
it's building the
whole thing. it'll
take a few hours. Like
this isn't something
that'll be done quickly,
but this is what
it looks like.
Rate limiters.
So this will basically
be a meter-based
access system for
anyone that wants
to create a service
that is token-based.
So if you want to
charge your customers
on a consumption
basis per token,
that's what it's
currently building
as an edge
function that I
can deploy on super base.
And this is pretty
much everyone doing any
kind of as a service
agent right now is
charging based on
consumption. So it's, and to
be honest, I couldn't
find any decent
consumption-based systems,
so I had to build it.
I'll open source
that next week.
Rube, I just spoke
with Tibilt from
Requesti and I'm putting
into the chat. Those
are the, if you
select these models,
those are the
thinking models,
3.7 son of
thinking models.
They have a pull
request that's got
to go through with
RUCO before that
it'll be visible
in the drop-down.
Oh, well, there
you go. Thank you.
So, yeah,
they're charging
$300 a month for
metering. Is that
what Ben's saying?
Yeah.
I just heard
about that they,
in the valley,
they raise some
money to build
this, an X
-Stripe engineer.
Oh, no, no, I'm actually
using the striped
metering. I don't think
it costs anything.
yeah i didn't understand
why they have a
separate company for
metering as a sass
and charging for 300
times they create an
interface though yeah
i i just here it's
a really cool service
um i i to be honest
i'm burning sandbox
i never got to the
point of actually not
running in production
but i didn't see
anything about about
uh extra costs for
those are interested
This is probably
the most useful
thing for anyone
working on an agentic
system right now,
billing for it.
So in this
scenario, you know,
it's a meter-based
billing system.
And anyway,
next week I'll
show you how that works.
But maybe I
can bill up my
time per minute
or something.
That's right.
If 15-minute inference
wasn't enough work.
Per question,
you can have AI
listen to the
conversation and then
you just charge
per question.
back to the original
example I was showing
you guys earlier of
that phone agent. The
phone agent is cool.
Like Blandy, you can
sit on the phone and
listen to the call and
I can interact. Hey,
Blandy, do whatever.
But the problem with
Blandy was that it was,
it's expensive. Like
to have it run for an
hour on a phone call
like this would cost,
it's relatively
expensive. It costs $4.70.
Now, if I did that
across lots of
users using the
system, I'd go
broke. So I'm like,
you know, what
if there was a
way to meter that.
And this is just
me following
the rabbit
hole. I have no
intention of
creating a, you know,
a new startup. I
just was curious.
I should create a
startup. Apparently,
these guys are
grazing millions
of dollars on our
ideas. But anyway,
this is a cool feature.
We're checking out.
All right, who do we got?
Super. So, Vince
has made it
through the London
Underground.
Yeah, it's true.
I'm excited to
see this, Bensi.
The idea of a room mode
in designer capacity,
boy, it's just, it's
opening up so many doors.
Yeah,
yeah. So I jump
on the, you know,
the same red as
Rube started.
Sorry, then my windows.
So what I did,
I took the,
can you guys
see the screen?
Yes.
Okay, cool. So I
took the original
roof repo and added
to Claude because
I didn't want to
bother with the
JSON structure and
write it myself.
And I told to
Claude that,
hey, I'm using
an AI tool.
I want to create
with the same
structure, something
around design and
look at the
accessibility, you know,
add some nice
paddings and margins.
look at the contrast,
look at the colors
and everything, which
is, you know, the
UXUI best practice.
And then it's added
an explanation for the
read-me because I
uploaded to my repo and
open-sourced it and
gave me the actual JSON.
And then I copy-paste
it into RU code.
This is already
explained by Roof
that you add,
you click this.
and you just added
and then it appears
maybe you have to
restart maybe not but it
appears as an additional
design reviewer
or you can rename it
as you want you can
add some other stuff
and and the jason
file makes it possible
that it becomes a
quite a structured
instruction so you've
got an introduction
here a definition and
you've got like
a specific custom
instructions that you
can add more than that.
And then I was thinking
over that, hey,
why not hook up
an MCP server and
bring in some
trending fonts from
Google fonts?
And you can even
connect this concept
to a company,
brand guidelines.
So the design review
will know your
brand, your brand
colors or the hex
codes. and you don't
need to bother with
a manual review
of the front hand.
So that's it,
you know, just
a quick play
with a rule mode.
Did you implement
the MCP server?
No, no, I just started
a few hours ago,
so I'm going to do
it this evening.
What I wanted
to ask you, that
how do you do
that MNCP? Because
I created the
perplexity here.
it's but it's
not working.
So it's green.
Okay, so expand
that per sec.
So left-hand side,
yeah, expand that.
All right,
Asphalplexes. So
you get the
parameters, right?
So let's create
a new, let's
create a new
mode called MCP.
And everyone asks, so
let's, let's just do it.
Global.
Yeah,
Global, you can
use Global if you
want. And so just
copy and paste
one of the other
examples. So scroll
up a little bit
in the Rue file.
Yeah, find one
that's a little
bit shorter. It's
shorter, yeah.
Yeah, so see the,
yeah, grab that. Okay,
don't, you know, okay,
so add a, see the blue,
yeah,
add a comma after the
blue bracket right there.
Yeah.
So right after it,
hit enter, yep.
Remove the last comma.
It's JSON, so that
will break it.
Now,
create a slug,
call it MCP.
Yep.
MCP, just MCP.
The slug is just
for, yeah, and
then give it a name
MCP or perplexity
or whatever it
is you want to
call it, whatever
you want to do.
And then for the,
and this is what
shows up. So you
might want to, this
is what shows up
in your UI. So
you can click put
a, you can put a
emoji or whatever.
Yeah, so this is
basically you, you, your.
going to run the
perplexity MCP is basically
the the role
definition yeah the the
the perplexity MCP all
right let's get rid
of the Spark mode you
don't need that all
right and then under
custom instructions
delete all that you
don't need any that
right there to the end
of the quote yep and
then for this you
you're gonna you're
gonna you're gonna say
something along the
lines of you're going
to run MCP queries,
something like that. You
know, I'm using
vernacular.
Queries, and then go
back, and then on the,
go back to
your MCP server
on the left-hand side.
Yeah, at the
very top, you'll
see the third icon over.
Yeah, that one.
Now to expand that again,
copy and paste
the parameters.
Yeah, so you, there's two
things you're
going to want.
So you're going
to want the model.
So yeah, you want
the model. So
copy, copy all that,
including model.
And you also want
to tell it that, oh.
Like, oh,
no, no, you want to
put it, you got, you
got to go back to the
custom instructions.
So this is going
after run, you're
going to run
the MCP queries.
All right.
Yes.
You, you know,
you're right.
You are almost there.
Right.
Edit that, go back
to where you were.
you just had to type
in the instructions.
Yeah, in the
instruction, yeah.
Yeah, so go back. Yeah,
click on the
global, go back to
the room mode file
and edit that.
Yeah.
All right, so go
back and now go
back to your custom
instructions.
Now,
after the queries,
just keep typing.
Now you're going to tell
it, so go back to your,
you know, paste in
your parameters.
doesn't break the JSON,
so maybe put
it on one line.
Yep,
and just, yeah,
make it all in one
line. That's
probably good enough.
Yeah.
And then, yeah,
one more lineup.
Just put it all
in one line.
There we go.
And you're run the MCP
queries, the name
of the model.
Yeah,
and then tell
it, tell it,
bring back your MCP.
I don't remember what
the query was. was
so just bring that
back for a moment yeah
just go back to the
mCP expand that again
it's ask underscore
perplexity so tell
to run ask underscore
perplexity yeah all
right and and and it
looks like you're
getting some errors for
some reason i'm not
really sure was there
commas in there just
anything that you know
anything that's going
to break the jason
nice okay okay perfect
and now slapping a
slap in a icon next
to the name just so
we can see it you know
just a copy you know
like an emoji or
something there you go
uh no not the slug under
the name the emoji's
in the slug yeah
we'll definitely break
it yeah one one below
yeah there you go
All right
Okay
Yep Now go back to
the main Your main
mode in Yeah click
done Bottom left See
if you have the MCP
option What you do
Type type run
Now you might need
to give it a little
more guidance We did
this quick But oh
you know what we did
Cancel that Sorry
guys forgot one thing
Cancel out cancel
that Yeah cancel
that Under groups
See groups On
the right hand
side No groups
on your JSON,
just replace
read with MCP.
Yeah, just type
MCP in there.
And the brackets. No, no,
no, and yeah, undo that.
It just, you need
the brackets.
So just go back with,
yeah, go back, yeah,
replace just the
word read with MCP.
There we go.
Yep.
Now,
close this task,
start a new task.
Leave that open. We
need that. So open up
the root code. file
don't don't close that we
need that just to
optimize it a little bit
yeah there we go now
create go click done
all right let's make
sure this the type run
again now we've got
the right mode we've
got the right settings
let's see if it it
invokes yeah wants to
run the command run with
any specific um tell
me in the latest news
It's a little
dumb, but let's,
let's see if it
figures itself out.
It only, it's
only going to
run the MCP mode
at this point.
Here we go.
You did it.
Now you can auto
-approve, so always
at the top, see,
always, always allow.
You could probably click
that on if you
want, yeah.
And that's how you
set up an automatic.
And this works
great. You can use
this and you can
use this as party
for different modes.
You can create
different MCP modes
as part of my,
the Spark orchestrator,
and the orchestrator
can then orchestrate
different modes
for different tasks.
So if you want to
have an MCP server
for the deployment
to the cloud environment
or perplexity or
whatever it needs
to do, each of those
becomes its own mode.
The key to the MCP
modes is to make sure
they only do MCP.
But once you have
that, you can
automate pretty
much everything.
Don't even get me
started on the automation
of like hacking tools.
That's a problem
for another day, but
it can do all kinds
of crazy things
there, too. Basically,
it acts as a kind of
agetic orchestrator.
So each of those
MCPs can be agents.
And you can grab my,
my Edge Functions
folder and get all
kinds of crazy agents
that'll deploy and surf
and fill in websites,
you know, apply for
jobs, whatever it is.
We just clarify,
he didn't actually
build an MCP
server, right?
He's actually
running the Ask
for Plexity server.
Yeah, he's,
he's, he's, he's,
he's, He's invoking
an MCP server
that he has
running locally.
So if you jump back
to the MCP area
for a sec, I'll
show you that quick.
The third icon in
RooCode at the very top.
Yeah, just click
on that icon again.
And yeah, go to
the very top there.
Yeah,
right there.
And choose, no, sorry,
the MCP one,
one icon over.
There you go. No, yeah.
Yeah, that one.
All right. Yeah,
exactly.
So, yeah, click that.
Now, if you want to
create your own MCP
server, there's an enable
MCP server creation
button above there
that would literally
allow you to do that.
Now, a couple of
things to note, this
is probably using
Studio, Studio,
whatever they
pronounce it.
That means it's
running locally in the
environment, probably
on some port.
Now you can click the,
there's an option
to find, yeah,
edit the MCP
project, MCP at
the very bottom,
click that,
a little button,
yeah, click that,
click the other ones.
probably it's probably
running globally the
other button yeah
all right this is oh
sorry uh it happens
it happens all the
time sorry about that
guys i should have
known better um anyway
basically this is
invoking the mcp server so
these are the command
args that run it
locally you can run
remote as well there's
a great tutorial
from cloud flare that
allows you to run sse
that's the way you should
probably do it and
you can just deploy
them as edge functions
or cloud workers on
cloud player and it's
super easy it all
runs in the cloud you
don't have to worry
about local environments
or leakage of keys
or anything like that
it's it's definitely
the way to go um and
this is the future
sorry you awesome
thank you that
was cool yeah you
have to take your
key here a minute
all right So
the process that
we went through,
the MCP server was
already deployed and
we just made it
accessible from mode,
like one of those modes.
Is that what we did?
Because it said
it modified
some more files
or it just used.
What was the JSON
it produced and
you said approve
and let it go?
I'm not sure I
understand the question.
the demo we just work
the MCP server was
already deployed and
i'm assuming it was
enabled and in there
but then we went through
adding the new mode
uh right similar to
orchestrator and code
editing and debugging
we added a new uh
mode that you can ask
perplexity right in
the process and when
you did run what happened
actually when you
started like what was
the last step over
there so what what
what he basically did
is he had pre-installed
and configured a
perplexity uh API
that basically allows
without him to interact
with the perplexity
system programmatically
and he set that up
as an mCP now once
he had the mcp set up
and we could see that
it was running correctly
then what what we
did is we created a
mode which we labeled
like perplexity MCP.
And that mode only had
the ability to execute
MCP commands, right?
Because when you give
MCP servers the ability
to read and edit
files, it confuses the,
it confuses it. And it
has a tendency to want
to edit the perplexity
server or read files
that are unrelated.
So by giving it really,
you know, clear and
specific and narrow
focus, it doesn't
actually do anything
other than that. The
orchestrator allows it
to understand all the
various other modes that
are available to it.
So the
orchestrators, think
of it like a
puppet master.
It says, well, I've
got the ability
to query the
internet using
perplexity. I've
got a GitHub MCP.
I've got an Azure
deployment tool. I've
got a security
vulnerability checker.
And it can pick and
choose different
tools to do
different things
based on an
overarching guide.
every MCP provides
that secondary access.
After editing
the JSON on the
right for the mode,
what did you do
on the left? You
just said run?
Well, you need
to invoke it.
Yes, you need
The invocation
can be a prompt,
you know,
research using
perplexity to find me the
best code to build a
server or do whatever
it is I want to do.
and then, you know,
and then it might
go and do that.
And then you
might want to
manually switch
to the auto coder.
Now based on what
you learned from the
perplexity search, go
and build that server,
right? Or that's a kind
of manual invocation,
the orchestrator just
goes and does it.
So, yeah, when
you did run, it
showed yet another
JSON and it
was asking for
some approval.
Yeah,
that JSON was
basically the JSON
that defines
which MCP services
are available
to Rue or Klein.
Go on.
Okay. And that
includes environmental
variables, in this
case, API keys and
other sort of
commands to run the
server itself. So
the MCP essentially,
in this example,
was a locally
running server
with an I.O.
output, right?
you know, input
output on the
in the terminal.
And it's getting
that output and
using that as
part of the query.
When you run it in the
cloud, like
on Cloudflare,
that uses server
sent events,
which is an
HTTPS transport,
which uses server
sent events,
and then that can
communicate to the
back to you in an
asynchronous form.
So some events
might take a second,
other events might
take minutes or hours,
as long as the Rue
code or client is
open, it can then
report back later. So
it doesn't have to
happen immediately.
I have a question
for you, Ruben.
Do your tool names
have to be unique?
What happens if
you have tool names
that are the same
and they clash?
The slugs need
to be unique.
The tool names don't.
If you give it a
name that's the
same, it's going
to be confusing.
They don't have to be
unique. The
slugs do. Slugs
are always unique. Right.
So generally, the
slugs, I haven't
played around with
it that much because
this really only
came out recently,
but generally the
slugs are related
to the name of
the tool. It just
makes it easier for
the orchestrator
and others to figure
out what to use.
If you're
manually selecting
it, it doesn't matter.
But if you're using
an orchestration,
then it probably
does matter.
It's confusing to
have the same name
on the same thing
more than once.
How's it know to use?
Yeah, how does it know?
Yeah,
exactly.
So uniqueness is
important there.
and the role
and the custom
instructions are
also important.
Right.
Lots to play
with in this.
We have Ocean up
for the next talk
group, but if we
get a chance, I'd
love to come back
to how you set up
or whether or not
you're exploring,
setting up different
kinds of loops,
whether that's
predefined or how
much you leave to
it. But Ocean is,
ocean's got some stuff
specifically on
this. I guess,
as well on the MCP
server IP leakage.
Is that right, Ocean?
Not precisely, but
kind of. It's related.
So this is a slightly
longer backstory.
So about four or
five months ago,
when MCP first came out,
the fast MCP came out, I
played with that
very excited.
And then I
found NCP to be
very cumbersome
to deploy.
So I build a kind of
my version of fast
NCP, but basically to
deploy this kind of
thing, use some kind
of YML config file,
or it can even do
groups of configs, such
that you can have
one group of server,
and then inside will
have a lot of services.
And that will
lead to a lot
easier deployment,
for example,
like what you just
see in the rule there.
And then I run into this,
not really a question,
but a problem, but
more in my head,
this is not
safe. I'm using
external services
without, me
knowing way too
much about it.
So I started to think
around that route,
and then I encountered
a capability
-based microkernel
system, which was how
I was thinking,
how it can mitigate
this kind of security
vulnerabilities.
And then one inspiration
from this was
the E2B Sandbox using
the WebAsassembly
for code interpreter.
And I started
to see that if
the MCP server
themselves can be
wrapped in such a way.
And then you have proper
guardrail in
your own system.
And then this,
you can try to
control and do
the resources
and security and policy
enforcement much better.
But today, what I
really want to show is
the process of how
I come up with this
system. So it's kind
of goes back to what
happens before Roof
Star to automate all of
those with rule modes,
you kind of need a
lot and a lot and a
lot of specification.
And how I come out
was from this idea of
auto MCP and I want
to do something, I go
chat with chat GBT and
give me some ideas and
what area should I
focus on. And then I
started to do massive
amount of deep research
through all kinds of
sources I can get.
A lot of chat GPD
deep research,
perplexity as
well, rock as well.
So I ended up with
about 50,000 lines or
even more of just
deep research stuff.
And then how do I
turn all of that
into an actual
functional design?
So that is something
that what I've
done before on
symbolic compression
that actually
makes pretty well.
So even from the
spec spec process,
before you start
training. translating
all of those research
into your design,
you start to have a more
methodology to
analyze those.
Because a lot
of research,
I mean,
we all know AI how
to like to behave,
but to have kind
of a center way of
orchestrating all
of those and debate,
discuss, and
eventually come
to a set
specification design,
that process itself
is super important
and useful. But once
you get to that,
what you do next is
to kind of do us, how
I did it was a stage
and phase development.
So I started with
a very pretty long
guide on what are
we doing here.
And then for every
single phase, I have,
so for example, this
is exactly what we
need to do, and what
is the quality gate
that I will accept
this phase completion.
Well, this was
done in February
before the remote
come out. I think
I might automate
this process now
rather than do a
lot of manually.
So after you go through
all of this, you
kind of do a test-driven
development as well.
It's one thing I
have to say regarding
typed languages and
then things like rule,
rule modes.
Type language is
awesome for that because
every single time
there's a little mistake
compiler while y'all
at the IDE and the IDE
while y'all at rule
will go back and force.
So what how you get from
all of that. Oh, sorry.
So another way what how
you automate that. Yeah.
So how you automate
that is by kind of
doing a file based
handoff among the
different modes or
agents how you say it.
So for example here,
what I so I also have
a rule mode setup,
basically have a designer,
orchestrator, etc.
And then I, I, I
have all of this
different kind of
internal documentation
template that
I liked how the
modes to interact
each other with. So
let's take a look
at my rule modes.
So I have a designer.
I have a implementer,
and I have a researcher,
also an orchestrator.
And then in the
orchestrator, I ask it to
do things like if
it's under requirement
analysis use this
mode to that analysis
and give me report
research in the end i
guess you can add here
use perplexity mcp
if you like and etc
and then here's the
flow that once you
have that design docs
and here is what
you should ask the
researcher to do and
then the implement to do
this the good part
about this is everything
is documented every
single thing your
system ever do is
documented completely
in your repository.
This goes for very
easy to go back and
then review things.
And another way
that you can use all
of this historical
development notes
is to also symbolically
compress it as
the context for
future developments.
So that's basically
what I want
to show today.
It's about the
workflow of how
to come up with
this entire process. I'm
trying to automate this.
Can you run it?
Let's see it.
Let's see it run.
What thing run? The
mode? Yeah, sure.
Yeah, that's right.
I find it you've
taken a more in-depth
approach to your
modes. I, I separate
all that detail
into the client rules
or in the plans.
Have you had success with
such large mode
descriptions?
Uh, have some
success, but no,
that this lion,
the Rust one, I
was doing it
before the remotes.
The other one I
kind of did with,
but let's see, let's
see how this works.
Yeah. But this one
doesn't have convention.
Okay, let's see
the more heavy one.
All right, so.
No, heavy in terms of
like more restrictions,
like a lot more
documentation,
like need to lay
out everything.
So let's see.
Docs, meeting, okay.
Proding to my meetings.
What?
I'm always
curious to see how
others are building
this stuff.
Keep in mind,
this came out on
Saturday of last
week, right? So we're
at the frontier
of this thing.
Just because I do it
my way, it doesn't
mean it's the right
way. It's just how
I designed it. It's
interesting to see,
Oceans approach.
Oh, dude.
I'm not typing well.
So orchestra.
What haven't we
accomplished? You're
actually giving it an
orchestrate command?
It's an interesting
approach.
Orchestra.
We'll have what
we accomplish
according to our meeting.
And that's all
I'm going to tell
it. And you're
using thinking
as well for your
orchestration.
OK.
Yeah.
And then it should.
should have all
the information
about where is what.
If it's not,
then the prompt
should probably
be longer.
OK, so now it is start
to have a reviewer
to go take a look at
those meeting notes.
So first, read the
death guide and
then read the
meeting at March
29, March 31st.
Discuss what we
haven't checked
integration status.
Prepare for a structure
pending task for the next
do.
All right, so right
now it's reading.
Question this task, et
cetera, are getting,
are going into a file?
I'm sorry?
You mentioned
something that it
retains a lot of
context for future
development or
reviewing the stuff.
So the task thing
that you had expanded,
does that go in,
was that also added
to a file in the
system or not?
So what I'm doing
in between the
Mote handoff,
instead of a pure,
simple task completion
message back,
I usually would
like it to
write down a
mark down note.
And then to tell, I say,
I finish the task,
it's in this note,
it's in this note.
Okay, Strader,
if you want the
implementer to
implement it, let it
look at that note.
And then QA,
if you want to
double-check the quality,
check that note in
the implementation,
and then write
a QA report.
So that kind of...
So all your...
instructions have
file names kind
of mentioned that,
hey, please look
at the design. Dot,
or like,
requirements.org,
and when you're
doing testing, look
at the design and
the requirement
doc and make sure
they are like taken
care of. But I'm
not telling it
specifically myself.
All I'm doing is I set up
the workflow processes.
I set up what we're
doing for and what
is the overall
development cycle. And
then I leave it to
the orchestrator.
And because everything,
all the rules are
already established in
the form themselves,
in every single
template themselves
of how a problem
should be solved.
So these are the
more detailed
problem you can
think of it as.
The rule modes is a like
the agent handoff logic.
Yeah, so basically
it's checking those
meetings. It's going
to check those.
It's going to check
those implementation
of back and front end
as well. Backend here
is a Python. I think
I did this in a day.
The backend is a
Python base. This is a
kind of Asian native
IDE project that I was
just thinking about,
so I did it for fun.
But yeah,
this is it.
And this will keep
on going for quite
a while, because
I think there's
some processes that
need to be tweaked.
This is too much
paperwork for it.
It's awesome.
Good work, Ocean.
This is really cool.
So I have another
question which
kind of keeps
in bugging me.
AI is generating
too much code and
too much documentation
for a human
to kind of review
and feel comfortable
what's happening
and et cetera.
Do you think,
and it's going to end
up as only AI will
be able to go back
and fix it? Because if
a human cannot comprehend
like 15,000 lines
of code every day
that AI is generating.
Yeah. there's a solution
that I've been using
and I a couple weeks
ago I showed you guys
my Spark 2 framework
and as part of that I
created a vector of
every update and change
and document that's
being done by the actual
agent now most of that
stuff I don't really
need to see I don't
care about I don't need
to read 10,000 lines
of planning documents
I just need the summary
but those planning
documents work really
well for the agent so
what But what I'm
doing is I'm using a
similarity-based search
as part of the process.
So you know where
Ocean was just showing
you that whole research
process that it
was doing, it's
reading the documents,
it's iterating
back and forth.
You've got a couple
options to make
that more streamlined.
The simple option
is actually just using
SQLite and saying
rather than storing
all your files
as MDs on the hard
drive, you store it
in a database.
structure in SQL light.
Now,
that uses SQL as
a query, which
is fine for
smaller, you know,
datasets and
things like that.
But if you're
looking to really
sort of make it
run like, you know,
based on natural
language, which
is what the
orchestrator is doing,
you can create an MCP
based on a vector file
store. And there's tons
of different vectors
you can use quadrants,
a really good one.
And, and then
it'll, it'll use the
MCP mode as part
of researcher.
And, and And then
you're basically
saying store the
information in the vector
and then retrieve
that information.
And it's way faster
and it's less costly
and because it
doesn't require the
information to be parsed
as much by the LLM,
which is a cool. I'm
working on exactly
the sort of
integration of that
vectorization and
memory component. But
I think that that's
probably the more
efficient paradigm
going forward will
be like a vectorized
or a SQL style.
temporary and
long-term memory.
And would you be
working with Git actions
with that in order to
immediately capture
any new code or you
see it as a MCP server?
No, you've got,
so one of the cool
things about
Klein and Rue, and
I think Cursor
does this as well,
is they have this
checkpoint capability.
So you can use the
checkpoint capability,
which is like an
interim sort of step
within GitHub. So it's
not like a commit.
And someone more
familiar with GitHub, but
could probably explain
it better to me,
but it allows
you to use the
diff structure
from GitHub,
store the diff in
the vector as it, and
then you can query
that as a similarity.
Tell me all the times
you did a certain change.
I don't know what
those times were, and
that's where natural
language works really
well, and a similarity
search is going to
give you all the
most relevant and use
the most relevant
response kind of thing.
It's guiding it. better.
Question both for
Roof and Ocean.
I have the same
problem, right? Running
multiple deep research
on perplexity, on
MCP, on, sorry, on
OpenAI, on different
models, eventually
you need to integrate.
So you need to
synthesize what is the
proper way essentially
to do that? Because,
I mean, they may
give you different
answers. Some
duplication may be
happening, but some
unique parts may be
happening with
different temperature,
different ideas
may be popping
up. So what sort
of a streamlined
methodical way
to approach this?
And what problem are
you trying to solve
exactly? Any problem?
Like whatever you're
running, like as Ocean
was showing that he
ran the same exact
question on multiple
models, so you have
multiple files with the
deep research.
Eventually you need to
integrate it, right? Or
figure out what's best
before moving forward
to provide that plan
to implement. I think
what she's saying
is as the product
manager of the product,
right, you're doing
all this research on
use cases of workflows
and problems and it's
coming from different
systems, you know,
perplexity or chat GPT.
How do you converge
all that research
into one synthesized?
You and I were talking
about this
morning, Reuben,
about the product
manager, how you to
do all this research
on use cases stuff.
Yeah. And what is
the criteria? Like,
how do you guide
this thing. Like,
it's quite correct their
mind around, right?
Yeah. And that's
the plan folder I
was telling you
about. So what you
don't, and Ocean did
a great job of sort
of illustrating
how he's doing it.
You break it down
into a multi-step
phased plan. So rather
than having one giant
deep research
that's, you know, I
don't know, 200,000
words, you're creating
multiple steps. And
you're basically,
it's a project
manager. It's a project
manager. And you're
saying, each of those steps
are now a phase phase
one two three four
five right and and
each of those phases
should be implemented
separately from every
other phase and tested
individually and
explicitly for that
phase and the benefit
to that is you can you
can then do concurrent
or parallel development
I could literally
spawn up several VS
code windows and have
have VS or RU code
working on each of
the phases independently
of one another and
I can concurrently
build it more quickly.
And it generally doesn't
interfere with the
others. Now, you
might have some issues
around testing,
depending on sort of the
convergence of the core
of the application.
But the plan itself
should be narrow,
where the research
is broad. Still, the
question is if one model
approach one and the
other one suggests
approach too, they still
eventually would
converge into the plan,
but which approach to
choose or different
architectures or whatever
or tech stack, How
do you resolve the
different suggestions?
That's what
you're building.
She's talking about
converting the language
that comes from
perplexity on her research
and the language that
comes from chat GPT.
How do you converge
those two discussions
into one design
document? I think
is what you're
doing. You're doing
the ideas. It's different
ideas, different
approaches. Yeah,
different, yes.
You're doing the
inverse. You're
not converging.
You're separating.
So you're starting
with a really big
deep research
document, readme.m.m.m.
And that includes
everything that you're
getting from
perplexity or chat chit
or whatever you're
using for your deep
research. Then you're
basically saying
separate this into
multiple parts.
And then as part of that,
you can have, you know,
implementation
documents that
explain how far
along it's been
implemented,
where you're at,
that sort of thing.
So I guess the reason
and sometimes, I'm sorry.
I just want to say one
more sentence before
what Roof says. Sometimes
I do deep research
just to find out what
deep research to do.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's good.
That's not bad plan.
That's hilarious.
Thank you guys.
It's,
it's unfortunately the
answer is it
depends, right?
Which maybe
isn't the best
answer, but
it's the truth.
So depending on
your application.
you're always
going to be doing
different things.
So, you know,
that's the, that's the,
that's the drawback.
So amid middleware
is going to
be different
than a CLI or web
-based application,
right? So it's,
to me, to me, it was
more like, do you
need a human in the
loop eventually?
Or do you delegate
it to an agent
that has to be
sufficiently smart and
reasoning and
whatnot to sort of
assemble the ultimate
plan? In the AI 2027
write-up that came
out yesterday,
they really
highlighted a very
smart component
that they believe
humans will keep
the longest.
Research engineering will
be automated
by AI faster,
but research taste
will remain longer for
the human. so I think
there is a way to think
about it that this
enhances how you set
it up what you set up
you can delegate but
how you direct the
power of research is
something that for
some time we will still
decide and I would
imagine that you're not
going to know if you
like it until it's fully
built and I guess the
cost of change and
the cost of building
is going to be so low
that it will just be
a constant iteration
now, right? You don't
have to get it right.
That is the way I think
about technical debt.
It is disappearing,
by the way, or it
accumulates much
differently than before
because you can
always rebuild it.
And so that's a
great advantage too.
The other thing to know,
this isn't 100% set
and forget. There is
just, I don't think
we'll ever be a
hundred set, you know,
set and forget, you
know, when you watch
Star Trek and he
plots a course to,
you know, some nebula,
you know, somewhere
someone's telling
it what to do, right?
And the, a lot of
the agenics is
the abstraction of
complexity, right?
It's the ability to do
the things that you
don't understand,
but you still need to
guide it in the way
that it is understandable
to you and others,
right? And you'll see
that when you build stuff
and the UI isn't quite
right or the labels
or the workflow or
whatever it is that it
needs to do needs to
be sort of, you know,
massaged a little bit.
So there's always that
level of you kind of
stepping in and saying,
well, I actually
don't like that first
iteration. Go add an
animation or a button or
whatever it is that you
want to do. So there's
a bit of ideation and
iteration required.
And I don't think you're
ever going be like
just go build me a
startup and go to bed and
it's magically perfect
well the other thing
the other thing is that
if you do your deep
research and you get
19 ideas how do you
decide which who decides
which one is the best
one to start with right
or you're just going
to like take off 19
builds depends on your
goal right yeah you
could do 19 builds but it
wouldn't also ultimately
depending your goal
like if you're optimizing
for entertainment
or joy of a particular
user group like you
you have there's an
iteration process that
happens through product
development so i just
if you're optimizing
for revenue you're
going to have to find
sometimes you have a
bigger you know i guess
a feature set meeting a
market need that's that's
how i would imagine
it to kind of unfold
is like you don't you
know we can't know
how product's going to
be received until it's
in our customer's hands
well this is part of
the work that a product
manager typically does
for months beforehand
as to why you why
why you're even going
to build product and
they're still wrong right
and they're still
wrong so yeah it's uh
yeah totally and that's
what i'm up i'm up i'm
a me product and me
too i've done this my
whole career i'd say
rod for managers is more
important than the
developer at this point
you know developers suck
at building products
like it or not you
know the the the the
best product developers
are like the Steve Jobs
of the world, right?
They're visionaries.
They, they don't,
you know, Steve Jobs
never programmed
anything in his life, you
know, he, he couldn't
build any, he couldn't
really build anything.
What he could do.
Yeah, he needed
Waus. He needed
technical people
to implement it.
Was was nothing
without Steve, right?
He's smart and
capable, for sure, but,
you know, look at
he had no success
beyond the work he
did with, with Steve,
because he wasn't
a visionary. He
was an implementer.
So you need that.
You need the balance.
But this is
where I think the
world of agentic
systems is changing
because now you
have like us,
Alexander, you're me,
like we're sitting
on a very technical
meeting here, but I was
talking about writing
code. So I tell my
people, I'm a coding
product manager. I
can write code. I can
write Russ code. I can
write Go. I can write
you know, Python,
like a coding product
manager that can sit
down in front of BS code
and Rue and actually
think about what
he's building and why
he's building it, what
the use cases are,
the problem statements
are, the value profs,
and then actually
like write the code,
that's like way
more valuable
than a legacy
product manager.
That's the future.
And then the inverse
is the engineer who
writes the code, but
actually has a really
good understanding
of product management
and actually sits down
before he writes the
and sees, okay,
this is what I'm
building. This
is the customer.
This is the
problem statement.
This is the value
I'm trying to create.
Like, that's the future.
I think so. It's
these converge roles.
Yeah.
So I have a,
just to jump in
here for a second
roof, it would
be interesting.
So we're talking
about a lot of
front loading
the code. Like
I've got VS code
and whatever,
you know, doing
stuff while
we're talking
on the side.
It'd be interesting
to look at the
back half of the
system to say, like,
we use a number of
applications to look
at how users interact
with our products
and how we store that
interaction data and
assumptions on user
flows, right? So
because one of the
models that I just built,
I'm calling it
IWRML, so I have a
mock-up of it running
on the service.
I've scraped
72,000 frames
and thrown into
a database.
And I'm trying to build
a reinforcement loop
with the Shopify
plugin to say,
if some, if, you
know, if Roof gets a
suggestion of five
based on his face shape
and his prior purchases
because I know
the style and color
of what he likes.
You have that
reinforcement process
with recommendations
on a checkout,
but you have to
have the bridge of
the journey. You
can build the model,
but if you don't have
the signal for the
reinforcement learning
on the transaction,
you can't make better
recommendations.
Conversely,
if you're building
a checkout
page for Stripe,
right, and,
you know, could you A,
B, test the checkout
page? right and then
send a feedback loop to
their product manager
or the team so like
start building the back
half of the adjudic
systems to see like
hey by the way we can
start optimizing it's
not just about writing
but how can you self
-optimize ROI right in
terms of the AB testing
for checkouts or landing
pages or whatever I
like it and yeah yeah
the the idea of AB
testing is particularly
interesting and one
that's come up a lot in
my conversations over
the last couple weeks
the idea that you could
create custom throwaway
pages, you know,
for particular ad
campaigns. There was a
customer that I was working
with, and they
wanted to dynamically
generate reports based
on, you know, geographies
that they don't currently
support. So they're
like a research
analytics company, and
they support something
like 30, 30, you know,
locations around the U.S.
And they're like,
well, what if we could
like generate an ad
that we? We don't
generate the report
unless someone actually
visits that page.
And we generate the
page if and when someone
clicks on the ad,
right?
And it's like it
turned out that was
actually trivial once
we had a template
and we knew that we
knew that they were
searching Google
for a particular
location and a particular
research report.
Then once they visit
that page, it would
literally generate
the page specifically
for that city or
part of the city.
And then if they
actually filled out
the form, right when
they started to start
to, you know,
filling out the form,
the agenic process will
kick off in the back
end and go and do
basically deep research,
generate the PDF
using their sort of
predetermined design
file. And by the time they
were filling out,
done filling out the
form, they basically
got the research report
and they were able to
monetize immediately.
Taking that step further,
we could A-B test based
on the demographic
information that
we know is coming.
We're actually
getting quite a bit of
information from
Google. So we know, we
already know things
potentially like, you
know, their age or
other information,
you know, where
they work and other
things. And we can
literally customize the
experience based on
the information that
we're getting from
the system itself.
So you're doing this
kind of just in time,
AI driven commerce.
So I actually have
a separate project,
which is the last
part, which is telling
exactly what you said,
which is if I gave
you a set of suggestions
for your frames,
then how do I get you
into the store if,
in fact, you're trying
to go to a store?
And every single
store is owned
by any retailer.
It's basically
an exercise
in statistics.
When shoppers, drug
mart, or whatever
company plants a
new retail location,
they're looking at
statistics, and they're
looking at demographics,
and they're matching
it against their ideal
customer profile. So
there is truth to what
you're saying, because
I was basically
looking at somebody's
practice and saying,
look, if you have an IWR
practice, this is about
yield optimization.
And if you have 20%
capacity in
your schedule,
like we should be
automating that
whole process
with Agentics with
a practice co
-pilot, which I know
have a demo MVP
of on my machine,
which says, hey, like,
you're an optician,
you're not
a marketer, but
I can tell you
that next week
or next month,
you've got 20%
capacity or you're
underbooking. so let's
write an agenic script to
like get people in
the door and you can
do the same thing
with if you don't have
enough existing
customers you should run
that campaign with
API calls to Google
because you know your
average customer value
I think it's going
to completely change
how people run their
retail operations
are you saying that
you're buying long till
keywords in that
scenario like I'm a
little like I understand
I mean they've been
doing like long tail
page generation for a
while now right dynamic
content creation.
I'm just trying to
figure out, like,
I mean, the deployment
process is obviously
now, like you're
spending up a new page,
Ruby, we were just kind
of talking about that.
So I imagine it's part
of that feature set.
Like, you're
creating a report
and actually code
it and deploy
it. The page,
it's not a page.
Yes, the page,
as you point out,
is relatively easy.
It's the product
in which you're
selling that's
dynamically generated.
In this case, they're
research-based, you
know, product. So
it's easy to create an
amount. of the information
they have in the back
end and hyper-targeted
specifically to an
area that they hadn't
done before because
their previous limitation
was people creating
the report. So literally
they had a group
of people who sat in
front of the computer
and would put copy and
paste or put information
into a document and
save it as a PDF.
And then that's
essentially
what they were selling.
And that was limited
because they couldn't
do every location
because they needed to
infinitely scale their
team. to do that work.
Right.
I wonder, like,
what's that? Is there
a phrase for that
or, like, a term
that you guys are
using to, like,
describe that?
Like, one of the
first ideas that
comes to mind
for me is, like,
imagine, like, a
children's book,
like, tool where if
you just put it in,
like, your name,
everyone's name, and, like,
upload a couple photos,
and then it just
generated the children's
book for you in
real time with images
from Chad Shabit.
It connected to the
story, deployed it
onto a website of the
print or download.
And, like, that's
happening in real time.
Like, but that's just
one type of product.
I'm, I'm trying to
figure out like,
is it just called
like real time?
Is it always content
or is it, is it,
is it, is it, is it,
is it, is it, is it
doesn't move beyond
content creation.
It doesn't have to be
content. It
content's easy.
It could be anything
involving any process
that a person would
do in multiple steps.
Okay.
Like,
one of the, one
of the things that
happens in, in, in
this particular process
is, you know, it's
related to getting
information that's
not easily accessible.
So they've got a
custom database, for
one, but a lot of
the information
requires phoning up a
particular company or
service and getting
that information,
right? And that requires
an agent, a voice
-based agent to go call
a particular phone
number, sit on hold
for several hours,
ask a series of
questions and collect
that information,
put it back in
the database and
create a report.
Wow.
And so the limiting
factor was literally
a lot of this stuff,
especially when
dealing with like
bureaucratic agencies that
don't get back to
you right away or
require long wait times
or the information
isn't on a website
for whatever reason.
So now you've got
the ability for the
agent to have a sort
of pseudo human like
experience. It's
calling, it's waiting and
then chatting, which
is pretty amazing.
insurance companies
are totally *******
if this can be flexible
enough because so
much of their
business model and all
these business models
that are built on
trying to make it a high
barrier to resolution
I mean people that
build tools that
support that are going
to have a killing.
Yeah.
It's yeah it's
interesting times
yeah it's never
been easier
One of the things
that I think
I've discovered,
and this might
be self-evident,
but whatever,
I do a lot of these
vibe coding sessions
every week. People
randomly book me,
and a lot of the folks
are non-technical.
You know,
the things that I
take for granted
as easy and
whatever are, you
have to ask the
right questions.
And you have to, you
know, and tell it the
right things. Like
a lot of these folks
are saying, build me
an app to do this crazy
idea that I have. and
then it's building
them something that's
totally unrelated
and it's totally unsecure
it's not using the
right tech you know
so you still need to
have that ability to
guide it to do generally
the right things
in the right way so
if you give it garbage
it's going to give
you garbage back and
this is obvious but
you see it when everyone's
vibe coded themselves
into this hole and
they can't get out
of it what sort of
non-technical people.
I love code guide,
code guide. Dev.
And the reason
I like it is
because as you
start writing,
it generates
the questions
that you should
be answering.
And then you can
intervene and change. But
a lot of people have
a hard time expressing
themselves because
they don't have the
ability not only to
articulate what they mean,
but they don't even
realize that they can
improve their a
question asking ability.
So code guide, I think,
helps a lot with that.
It's good, it's
good suggestion.
It's exciting, though.
And, you know, for
us on this call, we
see the, we see the
incremental weekly
improvements that
sometimes we take for
granted because we've
been doing some of
this for a while now.
And it, and when
we take a step back
and the fact that
we can literally,
you know,
I've got currently,
as I talk to you,
four different
VS codes running,
building things
independently of each
other, it's pretty
amazing, right?
We're able to
do things at a
scale that was
never possible.
I don't know what
that actually means
beyond that it's
pretty amazing, but I
think it does
fundamentally change the
sort of nature of
development of stuff
or the management
or the, you know,
this idea of 10,000
Xers and whatnot,
right? And what
does that do to the
sort of world of
just information
technology in general?
It's just we're
living in some pretty
spectacular times.
Good question.
Does anybody know of
a system that will
kind of read the
repository and give
you a kind of a
high level overview?
Not at like code
level thing, but it's
like architecture
level and what are
the subsystems and
what are the like
high level things?
I've heard of it.
Get Remix, I
think, is one.
Repo mix.
It flattens the
repo, and then what
I do is I give it
to Gemini 2.5 Pro,
which is the longest
context window.
And I just tell
it, please analyze
this code, give
me an overview.
I have it generate
mermaid charts
so that I can look
at the relationships
of different
things visually.
And I find that
very useful.
So we got a
repo mix mode.
Hey, so you take a
mix and then output
to a Gemini model
and tell it to
generate and
summarize food to try.
Watch you up for the
large context windows,
especially Gemini,
2 million context.
If you feed it 2
million lines of a repo,
it's going to lose a lot,
especially the
stuff in the middle.
there's a common
problem with
that U-shaped
curve that you have
with larger
context windows.
And basically what
that means is the
information at
the beginning and
the end takes
precedence and the stuff
in the middle,
some gets muddled.
I don't generally
do context stuffing,
at least for larger
repos like that,
because I just
don't have any
success with the
nuance in the middle.
I think David's
suggestion of Mermaid
and some of the
suggestions are
on graph does
address some of that.
So you're always going
to be better with a
more incremental approach
and try to separate
it as much as you can
and only work on a
modular basis. There's
very few times where you
need to know the entire
architecture of a
massive repo. Like you're
never going to work
on the entire thing.
You're going to work
on some parts of it.
I can tell you some
researches that I've worked
with on that particular
problem of the length
of context window
and what they focus on
is they the research
is that if you if you
just work on the first
25% and the last 25
% and you discard the
middle 50% you get the
same answer all you need
is the beginning of
the end and there's
tons of research that
proves it so if you're
doing a two million two
and a half million you
know token window it
doesn't really matter
man it's just the the
beginning in the end
25% and that's apparently
that's what they're
just doing the middle
doesn't matter they're
mimicking human activities
yeah yeah nobody
remembers the middle
man they remember
your opening sentence and
your closing statement
and that's what you
get judged on yeah
there you go i think
you prove the point well
rube can i can i make a
closing statement here
i know unless you
guys want to close it
out but i guess one
statement i want to make
everyone if you're not
aware there's a new
foundation that has been
launched by rube and
led by rube and team
here robert and others
can you all hear me
yeah okay um it's
called it's called the
agenetics foundation
um we have launched
and we're welcoming
members so we're
putting together events
we're putting together
um all sorts of
educational content
and really building a
community we're looking
for volunteers to
help build it out but
also just join as a
member so um we don't
know if it makes sense
is have you have you
had a chance to show
agenics.org off yet
today no i haven't
um i'm gonna yeah i
think you want you want
you want to go You
want to go for it or?
I don't have, has the
signup been fixed yet?
I did fix it yesterday
and I apologize.
This bugs.
I'm really good at
breaking things. I signed
up as a pain member
while we were in the
conference so I can
confirm it. Amazing.
Thank you, David.
Yeah, yesterday, I broke
it earlier this
week again.
Like, apparently that's a
weekly thing
on my behalf.
I need a better
job of QAing.
Maybe there's an
agent or something
I can devise for
QAing better.
But anyway, just
on that same fix.
yeah i had actually
posted it i posted it
in the village global
uh startup channel
and a whole much of uh
startup CEOs started
to go in and and
devs and they're like
it's broken what's going
on the site doesn't
work so it's just
at that time and so
there was a question
that came up in chat
there alex just for a
second was um so matthias
was asking can we
access the session
recordings in there
and so this is going to
be like we are going
to house everything
um you know that
we're doing inside
of this inside
of this community
Not everything's
been fully built out
yet and big, but
there's, you know,
a sizable team that's
starting to form
and, or that has
formed and establishes
it's a not-for
-profit. It's totally
just a bunch of us
that want to keep
pushing this
forward, pushing the
research forward,
making it accessible.
And we want to
welcome everyone
to, you know, get
involved however
you can either
as a member,
get your company
involved or join us as
an ambassador, even
like host events and
community events.
So we just want to
really welcome everyone
to it. it's super
exciting and yeah
it gives the chance
to collaborate more
frequently as well and
we and by the way our
friends at Kaltura
have put together
a video portal for
us as well if you want
to go back and see
our previous rants
video.agentics.org
I you know I
realize that I need
to change up my
shirts more frequently
on these calls
but whatever.
Here you go.
These are all our
pre- and we also do
the live hacking
on Thursdays, which
is even more technical
than this one.
For those who are
curious on how things
are being built, we
basically is vibe
code for an hour
and a half on
Thursdays, and those
are recorded as well.
Yeah,
that's what we're doing.
The only other
thing I mentioned
is everybody
apparently wants
to be like an
identics engineer.
We probably need to
figure out how we can
actually do some kind
of like qualification
that it allows people to,
prove their abilities
as an agentic engineer
like the stuff that
you saw from ocean
you know he's he's
obviously proven himself
to be highly capable
and skilled at agentic
engineering how do
how do we make that a
thing and how do we
allow someone like
ocean to to maybe even
train others in in the
ways of agentic
engineering right education
and courses now
that'd be a great one
identify the criteria
and, yeah, play it up.
Yeah, like it or
not, I don't think
everybody wants to just
learn from chat GPT.
I think that
there's this human
element that we
bring, right,
that we're
doing right now
that facilitates,
you know, just
asking and seeing and
interacting is better
than chat GPT just
blindly giving me a
response to something.
Hey, Rube, I had a
question about what
you just mentioned
in regards to agentic
engineering as we
close. Hopefully this
doesn't overwrite your
comment. Alexander.
So the young lady
mentioned the conversions
of two different
outputs from chat
GPT and perplexity.
And so I can see,
and we dove in
somewhat on the
question, but it
was really broad. We
didn't have a clear
answer at the end.
I can see clearly N8N,
agenic engineering
being like N8N on
steroids, where
you have logic, you
have some thinking
and it applies to
things like real
-time products, real
-time information,
but how,
and what is your
opinion on agenic
engineering in regards
to platform engineering
and building
systems? And my brain
and where I'm coming
from is from agile,
DevOps,
and a notion of
eliminating waste where you
don't you deploy systems
in a in a in a in
a cadence but agenic
means that it's always
flowing it's always
moving it's always
growing in my mind so
what is your thought on
agenic engineering
or agenic engineering
and for platform
engineering if that makes
sense versus some of
the other things topics
you talked about is
like n8 in on steroids
and make sense to
apply eugenics in those
fashions. But what
about if you're building
a Zoom alternative or
if you're building a
platform like Uber
and you want to apply
agenic program and
agenic engineering to it?
How does that
look? What do
you think about
that in regards
to the stack
and the process?
You know,
at the very beginning
of this call,
and I'm almost out
of time here, I had
probably check the
calendar. But the,
you know, I was showing.
you this idea of a
startup that that I
was building and in you
know not a real startup
but a fake startup
just for the sake of
it right this this
intelligent voice agents
for the modern workplace
or whatever you think
and the and at the
beginning of the call
I set up the agent to
go build the back end
this is a platform right
a platform you know
includes the the front
end which is you know
a system to facilitate
you know whatever it
is that you're selling
but then you also need
a system to manage
who's using it,
how much you're
making, and
all the things.
In the time it
took us to do this
particular call today,
less actually, I
think this was ready
a half an hour ago.
I was able to build
the entire platform
backend that facilitates
this and deploy
it to cloud cloud
player. You know,
that used to
require a whole team
of people, right?
In multiple parts,
a system integrator,
a DevOps person,
a security engineer,
a data architect,
project manager,
a lead developer,
developer, a QA person.
Now, and never mind
my QA issues with
Agentics.org, but now
all those things are
different roles within
different agents
that are running to
solve that problem.
The fact that I can
do this stuff in the
run of a call should
illustrate, you know,
these opportunities
quite well, right? So
what you're describing
in terms of platform
engineering or mobile
development versus
embedded development
versus different sort
of type you know areas
they're just to me
they're just semantics
I don't see a difference
in terms of development
in flow like I
can just as easily
build an embedded system
for a piece of hardware
as I can a UI for
a website it makes no
difference to me at
the end of the day it's
just how I describe
the problem I'm
looking to solve in
guidance that I give it
to solve that problem
right on thanks
makes sense
we've got you
know this is like
superhuman powers
you conjure
anything you want
by asking the
right questions
you know it's
asking you shall receive
yeah it's it's like
spell work or something
right if you know
how to ask the right
questions then you
can get the right
thing that's it that's
that's the that's the
most exciting part of
the whole process so
um yeah does anyone
else want to run through
a brick wall right now
yeah sorry i'm just
feeling so excited
so jack well what
what's great about you
people like you, Alex,
is you've got
these ideas, right?
You're an ideator,
right? And suddenly
on a random Tuesday,
you can say, I want
to build this company
or this product.
There's nothing as
long as you know the
right system, you
follow our guides,
you now can do that
without any real
support. And I wouldn't
have been able to
do that. And I feel
so empowered. I would
not have been able
to do that without
you, Roof, in this
community that you
and Robert and team
have put together,
which is why I feel
so excited about what
we're doing with
Agenics because I want
other people to feel
this creativity.
So thank you for being
so consistent for
being so generous in
public with all of this.
And I think we all
are excited to keep
showing up on
Thursdays and Fridays.
And I appreciate
everyone who
does because I
love to share.
It's not fun to build in
a vacuum. So here we are.
Right. All right.
I'm out of time. I'm
probably late for
my next call. Thanks,
everyone. The video
.agentics.org site
from Kaltura is up.
All the previous videos,
yeah, thanks to
Zohar and crew.
You know, we've made some
progress on our Discord.
Thanks to Martin
and company, C.J.
David, and everyone
who helped get
our system up and
running on Discord.
We're volunteers.
There's bugs. People
are getting
double paid. We're
doing our best. If
you want to help,
we're all
volunteers. None of
us are getting
paid to do this.
other than our
consulting, I guess, or
whatever you're
second-year-a-things.
But, you know, feel
free to volunteer.
We've got an
ambassador's page,
sign up, and we'll
put you to work.
Until next week, there.
Alex, you're happy?
I did the shameless
self-promotion at the
end. Yes, love it.
Love it. All right.
I'll see you
guys next week.
Bye. Okay.
See you.