All right.
It's March 21st.
It's the, what, the
seventh week in
a row of a number
that's divisible
by seven, which is,
it continues down
my lucky sevens
path since the
beginning of February.
Really, really exciting
week this week, you
know, there again,
like every other week,
there's so much to
talk about and describe
that I'm probably going
to forget all the things
I did on Monday by
the time Friday hits.
But yeah, we're
having a great sort of
adoption of our Agenetics
Foundation with, I
don't even know how many,
what's the, how many
different chapters,
Rob, have we, have
people reached out for
like dozens, I think.
Yeah, we've got
a, we've got 12.
Oh, for chapters,
it's like over 60.
So that's,
and the,
we just met with
the chair of the
chapter committee
there last night.
And so all of
that's going to get
pulled together
over the next week.
Yeah,
there's a ton of
excitement from all over.
Yeah, it's crazy.
So today's session,
we've got some pretty
good people lined
up. And I'm going
to try to do some
vibe coding real time,
showing you sort
of how I go about
building this stuff.
Everyone always
talks like, how do
you build this stuff
so quickly and how
do you know, I can't
get my stuff to
work or spaghetti.
I'm going to show you
a little bit about
how I do it. Maybe
that'll be helpful
for others who are
interested in building
stuff that are
powerful and complex.
And who do we
have presenting?
We've got Randy
Larrier from Enable.
They've got some stuff
that they're working
on that they're
going to be sharing.
And then ****** V3,
willie's built out
a new game that
looks pretty cool.
So he's going to
show us what he's
got on the board.
Nice.
Well, yeah, we saw
****** a few weeks ago.
He's always got some
really cool stuff. Yeah,
I need so. And a few
new members joined.
I just met Korn from
Indianapolis. Welcome.
And he's also interested
in creating an
Indianapolis chapter
for the Agenetics
Foundation. I'm sure
that'll be a speedy.
Okay, never mind.
That's a bad joke.
That's all I know
of Indianapolis. So,
yeah, we've got a
ton of things going
on. So I'm going
to jump right in.
So this week's been
interesting. I built
lots of stuff. And
I'm just going to
show a few of the
interesting things.
that I've been
working on.
So I'm going to jump
in and share my screen.
I'll try to keep an
eye on the chat. You
know, this is going
to last about 15
minutes or so. I'll do
some coding as well.
And at the end, if
you have anything
else you want to
build or ideas,
maybe we'll give
it a spin as well.
Let me share my screen.
And I'm just going
to jump through
and show some of
the highlights
here. So this
is my desktop.
Hopefully it'll
load here in a sec.
And let's jump
into the browser
when you're just.
So I'll show
you some of the
cool stuff first.
One of the cooler
things that we've seen
this week is the OpenAI
FM tool, which gives
you the ability to
have a really sort of
in-depth description
of the different
voices and capabilities.
And you can quickly
and easily integrate
this. So you see here
that there's a little
code option here.
You can choose
JavaScript or curl and
just customize it.
So basically, if
you want to change
your voice, you
choose a voice. If
you want to change the
style or see the
different sort of
prompts for it, you
can do that here.
This was obviously
vibe-coded. You could
tell kind of how
they built it, but
it did a great job.
It kind of reminds
me of my old DJ set
from like the 90s.
I'm not going to
bother hit and
play, but it
is. So whatever
you change, if
I say, you know,
I am, I don't know,
I am the AI,
oops, I am the AI hacker,
space, bot,
all right, something
like that. And
then you can see
here that it'll
update and put the
information in.
Let's look like it
actually. Oh, here it is.
So really, all you
need to do is copy and
paste this into your
favorite cursor or Klein
or root code. And
you're off the races.
So check that
out, openaI.fm.
Really cool stuff.
Now, one of the other
things I've been
looking at this weekend,
some of you guys
know, I've got a
ridiculously large OpenAI
budget. or or and oh
i locked me out of
course it locked me
out but and one of the
tools i've been using
is this new one i
was introduced to a
couple days ago called
requestly and requesty
requesty with with
a why is kind of like
open router but what
they've done a really
good job of hyper
optimizing your the
prompts so they sit
in the middle between
your coding system
like cline or cursor
or whatever and then
they they optimize the
prompt and they claim
they can do a 90%
reduction in tokens,
which is substantial
if you're
looking to reduce
your sort of spend.
So, which is interesting.
So I've been using
it for a day or so.
So let's log in. Of
course, it logged
me out right before
I'm about the demo
because, you know,
why would it keep
me logged in for
more than an hour?
So I'm going
to log in again
and see if I can
get this going.
I'm going to log
in with my GitHub.
All right.
Looks like it worked.
So when you're
logged in here, you
can see the cost.
So this is how
much I've spent
in the last day.
$31 for me is
actually quite low.
So if this is a
90% reduction,
that means I would
have what? Otherwise
spent like $250
or something.
So I think it's
actually working.
So just to see, you know,
yesterday here
I spent $10.
I only started at
noon. I didn't do that
much coding by my
standard yesterday. I was
busy on calls. And you
can see my token uses,
you know, here. So
I've got 2,498 tokens.
So that is 24,000 K.
What is that?
What's 24,000 K?
I guess is that
20 million tokens
or something?
So decent amount
of token use.
And so 20 million tokens.
And yeah,
and the other
I've got 93.
They didn't need to
lose a K. I don't
want to have to do
the math in my head
converting that to
millions. But anyway,
you can see here that
my models. I'm using
Sonnet 3.7. I'm back
to 3.7, by the way.
They seem to
work out their
kinks, and I'm
liking it again.
You can see my average
request cost is $0.5.
And this is the
important number
right here. I'm
cashing 85% of it.
Cashing costs
more up front.
You're paying 1.5 for
the initial cash hit,
but after you cash it,
it's substantially less.
So whatever you're
doing, make sure
you use cashing
when you're using,
it's on 3.5. I think
Open AI actually
auto caches for you
now, so you don't
have to worry about
that over there.
What else we
got here? We got
coding stats,
which is kind of
cool. Let's take
a look at that.
So, let's see,
analyzing my data.
I've got 12,887 requests.
That cost me $31.
Different price point
here, which is
interesting.
They're saying my
average cost per request,
and this one is
fractions of a penny.
I don't know what the
difference there is.
file interactions, 74
unique file interactions.
So that's kind
of interesting.
I'm also not sure what
this failure means.
Means some of the
requests I'm doing
don't work, which
is something I
might want to look
into, I suppose.
What else we got here?
So I've been busy
working on today's
demo, so that's probably
why we see so many
interactions this morning,
Friday mornings are
my demo mornings.
We've got model usage,
some more languages.
Let's see what I've
been working in Python
because I took a
bit of a breather on
TypeScript. So we can
see the majority of my,
my, my changes.
I can edit pattern,
the code generation.
Yeah, it's kind of cool.
All right.
So, all right.
Does someone
have a question
or is just,
you're unmuted?
Sorry, all right.
Oh, no, no worries,
no worries.
All right, so
what I want to do
quickly, I'm going to
show you some things
I've built, and
we're going to do
a quick little vibe
coding session.
All right, so
earlier this week, I
built a security
system, this entire
security system
is about 20,000
lines of code. It
can auto detect,
it basically can,
you point it out of
website and it will
detect all your security
vulnerabilities, both
on a command line.
It creates issues
in GitHub, so I can
literally point out
anything and find every
vulnerability for a
given project, not only
find them, but then
it suggests fixes for
them. This is, we'll
take a look at the
UI. So we go here, we
can start scanning,
we can point it
at a given folder,
I can choose which
branch, I get
different options
for how I wanted
to do analyzing,
so I can say,
use web search to find
the latest CVEs for
a different problem.
I can go in here, I
can do a historical
analysis of other problems
I may have had before
that were similar.
This uses a vector-based
caching system that
is using OpenAI agent
system and vector.
system and web
searching capabilities,
which is cool. I can
send a report. I can
have this auto send
every night. So it can
basically check my
repos every night at
midnight or something
for any kind of
problems. So even if
there wasn't a problem
yesterday, there might
be a problem today.
And it won't, it'll
actually even go
ahead and fix those
problems when I
tied in to my auto
agent fixing bot.
So now I've already
run it. So you can
see here now, I
found some issues.
Just to be clear,
I created a folder
just to make, called
vulnerabilities,
and I purposely created
vulnerabilities.
Turned out this
was actually
difficult to create.
So a bunch of
the vulnerabilities
I created,
GitHub didn't let me
publish. So I had to
go and try to create
vulnerabilities that
GitHub would
let me publish.
So essentially anything
involving like an
environmental variable
or key, it wouldn't
even let me do it. So
that's good, I guess.
But anyway, so it's
finding it's finding
the problems. You
can see here the
location. It's in my
vulnerability's folder,
you know,
category and the
risk score. And
then it gives me
a recommendation.
I can feed that
recommendation to my coding
bot and it can
automatically then fix
that problem and then
submit a poll request
and have the entire
system, you know, fix,
self-fix any sort of
security related issues,
which is pretty
cool. I've got a
history. So if I
pointed at any, and this
history is actually
being saved in
the local storage
on in your browser.
So I'm not looking at
it. I don't want to
see this. I don't
want to know about it.
So all this is being
actually stored locally,
not in a database,
which is kind of an
interesting way to go
about it. So I can go
in here. I can, you
know, look at a given
repo that I was looking
at and I can see,
you know, different,
different problems.
So this is pretty
useful for anyone. This
is particularly useful
if you're vibe coding
and you have zero
idea of what security
looks like. Point
this at your repo and
say, what are, what,
What are my issues? And
then you just copy
and paste the output.
And you'll see
here there's
a raw data option here.
Just copy and
paste the output
directly into your
coding system.
And you're good
to go to fix
any security
-related issues.
All right. So
that's cool. It's on
the agenetic security.
You can see all
the code. You can
see the folders.
The thing that
in particular
you want to look
at, you'll see
that it's an
edge function.
So if you want to
deploy it yourself,
you'll see that there's
a folder called security.
security scanner this
is this is the edge
agent so this this
this this runs all the
sort of security related
components for you
I created a user
interface because people
like to click things I
guess so this this is
this is what actually
makes it all work so
you can run it yourself
and I won't know
what where your security
vulnerabilities are
all right last thing
let's do a quick code
let's do a quick
vibe coding session
everyone's asking like
how do you create you
know things so quickly
and so efficiently
that's a great question
so one of the things
i've been working
on this is probably
a blog post or
whatever **** you call
linkedin posts for later
this afternoon i built
an agenic system
that allows me to
essentially deploy to
any cloud-based provider
it handles provisioning
configuration of
infrastructure and
monitors for problems.
It self-heels
infrastructure with no human
intervention. It's a
DevOps agent. So if you
want to deploy a complex
infrastructure to
AWS or Azure or Google,
one of the big cloud
providers, all you
really need to do is
point this agent at that
and say, go deploy my
given GitHub and make
a cluster, make it
scale to a billion
users, fix any security
related issues. So it's
got, it does all those
It's fairly complex.
You know, it's
autonomous, it's self
-healing, it's continuous,
it's everything
you expect. And I'm
using the open AI agents
again because I'm
kind of having a
bit of a love affair
with open AI agents.
It's awesome.
It's easy. And this
is a perfect example.
I did this in Python
because everyone's
like quit using
TypeScript all the time.
I want to see Python.
So this is
built in Python.
So what I want
to show you
first of all is
how I built it.
So you'll see here that
there's a plan folder.
So this, there's plans
and, oh, I didn't
actually copy all my
original plans. Whoopsie.
But this plan folder
essentially, let
me close this for
a sec. That's a
little, you probably
don't see that.
So when I build
anything, there's
two approaches to
building something.
One is from the top
down. Top down is
I've got this sort
of user interface
that I've already
built for something
or other and I
want to modify it.
Bottom up is I
have an idea for an
infrastructure. that
I want to build.
What's the
structure? What's the
foundation? What's
the architecture,
the API, the data,
all the things
that go into
it. So then I'm
building from
the bottom up.
That's how I build
complex things.
UIs are generally
not that
complicated so I
can go top down.
You know,
complex applications
like a detailed DevOps
agent system that
manages, you know, the
security and deployment
and management of
complex infrastructure.
That's complicated,
right? So for that
scenario, what I'm
doing is I'm defining
a detailed strategy
and then letting the bot
create a multi-phased
approach to implement
each step of the
process along the
way. To do that, what
I'm actually creating
is a series of tests.
You can see that I've
got all these tests.
Now, these tests
will actually run
and essentially
tell me whether it's
working or not.
So in this case,
and I never run all
the tests all at
once until right now,
which I'm about to
do. I run each test
for each function
of the application
one thing at a time.
And then I tell
it to only move
to the next
capability once that
function or
capability is working.
Once my tests work,
and I'm using mock
data for the tests,
then I know that my
actual implementation
will actually work.
I can set it and
I can forget it,
right? I can let it
run. I can let it
run overnight. I
can go have dinner.
And by the time
I get back, it's
built these crazy
complicated systems.
This application
is close to, I
think, 40,000
lines of code. I
built it in about
three hours,
40,000 lines of code.
Just to put that in
perspective, if I was
to build this in a
traditional way, as
a single individual,
that would likely take
me two or three years.
As a team, that
would probably
minimum probably
take me nine to nine
months, maybe,
12 months, and
that's like a team
of five people.
So it's crazy, you
can do crazy complex
things. it builds
by itself and so on.
All right. So
we've got this sort
of, you know,
baseline interface.
So now what I'm
going to do is I want
to, I create this
sort of funky, you
know, UI the other
day to sort of show,
you know, this is
about me, right? This
is like promoting my
consulting services,
but I want to kind
of use this now.
Rather than promoting
my consulting services
and a kind of retro
style, I want to use
this to sort of manage
the UI for this DevOps
agent. So I want to
change it up a little
bit. So this will be
a top-down approach.
All right, so I'm
going to do this
quick. So we're going
to go into RU-Code.
Roo-Code is my new
favorite system,
just to give you
a quick update
on some of the
new features.
I'm going faster, guys.
Hopefully we're
getting all this.
Right?
So you can see here I'm
using the
Requesti API now.
It's apparently
a lot cheaper.
You can see here, I
set my temperature
slightly higher. I don't
like it to be too low
because it gives it a
little bit creativity
I've got my auto
approved settings so I've
got all my auto approves
right operations
always approved right
operations I have a I
set a rather long sort
of a timeout component
so it doesn't so it
can wait I set always
you know retries and
different settings
here you might want to
screenshot this these
are all my auto sort
of components to allow
my system to run by
itself if you want the
system to run with no
human intervention,
screenshot this
and add this to
your, you know
what, and you can
basically make it
run automatically.
Here's my browser.
When I'm in the other
room, I want it to talk.
So I've turned on
the ability for it
to, you know, to
have text to speech.
So I've at my speed.
So it basically
yells into my other
room, hey, Roof,
I'm done, basically,
which my kids think
my computer's nuts
and I'm crazier.
Open tab. I only
want a certain amount
of tabs open. This
is actually kind of
high i should probably
set this to about
i don't know let's
send it to about
seven save that and
lines of lines to
read from a file
so i set rather low
because i don't want
to overdo the context
so terminal output
limit terminal shell
integrations these are
my settings rate limits
if you're on a new
plan you might want to
set the rate limit to
a higher value they've
given me tier five so
i don't really care
this is a particularly
important one
you'll notice that
there's different options
for diffs don't use
single block that's the
default and it's the
worst option it means
it goes line by line
through the code and
it takes forever to
do things either use
multi-diff or unified
diff if you're using
things like gemini use
multi multi-block if
if you get a lot of
failures for whatever
reason for like say
you're using like deep
deep seek or something
you might have to
switch back to a single
block but i'm using
unified dip right now
it's by far the best.
Match precision.
Match precision allows
you to adjust based
on the diff itself.
So sometimes there's
slight variance in
the diff between what
it thinks and what
it should be. If you
play with that number
a little bit, I
usually actually keep
that a bit lower,
like around 98%. That
it makes it a little
bit more forgiving.
So,
and then I've got the
experimental search
and replace that
that makes it work
a little better and
experimental insert
control. This is the
state of the art.
Curser doesn't
of this stuff exists in
cursor it's spectacular
all right so now
what i want to do so
let's go back and
look the file folder
structure let's a quick
time check uh rob how
are we doing are we got
a couple minutes you
want me come back to
the actual vibe coding
session in it we got
we got we got time
all right so i'm going
to try to go fast
because we i'm in blabbing
for for 20 minutes
but all right so we'll
see here that i've
got i we've got my
my core devops right
i've got a ui folder
which you see running
here in the corner
and which i'm going to
modify quick and we've
got a run cly so what
i want to do is i want
to introduce what the
heck the application
is to the uh a i itself
that's why i have
the sort of quick i
can run the cly directly
but this this tells
it kind of how it needs
to work so in this
case i'm just going
to say run the at run
cly which is a little
redundant i might
add and you know and
nothing else because
i'm really what i'm
really trying to do
is tell it what it
needs to know so Rather
than me typing on
a whole long-winded
prompt to tell it
what it needs to know,
I want it to discover
sort of the piece.
Oh, I tried to,
of course, let's
hopefully that works
one more time. I mucked
with the settings,
which was probably
not a good idea.
Let's give it
one more try.
Execute with value.
Did I break it?
Let's go back here.
Of course, I've
been working on this
all day, but I leave
it to me to break
it right before.
Let's, it's probably,
I'm not really
sure what I did.
did to break it.
Let's, let's, uh,
root try to execute
the man with a value
for a required
parameter. That's a new
error. I've never
seen that one before.
All right, let's just
switch quickly to a
different model and
see if that helps it.
Uh,
otherwise we may
have to come back
to the vibe coding
here in a minute.
Uh,
let's try it all
the more time.
The, the demo gods
aren't smiling on
me. Like literally
I've been working
on this all morning
without any issue.
It could just
be the model.
All right. Now I went
to a thinking model.
Probably don't need
a thinking model
for this, but I
was lazy and too
lazy to switch. All
right, so now you
see here that it's
running the CLI,
you know, and it's
giving some options.
So these are the
different, so
it's discovering
what it needs to do.
All right, now what
I want to do, and I'm
going to tell it to
run the other commands.
Oh, I got to spell. that
right other commands
so you can see there's
different commands
so it just ran the
most basic so each of
these EC2 GitHub and
deploy have sub commands
that i want it to
discover so i'm just
going to do that so
this for example list
instances create
instances stop terminal so
what i'm doing is i'm
giving it the ability
to discover how the
uh the agent actually
works from it from a
command line point of
view now once you know
i could do a couple
things at this point
i could create an mcp
server that allows me
to interact with my
AWS or Azure infrastructure
by just asking.
But to be honest, most
MCP servers aren't
necessarily. It could
literally just run
the CLI and get the
exact same result.
MCP is a bit
of a gimmick.
I don't, you know,
if anyone tells you
it's the next big,
big, greatest thing,
you know, it's probably
because they never
actually tried to use
an MCP server, just
throwing it out there.
But in this case,
I'm just using a CLI,
which is way easier.
It gets the same result
without having to do
all the convoluted
steps of an MCP server.
All right. So in
this case, it's still
discovering all the
features. Now it's
listing the components.
It looks like
it found in error,
but that's okay.
I actually don't
have the AWS
credentials in
here currently.
So now what I'm
going to do quickly,
and then what
I'm going to do
because I don't
have a lot of
time, I'm going to
go here and say,
create a review the,
UI folder.
So the UI folder you
see here is running
this in the corner here.
This is this, I want
to create this funky
sort of extension
for VS code that looks
like it's like 1981.
So I've already
created that before,
but I'm going to, so
my VS code extension
is going to be like,
it's going to be
like no VS code
extension you've ever
seen. Mostly VS
code extensions look
like the one over in
the left. Mine's going
to look like this
one on the right.
And so what I want
to do is modify this
to be more specific
to my Agenix DevOps.
So I'm going to
say review the
folder and create
a detailed,
multi-phased update
to the U.I to use the
Agenic DevOps application
and functionality
and in the you know
UI use mocking to
start and start with
mocking because it's
easier than making
it real mocking and
place folders for
content content content,
place in the
slash plans folder
as multiple MD
files in several
phases with tests.
All right, so this
is what, so I'm doing
one thing, I
introduced it to what
the heck the CLI was
and the agent was.
Two, I'm saying go
take a look at this, at
this tool, which I
already know works over
here, but I want to
modify it. you know,
make sure to call the
new UI-Agentic DevOps.
All right.
So I'm creating a plan.
So I'm going to go
ahead and start that.
So the first thing it's
going to do is it's
going to review the UI
folder and say, what
the heck is this thing
in the UI folder?
And then two,
I wanted to go
and create the
actual plan.
Never start anything
without a plan.
if you're if you're if
you're if you're sort
of vibe coding with no
plan then you're going
to end up with spaghetti
it's not going to
know what it needs to
do or why it needs to
do it and you're going
to end up creating
a whole lot of random
files and random ways
that don't relate to
one each to each other
remember context is lost
after a certain point
so without those plan
files there's nothing
to keep this thing
steering so what these
plans are doing is
using something you know
along the lines of a
power steering right and
it reminds it itself
what it needs to do and
why it needs to do
it. So everything I'm
doing is creating that
initial plan. I spend
more time as defining
the plan so I can just
step away and let it
build the **** thing
while I'm having dinner
somewhere or doing a
conference call because
then I know that it's
got a solid structure
that it needs to do.
You can see here now
it's creating the plan.
It's saying this
is how it needs to
work. This is how
all the components I
need. And it's putting
it into the plans
folder so we go
here we can see here
that there's going
to be a plans folder
so it's phase one so
and when i start to
implement the plan
i'm not asking it to
implement the entire
plan i'm actually only
asking it to implement
each step of the plan
now one of the things
that's really cool
about root code is i
can actually create new
windows of this
particular vs code and
then run each plan
concurrently to one another
so i can i could go
here and say file
new window open up a
new version of this and
say run phase two
create another window
run phase three and
then i can i can
simultaneously create
each step of the plan
independently from another
and then at the end
once all the plan
components have been
implemented then i'll make
go back to the original
window and say run
it or test it or
whatever i need to do
so i can run it you
know i can build things
in three times the
speed but what i
don't want to do is is
necessarily run it
sequentially or or without
a you know again,
without a detailed plan.
So now it's doing
phase two of the
plan, which is the
AWS integration.
Yep.
Quick question.
What did you have in
the UI folder? Was
it just some mock
-up or did you have?
It's another project I
did yesterday. So I'm
just because I have
so much stuff I build.
I've got the ability
to go and borrow
from all the things
I previously built.
So yesterday I
created a system
here. I started
with Lovable.
And basically,
it's this vibe
coding system, or
it's my vibe
coding consulting,
you know,
and you can see here,
so you can go in here,
and you can see that
it's totally retro,
and I get my info,
and I can, I've got
little menus,
I've got a little
command terminal and
all these sorts of
things, right? It's
meant to be stylized.
I can, I can type
commands in it.
So, and I can, I can do
whatever I need to do.
and in this case,
so this is cool.
It's basically
selling my consulting
services,
right? It's just
a really stylized
way to do it.
So I pointed,
I copied this.
And yeah, I copy this.
Now I want to
make, I don't
want this to sell
my services. I
don't really
care about that.
I want this to be
the user interface
for this super
stylized, you know,
DevOps agent that
I created. So I
want it to customize
this further.
So is it going to
take? this is an input
and try to morph it
into what you want it
to be? Or it's going
to take this as an
inspiration and create
a new folder and
create a new stuff
using the same styling?
It's a morphing.
It's going to take
what I rebuilt and
it's going to
modify it. So, you
know, if I want to
increase the fonts
or change it. So
what I've already,
to be honest,
this is what
I'm showing
you right here.
I built this yesterday
in 20 minutes.
So this is an
example of what
you can do in 20 minutes.
so I'm going to restart
the thing you know
and oops I was a
little too fast so it's
it's you know I'm
I'm an I'm old so I
like I like the look
of like 1981 right so
that's what I'm I
was going for super
this super stylized
kind of thing you see
it in like a movie
or or the silo or
something so but but
you know this this all
works right you can
see here you know it
gets information from
the web I got a little
message inbox and
And, you know, it's,
this is what a 20-minute
vibe coding session
does when you know,
when you have a plan.
I know the title.
Right.
All right. So let's
go back quick. I'm
almost had a time. We'll
probably come back.
What I'm going to
do, I'm going to
let this run Betty
Crocker style while
you rest of you
guys give your
presentations near
the end. We'll come
back and we'll see
what it's built.
But you can
see here, it's
still building the plans.
So once the plans are
done, I'll go ahead
and just tell it to
go execute the plans.
And we'll see what
the heck it built.
all right i'm
done sorry i went
along today i
apologize i'd
like i don't like
to go so long
what was uh ruve what
was the um the devops
um repo uh it's it's
a work in progress
i'm going to publish
it here later this
afternoon but it is
live um let me pop
that into the chat
area the text area and
zoom and um yeah
it's i i i'm it's i A
couple more pushes I
probably need to do,
but basically you
guys got a little
preview of my
upcoming, you know,
blog post or, you
know, LinkedIn
post, whatever
you call it.
Awesome.
Awesome. Okay.
So for Lightning Talks,
we've got a couple.
We got ****** V3,
and we've got Randy.
Randy's from
Enable, and he's
got some stuff
to show us.
Randy, are you there?
Yeah, I'm here.
Hey. I missed
your message
earlier. I was
transfixed.
That's okay. Very good.
Nice to see you.
Welcome.
Put my thing
up here. Sorry.
Yeah.
All right. You guys hear
me see you all right.
So I work in
Enable with John
Petty, who I think
most of you knew.
And he had a meeting
today with one of
our investors and kind
of fling to me and
said, hey, show them
some of the stuff
that we've been working
on. So my role in
enable the chief
product officers a lot
of times is taking
the crazy genius ideas
from John and
James and crew and
thinking about, you
know, how do we move that
into, you know,
production stability as
well as like an
interface that can
resonate and scale with
our paying clients.
And, you know, we
have so much cool
stuff that, you
know, we've built
and played with
kind of individually
or for our B2B
clients that like,
you know, the challenge
is always like,
how do we build an
architecture and
like make it scalable
to quickly take those
ideas and push them
into production.
Definitely on the
vibe coding bandwagon
since before it was
called the vibe coding. So
it's awesome to see
all this stuff. And
I'm like desperately
scribbling notes because
we've been doing a lot
of, you know, Klein
and Devin and stuff
like that. So like now
I've got to go back
and see how we can
incorporate some of
this into our workflows.
But yeah, so what
we've end up doing is,
you know, we built a
platform with a bunch
of different individual
things, and then
we've been trying to
stitch together with
a workflow that, you
know, lets us scale
and also lets us
reuse components.
So what I can share here,
I wanted to just kind of
walk through
how we do it.
Sure, there's,
there's a line
there's call.
Yeah, let me guess.
Sorry.
Cool.
So basically,
you know, what
we're doing is
we have a concept
called tasks.
We create some
database tables
to track tasks
that get created.
And then, you know,
our flow is basically
our users come
into our interface.
They're able
to create tasks
both by filling
out a form and
also by using,
you know, voice.
So we do, we do a
pretty good job of,
you know, parsing from
what they say into
these specific
configurations that we,
we've got our agents.
And, you know,
basically what
will happen is the
scheduler can be
set up as a one
-time run or on a
recurring schedule.
When it, when it turns
to execute, it goes
and pulls up the plan,
which was generated at
task creation time and
executes that plan,
you know, much like,
you know, an auto
gen or other kinds
of things might
do. And then each
agent is, you know,
individually able to
kind of take certain
inputs and receive
certain outputs.
What we've also done
is we've tried to
take every kind of
AI tool and component
in our platform and
structure it in a
way that it can be
called from this, so
that it can be called
from this process.
So we basically,
you know, when
we're building a
new feature now,
we're not just
building it for the
screen that it lives
on. We're building
the kind of middle
layer in between that
will let it be, you
know, called and
referenced through
this architecture.
So what's really cool
about that is then
we start getting to
the point where when
it comes time to do
testing as a team,
we can test the
individual components, but
we can also just talk
to our application,
right, and say,
like, I need to check
that the researcher
is getting these kinds
of results or has
this kind of latency.
And we can do all those
things and populate
our databases with
metrics so that we're
able to see kind of
what's happening and
where things are
breaking or where things
are, you know, not
behaving as wanted.
So it's basically,
you know,
the task object
into how we abstract
that into the
individual agents.
And this is what we
have currently on
our platform for
automation, although
there's another
kind of group coming
as we do kind of
weekly releases.
But the one that's
kind of the most
useful, I think,
is the researcher.
So, you know, we
just switched over.
We were using,
we have an Azure
platform, so we
have some, you know,
Bing functionality
that wasn't that great.
So the Open AI
just put it out. a
preview, it's a 4
-0 search preview.
It's relatively new, and
we just swapped that out,
and we're very happy
with the results.
So using that instead
of what we had
previously been using
to pull in research,
we find better results
and lower latency.
So we're really hitting
that hard right now.
But basically then,
you know, any kind
of task that I
can think of that,
you know, I was
pricing out some
electronics. I wanted
to try to do some
research. at where
the best price was,
or we do our weekly
podcast and, you know,
want to catch up on
what's happened in the
news or what are the
things that, you know,
might want to talk
about or go deeper in.
So we have the ability
to kind of just kick
this thing off. And
then through the, what
we call Canvas creator
agent, it can write
it in a different part
of our platform and
send an email when
it's ready. We can run
that on the schedule
too. So if you follow
John on social, you'd
probably see, like, you
know, every day he's got
something interesting
to say. And I'd say
it's been a out 50
% of the time that's
inching up, that that's
coming at least
partially, if not fully,
from this automation,
which is pretty cool.
So you found the
4-0 web search.
That is a definite
step up, eh?
From what we were using,
I've been using,
I heard Roof say
about, you know,
MCPs being a little
overrated and probably
true, but I've been
loving just the
ease with which I've
been able to get
perplexity at MCP
for our development
process. So like when
we're doing vibe coding,
one of the things
I'm always doing in my
system prompt is trying
to make sure that
the planning step is
going out to perplexity
and, you know,
considering all the
options for how you might
implement a particular
thing or what libraries
to bring in, I have
found that has been
tremendously helpful to
accelerate how quickly
we can build things
or like, you know,
avoid bad paths to go
down when the agent,
you know,
90% of people
maybe develop this
functionality one way,
but because of our
infrastructure and
our in our situation.
If we just let it
flow and do the plan,
we'd miss that. So
I'm a heavy user of
perplexity for that. I
haven't yet tried the
opening. I want to
kind of compare them.
I'm curious if anybody
else has, you know,
opinions or what
to get the research
to work, we need
good search.
And we also need
kind of good,
agentic flow to kind
of pull out the,
the bright level
of insight.
Right. That's
it. And it feeds
into all the other
tasks. What are
you typically
using that roof?
I, as you guys
know, I've built
several MCP servers,
one that abstracts
all my edge
functions and agents.
But I find that
it's hard to invoke
sometimes, right? And it
doesn't always understand
when and how it
needs to be invoked.
So if you are using
MCP servers, you
have to give it a pretty
detailed prompt to
tell it when and why
to invoke the MCP.
I actually end up
using a combination
of shell scripts
that do the exact
same thing. So,
for example, if I
want to use the
perplexity are now the
web search capability
from OpenAI,
I'm using a curl
-based shell script
with a command
line arguments,
and then just
basically telling the
Rue code, in my
particular case, when to
invoke those command
line arguments.
And that actually
seems to work better.
It's not as verbose.
I notice it takes like
a buck just to get
the, you know, code
inclined to even figure out
how to use the MCP
server, even though I've
already told it many
times how the MCP server
works. It's like, oh,
I got to go figure
out all the different
commands and do some
tests. No, I just want
you to run it. Right.
So it's,
I don't know, it depends.
One thing I've
seen with that is
the resource,
if you pull that
in first, and
the resource has
kind of like a
system prompt
specific to
the MCP server.
So we do all of
our development
tracking in
Azure DevOps. So
I've been having
a lot of fun.
with just using
Claude and like Cloud
desktop app and, you
know, giving it to a
kind of non-technical
program manager
and be like, you know,
what are we getting
done? Where are the
status of things,
right? And the problem
with some of that
is those queries
can be very finicky.
And so what I found
has helped a lot is
that the first step
of the MCP is just to
pull in like, this
is the project name,
this is who's working
on it. This is how
you spell, you know,
this is the structure
of what you need to
put into a query.
And that comes
in just as a text
file, as if it's
like a, a system
prompter an
attachment in there.
And when you
do that, I've
found it works
a lot better.
It also just saves
time from not having
to, you know,
script something for
each platform. And
there's a lot of
like people out
there doing it right
now. So it's kind
of like, you know,
vibe.
What's the vibe
server building?
I don't know.
In fairness to
my description,
I'm a power user.
I don't even
bother with the
desktop clients.
So it's a, I'm trying to
completely.
different things.
For what you're
described, it makes
perfect sense. Yeah.
No, and that's the fun
thing about my job
is I'm trying to
square both worlds,
right? Like, I love the
power use cases.
And we want to bring
as much of that to
people without them,
like, you know,
getting lost in, like,
one of the things
we're working on is
like, we can make
our platform into an
MCP client. It's
not too hard to do.
But right now, most
MCP clients just have,
you know, the config
file you edit. And that's
going to be too much
for a normal user.
So we'll have to put
an interface over that
or think about a way
to abstract that away,
just like we do with
the task service.
So overall,
so overall this is
a task, agentic task
workflow system or
task executive system.
Yeah, yeah. So basically
I can show you a
demo, but basically,
yeah, we are, we're
taking what, you know,
you could easily do
in Python, right,
or, you know, make a
tight script file and
do a bunch of things.
We're trying to
make that, give
it an interface,
give it feedback,
give you the
experience of
like an auto-gen
or, you know,
baby AI,
baby AGI, but without the
need for the
technical detail.
So like all this
stuff is kind of baked
into how we think
about it, you know,
from a data model that
can be scaled across
all the other tools
that we've built.
you know, putting that
into services that
use, you know, we
use transcription, we
use a parsing from
whatever blob of text
we get from the
transcript into a
structure of JSON that,
you know, has specific
things that will
trigger the workflow,
as well as, you
know, the ability
to kind of see
what it's doing.
so like if I can show
you hopefully the
demo gods are with me
but last 30 seconds or
so randy okay so real
quick I'm preparing
for the podcast this
afternoon can you
research the biggest
updates in AI news that
might be worth
thinking about then run
through our agent and
structure with bullet
points for me to brief
myself and then save
it to a canvas document
send me an email.
And this is slightly
slower just because
it's our dev environment,
but it's got a nicer
UI. So I wanted to
show the good stuff.
And are you guys
in beta, Randy?
Yeah.
We actually, we just
opened up a bunch
more seats. So
basically, you know,
anybody who's interested
can now sign up,
happy to kind of talk
off on about that.
But yeah.
So see, like this is all,
you know, under the
hood, there's. there's
a database and
there's data structure
powering all this,
but now we can kind
of, you know, we're
exposing the steps.
We're showing, you
know, here's what
I asked for, and
here's kind of what
it found from the
open AI search.
And then it's passing
that to the next step,
which is, you know,
just an assistant
that's going
to, you know,
structure it the way
I want it. And then
it's going to
create my document.
At this point, I can
open it from here,
but it's also going to
send me an email and
email looks like
this. And then I can
pop it up and, you
know, it's ready to go.
And, you know, all
the tools that we
have on our platform
are making their
way into this task
management thing.
And then I can
go in and I can
edit the steps
as well and
change the prompts
a little bit.
And eventually we'll
have reordering
and come some
other stuff here.
So it's just like
a cool way of
getting from, you
know, really cool
automation into
something that, you
know, we can share
with beta users.
Excellent,
Randy. Thank you.
Yeah, this is really nice
work. Really nice work.
Send me an invite.
Shoot me an email. I'd
love to play with this.
It's right up my alley.
All right.
I'll find every.
Can you throw
a link in the
chat, please?
What's that?
Can you throw a link
in the chat, please?
Sure.
Thank you. If
you're looking
to find bugs,
I'm your guy.
We know we know there's
still lots of bugs.
Be gentle with us. We're
still working through it.
If there's no
bugs, if there's
no bugs, if
there's no bugs,
bugs, you're not
doing it right.
Yeah, at least
in my opinion.
You know, anyone
who looked at the
first version of
the agenects.org
site knows that.
But I'm very much
of the ship before
you're ready.
And so we're at
that stage now.
Awesome. Thanks, Randy.
So we've got ****** V.
And then if we've
got some time,
we'll also sneak
in BB as well.
So ****** V's
got a new game
he's built wants
to show us.
Way to go, ******.
Hey, guys, I'm ******.
****** V3. Check
on my website
if you want,
****** V3.com.
I'll keep it short
and sweet, guys.
I was playing
around on this site.
You guys ever go to
this site before?
3JS examples.
It's freaking awesome,
okay? Go on here.
Look at this little
thing. It's not
really complete, right?
It doesn't really
fall. It's just kind
of like do this.
Physics examples,
animations
examples, right?
And then you can pull,
look, you click right?
and you got code right
pretty cool right i
was like hey wait a
second so i was like hey
wait let me let me
pull up this one little
animation thing let me
pull up the code for
it right and then it's
just this big html
file i can't do like i
don't really know like
how to render this
stuff really yet i don't
really know that much
about coding and stuff
right so i give it to
my ai i'm like hey i
got this html file
does this really cool
thing in three js i
want to make like a game
with it right just
render the thing right
right just like show
it first right and so
that's what i did first
i had to just build the
platform and show it
so I can move the balls
move the mouse and
the balls moved right
then I was like hey make
it so the balls fall
off the platform boom
okay now the balls
fall of the platform
that's fun right I was
like okay now uh wait
now so when the balls
fall off the platform
I want to have like you
know a game like tell
me that the the balls
are all done and like
then reset the balls
right and I was like
okay cool let's do that
and so I just kind
of keep going with it
right we put a a random
level generator in
here. So this goes
between 50,000 and 200,000
particles on the
platform at a time. Okay.
So this will show
you can kind of flip
through that. This
resets the regular
levels. So there's
like three levels,
levels one, two, and
three, 50,000, 100
,000 and 150,000
particles. You have to
push off the part of
the platform. Okay.
Then let's say we
wanted to mess with
things a little bit.
All right. Okay.
Ooh,
some, some, some
Okay, what
happens if I, uh,
turn the gravity down?
Whoa.
Whoa,
guys, look.
Okay, wait, let
me, wait, you
turn up the
particle size.
They fly all
over the place.
This is really
fun now. Okay.
Now wait, now wait, let
me turn the gravity back.
Oh!
All right, guys.
So,
uh, yeah, just really
having a lot of fun
over here. So, uh, if
you want to push some
particles off of a
platform, um, and kind of
just like, brain rot
you know just hang out
and do this it's
incredibly addicting all
right some of the feedback
so far has been it's
giving flappy birds
in terms of addicting
some of the feedback
has been my kid likes
to play this game but
in real life um so all
right guys that's that's
that's my show that's
what is uh what is um
what was it three j
s oh yeah three js so
you go to the uh it's
three js dot org okay
and then there's like
examples right here.
There's all these cool
websites that were
built with 3JS to like,
you know, and you
start poking around
these and you're going
to be like, holy ****,
I want to build this
stuff, right? And
then you go to
examples, right? And
that's where you can
start to see the code.
Another really cool
one is React 3 fiber.
There's a ton
of examples on
the React three
fiber examples.
A really cool repository
of examples here.
And then it opens up
in a code sandbox right
that you can just
go ahead and um look
download that to a zip
file right and then pull
that into your cursor
and use it as a base
for your for your next
game guys right and
you'll learn a lot let
me tell you something
game **** is way
different than like
trying to build like a
sass and stuff development
is totally different
and we'll like so
like i try i like watched
a couple of YouTube
videos and stuff,
there's tons of, like,
React racing games
and react whatever
games and stuff to
start looking at. But,
yeah, it's just a
lot of fun. There's
actually a couple
of examples of
games right here,
game prototypes. This
is the React 3
fiber examples site.
Right. So this
one right here.
Kind of cool. So fun to
play around with guys.
All vibes, right?
Super vibes. coding and
lots of learning
too, right? Because I
had it first, it made
this ***** thousand
line main JS file,
right? And then I was
like, hey, let's break
this up into components,
right? Let's put
the physics into one
file. Let's put the
game controls into
another file. Let's
modularize it. So it's
also like another
way to kind of, you
know, practice that,
you know, actually
learning development
and like software like
principles and things
like that in the
process of it. So it's
where I am, guys. That's
what I'm doing.
Thanks for listening.
I'm ****** V3. Check
me out. You should
make it multiplayer
and then time it and
see which team can
get all the balls off.
Oh,
that would be fun,
right? Right? There's
a lot I could do with
it. So thanks guys.
I love that part
where, you know, you
crank out an app
in like 20 minutes.
And the comment
was, why didn't you
include all these
other features and
the thing you built
in 20 minutes?
you know i get
that i get that
every day right what
are you going to
do yeah what are
you going to do
why did you give it
away for free no that
that's that's awesome
i love it you know it's
uh it's it's exactly
the sort of stuff i
love this i want to
play with the 3d stuff
too you could add some
voice components it's
like sims or something
i love it you should
add some audio um to
the experience it will
completely blow people's
mind and you thought
actually actually
go to you audio and
generate a bunch of like
tracks there and it'll
make some amazing uh
clips and that could
be very very addictive
to what you created
there yeah there's
there's a couple i had
i had like a little
bloop sound on there i
was i was playing with
it but um i don't know
if you guys ever done
game dev if you uh
trying to drop you're
dropping 100 of balls
at the same time and
i want one bloop for
each sound right audio
overload because they
dropped like 800 balls
at the same time so
that's the bug I was
trying to work out I was
trying to put the
sound but it kept on
bugging out yeah any
any solves for that you
guys know how to do
like audio buffering or
something like that
when you have like a
repeated sound that plays
800 times but it really
only needs to play
yeah yeah you you can
there's a few different
ways that I do it
I usually create a cache
of the wave file and
then I just you so
the first time if it's
if it's dynamically
generated I'll just save
it and then I do a
quick check if the cache
is empty or not. Now
you could do that
either local like you
can just let the user do
that and store it in
their local storage.
But the drawback
to that is it will
then, you know, every
time you'll have to
load it for every
other user. So if
you want to go cheap,
you can basically
create a central
cache for all users.
There's so many
cool hacks. like,
for example,
with animations,
if you have an
animation that
is displayed
more than once,
you pretty much,
instead of having them
run as separate scripts
pretty much inside,
you force it to,
okay, no, just run
this thing once
and just use the
same, you know,
the same process.
And maybe you can
off, you know, you
can offset the
display, but still
use the same
calculations to render,
the animation so you
pretty much cut down
the animation in half
by doing something
like that and it's extremely
extremely efficient
like i've done a
lot of like little
apps uh for mobile uh
and like efficiency is
everything i'm always
thinking about how
can how the **** can
i optimize this thing
so the mechanics don't
get stuck um it's
amazing because every
little thing counts
like every little
calculation and you have
to be paranoid about
it it's really uh fun
I love it.
Thanks a lot. I
appreciate that.
I'd love to ask
you to you, doctor,
about that. It
seems like you've
got some
experience there.
Yeah.
I mean, one
drink with the
audio, you can
add you on,
like, signal processor.
So you don't, like,
when you play the
audio, you don't
just play directly
to the output.
You run it through
some component,
basically, that
takes all these
waves and creates
a one super.
And one cool thing
you can do about
it, if there is
a lot of, like,
drops, you can
convert it to
like explosion
or something like
if there is a
lot of high-speed
momentum there after
a few balls people
are not going to
figure out whether it's
like hundred ball
or 400 walls or so
you just have like
one to 10 or one to 30
you will have separate
to it in a normal
way after that it's
like just keep the
same file with 100
balls $1,000. Yeah,
it just worked.
Guys,
we're going to try
and we're going
to try and get
Bibi in as well.
Bibi's got a quick
little demo, 155.
Go ahead, Bibi,
are you with us?
I see the screen share.
I don't hear
your audio, Bibi.
H.P. Mind, man, I haven't
seen that in 10 years.
Bibi, I don't know
if you got yourself
on mute, but we
cannot hear you.
Did we just go to
a tire machine?
Yeah, it's like I
spent so much time in
Ph.P. My Min back
in like when I used
to crank out on Drupal
sites and stuff.
In the 2000s icons.
Yeah.
I'm dying to hear
Bibi's voice to see
what the heck we're
looking at. But it's,
I thought I was
going retro with my
1981 design. time
this this yeah so
this is okay he's I
can think I it his
name on the screen
is 74 QWC 42 so
he's he's away from
the keyboard at the
moment so he's
screen BB you there
if we got if we got
a bit of time we got
a bit of time Chris
Royce has got a
little quick little
demo maybe he could
show it let's I'm
I'm sure he created a
quantum I don't do
a new dimension on a
vibe coding session
on a Tuesday night.
Yeah, that's right.
All right.
Everybody with their
vibe coding, right, is
having a problem of
your guys' AIs need to
understand the entire
context of what is
happening in the code.
So I built a co-base
ontology that plots
your entire co-base out
in the Neo4J as an
MCP then allows you to
query your co-base and
give your AI. agent
a complete understanding
of how every
variable file directory
everything integrates
together so every time
it acts it acts with
full knowledge of every
single thing that's
happening I can show
you a demo of it if
I could share my screen
yeah here we go I
didn't hear me know
well so basically it's
taking my code base
here and it is going to
then plot it all into
a Neo 4J database base
and it takes a second
to run. But then
once it's all updated
as the AI agents code,
you can have
multiple agents
coding at once.
As they code, they
will update the
Neo4J graph,
and then they will
continue to update
the relationships
as it goes. So I can
create a multi-agent
dev team that's all
working together
simultaneously at once.
So just a second,
while this code's out.
And you got a
repo link for
this? Is this
open source or?
I'm still building
it. I've just been
building it the
last couple of days.
I'm building the same
thing, by the way.
Testing.
Can you guys hear
me now? I'm testing.
Yes, we can.
Okay, so I would...
Let me know that
I can do a quick
presentation.
Yeah, we'll do, BB.
Okay, thanks. It takes
just a second for it
to get uploaded into
the online database.
So what are you scanning
all the files and
getting stuff in Neo4G,
about the structure?
variables the functions
the files so here
we go as a representation
so we've got the
utilities file it
you know it tells
everything that it
defines it tells you
references uses imports you
know we can increase
this to and and it
shows you how just
like everything in the
code is interconnected
and right now I'm
I'm fixing it because
I was having some
issues with cross file
functionality but it's
going to show how in
my current version,
it's going to show
how all of these are
connected together and
interwoven together.
Does that make sense?
And then you can
query this and you
can have the MCP query
this and just tell
your AI coding agents,
everything that is
happening at all times
throughout the co-base.
It'll have a complete
understanding of how
everything interacts.
And Chris,
yeah.
Tell us about
your background.
Like, how did you
get to this point?
If I'm not, if not
mistaken, you're
not like a
programmer by trade.
Um, no, no, I'm, I'm a,
I'm a vibe
coder by trade.
All right. So I've
been, I've been using
AI for like three,
four years now. And
I've been just doing
nothing but trying
to figure out how
to get AI to give me
the best answers.
And then eight months
ago, I decided to
get into trying to
build a program for
my company. And then
that's when I started
using AI to code.
After two months, I
was recording like
millions of people on
Twitch, analyzing billions
of messages with
AI models. and then
I got invited into
the Ph.D. program at K
-State for computer
science, even though I'd
never even taken a
computer class. And
I've just been doing
all kinds of crazy
stuff. And it's more
about, I've been more
about learning, like,
what is all possible?
And then when I
do find out what's
possible, I then ask
AI how to do it. And
then I just follow
the steps like a
recipe. And I've just
been able to learn
just, like, so much
in the last, like,
two years, amazing.
And are you using,
sorry,
are using Z or,
like, Rue or
Klein or Cursor,
like, what's the
tool you're using
to build it?
I initially just
used cursor to just,
like, build everything
out and give me ideas,
and I went through,
like, four iterations,
and then after
understanding how the
MCPs worked and how
everything worked,
then I came up with
an ultimate plan, and
then I started
building that plan out
with Rue, but I used
cursor to just, like,
run and test everything
and, you know, do
all my mess-ups, right?
But I did, like, I
went through, like,
two, three days of
messing up and understanding
everything. And
then once I got the
great plan in action,
then I went to Rue with
the plan, you know.
Hey, Chris,
one interesting
thing to try is,
like, instead of
this Neo4J, like,
which is labeled
property graph,
use like RDF type. Like,
so if there is a, like,
a service called Star
Dog that gives you, like,
free database, maybe
with five million, like
entities you can put
in. Yeah, this gives
me a free database.
This is free. Right.
The free version. So
Star Dog gives you
free, like, biting
limit is, like, like
5 million entities
or something like.
Yeah, but Neo4J comes
where you can put
vectors in. You can
do vector searches.
Yeah, but Neo4J
is not the full
knowledge graph. It's
the labeled property
graph. Like, so
if you just try
the startup just
for the Giggles and
see if you get
better performance.
Yeah, but that's
what I want. I
want the property
graph because like
all of these notes
have all of the
properties in it,
including IDs.
So I can do temporal,
I can like track
temporally everything
that's happening.
I want the properties
and I want to add
more properties
No, the RDF, it's a
different You still
have properties But
it's a different type
of guys It's more
richer representation
I mean, if you did
some idea to look at
What is it called?
RDF
The type of like just
Google RDF graphs
You will find the And
just point your AI
and see if you can
just write code Yeah,
you know what you
should do, Chris
also I did a project
with like six or
seven months ago
now, probably longer.
Hypergraph,
check that out.
So you can define the
hypergraph structure
and save that to
the open AI vector.
You can do all kinds
of crazy stuff with it.
Yeah, but this just
uses like TS morph,
right? And I don't have
to pay API fees and
stuff. And plus, I
don't want the LLMs
analyzing or coding this
out because they make
hallucinations, like
doing it this way.
Like, I know 100% like
it's correct, right?
No, the RDFs actually
reduce hallucinations
because, like,
just try it, like,
and see, like, if
you, like, just
wipe-coded. It's
probably going to be,
like, three lines
for you, like, too.
Okay. You can just
ask client to use the
RDF graph instead of the
label property graph.
Have you got this
up on a repo, Chris?
No, yeah.
I'm still finalizing.
All right, well, do
share when you do.
Okay.
Yeah, because if you
can see right now, the.
cross-file relationships
aren't very
strong, and that's, I'm
having to rework the
system to make that a
lot better. But, yeah.
Yeah, a visual
representation. Yeah.
It's spectacular.
We're going to try
and, thank you, Chris.
Let us know when you
got that repo up.
Love it. You guys,
that's awesome.
Chris, you're doing
amazing work, by the
way. And just randomly
creating these
crazy awesome
things. So good job.
Fantastic.
Bibi you got four minutes
tight four minutes
sorry guys can you
hear me now yes so
I will introduce
myself quickly because
it's my first time my
name is Bibi so I had
my master degree in
diffusion model from
Paris University 15
years ago and at that
time I was putting
on my resume all my
math that I did and
I never find a job so
I had to change put
my programming skills
as C++ math lab at
that time and I worked
Since then, I worked
as a data engineer,
data scientists for many
corporations,
like Volkswagen,
Air Liquid,
and recently
Dejardin Bank.
And now I am
building, I built
an agency for a
branding company.
So what I want
to show her, so I
built everything
for him, for them,
and I doctorizing
their documents.
And I used ChromaDB.
And when I was, when
I started scaling,
I had. some performance
issues. So I had to
adapt the quads. So
they already have my
squads. So you see my
screen about my squad.
So I had to find
a new solution.
I want to use PG vectors.
But PG vectors, they
already have the
database. They don't
want to invest in
another database.
And also I have to
modify all codes
in order to make it
work. So I came up
with this solution,
vectorizing
documents that I
want to show you
very quickly.
So let me let me just
delete see for the demo
so my most experience
is as uh work
on corporation so
now i'm trying to
apply my experience
for that's no so
i build an agentic
delete from sorry
built us in php
yeah yeah my squad
phton my squad so
i just i use uh i
must No, I built
it on React, sorry.
But I use this
database of MySQL.
Old school.
So as you know,
when you notice
PGVector, they
have their own
embedding, right?
But MySquare, they don't
have it. So
what I did is,
so when I go
to the website.
And why not just
use PGVector?
Because they already
have the, they
already have MySQL.
and I have to, they
don't want to invest
in a new database.
So, so I used, I
build my own PG
vector, but with my
squire and, and, uh,
and, uh,
what you're called?
And, uh, my squad
and, uh, embeddings.
And you can do
similarity and,
and all the
various, okay?
Yeah,
yeah, yeah, I
show you. Yeah.
So, and I'm
applying to, I'm
applying to open
source it. So the,
the basic idea
is sometimes,
uh, don't rely on
tools. use your
own solution sometimes
is better and
more efficient than
trying to. So let
me take this
document for example.
So when we go here,
and you can see
the embedding.
I hope this.
And why aren't you
using like UI libraries
like Shadzian or
anything like that?
No, I'm not using. I'm
using my own. This labor,
Shatzian, what did
you use Shatzian?
Makes it look good.
Yeah, I know. So,
all this code that I
did, AI agentic, I
did during questions.
See, I did, no, the
embedding are here.
I did it during
COVID time.
I didn't use AI 5%.
No, I use little bit
if I don't have time.
I use if I have
sport trobe shooting.
So,
what I did also?
So now you see all
I'm bidding here.
And I built an
adjunct for them.
I get inspired because
I worked as ORAC
business with
consultant architects.
So they have
what called the
Orak background
process at night.
They process
all documents.
So I know I'm
doing as an agent
who process all
their document
and vectorizing
their documents.
They can use it
in the morning.
that's all and i am
planning to
open source this
you build a pg like a
vector extension
to my SQL
again you build a vector
database extension
to mySQL exactly yeah
it's like phdg vector
version but for my
squad so now the users
there are many company
big company use my
squad uh they just need
to get to get they can
get my solution so
they don't need to have
another pi-con or paying
solution. They just
integrated the solution
and they are fine.
And I tested it.
I tested the
architecture. I
did everything
from A to Z.
Even during COVID time,
I built everything.
At that time, I
remember I said an email
to some lawyers. I
want to do CHAPT for
them, but they never
answered me. But no,
since three years,
now I am just
deploying models,
custom models.
So for the company,
I deployed DIPSEC,
and I did this RAC
solution for them,
and they are
happy about it
because they care
about privacy.
They don't want
to use API because
they have some
sensitive data.
This is why I
came up with this.
Let me get this straight.
They're care
about privacy, so
they used a Chinese
language model?
No,
it's deployed in my,
in Canada cluster.
How do you get
around all the,
you know, did you
retrain it to get
rid of all the,
like, you know,
vulnerabilities and
all that sort of stuff?
Yeah, yeah, I play
some function to
take all Chinese,
Chinese language,
all the English,
and I think this thing,
they found everything.
So, as you see, it's
in Canada, cluster,
so it's, it's
custom, it's custom,
it's custom, custom
what they have.
Okay,
cool. and yeah this is
what I am working on
so I am more corporation
so I always this is
why my design is not
nice when you notice
people find sometimes
they have some solution
just they do process
their data this is why
but I am full stack I
can do from A to C from
training models
vectorizing documents RAD
solution and database
connection and all this
except my I am not
good at design design.
Yeah, so, so thanks for
presenting, by
the way. You know,
always interesting
to create a
new vector for my sequel.
Yeah,
my opinion is
there's no reason
for your stuff
to look bad,
just straight up.
Like, there are
so many libraries
out there today.
The only reason
something looks
bad is you didn't
take the time to
go find the right
library to use.
So, you know,
it's literally, I
showed you guys what I
designed in like five
minutes, right? There's
no reason for
something to you just
choose the right library
um all right you want
to stop sharing for
sec yeah yeah yes baby
sorry no yeah yeah
there's a there's a
there's a library
called chad cn i don't i
use that frequently
it's it's you know the
examples that i'm
showing you is it uses
that um and bb we can
still see your desktop
i'm trying i'm not to
stop sharing because
i'm i am used to you
with microsoft tips
when you share you
will all right take
those so here While you
guys are presenting,
I actually let my
bot continue to work.
So just as a
quick update,
just to guys
show you this.
So previously when
I was showing you
guys, my retro style
VB code extension
here, now it's,
let's go here power.
I'm going to
restart it. I'm
going to go to
restart system.
And, you know, this is
using Chad CN,
by the way.
And so essentially
what you're
seeing. So now it's
branded DevOps.
and DevOps v.1,
and someone's
breathing into the
screen. Can you
mute yourself?
My dog's going crazy?
One sec.
All right.
So now, so what I
did is I create that
plans. Now when
you go in here, you
can see now I've got
eight AWS options.
I've got a menu,
help terminals.
I've got, you know,
this has been sort of
customized specifically
for the needs of
deploying an agent-based
system, right? So, you
know, you've got all
the capabilities I just
exposed from the CLI.
You can go in here,
you can see different
tasks that were done.
It's done in a super,
you know, stylized
approach because, you
know, I'm not creating
a product for someone to
buy. I'm more showing
what's possible. But
you get the idea here,
right? So I can interact
with my agents. I
don't think I've, I
don't think we've seen
any kind of BS code.
extension that looks
quite like this, right?
So there's a disaster
recovery plan updated.
So basically I'm
communicating with
the agent much the
same way I might
communicate with a
member of my team.
And that gives me
the ability to more
cleanly interact
with, you know,
the systems in a way
I might use Slack
or something for
other teammates.
Yeah. So again,
the key here was
to use the plans.
And then so I
implemented each
of these plans.
And there we go.
yeah in my case i spend
more time on training
and doing you know
i'm not focusing on
design but i would love
to be really good in
design to be really no
worries baby we've we've
we've moved on um
anybody else anybody
else have anything they
want to present today
or to discuss um you
know this this is this
is the this is your
moment to uh to show and
tell if if you want
present anything or
just randomly talk
otherwise we'll take a quick
moment rUv, just uh
if anybody does want
to put their hands up
just do so but i'll
just take a quick moment
about the committees
um so first of all
discord uh ocean and in
crosswood will be on
that this weekend to
clean up the access
so that we can see the
historical uh chats
in the various discord
channels and well i mean
in practicality we'll
probably keep both of
those um communication
or both of those
channels going
WhatsApp and
Discord for a while.
The chapter management
will have a sign
-up form coming,
and we know we've
already gotten a whole
pile of requests.
So we'll sort all
those and we'll
be in touch with
you soon on that.
There's lots
of committees.
So, well, I think Brad's
here. Brad can pop
that sign-up sheet
again, but keep your eyes
open for that in the
WhatsApp community.
A ton of people
have signed up.
There's still room for
more participation.
There's lots of stuff
that we can take on.
So it's going to
be a real busy and
fruitful April as
things get started. The
marketing committee
is just digging in.
So thanks to everybody
who has signed up.
And looking forward
to everybody else
who is going to join
in one of those dozen
working groups
that's getting going.
It should be
a lot of fun.
yeah for sure when are
these sorry when are
uh like how can we
be updated on uh or
when when it's like the
the next like official
event or yeah so the
first uh you know
the first if you're if
you're talking about
an agenics foundation
event um the inaugural
event uh that's just
being mapped at when
that's going to come
together. So Alexander
or Alex Gross is
heading up the events
group.
So, and there's
a number of folks
there that is
working with that
volunteered to
sign up for that.
So that'll be in
conjunction that, I mean,
we expect probably
in the next 60 days,
something on those,
the kickoff event.
Don't hope for that.
Because I'm
not the chair.
Probably, I mean,
I'm probably not
the only one. A
lot of people have
this. We focus on
too many things.
And I would love
to participate and
kind of align in
some way or another.
And I went at some
point and subscribed
like for a few
of these things.
And then I'm
like, okay, how do
I keep track of
this? Because I
got so much ****
going on, right?
And I need more
help. I need more.
That'll be the
role of the
chairs is to
make sure that
everybody who's
on that committee
has got a clear idea
of what the schedule
looks like. and,
you know, where
every group will
meet every two weeks.
Will I get an
email, you know?
Oh, yeah.
Where is this
going to pop out?
Are you, have you
signed up? Let's
get the sign out
sheet up here.
Yeah, it's every chair
is pulling together
their group and then
I'll set up the schedules
and work, because we've
got time zones too.
We have people from
all around the world.
So it's got to work for
everybody in
that committee.
to lay out what the
first 30-day tasks
are and what the
30 and 90 days and
really set the tone
for the course of the
year and what the
foundation is going
to do to support.
First, the members,
secondly, other
committees, and then
the public in
terms of awareness.
There's so much
experience and so many
skill sets in the
community. So looking
forward to seeing
how that grows.
and for anyone that's
interested in helping
support us you
know we we've got a
membership drive of
sorts so there if you
go to the agentix.org
site slash memberships
you'll see that
you can sign up you
know right now we're
we're volunteer-based
organizations so
we're all contributing
to the the process
and where as we build
out all the features
and functionalities
we'll make them
available the site's a
little bit you know
wishful at this point
But we're building
it, ambitious.
There you go.
That's the right term.
But, you know,
it is what it is.
So we're, if
you want to help
in any way,
whether that's
financial, finding
us sponsors,
contributing code,
building stuff, whatever,
opening up new chapters,
you know, just
whatever it is
that you think
you can help.
We're, we're
the crew, right?
We're not in
this to make any
money. It's
not for profit.
So this is, it's an
organization to do what
we. love which is build
stuff really that's
it that's the that's
the entire plan um
so if you're into it
we'd love to have you
help just we've got
discord channel for
those you like discord
the WhatsApp continues
to be quite active
for those who prefer
WhatsApp or GitHub
whatever we've got lots
of different places
for you to contribute
and we've got multiple
meetings now for
different groups which
Rob just mentioned so
yeah um I Excellent.
Just so I've spotted it,
Dr. Suarez, is your
first name, Gabriel?
Yes,
yes.
Gotcha.
Okay.
All sounds good.
Yeah, so it's
cool. It's cool.
It's fun to
build this stuff.
I'm a building.
I'm a builder.
I am one of
those people that
somehow I got the
pipelines really
oiled up to make
whatever is.
running in my
head it becomes
a reality that
you can play
with in the end
so it's amazing
yeah it's the it's
going from idea to
implementation is now
like there's no friction
it's just asking a couple
questions and voila
but especially right
like if you've been
playing with this for
a few years now right
because like if you're
just entering yeah it's
going to take a little
while to, you know,
learning curves and
getting the hang of,
like, how do I squeeze
the most out of, like,
AI or AI agents
or whatever
you're waking there.
But eventually, yeah,
man, you develop,
like, little
approaches, pipelines,
you know, you have
a nice stack, and,
you know, you do your
own little scripts
for this, for that, you
automate this, that,
and suddenly you're
like, you're a beast,
like, in your case
right now, like that
approach, where you,
you, you, you you
segregate your plans and
you just let it do like
little modules thing.
And if it fails a
little portion, that's
all right. It's fine.
You know, it got all
these other things
right. I'll just tweak
this one and boom.
Oh my God. Like you
are industrial pretty
much. It's industrialized
development.
So I want to clarify
something very quickly.
So people know
everyone talking
about using code for AI,
using coding
with AI, which
is very good,
very helpful.
But there is a nuance.
If you don't
see something,
you cannot
understand it. You
cannot run 10
,000 line of code.
You have the app.
But when you run it
in the production,
there are some issue
where you have to go
do troubleshooting
and all those stuff.
So this is why
that people
they have to understand.
You can know.
No, that's totally wrong.
So I put out 10 million
lines of code last
year. Obviously, I
didn't look at every one
of those lines. every
one of those lines
of code the the it
isn't it isn't possible
i've proven it's possible
i my my customers
are fortune 500
companies the the the the
problem and the the
solution that problem
is tests and structure
right if you're
just haphazardly creating
code with no real
plan then of course
you're going to garbage
garbage in garbage out
so the you know i've
i just proved you
that i can put out 100
,000 lines of code in
three hours and it'd
be completely functional
without any security
concerns because
I have a clear and
defined strategy for
testing, implementation,
and deployment.
Now, if you skip all
those things, you
know, do I have to
look at every one of
the lines of code
to know that that is
correct and inappropriate?
No, of course not.
In the same way
that you start a new
project, you're not
looking at every line
of code. You know,
I don't know how the
Linux subcernal
works, because I never
looked at it, but I
know it works, right?
My point is you
know coding. You
have all those years
of experience,
so you know where
to go to fix if
there is a problem.
So you know what I mean?
This is my point.
I know what you mean,
but I think you're wrong.
Okay.
I think it sounds
like this sort of
thing, like an old
school developer
would say, you know,
my job is safe. No,
I can automate
everything you do
right now, today,
without any question.
And that's, and, you
know, that is the
reality that we face.
I'm not saying that
to diminish your 20
years of experience.
I'm just saying
that as a matter
of fact that me
as a developer,
my role as an
agendic developer is
to literally put
myself at work.
And that is a fact.
That's nothing
I can do, you
know, the way,
the reason I can
create these
highly structured
approaches that
automates myself, of
course, is because
I've been doing it
since I was, you
know, eight years
old and I've got,
you know, 36 years
of experience building
these systems.
But once I've
implemented structures
that takes my 36
years of experience,
you don't need
me anymore.
That's just
the way it is.
Yeah, yeah.
So my point is...
I think people
need to
appreciate. People,
there's like
a separation.
I got like a break
between the old
-timer developer. My
brother is like a
full-stack developer.
And I tell him
I'm a full-stack AI
developer at this
point. And I can do
whatever, really.
And the thing is
that there has to be
kind of like an
understanding where, okay,
you guys are telling,
like, crying out that
pay me $1,000 now
to fix your AI ******
code. I'm like,
because you don't
understand anything. Look,
you got to understand
that at some point
there's going to emerge
some form of hybrid
like myself and probably,
you know, that are.
have enough code
understanding.
I'm not a programmer,
right?
But I have enough code
understanding that I can
communicate to a
programmer almost exactly
at his level, almost
as if you have people
from two different
countries with slightly
different tonal
intonations in their
languages. But I can, I
speak Spanish and I can
understand an Italian,
right? If they speak
really slowly. But
the thing is that the
code can have really
weird things, but at
this point, after years
of working with AI
development, I
understand a lot
of the lines,
and I actually
write some of
the lines myself,
very rarely, right?
But yeah, I tweak
parameters, you know,
and I decide whether
what the AI is
giving me is **** or
no, and I know, I know
I can read through
line by line, code
by And so, and I
don't consider myself
a programmer still,
but I know full
stack development,
back and front end,
API integration,
database, SQL.
I don't care,
AWS deployments,
load balancing.
I don't care.
Like, we'll talk
about anything,
and I can go all around
it. And because AI,
I've learned the
structure of development,
which is a whole
different thing
than just coding.
And people,
like the all
-time developer,
what is the difference?
We copy-based
stuff from AI, but
you guys go to
Stack Overflow? Come
on, we've been
doing the same ****.
AI is very efficient.
It's just way, ****,
more efficient,
right? As all,
it's the same ****.
But my point
very quickly,
let's see this scenario.
One person who
has background
in architecture,
development,
MLOPS, everything,
and he used AI.
And another guy,
he used only AI, but
he figured out coding.
Which one is more?
They use the same way
to do using AI. Which
one is more perform?
Sure. That's a
matter of time.
So the curves are
going this way.
And the work,
you know, the tools
are becoming more
and more powerful to
handle more and more
of the complexity
requiring less and
less technical
awareness. But of course,
the experience
person has the
advantage coming
in right. now.
And that's going
to continue
until that
crossover happens.
So at some point in
the future, yeah,
absolutely.
Yeah.
So I'm not against
you. I use AI. I am
AI guy. I use AI.
But my point is, if
you have the whole
picture, you are
outside of the box and
use AI like everyone
know, you would be
more performance.
You do a better job.
This is my point.
I like to explain the
full impact of what
the demo I just showed
you is actually going
to do. So if we have
a Neo4J. graph, a
visualization of the
entire dataset, and
every time an AI agent
makes a code change,
and it updates that
visual graph, that means
I can have five, ten,
AI agents working
on the code all at once.
I can have an agent
looking for tech
debt. I can have an
agent analyzing the entire
architecture looking
for ways to improve
that. I can have
agents coding this. I
can have them looking
at domains. I can build
an entire dev team
that will be a thousand
times better than
any developer ever,
right? And that is what
this Neo 4J graph
unlocks is a dev team.
I don't think I disagree
with what Bivie is
saying. I think the
difference is right now
versus where we're
going. And right now,
100%, an ML architect
is going to know more
about the implementations
of an ML model and
stuff like that. And
that's why people hire
me. And I'm cognizant
of that. I think the
bar is being removed
for a lot of the things
that used to require
technical proficiency.
What used to
require, you know,
knowing how to, you
know, build PHP,
now you can use
WordPress for,
right? And each step
makes it easier.
And as we go forward,
there is a sort of
abstraction of the
complexity of these
systems to a point
where it's just going
to be, you know, ask
the AI, it'll go do
it. And we will
reliably say that when
Open AI, you know,
builds me a website or
application, it'll
do so in a way that's
scalable, secure,
and efficient, right?
Are we there yet? No.
Will we be there
in nine months?
100%, maybe 12
months. But so your
time for being an
expert is over.
That's all I'm saying.
Yeah, you have access
to all knowledge
that's what I
agree with you.
Yeah.
All right, we're
at time, guys.
I love these chats.
This is like the
highlight of my week. I
end the week with a
group of people that
inspire me to push
harder and build more.
of all the various
schemes I've come up with
over over the last you
know multiple decades
this is definitely
one of my my favorites
so I really appreciate
everyone who takes
the time to show up
every week and indulge
indulge us in in
their in their various
pursuits thank you
yeah so again if you're
interested in helping
us or know someone who
wants to help us invite
them show them theaedics
org i'm soliciting
because we can um
you know if if you're
going to afford 10 bucks
a month sign up for our
subscription because
it helps offset some
of our costs because
that's all currently
mostly coming out of
my pocket you know so
you know anyway thanks
everyone thank you
thanks rib thanks guys
thank you thank you
doodle robert bye bye