a question all right
so here we are we're
we're april 11th uh 2025
four months in episode
50 roof 50 all right
wow does that does
that include all those
random vibe coding
sessions i do on thursdays
or just no just this
is the 50th friday okay
and i am attempting
to to broadcast this
live to youtube just
because we we can um
and i'm just going to
share that link i i
leandro has been helping
with our marketing
activities and social media
engagement so thank
you uh leandro for
helping get all this
stuff set up um i i just
quickly shared the link
that won't be the final
resting place for for
our things this is
using my own personal
one we haven't been able
to figure how exactly
that works um so what
do we got lined up
today rob oh we got a
couple well first of all
craftsman craftsman's
gets i'm really i
can't wait to say this
he's got an ai tool uh
for gaming and character
mods so uh uh very
very fascinating i
think we got a bit of a
theme going too because
um david uh our own
david gratton he gave
a talk last week to 40
gaming startup developers
founders so he's
going to share uh some
of the the feedback and
what that experience
was like kind of some
of those uh concepts
that he got into and i
wanted to give a quick
shout out to our our
beloved chet he's got
his mckinsey in a box
getting ready everybody's
excited to see it's
a popular idea it's
it's very much time
somebody does that well
so uh looking forward
to see what that looks
like and and wow was
and then uh also brad's
got some updates uh
around the egetics
and the committees and
stuff. So I don't know
if maybe you want to
give Brad the mic for
a few minutes and then
we can dive in. Yeah.
I love the idea of
McKenzie in a box, although
I'm a little more
preference towards EY
in a box, given I built
the EY.AI platform.
But it sounds, tons
of interest in that
space, this kind of
like a functional, deep
research with a purpose
yeah so good good
good to see chef doing
that for sure he's
he's a ambitious
smart guy excited to
see what what he does
there maybe it'll be
the second company
we can claim we had
some small role in
their their success yeah
that's right um yeah
so brad want to give
a quick uh foundation
update yeah yeah
thanks thanks guys i
won't be long i'm really
looking forward to
the presentations,
but a quick foundation
update. We have 744
foundation members.
Thank you very much.
We have 72
subscribers and just
wanted to acknowledge
and say thank
you to our latest,
latest members,
different tiers.
We have Mandeep,
Audrey, um fellow harvard
person mark t david
o david b roland h
rushep p and raul b our
latest members so
welcome welcome to the to
the crew thank you
very much um for the
committees we have 12
committees going on right
now uh everyone's full
steam ahead there's
different committees
i'll be posting a sign
-up form if you do want
to join any of the
committees the sign-up
form will be in the the
chat um but all of the
committees are moving
forward on the financial
side uh um we're
there so any committee
chairs anyone involved
in the committee uh
there's a form uh to
fill out if you if you
want some financial
money um but um yeah any
anything else you want
me to provide an update
for here rob or no
that's good if we got
the committee sign up
sheets uh to circulate
there's lots of really
interesting work that's
going on so there's
and a lot of different
places to dive in
so uh welcome
everybody who
wants to wants to
throw a shoulder
behind somebody's efforts
mayor it's a we like to
call it a meritocracy
which means that if
you volunteer you're
in um that that's
the the only real
prerequisite is is uh
you know offering to help
us we're all volunteers
this is it's a not
-for-profit we're doing
this because somewhere
someone needs to push
the ideas of human
-centric agentics and
that's what we're
trying to do so here
we are sales pitch over
so like it's been it's
been a really big week
for Google I think
almost all the the big
news this week has
been somehow Google
related but so I figured
just while we're on
the topic of Google
let's let's do some vibe
coding with the new
Google studio system
but to start things off
i want to just let's
just look at my stats
on how much i i've
spent and created this
week um you know from
our friends that were
questy um so this
is the last seven days
i i find this this
this board particularly
interesting so i'd
like to start with it
just because it it kind
of quantifies all the
crazy stuff that i'm
building this week
and keep in mind this
week's been particularly
good i think i put
out close to two million
lines of code not
you know this is final
functional code, 2
million lines. I don't
even know how long
that would take you.
A regular developer, a
lifetime probably. And
this is seven days.
So, but what's
interesting, I've saved
on a daily basis.
This is per day,
$1,186. So give
or take, what's
that? $7,000 in,
you know, more than
$7,000 in the
last seven days.
And I spent $433.
So there you go. It's
pretty amazing. It's
a 73% savings uh let's
just quickly where's
my models i think it's
probably what everyone's
mostly interested in
i'm still using 3.7
latest looks like i i
jump around a little
bit to 3.5 i like 3.5
i to be honest a lot
of times i find 3.5 to
be good but it looks
like i'm doing uh i'm
doing better in terms
of caching and and just
it's just a more cost
effective model looks
like these 3.7 so
there you go that's
that's what i'm using um
they got a big they
have a big update coming
next week i won't you
won't uh um uh spill
the beans at all but
uh i'm pretty excited
they got some stuff
coming next week that we
should see too oh good
great yeah my only
thing i still haven't
been able to get their
thinking working so
i'm not sure what the
deal there is but uh
no i have to use the
anthropic model directly
for thinking so when
it comes to like doing uh
you know my orchestrator
or stuff like that.
That's I use thinking
for that. And then
I use the instruct
model. As you can tell,
the instruct model is
doing the vast majority
of the work. Yeah.
All right. Well,
speaking of free, we've
got this new Firebase
Studio. So this is
an interesting tool.
It's kind of like
a cross between lovable
and code spaces.
So you can see here,
I've got a few code
space or whatever
they call their
workspaces, I guess is
what they call it. And
And over here, we've
got some examples.
So let's build, any ideas
what we should
build here?
Let's build something.
Let's build, create
a finance dashboard
to manage the
subscriptions for the
Agentix foundation
using Stripe API.
That seems like an easy
one that we could use.
I'm just going to, let's
just see what happens.
Let's hopefully the
demo gods smile.
So then remember,
there's two ways to
use this. As far
as I can tell, you
can clone GitHub
repos, but the problem
with the GitHub
repos, that's
basically just a code
space and it doesn't
use this kind of
lovable approach.
All right. So now,
okay, it's creating
a Stripe integration.
And what's
interesting is it
looks like it's using
exactly the same
sort of approach
that I'm using with
my Spark process.
So I guess that's
confirmation
that that
approach was good.
They seem to be
using their own
version of that.
So now we've got
colors. No, I
don't know. Well, I
guess Leandra will
like the colors.
Let's see. Yeah,
let's go with that.
Whatever. I can
change those later.
All right. So now it's
creating a blueprint,
exactly how I would
do it it's super fast
way faster than
Sonnet and it doesn't
cost anything which
is also a plus
for now
I kind of like how
Google makes their
stuff free they're
like taking like the
the crack dealer
approach to AI get them
hooked and then jack
at the price when
you're hooked on their
service or something
but it's not a bad
approach I guess
it gets a little
confusing though because
they have like google
ai studio and they have
yeah firebase studio
is it a replacement
or what is it you know
yeah exactly startup
i'm going to say
make it more start
looking with a sticky
header and nav footer
and nav items all
right so it looks it it
looks like a it looks
basically lovable
it's it's faster
than lovable
substantially faster yeah
yeah do you think do
you think it's going
to be like a a big
trouble for those
lovables of the world
uh that google is now
competing against them
directly it's i think
lovable do well they
went from zero to
40 million dollars in
ARR in four months.
They're arguably
the fastest, most
profitable growing
SaaS company of
all time. I think
they'll be fine.
And let's be honest,
Google has a tendency
to over-engineer
its products, right?
Sometimes simple is
better. What I think
both are missing,
to be honest, is a
maybe some MCP integration
and I guess there's
a new tool that
Google's coming out with
called their agent
platform or something
like that and so
which will provide the
ability to integrate
different agents and MCPs
I'm kind of rooting
for the underdog here
personally I like
Lovable you know I've
been I think everyone
on this call knows
that we were I think
one of the first
users of their platform
when it was still
a private beta
engineer The engineer.
So as far as
early Lovable
goes, we were early.
So far, the UI
isn't great.
What Lovable does
with the UI, they
give you a package,
like a sort of
running start, which
generally looks
better. So let's
use shad, cn, fork,
and what else?
Tailwind theme.
See Let's see if that, it
looks, it don't
look very good.
Let's see if it
figures that out.
All right, let's do,
it's certainly fast.
It still looks the same.
Make it look
more like a YC,
a Y Combinator style
dashboard, I don't know.
that the YC teams
would invest in.
I'm not a fan of
Y Combinator, to
be honest with
you, but whatever,
let's see if it
makes it look better.
Anyone on the
call that's from Y
Combinator or
whatever, my apologies.
All right, so this is
what we should get.
It basically looks
like lovable,
except the design
isn't quite as good.
Yeah, it's struggling
with the design for sure.
All right, enough of
that. I'm going to
show you guys some
other stuff I'm
working on. So this
week I was working on
a dashboard for MCP
and I had an idea.
The idea was basically
what if I could use
the server sent
events, the streaming
protocol for MCPs to
create a kind of hybrid
agentic network,
multiple agents that can
collaborate with each
other, do tasks, and
essentially create kind
of websites that are
able to communicate
with other websites.
You know, that was the
idea. And on Wednesday,
Google came out with
this new specification
called A2A, which
is basically very
similar to the robot
.txt concept we came out
with a few months ago.
So I thought, well,
they're Google and they
have like all these
companies signed up
to use it. So why not
just use that since
it's almost exactly the
same with a few
differences. So first
thing I did is I went
in and created my MCP.
And then keep in mind,
this is about 70,000
lines of code built
in roughly six hours,
almost entirely
autonomously.
Then once I was almost
done, this agent-to
-agent protocol came
out. I'm like, oh, it's
a Python-based environment.
So I don't want
that. I I mean, I
have to create an SDK.
So I created an SDK
and then I created a
dashboard and I'll
show you the dashboard
components. So in this
case, what I'm doing,
this is the MCP. So
for those who aren't
familiar with MCP,
there are two parts
of MCP, the local studio
environment, which
is the IO or terminal
output from your
operating environment.
And then there's
this new HTTP protocol,
streaming protocol,
this is based on the
concepts of server
sent event. that
allows you to use the
well-known folder
which you'll see here
the well known folder
basically provides
a discovery mechanism
for services on
a website usually
that this was used for
like site maps and
SEO optimization but
in this case what I
wanted to do is use
it use it for creating
and connecting
robots and services
and other things that
I didn't have to worry
about configuring
locally but the problem
with that is it was
a pain to sort of
configure those things
locally. So I needed
a quick way to create,
you know, different
endpoints. So if I want
to create an endpoint,
I can go here and
call it, uh, you know,
agent or whatever,
and, and then create
the paths and stuff
like that. So this is
creating the structure
for discovery more
than anything else.
Then I can save it.
Then I can test it,
you know, send a
response. I can, then I,
then I want to be
able to connect remote
MCP servers that deploy
as edge functions in
the cloud like using
cloud workers from
cloudflare or aws or
whatever so in this case
i can go here so this
is this actual site
it doubles as an mcp
server because you
know why why why do
separately so i can do
i'll do test i'll add
that here i don't have
any any security on
it so i'm just going
to skip that now now
i'm connected now i
can start testing this
so i can And so this
is a remote, the other
one was the local,
they're both local,
but for the purposes,
I'm using an IP address
versus a local host,
same general idea.
And then I can see
different options, I
can connect, I can send
information, I can
select the status, I can
configure, I can see
how it's connected,
all kinds of
different information.
Then I can federate
them. So then I can
get groups of
websites that have MCP
servers to coordinate
with each other.
enter the idea of A2A.
So MCP is basically a
direct communication
channel between two
different LLMs essentially
with a unidirectional
com. Unidirectional
means that once you
send in a request, the
response remains open
opposed to bidirectional,
which should be like
a web socket or like
a chat system where
once that connection is
made, it stays connected,
but that creates
problems for like
different types of
firewalls. And it's just
generally web sockets are
difficult to play with.
So a service kind of
adds easier in simple
terms. So in this case,
now I've got an A2A
dashboard and MCP
integration that I've
combined to create a kind
of new hybrid approach.
I've got a couple of
example agents I can
discover. So in this
case, I can do the same
thing. I double the
system to actually act
as a discovery tool.
So if I'm deploying
agents or I want to point
it at google.com. All
I need to do is point
it at the URL and it'll
self-discover all the
various MCP and agents
available to me on
that server. So if I
click discover, you
can see here that it's
discovered that I've got
three skills available.
I get text processing,
image generation,
and data analysis.
Again, I did that just as
a demo. I can go in
here, I can create new
agents. These agents
are, again, can do
whatever. And the cool
thing about these agents
is they exist as a kind
of parallel to your
website. So if you're
creating a website and
you want the information
to be consumed by
agents in a certain way,
maybe you might have
rate limits, maybe
you might have certain
limitations or access
rules. You can define
all those things using
this approach. Keep in
mind, this entire thing
was built without me
doing really anything
in something like six
hours. So I can copy
the JSON structure, I
can add new skills,
all that kind of stuff.
Taking it a step further,
you know, and there's
a whole system
here tells you about
how the A2A discovery
protocol works, if
you're interested.
I can go create task
system. So in this case,
we can, similar to
the other one, I
can test it. So in
this case, I can test
my different, you
know, processes,
data transformation,
and I made these
up, by the way,
these are arbitrary,
multi-step workflows,
I can see the different
types of skills available
in this particular
agent, I can see the
code. I can save it
as a template. I can
send it to actually try.
So now you can see
that I sent it to the
actual agent to interact
with. So in this case,
I can see that the
response types, these
are simple. I'm basically
sending an echo.
Echo means give me what
I send. I said translate
the French, which
basically just responds
with translate the
French. And then to make
sure it's working, I
do an inverse result
or reverse result,
which is basically the
words backwards, some
text analysis, code
generation. So now I've
got all the sort of
components here to build
and deploy these agents
in a way that allows
us to do all kinds of
interesting things. I
can now create a repo.
So I can create a
repository of all the
different agents that
I can discover, create,
deploy. And this is
completely decentralized,
meaning that all that's
required for this
to work is you basically
including the file
of the template that
i'm giving you put
on your website and
suddenly you can
communicate with any other
website in an agentic
sort of style so
i've created a whole
bunch of different
templates that you can
play with and then the
server side or browser
side i that's the
craziest part it's
both i so what you're
looking at right now
is client side client
side is super easy to
work with almost
every website's client
side obviously but i
also built an entire
sdk because i could
And the SDK is that
they built their agent
system using Python.
Nothing against
Python, but Python kind
of ***** for
building agents. So I
built this using
Dino and TypeScript.
So, and I didn't build
it. The agent built
it more than anything.
But basically,
this is, and it did
self-documentation.
Here's the entire client
API. Here's servers
and everything you
need to use this. So
I've got a better,
fuller, more complete
implementation of
Google spec than Google
does by far. And it
took me six hours.
So it's pretty cool. It's
got everything you need.
Quick question.
If it's client
-side, how are you
protecting secrets?
Like, say, this
talks to Supabase
or something
like that. I'm
using a combination.
It's a really good
question. I'm using a
combination, of course.
So first of all,
you can see here,
these are the diagrams
that used to auto
create it. This was
almost entirely created
without really much
input other than my
initial requirements.
Then I've got the
Supabase function.
So then I import
my edge functions.
You'll see here
I've got an
edge function
called A2A Hello.
This is basically the
remote function that
I deploy to Supabase
or whatever cloud
environment I want to
use. But the important
part in how it's
secured is using
cores. So cores
essentially defines my
origins. So I'm using
a combination of a
defined and secure
domain. So I'm using
Cloudflare's domain
security. So I guess if
my domain is hacked,
then I'm *******. But
generally speaking,
I trust Cloudflare.
So I think it's okay.
And secondly, I'm using
an anonymous key. So
the anonymous key is
what would leak
potentially in the browser,
but it doesn't matter.
It's an anonymous
key. It's just a mechanism
of, it's the first
factor in a multi
-factor authentication.
So I could probably
skip it all together
to be honest, but
that's the way edge
functions seem to
work. So I figured I'd
stick with it. So it's
essentially a multi
-factor authentication
in simple terms.
Yeah, so it built an
incredible
amount of stuff.
So you can see
here that what it
is, is I imported
the original repo,
then I pointed it
at, and then it
created a detailed
plan folder,
which I was showing
you here a second ago.
And you know, where
did I put that?
And I think it's
in here, plans.
And you can see that
it's made up of dozens.
Then it implemented
each one of these
steps, step-by-step,
here are the tests,
here are the diagrams
and data structure.
The other thing that's
really cool, and
I don't have time
to show you guys
this today or maybe
I'll show you later.
There's a new MCP that
came out for Supabase
that allows you to
completely automate
all the processes of
complex data architecture,
real-time interactions.
And I just
let it run for like an
hour and it built the
most remarkable sort
of data infrastructure
and it tested it, it
revised it, it fixed
it, it updated the
code, it secured it.
It's worth a look.
Am I running it here?
Let me let me check my
uh let me check quickly
if i've got it running
do you have a room
mode for your super
base mcp yet yes i do
i i i you you guys
want to see it yeah
that'd be awesome let's
see i think i think
it's in this one um
anywhere you've shared
sort of like a uh
collection of room modes
or anything with uh
yeah it's on my gist um
this one actually
this one's using my vs
code implementation but
it's very similar so
two things look at
quick here's here's the
uh here's the super
base running i'm not
going to show you the
configurations that
i'll show you my my my
key but in this case
you can see i have
different options get cost
i get create project
I've got restore
questions. The one
that's most important for
Supabase, list tables
and the execute SQL.
This will do
everything you need.
And I don't have it
in this one because
I actually haven't
done any database
work in this
particular instance.
But basically, I
did it similar to
what you're seeing
for the VS Code.
So in this case,
the VS Code, this
allows me to essentially
run multiple VS
Code windows and have
them all orchestrated
and using each
other. So the
first thing I did
a test is I created
greeting mode. Then
I've got list files.
Then I've got
different Booleans for
various types of automated
development. What
I'm really trying to
do is run multiple
versions of the VS
code simultaneously.
So I can write
files. I can execute
commands. And I'm literally
just creating these
MCP servers just on
the fly for whatever
reason I need to
create it for. So
I've really moved to
a much more MCP-driven
development approach.
And the key to
making that all kind
of work is actually
making sure you've got
this RueModes file.
This RueModes
file basically
gives it the guidance.
So you're running
those in Codespaces, or
where are you actually
hosting your MCPs at?
uh well i've been using
studio mostly because
i was lazy but now that
i've got this project
i've moved i'm
moving away from from
locally local studio
style to sse style and for
that i'm basically using
this and i'm creating
a little uh this is an
mcp for mcp creation
so i'm using this to
create and test mcps
and then deploy the
clusters so this is the
front end for it but
basically, I just point
my root code at this
and say, build me an
MCP to do whatever it
is I'm trying to do.
And so this is kind of
self testing
at this point.
So the better and
smarter AI gets, the
more efficient I get.
It's like, it's so
recursive at this point.
Oh, hey, Shep, how's
it going? Congrats
on the new company.
thanks thanks for
sharing your super base
mcp setup by the way
it's all super cool
yes yeah it's it's it's
amazing like i i am
i'm i'm like running
five different vs in
windows as we speak
right now all doing some
crazy thing for you
know various reasons
most of which are are
uh you know to make a
buck but um the fact
that i can orchestrate
and by the way what's
cool about I haven't
even showed you guys my
GitHub implementation,
which does all the
project management.
I can actually do all
the memory for the
Spark-related
activities, and rather
than saving it as an
MD file on the hard
drive, I actually
save it as an issue in
a GitHub project.
And then it refers to
whether it's been
done and how it's been
done, and creates
an automatic update
to the project as it
completes the various
parts, which is
just mind-boggling.
Yeah, that's awesome.
I've been wondering how
to record my checklist
in my goals file that
I set to my agent.
Yeah,
there are two ways
I'm doing it. One, I
vectorize it. And the
simplest way to vectorize
it is, again, Superbase
has a PG vector.
And if you do vectorize
it, make sure you
include the contextual
information relating
to whatever it is
you're doing for that
goal. So, the contextual
information would
be things like a
diff, files related to
what was done, like
a directory structure
relating to the update,
and potentially a
secondary log of all
the things that it
did to get to the
point of a functional
implementation of that
thing. So, the tests.
And then, the great
thing about that
is you can refer
to that later if
you run into similar
problems. Didn't
I fix that yesterday?
It'll go back
and it'll just
use the same diff.
hopefully that's
you know I've been
rambling for 28
minutes sorry guys okay
I'm done I got lots
to cover yeah lots
to cover that's
great thank you so uh
Krasun are you all
set yep I'm all set
oh new new glasses
too looking good thank
you thank you yeah just
broke one I wish an
agent is there for it
but not yet cool let
me share my entire
screen cool so what's the
problem statement
for today the problem
statement is i love
games and no one is
developing mcps for games
but they're developing
mcps to to game
development i'm not against
but i'm like come on
guys we had we have
google's chess game
engines but why no one
can do it yet and it's
like okay let me build
a proof of concept
and i was like started
integrating with unreal
engine unity that's
a demo for a later
day but this was my
first version to just
prove the idea that even
it exists so probably
a quick system flow
what how do we control
the character this
is a simple game engine
of mortal combat i
built and all the
characters can be controlled
by an api which is
required by the mcp
yep that's hoping so
that's the way that's
what we have this
right you see each npc
can be controlled
by a player id so in
the future you don't
need to bother you
just get the player
id with npc id and you
can control this one
llm as long as it has
sufficient compute
boom we can compute
and in this case i'm
using grok and you're
going to see how
freaking fast it is and
basically you get the
player id we have a
pi game game engine
it has the game logic
has the physics it
has everything. Every
single second, we'll
be sending an image
to this. We'll be
sending screenshots
because GROC doesn't
support video streaming
yet, but Gemini supports
video streaming.
But at least I
don't have it in
the API yet, at
least for now
when I was
playing with this.
And take a
screenshot, send
a response, take action.
And this is the
data for diagram.
And this is how the
vision control works.
Take a screenshot, send
a screenshot into a
queue because it takes
time for getting the
response, right? Like
suppose if there's a
latency in the GROC, you
don't want to send 10
20 instructions at
a given time so just
implement a simple queue
process the image have
a prompt construction
and this one and
today what i did was like
okay i want to implement
a2a and use anthromics
and mcp and i
love a2a but also at the
core of it right what
is an a2a is basically
an mcp hooked up with
an agent but one mcp
agent which is who
cannot connect with
another mcp connected to
an agent right so no
complications no biggie
right and at the end
of the day all of these
are agents like the
two gaming characters
are agents and everything
are agents so this
one and i just took
this as a lesson like
what is sse what is
studio i implemented
both see the pros and
cons like you can't learn
without implementing
it right i mean anyone
can read theory but
i like to implement
and learn it from
practical practical so i'm
more like a this one and
it and one interesting
thing takeaway um
when i give grok or
like this slms right to
just give an instruction
it does a ****** job
but just an extra
statement like this why
it should do a reason
right it for it does
actually much better
thing because it knows
what it does really
well and this is very
much true to all slms
yes obviously json
reconstruction ***** so i
have a i have a
rejects build to repair
Jasons and it works 95
% of the time, but yeah.
So let me run, um,
let us run one agent and
let us run one
agent here.
So I'm running player
two, I'm going to
be player one. So
let's, let's run both at
the same time and just
see, and then I'll
play like Risha human
versus this one.
So try to dodge. Yes.
Obviously there's
a latency thing,
but when it sees a
punch, it tries to
dodge, dodge the
bullets and dodge
everything and let me do
one more thing i'll
terminate one api
and i will do this
and i will turn so
and i'm playing the
game now so it's you
are you're manually doing
it or you're playing
against computer
what's happening i'm
i'm controlling the red
player now blue place
on controlled by me
but i'm now controlling
the red player so
let us see oh **** oh
**** oh man one **** so
okay and that is open
source is this open
source i'm going to this
repo now if it is yeah
it's open source i
mean i haven't pushed
the code yet it's
local but the crazy
thing is this is grok if
i'm using uh gemini it's
slow as **** but when
I'm using Grok it's
extremely fast right
when you're like
getting 3000 tokens per
second but I think the
amazing point over here
is right this is I
feel people should this
is a really good use
case where of where I
like MCP like this
standardization can help
to control NPCs like
using this by swapping
the player ID it could
be NPC ID right and
just give and you
have the NPC ID's
characteristics stored
against a prompt database.
And boom, you can
control hundreds of
NPCs just on one
machine language model,
as long as you have
enough computer
to scale it out and
you're running it
out. So this was
just the idea I had.
So I noticed you had
A2A in there as well.
So where do you make
the decision when
you use an MCP versus
the A2A protocol?
I don't have any
strong opinion with A2A
because I believe MCP
connected an agent
is, I'm not going to
call it something new.
I'm just going to call
it an MCP hooked up
agent. But the A2A
protocol is very
interesting when you're
using Gemini because it's
easy to get stuff
in. But in this case,
I just copy pasted
the documentation and
just swabbed it with
LightLM. And now I have
A2A because in this
case, I'm using two
agents. In this case,
this one and this guy.
And you have,
okay, I actually
closed it accidentally.
So you can see in
this case, it's the
eight way mode and
it is, and these
agents are streaming
their actions
continuously with
each other because in
text, it sees what
is the performance A,
but yeah, but I
thought I was expecting
it to be slow and
it was extremely
slow when I was using
GROC, but it's now
extremely much
faster with, I mean,
it's faster to grow
slower than Gemini.
So, and with GPT 4.0.
And this is using
server-send
events or studio?
SSE.
Nice.
It's streaming,
the responses
continuously. We can
see it's streaming.
Obviously, I'm not
doing it because
I'm running on
my Mac, so I
don't want my
Mac to die yet.
I keep streaming
all the events.
I think that's right.
i i'm going to make
a prediction that a2a
wins over mcp it's
got all the same
capabilities as mcp and
a whole lot more it's
like where mcp is
singular it's like
it's like a transaction
and you know ask and
you shall receive
a2a is like i don't
even know what i need
to ask you go figure
it out and then let
me know when it's
done and also google
made it so like you
know when you put Google
Anthropic, they're
kind of different
companies, you know,
there's, there's a lot
of problems for sure.
One was data centric
and the other is
operational, but I think
the, an A to A being
operational, I think
operational is probably
more useful for broader,
you know, applications
than send me a
request and give me a
response, which is
basically every API ever.
Yeah.
I think my opinion in
this case, I'd like,
I, yes, I, I think the
AAP is winning from a
technical point of
it's a rapper of MCP,
right? I mean, if I
want to go to the rapper
route, I can say it's
a rapper of everything.
It's a rapper. Yeah.
But the point
would be adoption.
Like I really do not
have this metrics to
say, and currently MCP
is the hottest adoption
across every major
company. Right. And A2A
just came day before
yesterday. So I don't
really have a take
on it, but I think if
Gemini A2A comes in
first and like people
really start adopting
and i'm just going to
say it way is going to
win right and i feel
in this case where you
want to put npcs to
watercraft farming and
in my favorite game is
clash of clans and
clash royal i just run
an emulator and it does
all the farming for
me and i just keep
leveling up automatically
without me doing it
because this is a
gemini model right so
i mean this is a vision
model so i just long
as i hacked my emulator
running i'm fine and
it can do all that it
can figure out that
in fact But next week
I'll demo how I use a
cloud computer used to
play Clash of Clans
and actually it was
really good in Clash
Royale also, but not in
the higher level because
every second matters
in Clash Royale, that
latency, but this
one, but yeah, I think
what I'm currently
working on is on just
making it work on 3D games
and physics animation
engines because it's
more 2D, but my next
step is making work
with Tekken from Tekken.
so that is my game
thank you what's the
anticipated lag between
actions within the game
state and then a response
SSC does that better
because like I
can almost if I get
in 50% of the state
right I can always
predict the next
action despite
rule-based in this
case of SSC if I'm
streaming responses
but yes I agree that
I think only currently
Grok is doing decently
well to show you yeah
it's actually making
meaningful performance
and i'm playing against
it there's two two
considerations when
it comes to latency at
least in my experience
with working on both
so i've built about
12 mcp servers at this
point and most of which
were were these stdio
studio is what i call
it i don't know how
you pronounce it but
that that basically is
for local low latency
applications, you're
going to use the IO
directly, right? So nothing
is going to be as fast
as something running
locally on your hard
drive. But most things
in terms of data
don't reside locally,
right? So the benefit
to an HTTP transport is
you've got this make a
request and then just
send me everything I
need if and when you
need to send it to me,
which remains open. And
once that connection
is open, the idea of
latency goes away because
you don't even care
if it takes 30 milliseconds
or three minutes.
It's just coming to
you whenever it's
done. So most applications
are fine with that.
Now, there's going to
be reasons why some
applications don't want
that. And that's going
to mostly be like,
how do I interact with
the hardware or the local
environment directly
for whatever reason?
but that's that's
likely an edge case for
most things unless you're
working on hardware
related things well
that's a good segue to
um to david david had
a a talk in the gaming
industry there last
week david you with us
yep i'm here yeah yeah
um great yeah i'm sure
i'm happy to uh So
this is a presentation
that I gave over at
GDC, and I'm just going
to run, just to give
you a run over just
the general flow of the
presentation that I
gave, and then just have
just some of the
ramifications and maybe how
other people can apply
some of the processes
that I did here.
Because I gave this one
presentation and subsequent
presentations and
consulting opportunities
came from it. So
people can look at
maybe this process here.
So I just ran
about who we were.
That's my business
partner. Talked about
what we're calling
like an agentic first
development studio in
games in the process of
this. This is like the
technology adoption
curve. If you guys are
familiar with this, this
is Stanit, right? uh
basically saying this
this is where we are
and it's crazy because
seven months ago we
were there uh and
probably going to be
here backed up by what
anthropic said and then
so the the first thing
that i wanted to address
in the games world
especially for studios
that have existed
in a long time is
this when it comes to
agentics a lot of people
have tried it uh you've
all seen the stuff
and they failed so i
first uh wanted to
address with the first
objection that most
people would have um and
then supported by
something that um was uh
posted literally minutes
before i presented
so i copied and pasted
this from uh linkedin
i really like this guy
here from uh saying
vibe coding doesn't
work if you're building
a serious business
app i help open ai and
anthropic build their
models well that's big
cred stamp i guess
right but um kind of um
i then just basically
addressed the issue
about what agents do
really really well and
that it can be applied
right off the bat um
they didn't you know
still um i've tried it
doesn't work anything
then i gave our use
cases um about uh how
we use agents in our
company um and um
explain that if you're
actually not doing if
you're not in the space
and you're just trying
it on the side you
actually don't get it
you don't and that's
why you're having these
problems um explaining
that you're cutting
and pasting between
your LLM and your IDE
is not agentic coding.
Explained to them
how our setup worked.
Talked about the
process of human in the
loop iteration, where
we spend most of our
time writing the technical
docs and exploring
the architectures
that we want to have,
explaining that this
is where you spend
the majority of your
time. Talking about how
a typical producer
and product manager's
role now has become
very, very technical.
And talked about if
you're not that, you're
just going to get
in the way. and this
work should be done
by your tech lead.
And then code execution,
right? Basically,
put your first task
in, go for a copy.
You'll monitor,
you'll understand if
you're going to
monitor. You've seen
this is the same
process that Rude uses
and almost everybody's
established.
So then the other
thing is, is when we're
thinking about
architecture, especially
in games, thinking
about microservices.
So everything is
a microservice,
keeping the
contacts down.
So things like
character skin agents,
micropayment agents,
animation agents, like
these are the things
a way to think
about getting it quite
narrow um and then
of course everybody
wants to make gta
fix so let's do that
i explained that
right now game engines
are monolithic the
context is too large
uh so question auto
six is just not going
to happen yet um
and that the other
issue is that unity
and unreal and game
engines use um human
interfaces um and
And this is not
particularly awesome
with AI automation yet.
We probably want to
go to something back
to the command line
interface and YAML
stuff of building
games back in the 90s.
I talked briefly
about where agents can
help you today. So this
is what my previous
company used to do
for 15 years was game
services. This is full
stack development.
So everything around
having agents build
your code is absolutely
applicable to
game services because
this is full stack
development. It's
outside the game engine.
So if you're
not doing it,
you should be doing it.
Talk about NPCs, which
is a lot of people
working on, how it
can be applied to live
ops, how it can be
applied to game testing
and balancing way better
than human beings,
how autonomous procedure
generation game
levels and worlds can
be done. This would have
a high human in the
loop element, but right
there. and one area
where most people aren't
talking about using
of ai in games is in
concept and planning this
this can be tightened
up so much because
even though this is
soft um uh if you
look at ai agents as a
colleague you're now a
game designer i can now
get my idea way more
concrete way faster um
and more precise um
with a lot more clarity
i can even i don't
have to wait for my
concept artist i can tell
a game and i can tell
an ai to go create me
the first 25 minutes
with 20 thumbnails,
right? So I can
generate that really,
really quickly.
Anyway, so this, what
I put, big conclusion
here is large amounts
of capital are no
longer the moat for
creating a AAA game.
And I said, I've
made the conclusion
that a tiny team
will build a near
AAA quality game
in about two years.
And by tiny team, I
mean a team of like 10,
right?
Then I talked about
what an agentic first
studio might look like.
First, I then wanted
to reverse it what an
agent really is, took
them through what LLMs
were previously three
years ago when I was
working at FinAI, how
we worked with LLMs,
then when ChatGPT came
about, and then really
what an agent is.
And this was important
because for a studio
that wants to continue
this, I really wanted
to make it clear that
agents are their IP.
Agents aren't generic
swapping between
studios. You can't
take a coalition suite
of agents that are
for the coalition
studio making gears
of war and then give
them to nintendo
to make um uh zelda
they're different
these are core pieces
of your ip agents
are your taste and so
um that made people
feel a little more
like okay there's like
there's a place for
us here still this is
not about bots taking
over the world um
i did make it clear
that there probably
is a new position here
someone here this
agentic programmer prompt
engineer whatever
you want to call it
brand or taste programmer
this is going to
become a role in a
studio is my is what i
think um core team
structure change it
doesn't change you still
have these core human
leads and then but
agents as colleagues
and through these
these all these other
areas but what about
the producer or product
manager right which
was my core role for
a long time and i
actually think that this
is the job that's at
at risk and um they
either need to move
into understanding um
customer and go to
market um and research
a lot better, or they're
going to be gone.
But if they do
understand that, they
have a place. Because
their role right
now will be split
up between the tech
lead and orchestrator
agents and NPC
servers, because I
won't go into the role
because time is of
the essence here.
But they can become
the visionary
of the product.
So that is a
place where they
can move into.
So what did I say that
I recommend everybody
do? Put a team of
three together with the
goal of creating a
complete game in three
months ago that's how
you're going to immerse
your team into
actually understanding
this you can go to like
we put on a workshop
after this to talk about
how to get yourself
structured but you can
have as many workshops
as you want at the
end of the day you
got to do it and this
is this is this is the
investment that i
think you need to take
to do it and then for
all most game studios
or outsource studios
um and i've just as as
a former one that ran
one outsource development
studios or labor
arbitrage It's really
important to understand
that. And so that
business model is
probably gone with an
agentic first development
world. So anyways,
that was the summary
of what I did in all
of, I'm not sure how
many minutes that took.
But I think the key
takeaway that I would
have from that, and
the success that that
talk had, is that by
talking about agentics
in a vertical and how
it can be applied to a
vertical and using
the language of that
vertical, I think would
be very helpful for
anyone who is doing
consulting in any space.
Done.
Guy has a question.
one yeah so i find in
video games and robotics
that real-time behavior
is really important
right you know so
like a lot of the
inventions of like zero
buff and dds and some
of the protocols that
sit under that for
communication um if it if
it's delayed even by
a little bit the game
experience gets ruined
so my question is how
is the proposed aca
protocols something
better than you know
how we currently do i
would say microservices
and unreal engine
communicating over event
queues and things like
that but what is
your opinion does it
confuse matters or does
it actually help um so
i so i let me re
-articulate the question
that that you're asking
is that Are you asking
me, does an agentic
approach to a studio
or to a game, again, if
you're asking me what
the tech on the issue
of latency on game
performance, is that
what you're asking me?
how all the microservices
or in the future
agents communicate
in a real-time way
is is a2a or mcp really
covering that or do
we already have solve
solutions for that
with message queues
and zero buff and yeah
dbs and all those things
yeah so i think we
already have those
solutions i think that the
issue that i got that
i'm talking about
is is how the studio
operates and the workflow
within the studio
not the actual game
engine and and and the
services within the
actual game itself so
the the services the
intergame services themselves
i think are already
those are solved
what we're doing is
we're putting together
agents on the architecture
and the development
of the game not the
performance of the
game i think i think
there's two parts and i
shared a quick link to
some thinking i did
two years ago in early
early vibe coding
sessions before you could
actually build the
crazy ideas that you
you sort of dug into
the rabbit hole and as
part of that you know
it occurred that there's
two there's two
predominant sides to the
game there's the
development of the game
which if you look at
gta 6 or whatever it
takes 10 years to build
billions of dollars to
devise now some of
that you know some of
that cost is not going
to be you know you
can't get around there's
ip related costs music
and whatnot but the
a lot of the problems
of a game is the
procedural parts. These
are things that involve
just people going and
testing and fixing
and understanding the
structure of the game
itself, how it plays,
the map, the experience,
all that sort
of stuff. And a lot
of that was just
laborious, back and
forth, back and forth.
What you can do
with, I think, AI
as a development
partner is code aside,
like let's just assume
programmers keep
coding it the way they've
always done it. You
can create coherence.
You can create systems
that will optimize
and test in a way that
is end to end. And if
you look at the sorts
of stuff that we're
building, most of the
advancements we've
seen over the last few
months hasn't been in
the improvement of any of
the language models
at all. The language
models, the latest
version of whatever is
incrementally better
than the last. What has
changed is our ability
to recursively fix
problems and self-optimize
those problems with
no input from me. So
now, once I realized
that I could set these
tests and let it run
for several hours, come
back and have a fully
built application, that
changed everything.
So now when I'm doing
data science projects,
and they're like,
well, what's the best
possible result out
of a million different
results? I learned
to set my MCP server,
say, go figure it out,
run it until I get a
99% coherence, and
then send me a message.
And then that might take
an hour or might take
two days i don't care
why that's the games
and and and then
anything's possible you've
got the self-creating
optimizing and running
opportunity of some
sort yeah it's a
really good point that
you made around i mean
when we think about
like with the role of
the product manager
and producer and that's
to me that like their
primary role is coherence
within the team itself
and um ai is way
better at doing that
that's why i always
challenge it that the
producer This is not about
engineers losing
jobs. This is really
about producers in the
game space. It's about
producers and product
managers really
understanding what their
new role is going to be
because they're
the ones that
are actually
being pushed out.
There's some
questions here. Scott,
we haven't heard
from you yet.
Hey, David. Thanks
for the presentation.
You were mentioning
something about a taste
engineer or a taste
kind of director. Can
you expand more on that?
yeah sure so the idea
there was is that um
like when you have
agents um working on
like let's on on any part
of your game it is it
is tuned to your game
and to your process
and to be all the way
even to the way you code
the way you guys want
things done and that's
the taste of a studio
like when you are a
studio you are you
you have your triangle
like everybody else's
right time budget
quality and it's that mix
and and how you communicate
those three things
that allows you to
get a deal versus
somebody else or to win
some someone's ip than
somebody else and so
it's that combination
that is your taste and
and i mean that in a
broad sense of taste
right and and and so now
so agents need to be
optimized for that taste
and you so coalition
makes great um gears
of war nintendo makes
um zelda those are
you can't take those
and flip them across and
and not just because
the games look different
it's because the way
they think about games
is different let alone
the language barrier
just like that that's
what i meant by it
so it's kind of like
taking whatever their
process is that kind
of creates that gears
of war feel encoding
that into an agent or
kind of an agent
framework yeah yeah so
it's it's and And
it's, and that's what I
think about when I think
about agentic first,
where I'm trying to
just think about where
we are in two years.
It's not about
retrofitting agents into
our present workflow.
It's about thinking,
well, what is the type
of company and what's
the type of games that
we're going to
create? What's those,
what's that, how do we
work? And those are the
agents that we're
going to create. And
that's unique IP to your
studio, not something
you can just snap and
go on and put them
into another studio.
That's my, my thesis.
is um are there like
frameworks for that
right now or is that
just kind of like a
wild west right now
where it's hard to kind
of put that into a
framework and kind of
take that with you i
think it's evolving and
i think the groove and
people in this group
and on this file are
probably the leaders
in that space right
um but it's evolving i
mean very rapidly
there's a number of tools
out there to create
agents like my company
makes them there's
there's a ton of them out
there right and there's
bespoke agents that
ruv makes all the time
so like it's um and
we just saw like you
know things like bubble
bowl and so forth
coming up like so it's
evolving i don't i i
get there's not i don't
think it exists today
okay scott i think
i can answer that part
there is mcp agents
by unreal engine and
unity currently unity is
really well supported
unreal engine is like
because there's too
much i mean when unreal
is superior like you
have so many ways to
handle stuff and make
it much more polished
but I think two things
is one there are
already several game
companies who are doing
it in fact I am having
my own MCP agent which
just like since I'm
building integrations
right it just knows to
do things and obviously
when I face bugs
that's where I take
over but I think it
comes down to two things
at least and I'm building
game engines i use
uh ids like rider
storm from jet brains
for two things while
ai may lose a lot of
context because games
are inherently have an
insanely large code
bases and ai can also
generate a lot of sometimes
not all the time a
lot of more bloated
code right and sometimes
you have to be there
to steer it but these
ids there are certain
things where they're
extremely rule-based
they do a lot of rule
-based refactoring for
you to make sure that
it's AI ******** up
some things and it
helps you with consistency.
Maybe for Python
or JS code, it's fine.
But in the case of
game engines when even
one single C file can
potentially screw up
your entire game file.
I think these type
of you have to have a
heuristic things which
helps to ground the AI
at the same time and
make sure these entities
are linked properly.
The path functions
that want the data put
properly. The water
flow dialogue is
centered properly. But
at the same time, it's
also about how do you
accelerate, make it
work, and then you just
figure out how to
make it perfect later.
Well, I just
want to punch
something out
there, Rashad, that
you mentioned,
or Craftsman,
and that Rube was
talking about. I think
the term, or one of
the terms anyways,
is second-order
engineering. So you're
not building a
static system. You're
building a system
that has the intention
and the ability to
learn and improve
towards a set goal
or continue to be
dynamic and continue
to improve, right?
Yeah,
declarative and
self-learning. Well,
we got Mario. How's
it going, Mario?
Hey, pretty good.
Thank you so
much for the
time of everyone.
So when you're talking
about uh npcs and
everything um i
noticed that in general
everything's talking
about evolutionary
algorithms since it has
to take into account
the context and so on
what it worries me is
that sometimes uh you
need to have like to
consider long-term
context and um when
trying to check is how
can we take that into
account and possibly
integrate it with
other kind of RACs?
Let's say, for example,
Graf RAC,
because it tries to
infer some relationships.
So I was wondering
if some of you have
already kind of made
some experiments with
Graf RAC by chance
just to share your
knowledge. And also
just wanted to share
you some of the things
that I saw a few
days ago related to
MPC's development in
the chat. There is
from NVIDIA, such as
technology called
NVIDIA ACE, where they
try to include what
they just have done,
like integrated
the AI technology
so that an MPC
can figure out and
take out decisions
in real time.
I also shared in
the chat another
framework related to
computer, let's say,
some decision-making
in video games,
where Red Revolution
was an example,
and it tries
to figure out
how to make decisions
in the game.
The thing here is
that sometimes,
since there is like a
lot of computer vision
algorithm, the latency
is not the best
one. So over here, I
think that there will
be a lot of research,
but I think the
computer file will
come to the discussion.
So I hope that the CRYL
framework, NVIDIAs,
and so on can help
for MPC's development.
But I think that one
of the things that
will be important is
how to take the long
-term context, especially
if it's like a
main character or main
NPC into everything.
So that will be
really awesome.
There's an approach I
think that's the easiest,
and I think that's
the same approach we
take sometimes when
looking at long-term
context for coding, which
also requires substantial
amount of historical
and multidimensional
data, right? What
was changed? Why was
it changed? How did it
change? That kind of
thing. When it comes to
a game, it's not code,
but contextually,
it's multidimensional.
In the world of
the game, there's
a lot of different
moving elements.
So what I find the
best approach is,
again, the idea
of contextual RAG.
And for those that
aren't familiar with RAG,
just quickly, the
most basic form of RAG
is basically the
conversion of a document
or, you know, some kind
of information into
vectors that are then
interpreted by natural
language, which creates
a similarity. So
the more similar to
the request, the higher
the result and
likelihood of the result,
you know, being correct
will be. Now that
for certain things
that works really well.
And for other things,
it's harder to interpret
that information. So
when you're looking
at using this kind
of memory style, you
know, ingestion of the
information, what you
need to do is think of
the core information,
you know, a gamer
bought an element in
the game or interacted
with an NPC, and then
that therefore creates
a secondary output,
you know, a response
from the NPC in a
certain way. And then
that gets logged as a
contextual bit of
information in the vector.
So what that means is
later, if you encounter
a similar character
in the game or a
similar situation, and
you don't want the game
to be repetitive, then
you can then use a
kind of natural
description to say, well,
this already happened,
or did this already
happen in the background?
And then the game
itself can adapt and
make sure that the
response or the situation
of that character or
gaming element isn't
the same as it was
before, which fixes
this idea of procedural
development within a
game. Most games up until
the last few years
have been procedural.
You'd have a key
series of steps, step
one, two, three. And
if you went beyond
those steps, it just
would do the same
thing. And anyone's
ever played Grand Theft
Auto sees an NPC
and you know exactly
the difference between
a real player and
an NPC because the
NPCs generally do
the same things, that
solves that issue.
Anyway, long story
short, contextual rag,
meaning add more
information to the
vector that relates to
the other information
in other areas of the
vector data store.
I hope that makes
sense. I'm trying to
explain it in a way
it's not too crazy.
But anyway, thanks for
the question, Mario.
Chris, and we're
at the top of the
hour, so we're in
the after show here.
Chris is our favorite
neighborhood vibe
coder. I'm sure he's
hacked the multiverse or
something this week what
are you up to nothing
like that i just
wanted to talk on the
game subject so i used
to play muds growing
up and there's a lot
of mechanics in muds
that i've never seen
implemented in any game
but ai should allow a
lot of these features
to exist like think
about everquest or
world of warcraft
these games have like
religions or gods that
like have like you know
the way that they act
or their deities and
in the muds that i used
to play there would
be gods that were played
by humans and then
they would enforce
role play and if you
followed like the gods
religions you were
rewarded and such how
far off are we from games
like that where you
got like ragnaros comes
to life and then if
you like act in like
the way his deity
says to act you get
rewarded special powers
etc i'm wondering when
are we going to get to
that and that sounds
that's what i'm waiting
for problem is you
like the time it takes
to create a game is
almost is longer than
generative AI has been
generally available.
If you think of day
one generally being
the launch of ChatGPT,
that was two and
a half years ago.
A game,
a decent high-level
game isn't being
created in two
and a half years.
So I would say
soon, but I'm like,
Rishabh.
I think,
I'll just say
from what, I think
if anyone has
attended GTC, I
think this would
be an answer.
We are just currently
hardware limited.
We are not software
limited currently. It's
just surely hardware
limited. And I
think any breakthroughs
of hardware, like
quantum and stuff, I
think we'll be already
there, right? Because
we just need to
know, we need more
computers to calculate
all the possible
permutations and
combinations in any given
real-time situation.
And I was trying
to run the
GTC event
locally. I mean,
whatever they show
the framework,
man, it kills your GPU.
And I'm just saying,
seriously, I had to
retype the entire
fricking thing on my own,
which is not possible
as of yet. but it's
just a simple of
hardware limitations
i'm betting in three
four years because my
two bets i'm seeing is
mac has given some
insane amount of compute
compute for three
thousand dollars with
mac m4 max right like
512 gpu of unified
memory meaning at a 512
gb of gpu memory and
if someone actually
which unity is already
working on and unreal
engine is just like
you are not performance
based and that's
true because max *****
in the number of cpu
cycles it just has good
software optimizations
and arm optimizations
but they the day
they crack i think
pretty much all the
consumer gpus are dead
our consumer things
that everyone be like
mac mac mac mac mac
like i'm sitting ducks
so i think we're not
far off from guessing
max who's usually slow
and steady is going
off fast, I'm betting
on that. And I think
NVIDIA is not going
to be sitting duck,
right? Probably in the
next three years, they
will release like,
hey, at 500 watts
an hour, we can run
this one terabyte
vGPU system and one
terabyte you can
pretty much do. We
can synthesize the
whole **** Sonder 3
.5 in your local,
which has apparently
created 20 billion
parameter models.
So they're not far off.
with the advent of
diffusion based models
for llms would that
also would that negate
the software claim i
think it's the hardware
claim i'm saying but i
think it comes to two
breakdowns i believe
it's as i see gamma
right you see for gamma
27b and serum breakers
where small models
are performing really
well one way i can think
is npcs can perform
really well by just
doing laura tuning and
just you change the
low rank adapters and
creeps wrapping the
low rank adapters based
on the npc ids so boom
like one llm can do
hundreds of things and
obviously i think in
this case this is a
software optimization
where how fast can you
load and unload a low
rank adapter over
loading and unloading an
entire gpu module right
because loading and
unloading in lower
adapters a billion times
faster because you're
just only going to
change a couple of
million parameter models
At least there is a
lot of pros for it,
but it's not applicable
to the universal
models yet. So I
think that would
be case zero. And
one case of, this is
which I love from
Unsloth, Daniel Hand,
is quantizing billions
of parameter models
into 1.76 bits, like
what he did for Maverick
and Scout of Lama,
where he could get
about 80% performance
of a Maverick or a Scout
on just So a single
H100 GPU where you
would need technically
hundreds of H100 GPU.
But I still
think it's still
a hardware limitation yet
because software will
be evolving faster and
the chances of iteration
is insanely high.
This very group
exists because we
could iterate
software a billion
times faster than
anyone else, right?
That's who we are.
It's an
interesting space.
Yeah, yeah,
totally, go ahead.
yeah sorry my camera
doesn't work but i think
that's uh when people
like talk about ai
taking hardware resources
we already told that's
the the hardware is
the way that limits
llms in in the game like
real person but what
i think is gonna happen
is that ais will be
used to produce those
optimized characters
like in old school games
you have all 3d game
like quake limit on
really limited hardware
i think he can run
on any like processor
right now like and people
from id team they use
mathematics hacks to
basically produce all
these lightning effects
without full shaders
and those crazy stuff
so i think that if
the llms will be or
neural networks will be
put to the task of
optimizing some maths and
optimizing some models
we can get much better
uh games and personal
and and and characters
and the second idea
was actually about the
characters this mod
idea when you can eat
the monster i really
like this idea when you
are there and you need
some resources to manage
yourself you can
actually eat monsters in
the dungeons and then
you get some abilities
it's really hard to
implement given the
amount of time you need
to make artists draw all
these things but for
if some person can
structure all these
actions then some other
person can draw an
example how you would like
to draw one just one
thing then LLMs can
quickly copy this stuff
and it's already could
be done i think so and
then you just upload
all this stuff to uh
to the cloud you don't
need loms running on the
back uh back so that's
just quick ideas how
it's gonna happen in
faster than two years
yeah interesting you
mentioned eating the
monsters because i used
to play nethawk which
is i don't know like
30 years old game it
in surprise it's still
actually being developed
and they're eating
like anything you
can eat any object in
the game but it's a
text-based game so there
is you don't need
artists yeah my my one
of my first paid gigs
was in 1988 i was 10
years old it was for a
company called sierra
online and they were
famous for their king's
quest games for
anyone's old enough to
remember the the 1980s
and um they decided to
create an online gaming
community when when
everyone had 26 you
know 100 baud modems
which is like bytes per
second kind of thing
and uh they they
recruited us to uh do this
online gaming community
um called imagination
and uh anyway
miserable failure uh it
was too early and it
wasn't you know the the
infrastructure wasn't
there to support it
but what was interesting
is you know a lot
of what's you know
early in this space and
we it ends up ends up
being ends of happening
and what's interesting
is the very technology
that people imagine
in these games like
there was this one game
that that was created
by sierra online
called uh space quest
and it had this sort of
visual console concept
as part of the game
where you could sort
of interact with other
you know npcs in the
game and it was like
this whole sort of
secondary online community
fake obviously but
and then they ended
up trying to build the
real thing and passed
for a few years and
it became a thing just
not by them but yeah
i i think gaming is one
of those interesting
areas that pushes
the boundaries of our
imagination in ways
that you know we we try
to to actually facilitate
and create eventually
so everything i think
we're saying today
will likely become
a thing i think that
ai will probably be
infused in everything
going forward and this
idea of dynamic user
-specific entertainment,
whether that's a game
or a video or any
other piece of content,
AI will probably
be a big part of
that transformation,
I would guess.
And it's not like
the garbage you'd see
generated on some
people's social media, but
I'm talking high
-end, high-quality
entertainment value, maybe
specifically for you.
Now,
random thoughts
on a Friday.
All right. So we're
doing well here.
We've got, you know,
I'm going to put another
solicitation out
to anyone that's
still on the call
because if you've lasted,
you know, this long,
then you're probably
into this sort of
thing. We're looking
for help on our
Agentic Foundation.
We're looking to launch
a number of local
events, probably get
-togethers, some beer and
pizza sort of things
in different places um
so if you're interested
in helping we we have
a number of different
forms i think uh rob
and brad and others
can probably share some
of that um again the
other part you know
we're we're looking to
sort of push the idea of
agentic engineering as
a as a not just a not
just a thing but a
profession and in some
weird way i see the
agentic foundation it as
like this kind of
guild of sorts for like
-minded people who want
to be agentic engineers
and if i'm any indication
of the opportunity
there's a ton of
opportunity right now for
people who can step
into a business and
figure out how to optimize
automate and create
these types of systems
and there's literally
no one out there that
they can find to do
it so if you're looking
for work and you're
interested and have a
technical sort of you
know background and
want to make this happen
there's this rare window
of opportunity right
now where you can
insert yourself as an
agentic engineer literally
by slapping a little
infinity logo on your
website or LinkedIn,
starting a meetup and
be the local expert
in it within a matter
of minutes, I'm sure.
And we're happy to
help. So if you're
interested in that
sort of thing,
reach out.
That's the
ambassador program as
well on the
website, right, Rup?
Yeah, we have
that link handy.
We can slap it on there.
Um,
but other than that,
yeah, this is just,
it's exciting times.
Like every day
there's something new
and amazing, right?
I got a question
for you, Ruben. This
is Dave Brace in San
Francisco. So how do
I find the local guy,
you know, for the
local chapter here
in say San Francisco?
How do I figure out
who they are? How
do I get connected
with them locally?
You know, was there
a list somewhere
on some link
on the website?
We should probably,
we should probably do
that on our ambassador
page. but in san
francisco we have been
talking to a group called
the frontier building
and they're they're
a new building that's
basically been divided
up into different sort
of industry sectors
it's i think i think
14 floors or something
it might be 13 maybe
they're not counting
a 13th floor but 14
floors and um they
basically they've offered
us the sort of space
to do AI and agentics
at no cost. So we've
got a small crew forming
in San Francisco.
Obviously a lot of
interest in San Francisco
around what we're
doing. Our biggest hubs
right now for like
the work that we're
seeing in terms of
collaborators and people,
just people in general.
London, I don't know
what's going on in
London, but everybody
in London wants this.
Toronto, where I'm
from, and San Francisco
seems to be the hot
spots that we're seeing
a ton of opportunities
coming from but that
said it's everywhere
it's it's crazy here
in silicon valley
for sure i just wanted
to know if there's a
place i can go to
figure out who the local
guys are that part of
the agentics foundation
and then i can you
know reach out to
them and go hang out
with them and help them
out yeah let's connect
okay yeah sure no
problem we're we're
putting together a list
we're you know
again we're a little
bit disorganized
ironically um we're
all this isn't a full
-time job for anybody
and we're all
spread pretty thin.
So anything, if
you're interested in
helping facilitate
that, we'll take
anything you can offer
in that department.
Yeah, so it's been,
anything else you guys
want to see, cover,
discuss? We've got a
few minutes before
I get up on my next
call. I have kind of a
mundane question, but
it was interesting
to me um yesterday i
was vibe coding with
ru code plus the um
sonnet you know 3.5 kind
of hack or the cheapo
version you know that
using copilot that
guy shared it's like
a couple weeks ago
and um it was doing
well but then it got on
this one kind of you
know thing that it was
kind of going in circles
and not fixing it
so uh soon there soon
thereafter i got throttled
and i thought okay
i'm going to switch
over to use the new
copilot agent feature
switched over it's also
using sonic i pointed
it at the same problem
and it had a one-shot
fix right away and i'm
just wondering does
it possibly get like
different that radically
different result from
different 100 percent
it's the issue you
faced was prompt so
that is an example of
prompt engineering so
the the key difference
between the two would
be the mechanism in
which you describe your
problem and the the way
in which it went and
what was solving it
so one of the you'll
you'll see these recursive
you know holes it
sometimes finds itself
in and the reason why
you want the approach
of a test-driven
development strategy
versus a vibe-coded, just
kind of wing it until
it's done approach, is
the test will self
-resolve, where without a
test, it could potentially
lose its context
and try the same solution
more than once in
a kind of repetitive
loop of sorts. When you
went to the new co
-pilot agent, you broke
the loop, right? You
created a new starting
point based on wherever
the last loop had
ended. So when you think
about the process of
these agents, remember
that they're working
in a reciprocal loop for
the most part, right?
Feedback loop, back,
forth, back, forth.
So what you're trying
to do is guide those
loops in a way that
don't get stuck, right?
And that's where the
tests allow them to not
get stuck is as one
test gets fixed, the
next tests go, you
know, we move on to the
next. One of the features
of Roo is that you
you want to enable in
particular for long
running types of
applications, other than the
fact you want the
boomerang orchestrator
approach that I outlined
a week ago. You want to
make sure that you
turn on power steering.
Power steering is an
interesting option
that they've added
a few weeks ago that
allows it to remind it
what its purpose is.
And it also can help
solve that problem.
Lastly- Great with
boomerang, sorry, go
ahead. Yeah, yeah,
it works great with
boomerang. The last
part is the rules, they
call it, or Klein
rules, if you're using
Klein. And those are
sort of the overarching
rules in terms of,
like, how to think,
how to operate, and
what's the purpose.
You need all of those
pieces working together.
Unless, of course,
you're just vibe
coding, and you
don't really have a
general direction,
which is fine as well.
I was using the rules.
I mean, I had a
nice, you know, goals
.md file and I had
turned on power
steering and I
thought everything was
going great, but
yeah, I just don't
know if the context
window got too large
or, or what, but
I was surprised.
Are you, are you
using the orchestrator
or are you doing
direct requests
to like the coder
or whatever?
I don't, I'm not using an
orchestrator
that I know of.
Is that the boomerang?
Room modes. Yeah,
it makes a huge
difference. I basically,
I use it for everything
now. And the task,
the tasking feature
in particular works
amazingly well. Now,
if you're not using
Sonic Thinking for the
orchestrator, you're
going to have to
include the, tell it to
use new underscore
task as part of the
initial guidance. If
you're using Sonnet 3.7
or some other model
that isn't thinking, if
you're using thinking,
it generally figures
it out and it can
allocate the subtasks,
but it works spectacularly
well. Everything
I showed you today
was built using
that approach almost
entirely autonomously.
There's some really
neat ideas for
custom remotes
surfacing too. I
think that might
be a neat resource
to keep on top
of and compile.
Yeah.
Flow codes, things
like that. We
see Adam. How's
it going, Adam?
Guys, thanks for sharing
today. Awesome,
as always.
I saw in your dashboard
that you're mainly
using Cloud 3.7 for
everything, but for us
everyday folks, that
can get very expensive
after a while. So I
wonder what are the
recommendations or any
experience with cheaper
or open source, mostly
open source models
that could perform well
or perform well while
using Rue and the
modes and all of that.
Thinking about like
Mistral's Codium
or Quan's Coding
Model or anything
else. Like is
there anything
else there that
one should explore?
coach they call it
yeah go ahead i've been
using gemini and it
gives you so much free
access every day and
then i've just got 15
gmails with 15 api keys
and then once it locks
me out of one i just
move to the next and
like every day it seems
to like refresh and
then if you also put
a card on an account
they give you 300 worth
of credit be careful
with it but you can use
a little bit of that
too across multiple
different accounts too
so that's one way
i've been able to use
gemini for free if you're
looking for free yeah
if you're looking
for free like totally
free obviously vs the
vs code approach that
guys mentioned is good
you turn down your rate
limiting so you know
in rue and client and
cursor you've got
rate limiting options
crank that up you know
to like five to ten
requests or up or down
whatever you want less
requests per per minute
so turn it down i
think And the other option,
you can use Codestral,
but Codestral in
particular, you're going
to need to do quite
a bit of fine tuning
of the actual prompt
itself. So within Rue
and Klein, you can
modify the system prompt.
I should probably publish
it. I did it about
a month ago. I did a
Codestral implementation.
It worked great.
It's not as good as
3.5 clod or above,
but it's free and you
can run it using olama
so you know there's
that um and if you're
just learning how to
get going it's not a
bad option the other
thing you could do is
you can use a combination
of lovable or bolt
.new or now i guess
the the guys at
google their and their
system as a bootstrap
so what what you can do
is you can start your
project using the
fire firebase uh studio
and then then you
can switch that to the
workspace option within
Google. And then you
can actually load
Klein and Rue directly
in the workspace.
And then you can use
a combination of both.
So for harder problems,
you know, let's say,
you know, there's
a problem it doesn't
solve for whatever
reason, switch over
the Rue, solve it,
switch back.
Oh, so the end move
back and forth.
Yeah,
which is a nice feature.
And what I really
like about the gemini
to uh you know to
chris's point is it's
substantially faster
than sonnet of all the
things i love about
sonnet it's it's the
most capable coding
system by far with
nothing comes close but
it's slow it's like
why can't they get the
**** thing running
at a decent you know
tokens per minute like
it's obviously possible
you know they just
they're it's the
fast it's the slowest
but best model and also
don't have a motivation
down to to make
it faster if it works
like this as well
right well like if
users are still using it
well the motivation is
if if you can increase
the output dramatically
let's say 10x
you know hypothetically
for people like me
who are the power
users they're going to
spend 10 times more so
depends if they have
the GPU is actually
available. Who knows?
They might have
some scarcity.
Last question
about the model to
use for coding
around temperature.
Should we take down
the temperature
to like 0.something
or leave it?
0.2. So there's two
temperatures
that I modify.
And depending on which
mode I'm using, I
switch the temperature.
So for thinking models,
not all of them support
temperature, but
for the models that do,
and I think 3.7 does,
crank that up to
7, 7.5. You want
verbosity, verbosity on
the thinking process.
You want it to be
full and creative
and to think through
all the possibilities.
You don't want
that for code
implementation. So
on the instruct,
you make it
deterministic. You
crank that down
to about two.
You don't want
it zero. Zero is
weird artifacts start
happening at zero.
I find somewhere
around 0.15 to 2.5 0
.25 for temperature
on instruct models
works the best with
the least amount The
last thing, if you're
using Rue you'll
see that there's an
option for a diff
and if you guys want
I can share my screen
quick and I can show
you exactly where
this setting is and
did it log me out?
I've been blabbing
too much um and and
basically you know i
just gotta i guess start
my code space up again
but basically what what
this does is there's
a diff option and
the percentage diff
option is the chunk in
which you can get the
overall code changed and
if you use things
like klein and i think
cursor as well they have
a tendency to change
line by line which is
slow and cumbersome
when you when you use
the the the chunk dip
setting and set it
to a like 89 percent
setting it can chunk
the entire code base and
make the change all at
once which is faster
uses let uses the
cash prompting better
and it's cheaper as
well um so there's lots
of little settings you
can you can fool around
with here i'm just
waiting for my code
space to start up that
i can show you but if
you're familiar you
you can hear i think
it just started once
and then as well uh roof
the um excuse me uh i
did get the thinking.
Sonnet 3.7 thinking
working in Requesti.
Oh, yeah. That's in
there, yep. Scroll down
a little bit more,
and that's in there,
which is really
great. And you can, so
then when you're back
under in Rue, when
you're back under
prompts, you can select
the mode, the custom
mode, and then assign
a specific API config
for that mode. And
that's when you can
assign the thinking for
the orchestrator and
the instruct for the
actual coding yeah
exactly all right so
so here a couple things
to note this this
part let's go to start
the bottom because
the most interesting
stuff at the bottom
match precision
enable editing through
diffs mine's set to 89
oh that's aggressive
and i i uh i stopped it
apparently 89 because
it seems to be working
pretty good and i
never touched it since
so i guess where it's
where it remains uh
work with every model
by the way because
last time i tried diffs
and i tried it with gemini
that was with gemini
2 pro uh ru was losing
its uh thing with
diffs when using gemini
and it was like i
don't let me go back to
claude don't don't use
gemini for instruct
use it for thinking but
you never want to use
a thinking model for
for code implementation
it doesn't work it's
just it gets too
creative it loses you
know it just makes a
mess but assuming you're
using an instruct model
that these are the
settings and you see i
i turn i turn off the
power steering when i
get to later part in
a project like when i'm
cleaning up the very
last bits i turn that
off i don't need a
power steering i just
want to fix some tests
or do whatever and to
uh rob's point when
you're playing with the
prompts you can go in
here. So you can see
here, I've got different
settings. So I've got
the orchestrator and
I got thinking here
set up and you've got
different, you know,
prompt settings and
things like that. So
you can override the
settings. So, and, and a
lot of this is being fed
through this root file
over here as well.
Um,
so you've got
different, you know,
uh, you know,
operational modes. I
think you can
customize that as well.
Um,
and obviously there
there's the different,
uh, mcps the key to
the mcp just i think i
might say this earlier
but i'm gonna say
it again create a mode
specifically for the
mcp in which you want
to work don't don't
try to encapsulate
everything you know notice
i've got pretty targeted
groups here only
read only edit you know
for a lot of things
this one's a little
broader it includes
you know some mcp
options but if you're
looking to like optimize
your database just
give it like read and
mcp and nothing else.
And then copy
and paste the
various settings
like here.
And then just
basically going and go
here. I'll just do
it actually. And I'll
say something like
create a super base
mode mode in at dot
roo modes with detail
query instructions
and only the MCP as
the group. Something
like that, right?
Then I'm going to
paste that in there.
and now i'm uh now i'm
going to create an a
super base specific
mode that i'll use to
interact with uh you
know the super base mcp
but this works for
pretty much any mcp right
but the more target
this and then it keeps
it on track it won't
veer off and do other
crazy things so you
notice here i'm using the
edge orchestrator
which i probably didn't
need to do i probably
could have done this
directly um but it's
thinking through the
process it's probably
going to create a whole
convoluted i'm actually
going to stop that
for a sec that's a
bit much so i'm just
going to do that one
more time but this
time i'm going to
choose a better mode so
i'm just going to
close this i wasn't
really paying attention
to the mode so i'm
going to switch to an
implementation mode
in this case i'm
just going to choose
the coder probably
good enough and i'm
going to start that
one more time notice
that my my model changed
now it's not using
thinking it's using
sonnet 3.7 i didn't
i don't want the
orchestrator here
because it's a it's a
simple little thing,
like why bother with
an orchestrator for
a one-off group that
I want to create.
And this is, how
many lines is this?
Let's see how it does.
This is 210 lines.
Remember, never
create files more than
about 500 lines, ever.
There's pretty much
no reason, unless
it's an MD file
possibly, to have
anything above 500 lines.
All right. So let's
see what happens
here. i'm looking to
create a super base
mode thinking
looking here we go so
you can see the chunk
see how i chunked
it boom done no running
through the whole
darn thing it just
did it in one go
now did it break
it it did i'm
going to cancel
that and fix it
there we go and
now we go here
and we see and
you notice that
i was quicker
for me to just
fix the error than it was
to let it figure it out.
Now we've got a Supabase
option here
somewhere, I think.
Here it is, oh, no,
where is it? It's
not showing up.
I might need to
refresh this. Yeah,
sometimes you gotta
have another prompt
or input in that.
Yeah.
Yeah, so I might
just need to
refresh it or wait
a sec, but that's
okay, it will
eventually show up.
let's let's just there
does it disappear
yeah disappear now
paste it back in
all right here we
go does it work this
time do i have is
there a limit no
i don't think
there's a limit i'm
not sure why it's
not showing up maybe
i've got some some
kind of conflict
demo uh the the
demos doesn't want it
doesn't want to work
for me at the moment
but then Generally,
this is how you do
it. I'm not sure why
it's not showing up.
There's probably a JSON
error in here somewhere.
I don't know.
Anyway, that's
how it works.
I'm sure it'll show up.
As soon as I close
this, I'm sure
it'll work. I'll
copy and paste
this in the text
for you guys.
But there you go.
and i don't know
if if anybody had a
chance to play with um
polaris alpha for the
one day or so that
it was up but i was
running that through
um through the rue
uh custom modes and
uh it did pretty well
i don't know what
that model is going
to end up being but
yeah it's open ai or
no one knows for
sure but where it is
it's it's 4.1 mm-hmm
that's what they're
saying it was
interesting very fast
be interesting
what the nematron
models do when the
dgx spark comes out
they're they have some
pretty cool models on
nvidia but they're not
widely used because
not a lot of hardware
can support unless
you're rocking an h100
or something like that
yeah
I'm not rocking
on an H100
yeah I'm GPU 4
I think I think
that's it for today
I hope this was useful
for you guys thanks
for your support
anyone that wants to
get involved reach out
to us I'm sure that
there's plenty of
ways for you to become
agentic engineers
and help support us
for those who are paying
to be supporters
thank you, you're
helping keep some
of the lights on or
whatever, lights
blinking anyway, and
everyone who presented
today, thanks
again for contributing
this is always
a highlight of my
week it's a nice way
to end the week
when you've got this
sort of, here's all
the stuff we built
so again, thank
thank you,
and Rob, thanks
for wonderful
thanks, Rob, take care
Thank you, everybody.
Okay, until next week,
have a good weekend.
And happy holidays to
those who celebrate.
All right.
Bye.