the new roo update that
came out last weekend.
This meeting is
being recorded.
Yeah,
it has its
quirks for sure.
But once you figure
out those quirks,
it's pretty
freaking powerful.
Not cheap either,
unfortunately.
No, oh my gosh.
I'm hoping the
tenacity of
your custom instructions.
will overpower the
shortfall of Gemini 2.0.
Well, Gemini, yeah,
you can use my Tumblr
to get around that,
but that's, yeah,
there's some mixed
feelings on whether
or not that was
appropriate or not.
The Google guys said
they didn't care.
They, they, they
basically said that, you
know, more, the more
the merrier, I think.
And the Google's on a
role this week, it would
appear. And so lots
of, apparently they've
got a new model coming
out that's like even
more powerful than 2
.5 that'll apparently
blow our minds that is
what they're telling
me. Have we explored
the model for image
generation experimental
that can you give it
a prompt that creates
animated user story,
basically stories.
So like,
let me just, do you have
time to show
you something?
It came up.
Yeah, sure. Let's see it.
I saw a LinkedIn book.
generated me. So do
you see my desktop now?
Yeah.
Well, sorry. You
see my desktop,
right? So I'm
just going to
move this thing
slightly so
it's easier
for me to show.
Okay.
So I, oops, sorry,
too many windows open.
So I had this,
this person,
sorry, I don't
have to show
you here. Um,
probably I just,
anyway, let me cut,
so it was a LinkedIn
thing, right?
So, on the post
about robotics,
like, you know,
needs training
robots to be
happy, sad,
and all of that
stuff, right? So
a simple video.
So I kind of
played out with it
and kind of used
this model here.
This one.
So this feed it.
And it kind of,
obviously, you can
get that story in
like, so I said,
created for a CEO,
as well as for a
high school or a
primary school,
the primary school
student, right?
So it's pretty
good way of
storytelling, I guess.
And he says,
is it animated
or it's just multi,
multiple, uh,
I can, I can obviously
use some of the total
animated, but it's,
okay, so it's one go.
The whole story,
the whole story was
generated one go. Well,
it's pretty consistent.
That's for
sure. Yeah. Can
it, can it do
PowerPoints?
Like,
I would think so
because, I mean,
this was one thing
I tried before,
which was like
generate a story
about it will be
good adventure.
So I'm presuming
if you play
around with the prompts,
they are limiting
it, but like every
day they open up
some tokens to use.
Okay. So it seems like
that's pretty good.
That's pretty good.
Chenna this one.
Yeah,
that's why I'm
sure. Awesome.
Okay. Yeah, thanks
for sharing that.
I think I got my new
PowerPoint builder.
I use ideogram for a
lot of my like text
-based stuff that I
find still the best
for text. Although
if you don't mind the
slow of OpenAI, it's
gotten pretty good.
If you want PowerPoint
decks, use gamma.
Any kind of websites
or a PowerPoint. So I
have used gamma.org,
so it's pretty good,
very, very good,
actually. Oh, no, I don't,
yeah, I don't actually
want the PowerPoint.
I just want the
design, you know, yeah,
I don't want, I
don't necessarily
need to layers
and all that.
But yeah,
gamma, gamma,
whatever they
call themselves,
is a good one.
All right, I think
a lot of people want
to know how to do
the automated stuff.
So I was going to
just show you quickly.
So basically, I
have got multiple VS
codes running at any
given point. Here,
let's take a look at
my current screen.
Like, while I'm on a
call, it's my AI never
sleeps. And that's how
basically a company
of one can do so many
projects. You know,
basically my
consulting is basically
me, my agents and my
wife, who basically
make sure that
people are paying
us. I pay probably,
I don't, I probably
don't pay enough
attention to that.
And she just makes,
she just hounds them
for invoices and
whatnot. So that's the
entire company. So
we, we can do the work
at probably, I don't
know, a much, much
larger company just
because, you know,
I've got agents doing
this sort of thing.
So what you're seeing
right now is step,
essentially step
seven in a multi-step
phase development for
a customer. And the
customer wanted to
build an agentic
system that basically
allows the use of
the ages for various
tasks or whatever.
But the important
part was they wanted,
they needed a billing
system, they needed
a token credit system.
And by the way,
the guys that Stripe
recently came out with
a new credit-based
option for Stripe, which
is pretty cool if
you're doing agentics.
So you can basically
get people to buy
credits and then you
can sort of debit
the credits over time,
which is a really
nice feature if
you're doing any kind
of AI-centric work
where you're sort
pay, where you're
paying for like the
amount of consumption
of the, of the
LLM, which is
generally an AI based
approach. So they
wired all that stuff.
So in this case,
I'm running the RU
code auto coding.
So this is a subtask
of another task
that I created.
So the subtas can
allocate each of these
different steps,
right? So you've got
these different options.
I'm just going to
meet you guys again.
This is the call that
doesn't auto mute
for whatever reason.
So in this case,
you've got all these
different modes, right?
So the orchestrator mode
basically is the
mode that will spawn
other modes. So this
mode basically does
nothing other than sort
of orchestrate other
modes that I have
available, like testing.
Or in this case, you
see it's in the auto
-coder mode or
architect, depending on
where it is, testing,
that kind of thing.
So it can spawn
and do that work.
And I literally
just leave this
thing running
pretty much 24-7.
And it just does whatever
I need to do. key
to making this actually
work are a couple
points that I'll
walk you guys through
here today on how to
get it up and running.
So I'm going to stop
sharing this for a
second. I'm going to
drag in another VS
code that I'll run
concurrently. And you
can run multiple BS
code instances at the
same time. You can also
use the code spaces
on GitHub or other
sort of hosted VS
codes if you want. I
find for automation,
though, it works best
in the desktop app.
All right. So for those
who are not familiar
with using VS code.
It looks a little
daunting because there's
a ton of stuff here.
But the important
place to start here
is on the left
-hand side, you see
extensions, looks like
these four squares.
So VS code is free,
so go Google or
perplexity the
download link to get VS
code if you haven't
done so already.
So I'm assuming
you already
have. So those
who have it, feel
free to go ahead
and do this.
So in this case,
you can install roo
code by just, I
think, to see. typing
roo. And be honest,
roo is not me. Everyone
thinks that somehow
I'm involved.
It just so happens
to be three letters.
It starts with an
R, I guess. I'm not
the roo. I'm the
Roo, but I should
probably create Rube
code or something.
But anyway, you go
in here and you can
install it. Now, when
you install it, if you
use it across multiple
instances, you'll
see here there's an
option to apply this
extension to all
profiles. This is a pretty
good one because what
you don't want to have
to do is reinstall
it every time you
create a new VS code
instance or new window.
So make sure you do
that. And the sync this
extension also allows
the settings from
each of your root codes
to sort of be shared
amongst each of the
other the other ones.
So just just make
sure you turn that on.
All right. And then
when you first sign
up, you'll, I've already
signed up. You see
that it was running
in the other window.
You'll be prompted to,
you know, either use,
I think it's open
router or request me.
Those who follow
me, you know,
that I've become
a really big
fan of requesting
recently.
They have come up
with this kind of
alternative to open
router that allows you to
use different models.
But more importantly,
they've come up with
a way to strip all
the extraneous stuff
out of the model
request that greatly
reduces the cost.
So I'm just going
to pull up mine
just to show you
what that looks like.
It's, you know,
pretty spectacular.
My costs,
according to them,
they did a recent update.
Let's take a look here.
All right,
this is the UI.
So this is currently
my request.
You can see, I took
a day off on the
29th. I occasionally
don't work.
Mostly my kids
and wife told
me I can't
work every day.
But anyway,
you see I had a really
productive day
here. I spent $55.
This is a set,
right now my cost
savings are in
the round of 73%.
So that's dramatic,
right? So on
$100 spend, you
know, I'm spending,
what is that,
$20 or something,
right? So that's a
major discount. So
my bill has gone from
$1,000 plus dollars
a week to, well,
substantially
less than that,
right? So, you
know, for example,
on the 30th,
I saved $152,
right?
So I spent,
so $55.
So I, you know,
that's pretty major.
So if you're looking
to save money,
this is definitely
a way to go.
The internet face
is pretty nice.
There's different
options as well.
All right.
So use the request,
the option, big
fan of what they're
doing there.
So now the next
thing, so now you've
got root code
installed. you've put in
your keys, you've
got it connected.
The next thing
you're going to
want to do is
you're going to want
to install two
different files.
So in this case, I'm
using my edge
agents repo,
which has a bunch of
different agents
available.
Now,
this file here defines
the actual modes,
right? So you see
here that you can
do this in one of
two different ways. I
like this approach
because I can kind
of use AI to customize
it a little bit
further, and I've
fooled around and got
it kind of working
the way I like it.
But the
orchestrator mode in
particular, where
you'll see here,
it works really
well in the sense
that it allows it
to create these
ideas of new tasks
for each step.
And now I've actually
said this twice because
it needs to be
reminded apparently at
the beginning and the
end. So anyway, I went
ahead and told it
exactly what I wanted.
And basically now
that I've got that,
it can see the other
modes and it can
interact with it.
More importantly,
if I want to customize
this mode, let's
say I want to call
this data architect,
and then we go here
to roo for a moment,
and we can see here
that the mode here
now will be called
data architect,
or if I want
to call this,
you know, I don't know,
cybercoder or something.
Let's go cybercoder.
Now,
sometimes if you're
using the web
version, this
won't show up right
away, But on
this, it seems to
show up right away,
which is cool.
So it'll switch modes.
I'm going to just
leave it because I think
I've hardcoded some
of the modes directly
in the instructions.
Now,
in this case,
what I want to do,
and let's just review
the settings quick for
anyone that hasn't.
So I know I've
shown some of these
folks, when you see
I'm using Requesti.
I'm using the 3.7
Sonnet model. It's
still the best model.
Let's be honest.
Other models are
cheaper. If you don't
mind 3.5, you can
choose the VS code.
here.
The VS code is free,
but heavily rate
limiting. So if
you're going to
use the free VS
code, and if you're
looking to save
money and you're
just learning,
I would suggest
to actually using
the VS code API,
given that it doesn't
cost you anything.
But what you're
going to have to
do is you're going
to have to set
the rate limiting.
So there's an
option somewhere
down here on
rate limiting.
Let's see, where is it?
There's a lot
of options here.
Temperature.
You can play the
temperature two based on
settings as well for
for more introspective
analytical things set
the temperature higher
um generally i i set
it to about 2.02 for
coding works best
failed requests
automatically retry this
is if you're using free
ones this is particularly
important this
setting um always approve
mcp that's another
important one you can
see here my settings
you can actually
if anyone if you
want screenshot
this quickly if
i could just scroll.
I have a quick
question regarding
the Google,
like the Gemini's
latest model. So if it
becomes available
like as an API version
that gives you like a
much more bandwidth,
would you switch from
Sunnet to it like based
on your current
experience? I can't code
with it. I don't know.
Maybe someone else
has had more luck with
it. But for, for, for,
I use it for reasoning.
So for planning,
it's, it's okay. It's
pretty good. For coding,
it has way too
much shift. And
it's, it's, It
gets confused.
It doesn't respond
right. I get errors.
I think for when
for coding, you've
got to use an
instruct model.
And for those who
are not familiar,
so there's two
essentially two
different types
of models that
you're going to
use at this point.
Instruct models,
which are
explicit, do
this, do that.
Reasoning models,
which reason on the
concept, you know,
which are declarative,
generally do this ish,
and figure out
the optimal
solution to this ish.
That's great
for planning,
terrible for
implementation.
So what you can do
in this scenario is
now that I've got the
model, and you can
see here that I
haven't explicitly set
the model, but what
I might want to do
is I can go here to
this setting here.
Now that I've got
this file, I can go
and choose the SPARC
orchestrator here.
Now once I've got
that selected, I can
scroll down and I
can choose which
model gets used for
it, right? So in this
case, I might select
Gemini thinking.
And in this case,
it'll then use that
model for whatever
I need to think.
In this case, it's
free, which is nice.
So I have to do that.
So let's actually
just do that, just
for the **** of it.
So in this
case, I'm going
to go back and
click done.
And now you'll see that
Gemini thinking
is selected.
Now, there's something
I want to try today
just as to sort of
vibe code a little bit.
So I'm going to pull
that over as well.
Let's just a
minute. Let's
just jump to
that for a sec.
Because we might as well
build something, why not?
So I'm going to drive
over my complexity.
So I like perplexity
still. I've been
trying to use Open
AI and Google's,
but I still keep coming
back to reflexity.
So really what I
wanted to do today
is I wanted to
create a hello
world script using
the Master AI.
And I discovered
this recently.
recently last
week, actually, for
those that aren't
familiar with
Master AI, it's a
TypeScript-based
agent framework, which
is pretty nice. And
I, as you guys know,
I like TypeScript.
And a lot of the
agents I'm building
are sort of basically
custom, but these
guys have a great
sort of structure.
So in this case, you
can see here that
I've got lots of docs
to follow. You've
got research agents
and stock agents.
So I can go in here
and essentially
just copy and
paste the examples.
you know, they've
given, or I can just
go and basically ask
perplexity to do it.
And that's what I did.
All right. So I'm
just going to go here
and I'm just going
to grab this. This
is a super simple
example that I want to
sort of show how the
automation works.
All right. So in this
case, I'm going
to go back.
So I copied it,
which copies the
markdown, which
is a nice feature.
I don't think
that works in the,
in the mobile
version. But anyway,
so we're going to go
here and I'm going
to go back my file
and I'm going to go to
my super base and in
the functions folder,
I'm just going to
create a new folder.
And I'm going to
call that Mastra.
And we'll do that.
And to give it a little
more structure, I'm
going to create a new
another subfolder.
I'll call that Plans.
And in Plans, I'm
going to come. create
another file and I'm
going to call that file
readme.md and this is a
this is the hello world
this is not meant to
be the most complicated
thing in the world
I just want to fool
around with it and see
it works now I'm going
to get rid of the I
don't need any of the
the citation so I'm
going to delete those
quick all right so
we'll go here all right
so this looks pretty
good basic tool
functions and include
some tools I don't know
I'm I'm going to be
some blind coding.
Now we're going
to go into roo.
Now, in roo, I'm
going to make
sure I'm in the
Spark Orchestrator,
and I'm going to
say something like
implement a multi
-step slash phased plan
using at Mastra because
Mastra says plans
yeah there we go in
in the plans folder
and then and then
I'm going to say
because I want to
automate it to be honest
I would probably
create the plan
separately from the full
automation but let's
just do it why not
so I'm going to it
because sometimes
it's a little dumb.
So I'm going to, I'm
just going to tell it
exactly, even though
my document says how
to do it, I'm just
going to do it anyway.
So I'm going to say,
create, you know,
step one,
create plan,
plan,
plans as dot and d.
Two,
great files,
files,
folders,
three,
create unit tests,
and test until complete
complete and no errors.
and step or
I'll say something
run agent I'm not
going to include
the deployment
here because I'm
going to do that
separately I'm just
going to run agent
and fix any
issues and I'm going to
remind it where
my dot EMV is
dot ENV I think
it's in the route
I'm not sure why
it's not finding it,
but probably because
I've got like a
Git Ignore or
something set up. Let's
just double check
that my EMV is there.
The dot EMV is
basically giving it. So
it's there. It's just
not being found. So
I'm just going to
tell it where it is.
All right.
So I'm just going to
add that slash here.
News.
There we go.
I think that this is
a pretty good start.
And then last thing
I'm going to do.
I'm going to
remind it, use the
new underscore
task for each step.
All right, so this is the
orchestrator.
Fingers crossed. This
generally works.
It's a little,
sometimes it doesn't,
to be honest. I don't
know why it's AI has a
mindset zone sometimes.
Implement a, I didn't
spell it right,
a multi, I probably don't
use them, it's multi.
There we go.
I'm sure it would
know my spellings.
and basic plan
and let's see.
I'm using Gemini. I'm
actually not going
to use Gemini
because I don't want
to figure out if it
doesn't work here.
So I'm going to go back
to Sonnet thinking.
I know Sonnet thinking
works. I'm going to
stick with why I know
works at the moment.
All right. If I
wanted to add an image
or guidance, like
this is a backend
agent. Like if I was
building a UI, I might
upload a picture or
tell up the circle
website. But in
this case, I just
want to create an
agent because why not?
So let's click
send message.
All right. So now
what we're looking
at in the bottom
left-hand corner,
we'll see that
the system should,
if it works correctly,
create sub-tasks for
each of the things it
needs to do. And it
will run because I've
set the auto-approved
turned on here. You
see I've got read
and edit and browse and
retry and switch modes
and all that stuff
turned on. So it should
automatically out.
allocate different
modes. I'm going to
minimize that slightly.
All right, so now
it went to the spec
mode. So we didn't
see it, but it,
because I was showing
you the other thing,
but basically it made
a determination that
it needs to start
with a specification.
So now it's, now it's
in specification mode.
It's going to, it should
look at the existing
specification file,
which it did. So it,
it, and now it's
looking to write a new
implementation plan for
specifically this. The
implementation plan is
going to, it's going
to be a new
implementation plan. The implementation plan is,
it's going to do it. It's, it, it, it, it, it,
it, it's it's it's it's critical. Without the
implementation plan,
it's going to vibe code
itself into garbage.
So this is allowing
it to stay on point
and track. So it's
looking at both the,
well, the original
plan, as well as a
plan to actually
take it and make it
something functional.
It's a little
redundant. I probably
could have told it to
skip that in this
step because it's not
the most complicated
app in the world.
I have a question
regarding
this. You have
the specific edge
writer now like
working here.
So how like accurate
instructions
do you give in
the specification
writer for the
specification itself?
The more the more
specific the better.
Right.
So I actually gave
it pretty broad spec
there. You saw that
the original spec was
basically a really
simple hello world.
And now I then asked
it to include unit
tests and configurations
and modularity.
So it took the
sort of simple
example and then it
made it more modular.
I like the modularity
because I was
planning to use this
for other things.
Oh, you'll
notice now it's
switched back to
orchestrator mode.
So that other
tasks closed,
it's able to spawn
subtas and close
those tasks. Now
it's thinking.
And now if it's doing
it right, it should
go into an implementation
phrase or creation
phase and should
switch to a auto-coder.
Yep, you can see
in the bottom
here just switch
to auto-coder.
So now it's based on the
implementation plan,
it's going to then
create the actual
code itself.
But the important
part here is that
code will likely
not be quite right.
So if all is well,
it should implement a
test phase after it
implements the code.
So let's watch this.
And keep in
mind, in my other
window, while
this is building,
I'm actually doing
several other
client projects
in real time.
So now you see at the
bottom, it's spawned
the terminal. it's
created the folders.
So I've got multiple
VS codes running
concurrently right
now doing three
different client
projects while I
do this live coding
with you guys.
A quick question.
The switching between
an orchestrator
and different mode
is done by the
orchestrator or
rule code itself?
It's done by root
code, which is the
orchestrator. The
orchestrator is the
mode and the guidance
for that mode.
So when you look at
the roo modes, you'll
see that I basically
told it to do nothing
other than to spawn
new tasks using the
new underscore tasks
option in RU code.
So they're basically,
I don't know
if I would necessarily
say they're
different. I
gave it guidance.
I gave it a
guidance system.
And that came out
on Saturday. So this
is like cutting
edge, but this wasn't
even available.
Well, I used it was
available before, but
nobody knew how to use
it. They came out
with the actual docs
to tell you how to
use it on Saturday.
So as soon as that
came out, I'm like, oh,
this is perfect. I'm
just going to use my
Spark methodology,
which I built last year,
and apply it to
their, what they
call the boomerang
component,
and it just worked,
which was awesome.
So it basically
automated what I was
already doing. This
is very similar
to if you had
multiple agents and
higher level instructions
will translate
into using different
agents to do the
job, a particular
part of the job.
Yes,
correct.
But sequential
agents, there's no
kind of concurrency
or parallelism
here. That means
that each agent runs
sequentially as a
task that's been
allocated by the
primary orchestrate.
But to be honest,
most applications
that you're developing
work better develop
sequentially
than concurrently.
Now, there are
reasons to do
concurrent development.
But for probably 99
% of the things that
you're going to
want to build, you
want to build it, test
it, build it, test
it, move on to the
next thing before,
you know, anything else.
Now, if you were using,
let's say, a micro
-services architecture
where there's
multiple endpoints
and each endpoint does
something differently
to one another, which
is kind of what I'm
doing here, then you
could create each
endpoint concurrently,
independently of the
other, and you could
build, you know, a
hundred things at once.
Then in that scenario,
you probably want
a microservices style
edge-based sort of
structure. Yeah, so
for now, one can use
multiple instances
of VS code, right?
Like, as you're using,
each one can do its
own microservices if
you really want to.
Yeah, take it.
Yeah, and actually
I was fooling around
with a hosted version
of VS code that you can
do, and you can
actually interact with
the VS code using an
MCP server and you could
spawn 1,000 instances
of VS code and then
have each one use the
RU code component.
There's lots of
different options
you have depending
on how deep into
the rabbit hole
you want to get.
But to be honest,
I like kind of
being the human in
the loop here, so I
don't necessarily
need to do that.
Does this cover address
the problem? I have
still using Klein,
but sometimes client
prompts you to execute
the commands even
though you have said
auto-approve everything
it still wants the
human to press it.
Yeah,
so yeah, client *****
for this. You can't,
for automation, you
can't use client.
The trick, the trick
really for making
this all actually
work autonomously is,
well, other than
the roo guidance,
this,
you have to tell it
which things to auto
-execute, like MV and
Python and whatever,
are they testing?
So adding these makes
a big difference.
And Klein doesn't
allow you to do that.
There's no concept
of auto execution.
They sort of
locked it down to
rudimentary auto
execution components.
So you've got
a lot, you have
a monitor client
a lot more.
Thanks.
Hey, Ruth.
Thanks a lot for
basically the LinkedIn
post as well, because
after that I was
trying it out quite a
lot and extensively.
And one thing I
observed, or one
thing what works
worked pretty well
is especially
for the planning,
for the planning mode,
taking a different model,
like a thinking model.
So I think right now
everything is set
to one model, but
in Boomerang you can
define for each mode
a different model.
And yeah, for me, it
worked quite well.
thinking model.
Yeah, that's
exactly what I do.
And if I'm looking
to save money,
what I do,
most have just jumped
back to orchestrator.
So finish the first
step of the task.
But yeah, so if I'm
looking to save money,
I switch code the
auto coder to VS code.
And then that doesn't
really cost me anything.
It turns out the
real key here is you
can use a really
rather rudimentary
model for coding.
You just need to
make sure that the
plans are using a
really good model.
all with thinking.
So, because
the plans guide
the implementation
anyway.
So whether it's a
top tier model for in
the implementation,
really secondary to
whether or not you're
using an instruct
style model, which can
follow those plans.
Do you feel
like the plans?
I mean, I've noticed a
considerable difference
between like running
an implementation
prompt in a 1 pro or
like in 03 Mini versus
like having it, what
it outputs here in,
in like where it feels
more condensed like
are you finding that to
be the case or do they
seem like they're
the exact same output
for you well there no
they're different because
the temperature set
differently so in this
case i've set the
temperature to be a rather
low temperature um i
think it's 0.2 where
in open AI like deep
research or the o3 mini
they've got the default
model set to 0.7 i
think 0.75 somewhere
in that realm so the
remember the more the
higher the temperature
value, the more verbose
the output becomes.
Now, in this
particular scenario, I
don't want any kind
of verbosity. I
actually want explicit,
you know, and,
you know,
discriminative
sort of output.
You know, I want
it to be exact.
I don't want any
variance in that
output. So the
lower, the lower
temperature works
really well.
For the reasoning
components,
like when I'm doing the
specification or
doing architecture,
or things that
don't involve the
implementation of the
code, then I'm going to
want to set the
temperature higher because
I want it to be
creative and think
through all the variance
and possibilities.
So in this scenario,
I can go into the
temperature, I can set
the temperature in
the prompt settings
specifically. And I can
actually set those in
the roo mode file as
well. So I didn't,
because for this, this
is meant to be like a
template for like for
folks starting out.
But for me,
I actually set the
temperature specifically
for each one of the
tasks or modes in the
I get it's running
right now so I
can't show you
that but you can
basically just
ask the AI to do
that for you and
it'll optimize it.
Cool.
Yeah.
And do you think that
if you were to like
feed, like is there
any way to feed
essentially what the
implementation plan
is and estimate
what the token cost
is going to be from
the outset based on
like kind of running
this framework?
Like it'd be like would
that even be possible?
You know, I, well,
no.
Yes and no.
I'm not sure if I
can answer. So let's
go back to request
you for a sec.
So,
oops,
I guess it's in my role.
Okay, I've got a thousand
ideas from next cut on.
Like, yeah, like, there's
actually afford to do.
Like, I want to put all
my resources towards
this thing here.
It's going to cost me
a thousand bucks to
get it done versus.
No, no.
Well,
like, look at my costs.
And I'm, I'm an outlier.
I'm building concurrently
multiple projects
a day for many different
customers who are
paying me to basically,
you know, build
stuff for them, you know,
based on their specs
or whatever they is,
they hire me to do.
And, you know, if
we look, if you
look at my costs,
you know, other
than Sunday where
I didn't, I managed
to get away of not
doing any work,
we, you know, I'm
sitting, I'm sitting
for the week, you
know, I'm spending,
where's my cost here?
So that this is my
savings. It looks
like my actual cost.
So we'll do it.
We'll take a look at.
I spent $203.
And let's do the last
30 days. I've only
been using the service
for a couple weeks.
So it's not going
to be a full view.
But, you know, I
had some pretty,
some, a few
epic days. So my
most expensive
day was $72.
And that day, I think I
may remember correctly,
I put out like 150
,000 lines of usable
code. right and so
that that saved me two
hundred and eighteen
dollars so for 150,000
lines of usable code
right so is this only
the request the
savings or like is this
like savings including
your Sintlang
implementation no this
is just this is straight
up just using their
other options I actually
end up using removing
the SINPLAing because
I was I was embedding
synth lane into my
client projects, which
is great, but they're
like, what the ****
is this even mean?
So it added a sort of
a level of, you know,
obfuscation, maybe
is the word, like
that they couldn't
understand. So anyway,
natural language
is a bit was a bit
easier here. But
I've saved $1,300 in
give or take two
weeks. A lot of money.
Right? It's meaningful.
And when you look
at, And when you look
at my bills, you know,
I'm spending, like
I was spending
in February, I
think it was like
$6,500 US in
basically just AI
costs for doing
this kind of work.
At 73% savings,
that means I'm
probably spending,
well, what's
75% less than
$7,000, right?
I'm spending $1,500 or
something, right? So
it's a lot. And that's
profit to me, right?
So rather than putting
it on my taxes as
an expense, I can buy
a new laptop, the money
I saved just in
February kind of thing.
This is awesome from
a, yeah, it's awesome.
From like a cost
perspective, that
LLBs are using next
steps and prediction.
So there's not really
a way to say how
much is going to
cost just out of the
gate unless you had
some sort of metal
data sales that
predicted like the level
of effort to implement
a change set.
But I don't know if
that answers your
question or...
Yeah, it'd be cool,
even if it was an
estimate, right? Like,
okay, we have a
sense of that this
is going to take,
you know, running,
setting up an
authentication, you know,
system is roughly
between this
many tokens and this many
tokens. And so
it's like, okay,
I don't know. I think
it'd be pretty useful.
Yeah, hopefully.
So now we're
looking at, um,
back to, RU
code automated
coding. It's
still coding.
So you see here, we're
in tester mode now.
So it's gone into
printing unit tests.
Now, let's see
if it actually
runs the unit
tests. Sometimes it
gets a little
confused later on.
We'll see what happens.
So the reason why I
gave it the original
sort of primary
instructions was because
the primary
orchestrator, it always
comes back to the
primary orchestrator.
Okay, good. Now it's
going to run the actual
issues and so now it's
moving to debugger
modes and this is
the mode specifically
for running the test
now almost always the
tests don't work the
first tuck try i you
know when we reach a
point where i can do
an entire build without
running you know
without the test
failing the first try we
will have achieved aGI
i think i think that
for me that's the
benchmark for aGI build
it and build all the
structure and have it
work right out of the
bat right of the gate
the first time that
doesn't happen yet so
it can build most of
it now the great thing
about the tests is
it it creates an
iterative feedback loop
and it'll run these
tests and then fix
each problem one by one
until there are no
problems at which point
it'll be done and
it'll say I built it it
works now if I really
wanted it you know if
I was in a set and
forget this like I wanted
to build something
overnight and go to
bed. And I do that all
the time from like,
you'll notice that
I have these crazy
things that I
launch on like 9 o
'clock in the morning
on a Tuesday.
That's because it
built overnight. And I
get up in the morning
and it was done and
it worked and I do some
random LinkedIn post
on it. That's literally
what I'm doing.
I'm just letting
it run overnight.
And those
things generally
I'm spending
around $5 to $10.
And that creates probably
around $20,000 to
maybe $50,000 lines of
net new usable code.
What's that?
Are you setting
it automatically
without it like,
because it seems
like going through
pretty quickly.
I mean, I've run the
orchestrator though,
and it seems like
sometimes it's just
get stuck. So it's
the fact that you have
all that automation
built into that, that,
that, those settings
there that kind of
keeps it from being
blocked where you
don't have to run in
the terminal manually
or I'm not sure of
I'm making sense, but.
Yeah.
So you're going to
run the two problems.
Sometimes the
terminal dies.
if you're using
code spaces.
So that might
stop it in the
midst of the
middle of night.
Also,
it can run into
other API issues.
So one of the things
you can do to avoid
the API-related
request issues, again,
if money isn't the
most important thing.
And again, customers
are paying me
to build this
stuff. So generally,
this isn't coming
out of my wallet.
but you in the API
they recently changed
their UI here and
I've only been using
this for a couple
weeks but you can do
features yeah so I
got remove MCP prompt
prompt system prompt
room oh this roo
custom prompt I'm
using my own custom
prompt here so I don't
do it here but you
can do it here there's
a fallback option
Where is it?
Yeah,
I think it's policies.
Again, they just switch
stuff up a little bit.
Make sure you
turn on this.
I'm actually not using
this particular API,
but the Goose
Coder and Seuss 1
is what actually
makes it even,
it makes it give you
all the source savings.
But you can do
fallbacks on the API. So
let's say you choose
the Gemini model,
and which is free,
but greatly reduced
in terms of like
rate, rate limiting,
you can then have a
fallback to like Sonnet
3.7 thinking if the
Gemini fails. So that'll
help sort of reduce
that sort of, you know,
it fails in the middle
of night problem.
Let's see the
policies here. I
think that's
where I said it.
Fallback chain,
fallback load balancing.
Yeah.
So this is, this is
where you set the policy.
So,
so you can,
depending on, you can
create a mixture
of different models
that automatically
works with RU.
So again, you could
create a thinking
model that you use
and then when it, you
know, when that
doesn't respond for
whatever reason or has
a problem, then it'll
use another model.
This is a great
feature. And you can
do that, you can do
the same for like
son 3.7. So you could
choose like 3.7. And
3.7 fails sometimes.
So you do a backup
of like, I don't
coach role or something,
which is kind of cool.
So yeah, you get
play with the
settings here.
Again, a lot of it,
I'm really happy I
discovered these guys.
They've got some
integrations
that I've noticed here.
I'm not really sure
what this stuff's doing,
but they're killing it.
So super helpful.
One of the things
I've been running into
is like the coding
tools will re-implement
change, like
they'll re-empt them
that'll be able to,
you know, So we don't
ignore rules. So
like always use Shad
and then they'll use
some other library.
And you're an
individual group,
it's probably
self-based issues.
I have been of trouble
hearing you, but
you're asking about
like, like get ignore
for like flying
ignore and cursor
ignore rules. Is that
what you're asking?
Sorry,
so my issue is like
I have an app and the
AI coding will re
-implement middleware. So
I have like a type
of app with Express
already has middleware
and then I asked to
add a future where it
re-implements middleware
using a different
strategy, even though
I've defined specs
for it and pair moves
and have its sense
of cloud rules files.
So yeah,
and I know I know
what you're saying.
So this is a perfect
example of what I'm
doing. So the reason
I didn't do this in a
blank repeat. to start
is because I actually
have all these other
examples of edge functions
or agents that I've
already implemented
that it can use to
guide the development.
And so the key here,
when I started, was
basically I'm saying
basically use these
as your guide and
then create a plan.
And then when I
implement the plan,
don't stray from
that plan. Only
implement what
I've told you to
implement as part
of that plan itself,
right? And that's
the critical
component here.
Otherwise,
if you don't give
it a structured
plan, a very narrowly
structured plan,
it'll go off and decide
to do things that
you didn't want to
do, like an express or
sometimes even puts
Python in middleware
into a Nojs app, right?
It makes no sense.
In this case, you
can see that the
structure was very
structured in terms
of following the
guidance and it's
still doing it, right?
So in this case,
it's iteratively
testing each of these
components and feeding
back into it and
making sure that all
the things are being
guided. And the
main orchestrator is
basically knows what
this sort of core plan
was originally, right?
So when it's done
each step, it goes back
to the orchestrator
and that orchestra
keeps it on point.
otherwise it's kind
of going off and doing
all kinds of craziness
which i don't want
how do you control the
uh includes for this
this file so that it
doesn't go astray and
it's not including all
kinds of **** importing
like uh external
libraries from all over
the place yeah that was
the plan so the plan
file it was was
specifically said which
which ones i wanted to
include look at this
33 test pass while i
was talking to you, it
fixed all its own
problems. Now it went on
to the next, so now
it went on to the next
stage of problems.
So the first,
the first group
of problems,
if we go up here,
we can see that they
all failed, or a lot
of, not all them, but
a bunch of them failed.
And so it iterably
went back and forth,
you know, looking
at the original
plan, looking at the code
that it originally
developed,
and then it's sort
of fixing itself.
This part,
right, right here
is the power
of this system.
It's the iterative test
-driven development.
And when you talk
to, like, developers,
and you talk to them
about, you know,
the London School
of Test-driven
Development, which is
essentially top
-down development,
most developers
will tell you,
I won't do it. And
the reason they won't
do test-driven
development is it takes
probably two to three
times as long to
create the tests for
your, code, then it
does to create the
actual code that you're
trying to build. So
if you're a developer
and you're like, I'm
going to go create,
you know, three
times the amount of
work, they're going
to say, take a hike.
But when it
comes to like AI
implementation, the
AI doesn't complain
about doing three
times the work.
And that, that
work actually ends
up creating that
sort of, you know,
recursive feedback loop.
All right. So you
notice here it stopped
per second. Let's go
back here just to,
I'm rambling. Hopefully
it makes sense.
But you notice here that
it stopped for a moment.
It's thinking, now
it's running PS.
Now this is, this
means that I have
to go and do
it. And this is
something I probably
should have added.
So I'm going to go
here for a moment.
And I'm going
to go and I'm
just going to add the PS.
There's certain
things you don't want
to add. PS is probably
not a bad one.
So I'm just going to
make sure PS is added.
All right, I'm
going to save it.
So next time it
encounters PS,
it'll just run.
It auto picks it up.
So PS is just
looking at the file.
I don't know
why it decides
to do that sometimes.
It's funny,
could have used CAT.
It's essentially
doing a search
for something or
other in the code.
It's not a bad
way to do it.
It's efficient in terms
of token optimization.
Anyway,
next time it
decides to run PS,
it'll just run
autonomously.
This is probably
because this server
is one that I
hadn't used recently
or not in the last
couple of days.
All right, so, oh,
it's going to find
out whether the deno
is already running.
Oh, okay, so it is
already running.
So this part is dumb.
It's switching the port.
It should just
kill the, it
just could kill the pork.
Here's what's
probably happening.
it's probably
running, I'm probably
running an MCP
server somewhere,
and the MCP server is
probably
conflicting with it,
which is, I try to run
MCP on random ports,
but in this case, it
didn't. All right, so
we got to the point
where we're almost done.
So it built this
entire agent. Now
let's go and proceed
while running.
And it's running,
it looks like it's
running the master
AI agent server.
It's also, Looks
like it also built
it as an MCP, which
is kind of cool.
All right.
Now it's testing it
using a curl function.
It built the
entire structure
of a Mastra
multi-tool agent
that I'll
probably do a demo
on later today
automatically.
And how about we're in
apparently 47 minutes.
But this is how
long it took us.
And I think it costs,
I don't think it
costs a lot. I remember,
it's breaking down
the cost individually.
We can take a quick
look, but I think it
was some five bucks.
It's probably in
the, you know,
three or four
dollar range.
All right. So now
it's, it's looking.
It works. It's
totally functional.
Now it's going to create
the documentation.
Now, keep in mind, this
is what's happening
while I'm sleeping
or at off dinner or
coaching my kid's
soccer team or whatever.
It's still doing all
this stuff, right?
All right. So now the
last step, it's switched.
create the docs.
This is like for me,
this is kind of like
deep research, but
deep research that
actually builds stuff.
And I could take
this a step further.
I could, you know,
I could add an MCP
option to my root code.
So not only can it,
build it, it could
deploy it, it could
market it, it could
create an ad campaign
for it. It could
iterate, you know,
back and forth with
my Google ads and
figure out which ads
are optimized for it,
it could create a
landing page for it.
Whatever it is that I
want it to build, it
can it can build it,
but it can actually
then operate it. Like
it can mimic what you
do as a startup and
like start, you know,
accepting payments
with stripe.
It can A-B-test
those payments to
figure out which
ones convert better.
And I just leave this
thing running, right?
And while it's trying
to optimize the
conversion rates
on a landing page.
and deploys it
to the cloud
or whatever it
needs to do.
Root, what's your
estimate currently
on your productivity
using this automated
tools on the background,
like compared
to our regular
development teams?
Would it be worth like 10
developers or 20 or like,
how would you? Well,
in November, I don't
know who it was.
I should look
up the post, but
someone did a research
into my GitHub,
and they said that I,
and this was in November,
that I was 10,000
times more productive
than the app.
average developer.
And I think I'm, if you
believe that number,
I don't know if it's
******** or not, but
take a look at my GitHub
just as an example.
And that'll give
you an idea of
productivity.
Like this is one
guy building stuff
just because,
and this is
even my client
projects. This is
just stuff I put
on LinkedIn for
the **** of it.
You know, I've
got, you know,
here are my agents
of frameworks.
I've got, you
know, guardrail
systems, neurosymbolic
reasonings,
DSPY,
rebuilt in TypeScript,
onyx agents,
midstream, you know,
streaming platform for
in-flight analytics,
conversational
UIs, you know,
custom programming
languages,
agentic automation
systems, Q-Star,
in-flight,
hello world agents.
And each one of these
has tens of things.
thousands or hundreds
of thousands of
lines of code and
this is the stuff all
works um data analytics
developer tools
auto browsers
visualization systems
futuristic uIs like
all this stuff like
it's crazy right quantum
computing systems
deployment tools
and almost all this
stuff was created in
the last 12 months.
Can we just give
it up to roo
for just two
seconds here? I just
think this is
so impressive.
I don't know if
you guys think
that it is
freaking insane.
And this is great.
I tried this yesterday
and it was amazing.
Yeah,
this is next level.
I've been working
with Y Combinator
startups for
the last three
years. And like,
you know, I work
at Amazon and Gen.
I and decided on all
the Slack channels
and everyone has
inventing stuff.
you're a weird
way of the pack.
I'm a program
person, right?
And for me to be in
a stage with opening
visual studio and
probably this is actually,
and I'm not always
regular as well,
but just listening
to and seeing
what you're
showing, right?
I'm able to execute most
of the things myself.
And that is like
really, and that's
really kind of
very different.
So I'm feeling, I
mean, for me, like
product management will
take a different view
now because I think
any product manager
should be able to
within 24 to 48 hours,
discuss with
business, verify the
concepts before
you go in. I mean,
it is no longer, it's a
different way of working.
I see how I see it.
So really thank you
for actually starting
this initiative.
It's, it's, these
are like legitimate
apps. Like they're
not, you know,
they're not like
half-*** things. Like
we're talking things
that actually,
that actually work.
So that brings up to.
question that there has
been some debate that
who is going to be
the first guy to do the
single person unicorn
so is it going to be
europe i don't know
well if you look if you
look at these things
i've built my problem is
i do too much and it's
so like let's let's
go back to like one of
my examples here um
like you know you know
a deep seek at all all
the uh glad you know
glory for doing you
know gspo right back in
like late december when
you look at like my
Strawberry pie?
Strawberry pie
is Deepseek
built last September.
Apparently I just
need to spend
more time on one
thing or something.
You need a commercial
officer or a business
partner to go sell it
all this brilliance.
This literally is Deep
Seek and I predate
them by probably
almost four months.
This will train,
this will completely
train your own custom.
reasoning model
before reasoning
models were a thing.
I guess my problem
is I said, no
rights reserve go
crazy. Maybe that
was my issue, but
maybe I should
slap a strike
payment system on it.
Hey, can you comment
a little bit about
the testing aspect
and the web UI stuff
in the RUCOD mindset?
I know you do a
lot of curl and a
lot of shell script
harnesses, which is
really awesome. but that
web UI testing or
comprehension there,
what are your
thoughts on that?
The testing is the key.
It was the missing piece.
And that's something
I was able to sort
of figure out early
on. So back last,
I think it was
last April, like so
a year ago, I guess,
we're April now.
So last April, I sort
of determined that
if I sort of started
adding a gentic test
-driven component to it
and allowed it to sort
of, you know, execute
the test and then
go back and forth
between the test and the
output in a feedback
loop, I would be able
to automate the
development of anything.
And at which point,
once I figured out
that the, I think
they call it the
London School, which
is funny name for it,
which is basically
a kind of top-down
approach to test
-driven development,
that supercharged my
output. So I went from
doing sort of these
rudimentary, you know,
examples.
that I was essentially,
you know, kind of
copy and pasting from,
from like perplexity
and chat GPT to an agentic
flow that basically
ran 24-7. Suddenly
my output went from
hundreds of lines per
day to tens of thousands.
And by the time the
end of the summer
rolled around and
models like 01 came out,
I was able to get
my output up to, you
know, hundreds of
thousands of lines a day,
basically millions
of lines a month.
But the issue I faced
with 01 was, it was
ridiculous expensive.
So my, my costs for
doing that exploded
in around October.
So suddenly I was
spending $10,000 a month
and that was eating into
like the profitability
of the things I
was doing because a
lot of this is just
like marketing exercise
to find and discover
consulting projects.
And to be honest with
you guys, I don't
charge, I charge a lot
for consulting. So it
was basically, you know,
5% or whatever of my
overall costs were
essentially going into
these experiments and
then some random company
would say, you know
what, I saw your
experiment. Could you
do that for us? And that
was the entire marketing
scheme that I had.
Yeah.
Deep, deep in on the
test driven development,
absolutely.
I'm thinking, are
the tests in the
shell scripts? Are
they using browser
use? Like, you know,
render the form,
test the fields, click
the button, those
kinds of things.
Did it satisfy? Is
that the style that's
going on there?
That's exactly
what's happening.
And you see that in
this, in this scenario,
let's open the terminal
again just quickly.
You'll see that, and
we did this relatively
quickly because I
had a, you know,
a,
you know, it was
a, so you see
there's, there's
a bunch of errors.
And then,
well, actually, let's
go up to before.
And just kind of
one by one went
through and fixed
each of those
errors, right? So
here we had 22,000.
If I scroll up,
there would have been
less past. And as it
sort of went through,
the next run, more
things passed,
a few things
failed or whatever,
and then it fixed
those things, and then
it just keeps trying
until there are
no more. See, there's
a few more errors.
In this test, there
was, let's see how
many errors there
was at the end. See,
the error actually
went up a little bit in
this case. There's 29
errors in this case.
Sometimes the functions
are interrelated
to another, so you
might fix one thing and
break three others,
which probably happened
here. but eventually
it figured it out
and we reached a point
where there were no
errors see in this
so the final version
here all 33 passed so
now when I see that I
know that the entire
application is
functional and then because
it's guiding it it's
like okay let's give
it a spin you can
see that it's like oh
the port was in use
and it did a convoluted
way to figure out
how to do that which
is kind of weird. You
just killed it. I
think the question was,
if I understood
correctly, I'm trying to
get clarity on your
test-driven development
is using APIs and
client side and CLI
to test the feature
and API at API level.
Do you do anything
or do you have
anything for, if you
were to develop a UI,
it will go and
click a button
and look for
somebody's just
appearing and kind
of thing. Yeah.
I do.
Back to my repo.
I've got a project.
I've got a couple.
Obviously, I'm prolific
or whatever the word is.
The best one for that is
when I call the
auto browser.
Yeah,
auto.
here it is. So I've
got auto browser and
I've got a couple
other ones as well. But
auto browser is what
I use. And I've got
two. different
implementations for this.
I've been using a
lot of fire crawler,
fire crawl, I think
it's called lately,
but this basically has an
implementation
that does both,
yeah,
it basically
will serve the
website and it
could click,
interact, do whatever.
Does your testing
framework or Spark
framework use something
like this to test
the UI part of the
app, or not yet? or
you do not do, I
think it's required.
Well, there's a couple
different. You can
use auto browser for
that, but to be honest,
most times,
I'm just going and
using the browser
capability built
right in the roo now
and just saying,
look at the website.
Like, I, as part of
this, so like, if you,
I'm going to,
I'm going to
go, it's done,
apparently,
so I'm just going
to let it, I'm
just going to go
show you guys.
But, so there's a
couple of components.
And look, look
at, just before
I do, look at
the extensive.
architecture.
So it created
all this stuff
on the call,
the middleware,
the cores,
plans,
tests,
documentation,
tools,
types.
And we did it in less
than an hour. This is,
if we, if I was
programmed this
manually, it would
have taken me months.
And I probably wouldn't
have done the tests.
Because you
mentioned that the
that the tests
are so crucial,
when are you
triggering those just
agentically via
Spark? Or do you have
a file as well in
rule code that they're
getting executed
after each run?
So it's this.
So let's go around
to the test.
It goes, oh, it's in
here. Let's just do DDD.
Right, where I got my
scroll bar. That's weird.
because once they
are built the test
driven file you could
basically at that in
a settings page or
in the settings file
of root code i think
in windsurf it's
possible and then each
time the agent runs
you can trigger those
test files just to
make sure or have like
something which is
more deterministically
firing it it's
this so this this is
this is the so each
has a mode right So
this is my TDD mode.
So you notice that
it's switched between
auto-coder and
debugger. Debugger
is similar, but the
tester, you know,
these two basically
worked it together.
And you can say, this
writes the tests,
this implements
the tests.
And I separated.
Now, I could take
it a step further.
And so, for example,
if I wanted to
use an MCP server
to do it, let's say
I have the test
running, you know,
independently,
then I might
actually get rid
of all the other
options here.
maybe I'll leave
browser to see the site
and maybe I'll leave
MCP to interact with it
programmatically, but
I'll lose the command
and I'll lose the
edit read. So I don't,
so maybe don't want to
code anything. I just
want to go and sort
of play with it. And
then what I might do
here is add an option
that I might say
something like, you know,
create a, you
know, create sub
tasks using new
underscore tasks,
right? And that
would give it
the guidance that
it can then go
and create
additional subtas.
Those subtasks could
be the other roles.
The other role might
be the tester or
the code implementator
or implementation.
So the more narrowly
focused you make
each mode, the better
the mode works.
And if you're looking
to use MCPs as power
the mode, you're
going to create a mode
explicitly just for MCP.
that solves the problem
of the roo and Klein
where there has a
tendency to go and
rebuild the MCP. I don't
want it to build the
MCP if it's already
working. I just want it
to go and use the MCP.
And so by removing all
the other options here,
browser and edit
and command,
it'll just do
that one thing.
And it makes it work
much more focused.
Hopefully that
makes sense.
RUD. What I meant is
more triggering the
test itself because
I've still, I have the
feeling that sometimes
once it's built,
sometimes it redos
features or just
removes things which
have been previously
built and I have
a feeling when you
trigger those tests
after each run,
it would figure out, oh,
basically it's
crashing here because
I might have
removed something.
You know what I mean?
Yeah, the,
that, I haven't
run into that
problem with this.
that's typically
like using Klein
with no guidance.
There's a concept of
a stability log that
for a stability test
where it's like once
something is working
and you add it with
a stability test
and the workflow run
that stability test
afterwards and I've also
created Playwright tests
which automatically
it's a browser.
So once you have a
feature implemented
and it's working then
we can, like, basically
say, run a stability
test, which is a
playwright test,
literal validity if it
works, it's expected.
So it's not perfect,
but it's another
kind of topplementary
strategy.
Yeah, that's a really
good strategy, actually.
And I think that
sometimes your
purpose is end
-to-end testing.
So what I sometimes do to
sort of augment
my own rules,
because I don't
want the modes to be
too crazy in terms
of prompts, because
that makes it expensive
and just makes
it hard. to, there's
conflicting rules.
So what I then
do is I use
this client rules file.
You can use cursor
rules, which
works kind of
the same way.
And then I customize
this particular
file by literally
going into a rule or
client and saying it
to customize it for
the specifics of
this particular repo.
So in this case,
you can see that
it's customized
location for CSS
variables. It's talking
about, you know,
which, you know,
types of, you know,
like test-driven
development
or linting components.
So it's using
GIST for Node
and Flake 8 for Python.
Dino has that built
-in. So it's saying
they use the built-in
Dino components, some
of the providers in
terms of preference.
So this acts as a
kind of global guide
where the modes
act as a kind of.
the kind of agents,
but the agents will
see both the tasks
that are given to it
as well as the overall
sort of definition
that's defined here.
You can see here
my loud commands.
Now if I want to
add more commands,
I could just add
them right here.
And block
commands, which are
equally important,
things I don't
want it to
necessarily run.
And then other related
tasks, you know,
for example, my MCP
servers I was telling
you about, I have
tends to to run them on
port 3,000, I find that
that's a good range
for these. They don't
conflict too much.
Here's some
other, you know,
development
-related activities.
Here's, you know,
command shortlists.
So these are commands and
how to run the commands,
which is useful.
Now, if someone was
asking about memory,
this is where you'd
set that up. So the
memory bank allows
you to incrementally
define where you
are in the process
and define the
prioritization of where
and how and when
those things are going
to happen in terms
of the progress,
the activity,
and remaining on
point and focus.
So you can do a
lot more here. I
generally keep it
simple to start,
but if I'm running
long-term, you
know, things, like
let's jump back to
the other project
that I'm working on.
No, look.
The memory is per
project or global or
because you're kind of
showing global setting,
but I'm assuming
the, it'll
apply to local
each project.
This is local, but
you can define it
globally as well, I
think, by going into
roo and I think
it's this one here.
It makes sense,
this button.
Yeah, here it is.
Global modes
is an option.
I do have a global mode,
you know,
and usually it looks
like my, it looks like
the default. roo and
then I literally just
point roo at it and
then I customize it for
each project and then
I get it let it run.
Have you ever built
anything like,
have you built like
an iOS app like
with this approach?
Like could you?
So iOS is funny
because of X code, you
know, Lutter is probably,
Lutter is probably
your best bet for
this because it acts
as an abstraction from
X. code so you can
kind of build it and
then and then have
it sort of run you
know independently a
little bit but using
X code directly is
problematic I haven't
had much success and
you guys can tell I'm
sharing my screen I'm
currently on a Windows
which is also you
know not as friendly
for X code I can
obviously run in Windows
but you know the,
if you're
building iOS apps,
OSX is still
the way to go.
I had a quick question.
I'm not a professional
developer, so if
this is a terrible
audience for this,
please somebody
to **** off. But I
work for a
manufacturer company.
We do a lot of dot
-net development,
so more so desktop
applications
for complex geometry.
And the stuff you're
posting is really
motivational to get
people going, particularly
with our company who
have a programming
skill set, but not very
advanced. And so I'm
wondering if it's a
bad decision or should
I not try and take
some of this framework
and kind of break it
apart and try and use
it for things like
the dot on development
is Visual Studio 2022.
I can't even use Visual
Studio code for some
of the stuff I'm
doing. And to try and
just at least create
some of these guidelines
and feed that into
something like co-pilot
or otherwise to help
create a structured
framework even if it
takes me longer and
isn't fully automated.
Yeah,
so, this is a project
I did for a real
estate analytics company
earlier this week.
I will show it to you
because of NDA issues.
But what I ended up
doing for these guys,
which is kind of cool,
is I customized this
part. See here, I get
the Spark tutorial.
So now with the
Spark tutorial,
let's just close
this for a moment.
And I'm going to go here.
See, I'm closing subtas.
I'm just going to
close it all up.
So now with this
Spark tutorial,
I can go here
and I'll just
do something like Start,
but I can create
customized versions of
the Rube code system
that are explicitly
trained, or not
trains, the wrong word,
prompted for the
particulars of that
project or repo
that I'm working on.
And in this
case, you know,
it's Spark, but if
it was like a data
analytics project for a
commercial real estate
company, which is
something I'm working on,
then it will literally
guide them through
the process of what
I built them and
how to customize it,
how to deploy it,
how to, you know, add new
features and
other things.
And all they need
to do is basically
interact with my little
tutorial system here.
And that,
all this is,
if you want to go
take a look at this,
is this entry,
Spark tutorial.
So for you, what
you'd probably do
is, you probably
grab my Roob modes
file and then you
basically customize,
you'd load that in the
repo that has the code.
Then you'd basically say
using the orchestrator,
you'd probably
say go review the
repo and all the
code and structure
and everything
relates to it,
then update the
dot Room modes file
specifically Slug tutorial
and create a detailed
step-by-step tutorial
that guides use.
through the process
of using that repo.
What's cool about
that is then you
can optimize the
actual orchestrator
and call it XYZ
orchestrator.
And then they can
use that as the
process for doing
updates, Git pushes,
PR's issues, whatever.
And it's all just
customized for them.
Super helpful. Thank you.
It blows their
mind, by the way.
I showed up on
this call, and
then I'm like,
here's a custom,
you know, chat
system, basically is
roo mode that's
been completely
customized to your
particular requirements
as a real estate
analytics company.
And then their
minds were blown.
You can see here,
like, here's,
this is just guiding you
through how to
use Spark, right?
So for anyone
that's starting out,
just choose the Spark
tutorial mode and
just ask it questions.
It'll tell you
how to use it, how
to customize it.
Like, I could say, like,
how can I optimize
the at-roo
modes file, a
way we call it?
Have you shared those
roo modes currently,
like in any of
your repos? Yeah, I
shared on, I did a
tutorial. LinkedIn
the other day and you
know and and and I
can share here in a
minute if you guys
want it's on my it's
on my just currently
I probably should
do a more complete
repo for it how do I
optimize room modes
for sport grocery
using the this edge
functions repo
so you know you
notice here in
the tutorial
I've only given
a read access
So it can look at the
files, but it can't
write, because I don't
want it to write.
So I want it to
get the general
idea of what
the system does,
so it's going to
figure it out.
You know, for the
for the orchestrator,
I gave it no ability
to do anything
other than to
just orchestrate.
And one thing to
keep mind also for
the orchestrator, it
can see open tabs.
So whatever tab you
have opened, it'll
be able to review as
well. So you might
want to start with
a read me there.
But yeah, so now.
it's giving me ideas.
So it's kind of
like a tutorial
slash whatever,
you know, ask mode.
So now it's
suggesting that I, you
know, add more edge
functions and so now
in this case, can
I ask a question?
Sure. Yeah, go ahead.
So, so let's say that
I wanted to basically
configure the Spark
to code like an agent
framework on top of
Azure and using the
Azure functions and
Azure AI search and
whatever other things
they have there. So
do you think that's
feasible? Like basically
to customize this
Spark framework for
that specific purpose
or like how would you
go about it? That's
literally what I'm
doing right at the
moment. So this this file
is meant to be a kind
of starting point.
Right.
So now I have a
starting point. I'm
I just I did a
quick sort of review
saying, tell me more
about the system.
Now I'm getting
the system
to self-optimize itself.
So using the original,
I'm telling it
to update the
actual roo modes and
optimize it
specifically for use in
this particular
context of this repo,
which is kind of mind
-boggling in itself.
It's recursive, self
-improving, you know,
AI.
So now let's
let, let's, let,
so basically,
once you've got
that sort of
default template,
just do what I just
did. Say, review
the repo and then
optimize the dot
root file
specifically for the
capabilities and
files and architecture
or whatever of this
particular repo.
And then what we should
hear is in a ****,
hopefully it doesn't
induce any errors,
an optimized version.
So see it's changing it
to edge function advisor,
edge function DevOps.
You know, it's all now
it's all related to
the edge functions. that
this repo is focused
on all right now
we're almost done it
looks like it kept the
spark tutorial probably
because i was just
in spark tutorial all
right hopefully it
doesn't die at the end
it's only 125 lines
it should be okay all
right there we go so now
look it it it reflects
immediately now you
see all these are
now optimized i have
to review it i didn't
look at it but it
optimized all my functions
to be related to edge
-related activities,
which will make
it work even
better for this
particular repo.
So if you look at
what you are, you
capture full edge
function APIs,
you create
scalable, secure
modular edge functions,
you write
clean, efficient
modular edge
function code,
you get the idea.
It's been optimized.
specifically for
the purposes and
structure of this
particular application.
Now, I can do that
not only for code
development, because we
have MCP involved here,
I could create a,
I'm going to go
here and just show
you guys something
interesting.
Is this the
MCP-only mode?
Well, that's exactly
what we can do. So
create me a new roo
modes dot MCP that only,
well,
what are we going
to say here?
You know,
that only orchestrates,
edge functions
using MCPSSSE
or something
like that, right?
And I'm just, I'm just
viving it right now.
But we're going
to go to edge
function coder,
that looks good.
And put it in root over.
See what it
comes up with.
now I'm skipping
any of these sort of
definitions and
specs. I'm just saying
to take a look at
this and do it.
Hey,
Rube,
well, this is
running, can I make
a quick announcement
about Agenics.
That order? Yeah,
sure, go for it.
So I just want
everyone to know,
if you're new here,
you've been
around, you've
probably heard of
Agenics Foundation.
Rube has laid out
a vision to make
this information
really accessible.
And so we've
been working as a
group, to establish
a foundation
called Agenetics
Foundation.
It can be found
at Agenix.org.
And we have a
membership tier that we
love people to join.
So I'm just going to
put a link in the
chat here. But please
join us. We're going
to be building out
some really cool
stuff over the next.
You know, hopefully
several years here.
But this includes
events like
this where we
have virtual
meetings and kind
of go together.
Actual, like other
events, we're
looking for
ambassadors to help
out with growing
in the community.
but there's a lot of
interest in this and
we just want to thank
everyone for their
support and come on
these calls but we'd
love to have you
join as a member too.
Thanks.
Thanks for doing.
Is there a sign-can-be
-reached kind of thing?
Alex, we can't
access your link.
Your link is working,
Alex.
Oh, okay, let me try a
different link
here, one sec.
probably did i break
it i'm really good of
creating bugs too uh it
it's working over here
but i'm just try to
paste it again tell me
if that works it might
be that i don't have
the the backslash
afterward no you shouldn't
have it shouldn't
need a backslash yeah
that's what i figured
but um it's rendering for
for me yeah look like
it's long for me too
I think it's a
region problem.
Some DNS proof
finished annex domain.
That's the era.
Okay, now it's working
in my end also.
I didn't use WWW.
I should probably
add that.
Yeah.
Do people still
use WWW? Is
that that that's a thing?
I thought that was
like from 1994 when
people thought, you
know, LinkedIn requires
it when you post a
link that like this.
this unfortunately.
So straight directed
to the regular
domain and that's it.
Well,
for those that are
interested,
I'm working on,
here you guys can get
a sneak peek of the,
I've been working
on the admin
dashboard to
actually create
some real content
for the site.
My apologies, I do
you can tell, I'm
pulled in a lot of
different directions,
but we've got a
learning content section
now. I can go in,
I can edit content,
you can see I get our
friends at Kaltura
in here, I can embed
code. I can use, you
know, little risk
text editor. I built a
frequent CMS because,
you know, why not?
We can go in here and
this, this has got
agents for everything
underpinning it. So
there's, you know, MCPs
and stuff like that,
little previews.
At some point,
I will open
source this whole thing.
But so the content
management system is ready
for testing for anyone
who likes testing.
I'm going to go actually
create some real content,
but you got, oh,
I'm still waiting
for the guys from
Kaltura to fix this
issue. They've
got some sort of,
they don't allow me
to embed their videos.
So I'm waiting
for that. I'll
bug the Kaltura
guys later.
I've got a
comment system,
likes,
all that, all the
stuff. expect.
I don't know. The
fact you can build
your own content
management system
in the time it
takes you install
WordPress is
pretty spectacular.
All right.
If code, repo, and all
that kind of stuff,
you can be able to
deploy the robots and all
right. I think we're
almost at a
time. I don't.
Hopefully this
was helpful.
Just a big feedback.
I mean, I've
tried to join, but
it keeps asking me
to repeatedly
login using Google,
but then even if I
say join as a fan,
it sends me back to
the login page again.
So it seems to
be going forward.
I can show you
what is happening.
Is it, it's, I
mean, it could be
a registration
issue. Did you
register recently
or a while ago?
Well, I registered.
Now I was trying
to basically go
to the next year,
basically the second
option, but it
doesn't seem to
give me the payment
screen or any other
thing in there.
I'll have to take a look.
It's not
diligent. I mean,
if you could let
us, let me know
when it works and
I'll sign up. Yeah,
again, it's one of
those things where it's
like, oh, it works
for me, you know, but
it doesn't mean it
works for anybody else.
Yeah, I'm just logging
in with Google here.
We're building it
while we're flying it.
Yeah, you know, it's
a little bit of that.
And we are looking
for volunteers for
anyone who might be
interested in helping.
You know,
we're all, we all
volunteer here.
This is a sort of not
-profit. I've got to
fix this problem. I
think I got to log into
Google or whatever and
fix that, whatever.
So it says super base or
whatever the
heck that is.
All right, logged in.
If you're interested
in volunteering too,
I'm happy to
coordinate that if you
want to hit us
up on WhatsApp or
join the Discord
or LinkedIn, too.
I don't know.
It appears to
work for me.
I'm trying one more time.
Now, just because
it works for me
doesn't mean it'll
work for anybody else.
It was like the error
page effectively.
So let me, if
you have some
time, let me
show it to you.
I've got a five
minutes for
my next call,
but here, yeah.
Okay, I'll try.
Yeah,
I don't know, it's,
sure.
I'm sure it's something I
can fix in like seconds.
I just need to know
what the problem is.
Okay.
So you see my
screen now, right?
So it goes back to
this error page.
So if I say, join
now, go to Google,
and I go to my
email address.
Comes to this
page, continue.
Then it gives me
the three options.
And it's gone back
to error again, yeah.
Yeah,
that's a,
that's a regression.
I fixed that last week.
Try it incognito once.
No, it's that error, that
error is a server error.
Do right click on
the page for a sec?
And do you look
at your console?
It's back, right?
Yeah, so
membership
error for closed
before response
was received.
It likely has,
I don't know,
it probably has
to do with new.
Can you register with
a user name password?
I can try and
breathe an
account, I guess.
It doesn't seem
to affect existing
users. It seems to
be like new users. I
remember a new user
is going to, has a
different process
when you after the O.
I had signed up
previously with my Gmail.
I was only trying to
upgrade at the moment.
So no, it doesn't
go anywhere.
look at the console
again the console
yeah sure i seem
to have lost my
20th yeah it's the
a yeah it's yeah
i think they have
to very end there
uh you know just put
the console let's see
see what what it's
saying click on console
uh it looks
like there's an
there's a user
sign up error
how about uh you're
already signed
up you said right
you should be
just uh you should
be just uh trying
to sign in, not
join the game.
Am I missing something?
Yeah, but I was trying to
upgrade to the next tier.
So you log in and
then upgrade, right?
Well, it looks like
he's, I don't know,
there's a 400 error for
sure, which is weird.
Off the looking at
what's caused in the
400 error. It's
basically the edge
function is not being
called correctly.
anyway i i'm
i'm sure i'll be
able to figure
that out it's
yeah i don't i don't
it's it's it's it's
odd that it's it's it's
it's hard that it's
work for me though
but um you think that
if you're already
registered it would work
for everyone the same
way but anyway um
well good to know and
yeah We'll fix it.
Thank you.
Awesome. Thank you.
Yeah, it's really
hard to fix
things that work
for me, right?
Now that what I
might need to do is
try a different user
or maybe I'll try
registering a new
user and see if I
can get the error.
But now I see the
error. I'm sure I
can figure that out.
Okay.
Thank you very much.
Bye.
All right.
Thanks, everyone.
Hello.
Can I ask a question,
please?
Sure.
Yeah,
I saw that in your
route line, you
have some custom
configuration and lots
of moors, client
rules, many things.
So is it open
source? Can I go,
can we got this
full configuration?
Yeah,
it's on my,
currently on my GIST,
if you want
that here. Let
me pop it in
the chat here.
there you go you can
just grab it there
and there's a there's
a tutorial on my link
to somewhere you can
probably find that
if you search around
for it okay thank you
all right uh i'll i'll
take a look and see
what i can figure out
with the sign up and
you might get an error
also if you decide to
log in if you signed
up with the wrong If
you signed in with
Google or GitHub or the
email, they could cause
conflicts possibly.
But I'll figure
it out, I'm sure.
The only thing
I'm better at than
creating bugs
is fixing bugs.
All right,
thanks, everyone.
And for everyone,
what's interesting,
we do, if you want
to show you whatever
you're building,
we've done the AI
hacker space on
Fridays, so you can
show off what have
you, what have you
built with roo over
the next 24 hours.
As always,
thanks, everyone.
Appreciate it.
Thanks for everything.
I'll let you know
with the bugs. And
we've got the, we
get the Discord.
Martin's fixed that
up. Hopefully we
have the rules figured
out there as well.
And we've got the
WhatsApp channel
for anyone who wants
to keep in touch.
All right, until next
time. Thanks, everyone.