Hello, all.
Okay.
Ghost
tools.
Reuven is on vacation
this week, as you guys
know. So we have –
so Jed's going to be
technical lead, and
then same thing. I'll
facilitate the guest
speakers and the various
lightning talks and
all that kind of stuff.
This is the pre
-show, so feel
free to unmute
yourself if you
want to chat with
anybody else.
We've got
everything else.
Better infamous than
famous, you know?
Yeah, that's right.
I'll take infamy. me
we are live in this
week uh reuben is on
uh reuben's on vacation
he's enjoying lobster
and and uh fish
fries no doubt on the
east coast and uh jed
has taken the helm
uh the technical
leave for us today and
then we'll dive
into all the various
presentations and demos
hey jed how's it going
hello everyone and
welcome to this friday's
hacker space so for
those of you who
unfamiliar a lot of us
use llms to write code
and see if i can get
this working today
i did not make the
requisite sacrifices
the demo gods
so we will find
out how well this
does or doesn't
while we're
waiting i'm going
to see if we
can kick off any
instance of cloud
code to generate a
browser-based game
and so as we're going
through everyone
else's demo we'll
let that **** along
in the background
and then come to
it at a later time.
Oh, neat.
I think that's
set up. Does
anyone have a preference?
As for the style of
game, you mean, Jed?
Well, I mean, Asteroid is
a classic.
Tetris as well.
I'm an Asteroids
guy, yeah.
Okay, so
create Asteroid.
How many quarters?
Okay, so create a
an offline
browser
based asteroid
game which relies
on yeah, androids
be
it another time you
can actually simulate
the war games you
know, from the classic
movie would you like
to, or shall we play
a game right, it's
more of a I actually
redid it with Lovable
about a month or so
ago just to play around
with it, but I like
what you're doing,
this is pretty cool I'm
excited to see what
this will turn out.
Use test-driven
development.
Create playwright to
renders correctly.
What else should I
be using here? Just a
note, at the beginning,
you have an Android
game because it's
right at the outset.
Anteroid. Okay,
let's see if it can
figure out what
Android actually means.
or what variation it
comes up with yeah
we could always use
a little more entropy
curious
what other game you've
already made too jed
because you've tested
this before showing
it i'm sure oh you you
think too highly of
me you know what i
want to do as a game
so you know in twitter
spaces i feel like
there's a lot of like
bugs and language people
use one i could say
i see that lately is
like um um like people
say all the time
so i would love to do
in like a twitter space
count the amount of
times everybody says
it and then have like
a contest at the end
like a fun little
because the agents could
like on the background
make like little
like like kind of games
like that you know
tally like interactive
games it'd be really
fun so what did you
have in there you had
uh okay almost go i
see initialize clause
flow we depend on it
for the system prompt
well that's so many
of those old arcade
cabinets have such
elaborate artwork
um i i mistakenly
thought like
berserk i thought
it was berserko and
you know i'm sure
there's several other
games but it's got
the name wrong.
That'd be funny.
AI is pretty good
about tracking
typos, but sometimes,
sometimes not.
I love misspelling
with it.
Anteroid.
You guys ever
prompt images just
out of random
numbers, see what
it generates? Just
like 10 eyes, 2,
3, 4, 5, 6, see
what it just...
It's kind of weird.
I wonder what
it thinks when it
tries to do that.
You should try
that. so i've been
doing that for fun
i download them
and then i just
keep a couple like
i do do a lot of images
but i it will be a
screenshot of something
i'm doing even a
terminal session or
something figure out the
prompt like jet post
something i won't even
give an instruction i
want to see what will
go it normally gets it
you know i see this a
prompt for cloud code
or something you know
i love that as a
process you take the
screenshot you give it
the error log and then you
give it feedback and
then like all three
combined is like really
strong yeah about that
um it's taking its
own screenshot and
because it's a docker
image it's already able
to tail the log out of
the docker container
that's being created
and in theory it's has
access to root within
this environment so it
can start and stop the
docker image rebuild
it and then try again
so this is taking
off we have five agents
running concurrently
and perhaps we can
bring up our first guest
wonderful excellent
jets i love this i love
this to get something
started and then
revisit it later on
in that in the in the
episode that's really
neat so um we got a few
folks today excuse me
sebastian who came to
us uh who we we uh
found and connected at
the toronto tech week
and meetup events uh
it's got some uh a neat
mcp tool to show us
And then we have
Sergio as well.
And Sergio has been
a long-time member,
so I'm looking
forward to seeing what
he's got. Probably
have some membership
updates and stuff
later on from Brad.
So why don't we
launch off? Now,
Lightning Talks,
usually we go about
four minutes. We
try to keep them
crisp, but then
there's lots of time
for question and
answer afterwards.
We've got a fair
amount of time today,
too. So if there's some
folks that have some
things they'd like
to share and or demo,
please feel free to
message Jet or I or
put your hand up, let
us know, and we'll
try to orchestrate it
all and weave it in.
So, Sebastian,
how are you, sir?
I'm well, ready
to have some fun.
Let's get started
there. I'm going to
screen share with
you quickly here.
I hope I don't have
any random message
notification pop ups,
but, you know, if you if
it happens, please don't
mind. yeah i've got
this uh okay go ahead
you should be good
thank you very much
so essentially i built
like a fun web app
thinking of like some of
the latest things we've
been like doing lately
so i thought about
making like a really
like super intelligent
scraping system so
building essentially a
bunch of mcps scraping
autonomously across
different specializations
and then also
applying learning like
intelligence to them so
they get better at it
and they could also
qualify like research or
essentially have a
very constructive
autonomous like cloud
deployment so that they can
24 7 go on and and get
papers also i added
to it i want to make
them accumulate all
the knowledge and ground
to it and then generate
its own like research
papers its own
discovery its own kind
of combinations of
things right now what
you're seeing and also
like a root agent's
favorite concepts with
like a little bit of a
temporal filter seeing
what it's great being
like recently maybe
you see like the most
recent like repositories
was popular i think
you just look that
up in github right now
you're seeing a lot of
like it's not like
it's it's not fully
deployed so i've been
going through the process
of essentially going
on my cloud services
so the initial prompts
were about orchestrating
the the visual system
a rough copy right
then after enhancing
the backend system
and then uh i was i
deployed the mcps locally
so it started generating
data but i wanted
to do it autonomously
and then being that
so so right now i'm
configuring the front
end with the deployed
backend uh system and
then here you could
see on my fire store uh
i got um there's this
thing i got like all
the data kind of like
collecting into firebase
right so it's going
to be interesting to
see once deployed i'll
update maybe next week
uh over the over the
weeks and months how
much it collects and
generates and we could
all maybe chat with it
uh and just like play
around you know maybe
you have like uh as a
group an interactive
mode so just thinking
about some of those
things it'll be cool to
see in the future but
yeah thank you guys
appreciate sharing wow
yeah my goodness because
think about the idea
of perplexity and all
these guys they're just
like a small startup
but they're probably
doing these kinds of
things right they're
deploying probably their
whole web but it'd be
interesting doing a
specialized a more
focused approach to maybe
see what we can come
up with it's more like
for fun creative right
now but let's it could
really maybe come up
with some really cool
stuff i mean i can
easily see applications
like um you know i
work with bid teams and
that's a high pressure
high stress environment
where tools, the more
tools you can do for
automating, paper
pushing, data pushing. So
my mantra is just
personal task automation.
The human being is
going to be the creative
engine, but the way
we can enable them to
get the outcome, this
is just a direct, it's
got that business value.
It's awesome, man.
Totally, totally awesome.
You know what's an
interesting
point you say?
You know how we have,
you don't have to pay
for all these apis or
databases sometimes
it's interesting
seeing what we have for
free but then you
know you get a lot of
abstract papers what
if the agent starts to
accumulate and combine
the concepts of that
researcher to then
try to generate it and
maybe in different
variations because only
human is just one human
or a small team but
imagine it might
actually be able to even
research papers or
compare it to the it'll
be interesting just Going
back to that, you're
writing an RFP, which
is quite complex.
Maybe you're
replacing, say, a
contact center and
a frontline system.
Welfare, say welfare,
you're dealing
with homeless people,
people without
money for food. And
that's a complex.
But you need to do
a lot of research.
Canada has a good
welfare system. Norway
has one. Switzerland.
You want to mine
the best and say,
for my country, I
want to replace the
systems I have. That's
a great point.
That's the kind of,
because I sit in
that space. You know,
I deal with a lot
of that kind of
environment, contact
center and omnichannel.
It'd be nice to make
a lot of research.
And you have teams
spending months,
18 months doing
that research.
And, you know, in
North America, very few
people go maybe to look
at Japanese universities
or they look at, you
know, in Africa and
all these places.
Imagine translating it
as well. And also, you
said that about the
distributing it, right?
Yeah, that's right.
It's just getting like
a global connected
parallel like kind of
system. i i noticed a
pop up there sebastian
that said no mock data
oh sorry sorry yeah i
know right now because
it's connected to it's
not built like the
the cloud deploy system
like i have it um
i need to connect it
properly to the uh so
that it's autonomously
working with the mcps
and playwright right
yeah so then it is i
was trying to finish
it yesterday but not
enough time like also
doing all these other
stuff so i'm gonna do
something i think this
is good if we do our
side projects like this
for fun maybe 15 or
30 minutes a day they
will accumulate you know
because i don't want
to overwhelm myself
and just being now i'm
going to put everything
away and focus on
it there's so much to
do but um i i think it
will come along over
the weeks i think we
could all do that and
just like kind of that's
why they just build
on top of each other
if i can uh talk
sebastian to mondrip's
question uh just to let
him know so i contacted
sebastian and we are
he's trying to give
me a little instruction
set on i should do a
i should do one
hopefully we're already
working on getting the
setup if you like and
the prompts it'd be
good to do a quick loom
just showing hey
install a quick mcp on
playwright and maybe
with jewels just like a
quick loom you know like
it'd be probably very
instructional because
we all have to go
through that process or
like people just it'd
be helpful to know how
to scrape something
you know these companies
are doing it why
can't we right so yeah
suggestion are you
planning to kind of share
open source this or i
want to share that
you know i feel like
right now it's a
community we have a lot of
really cool stuff i love
sharing with everybody
so that we can all
build on top of it uh
and look under the
hood what you're doing
because i can think of
like we can all contribute
to it open source
that's right because
there's perspective and
safety and all these
companies they're
they're making they're
charging but why can't
we have an open one just
for the community
you mentioned about
translation right so our
colleague ben's um ben's
basically has a database
um i'll show you
the link um he has a
database in hungarian
on psychology imagine
wow i heard my name
mentioned thanks your
translation thing that
you've done and that
is magnificent maybe he
should mention that
that's that's such a like
imagine oh we have
the opportunity to
combine everybody's like
expertise around the
world and like you can
just translate everything
now just in like a
button it's crazy to
have the ai google's
models are great for
that i mean even samsung
on their phone over
the last two three years
it's been really good
you've seen the voice
the streaming and
all that it's pretty
incredible i would love
to for this it was
just kind of like a sci
-fi thinking i guess but
imagine we all open a
workspace right now
and we all connected
our own dev tools
isolated and we all just
contributed to a project
like talking to it we
could just talk to it
maybe on a walk or you
know typing why not
contributed to a unified
commit or like a
repository that'd be kind
of cool i don't know
like it's if we all
had extra time to do for
fun right we all have
work and stuff but
stuff like that i think
will be very valuable
maybe in universities
or for people just like
a high school class
it'd be kind of fun
what they come up with
oh i absolutely agree
so the kids together
Sorry, go ahead, Jed.
Thank you for
sharing, Sebastian.
I don't know if we
want to move along to
the next... Yeah,
I'm sorry. Every time
we rant, I'm sorry.
No, it's great.
It's great. Just one
more quick question.
You're very
passionate. It's good.
We love it. Thank
you so much.
I love that about going
to Toronto. Everyone
who's around should
come. If I could
ever go on the other
places, I'll always
stop by. But it's
nice to see people and
talk about it just
for the passion of it.
And it could really
help others, you know.
this tuesday this
coming tuesday on the
12th is the next
one so everybody i'm
coming down and
there's some folks yeah
um antoineta and a
few other i guess
antoineta is flying
in she's going to be
uh in the city so
from the uh west coast
that's really neat
and that's awesome
um on some medical
sorry what's that
antoineta looking
forward to meeting
everybody there yeah
that's gonna be great
we'll all come down
early for the day
and we can grab some
lunch before the
event that'll be uh
it'll be wonderful
perfect super thank
you sebastian amazing
when we can uh
there's a way to play
with it really looking
forward to it 100
it'd be nice to push
through give me a
few weeks maybe a
week or two let's see
but i'd love to thank
you so much Yep.
All right. So, Sergio,
do we have,
let me see.
Sergio Pasquale.
Are you with us?
No, Sergio. Sergio
didn't make it in.
All right.
Sergio Villanueva
is in the house,
but I'm not
ready to present.
Oh, no.
it's okay like things
are so quick we you
know it's like i'd
love to hear the ideas
yeah so uh sergio do
you want to come back
and do a little demo
later on in the hour
or is it next week
no i'm i'm a i'm a
different sergio i'm
just um oh i see yeah
but um yeah i'm happy
i'm happy to i'm happy
to improvise something
but um but um i
have some cool projects
but i'm not a i'm
not part of the
schedule i'm a different
surgeon sorry very
good very good um okay
well i don't know uh
brad do i do uh uh should
i put you on the spot
see what thoughts
you have around the
website and how things
are generally going
with uh the volunteers
and the members
that are working on
that stuff oh nothing
like being put on the
spot can you hear me
okay here okay good
um yeah so website
we're up and running um
everything works we're
looking for content
so anyone that has
content that wants to come
ahead go on sign up on
the website community
.agenix.org if you're
an existing subscriber
we're going to bring
you over Nick and
I are going handhold and
make sure everything's
all set up you're
going to be on a legacy
system so you don't
have to worry about
anything so we're going
to take care of our
existing subscribers
right now we're just
really wanting to put
content on so So any
kind of courses, love
Sebastian's Loom idea.
You want to be a
contributor, a good
way to actually
talk about and
promote yourself as
a contributor to the
Agentex website.
So it's awesome.
So we'll be doing a big
push. We're going to
migrate all the existing
members right now,
about 2,000. Plus, I
believe we have about
500 to 600 that have
come through Looma and
all the other sources
that we're going to be
migrating. so that's
kind of our short-term
goal iteration process
makes make a whole
bunch of mistakes start
getting a whole bunch
of content provide a
lot of extra value over
the summer and then
the big push is going
to be coming in september
so if you know any
friends and family
get them started right
now we're going to be
doing a massive push in
september so we're
desperately looking for
uh not desperately but
it'd be really helpful
if we had some sponsors
uh to to actually
help us do this uh if
you're a course creator
it's a really good way
to promote yourself
create some courses
provide some value to
the community um it's
we're using something
called disco which has
a really easy ai you
can upload a pdf or
just verbally chat to it
and click a button and
it creates the courses
similar to what a
university or college or
an edx would do so that
content's all there
that's it for the
website one last thing
is we have a big push
and thank you we have
a massive community
thank you to everyone
helping with the
website matt nick the
other sergio martin a
whole bunch of people
are helping out but
we're also working on
a big push called
accreditation so this is
going to be something
unique in the industry
and we're looking
to be really the
first so we're just
brainstorming right now
we got a big community
but the the outcome
where it's going
right now um if it is
recorded um don't bring
this up later on uh
because things may
change but what we're
looking at right now
is we're we're going to
be starting with the
top of the top tier
agentics engineer
certification so something
that we go through
verify that you um
adhere to ethics and
safety and way things go
making sure that you
have a at least a solid
knowledge not not
just a basic knowledge
but a solid knowledge
of general computing
and computers so you
don't have to go to
formal school but
typically you would have to
be in the industry
for a number of years
so this kind of degree
is not really made
for a vibe coder at
the start you'll learn
your way to get there
making sure that you
contribute significantly
at least in one open
source project and
then we're looking at
more of like a doctoral
type program where
you present in front
of essentially a board
to to back up your
dissertation or a
project that is
fundamental in the hndx
community so those
are kind of the
guidelines for the big
degree it's going to
be very difficult
to do very exclusive
to help people
get there we're
spending a lot
of time on having
courses and
essentially similar to
a graduate school micro
certification program
so you go and if you're
just starting out
your vibe coder here's
a series of courses
past the courses we're
looking for course
instructors to provide
these you'll have a level
one then a medium
and an advanced and
finally after the advanced
hopefully with some
coaching and some hard
work you'll be ready
for the accreditation
so a lot going on in
the education a lot
going on in the website
stuff even though it's
summertime and some of
us are on vacation
um we're still moving
forward and i want to
give a big shout out to
everyone that's been
really helpful um and
if i missed your name
i apologize i'm i'm on
the spot here so brad
can i ask some questions
about um this um you
know first of course
the course material
um content etc so i'd
i've got a community
about 1500 across new
zealand australia and
minnesota and inner circle
build a circle etc
so i do a lot of
automated automated
course generation and you
were talking about a
place to advertise i guess
or to to get more
attention um you know i
i'm just leaving you
to think about some of
that um in terms of
accreditation uh that's
fantastic but there's
a i guess agentics is
a more technical more
uh more knowledgeable
communities how i see
it there's a lot of
people who i'm a carpenter
i want to be an ai
engineer we you know
that is something that
i would expect not not
that sort of content
is what you're looking
at um and also that
particular website
hnx.org i thought it
was i just uh if you
could post the link for
me to explore a little
bit i've looked at
disco since i've become
aware of it so it's
it seems to be pretty
cool um happy to help
in any way um you know
in terms of showcasing
or even collaborating
and adding content.
I think Jed's
created a lot of good
material. Mondweep has
been doing outreach.
He's come to us and
presented to our
community. So we
absolutely are heavily
engaged and we love
AgentX and sort of the
bleeding frontier
that it's pursuing.
I'm probably in a place
to distill it because
what I do is I take
every technique and
try to build a production
-ready system and
see if I know enough,
I have enough skill to
utilize that technique
that I'm finding out
of AgentX. mostly via
Chris Barlow who are
from our side they
attend it regularly and
New Zealand the New
Zealand crew right Mark
Vincent so Ravi I just
want to I want to get
to some of the other
questions as well yeah
sorry go ahead no no
that's okay um Lorraine
you had you had your
hand up there I do
I've just put in my um
project management hat
on so doing this
certification process
might take a while i was
thinking let's consider
things like cpd right
because um that's
an easy way in and
when you go to access
companies and you say
okay we can give you some
cpd points i think
that will be useful um
i also think that we
should be thinking about
you know tldrs so
maybe like bite-sized
courses so there needs
to be some sort of what
i would call like a
personality or an angle
which means why would
people come and use
our platform to learn
and do something so
we have like different
levels so accessible
to the novice accessible
to the expert because
you have different
you know different
needs and I also think
when framing if we want
to be really really
robust so to get like a
US visa there are
certain competencies it
asks for right if you
want to get the the
highest level so maybe
we can start thinking
about those things
because it's well if you
do this possibly you
could be eligible because
we ask you maybe
you've spoken at one
event or done something
else if we're benchmarking
against well-known
criteria so it then
doesn't feel like it's
made up it feels like
it's with a purpose
so if I was putting my
instructional design
hats on those are the
things I think we
should be thinking about
there's an entire
community Lorraine that
are going back and
forth over how to do the
certification I think
Brad we can we can pass
along the invitation
link yep so I think
that's great and just
very briefly we're yeah
I would love to have
you if you could help us
out Lorraine and anyone
else, we are really
looking at catering
to all different types
of agentic engineers
from people that just
started. So quick how
-to guides, getting your
repo set up, getting
code spaces set up.
What is an MCP? What is
an MCP? Security. And
these would be perfect
for anyone that's
good at Loom. So quick
two or three minute with
a couple of screen
grabs and going through
those so that We call
it the zero-to-one
type of market, and then
going right up to the
advanced, which is
taking some clips from
what Jed and what
Reuven and others are
presenting, what Bron did
a couple weeks ago, and
just maybe showing
here's what state-of-the
-art is, and then maybe
taking a little bit
more time to show this
is how you do state
-of-the-art. So we're
looking for all kinds of
different content to
cater to different
needs. um the big thing
is we're taking our
computer background which
is we iterate so let's
let's try something
get it going the
accreditation as Lorraine
mentioned we we have to
take some time uh to
do that so really love
you to join the
community I think there's
a couple of hundred of
us that are there and
we're pretty pretty
active brainstorming
ideas and um I think
we're moving moving along
sorry and one one other
thing um so i think
in terms of like business
model right is that
where we have this we
teach you all these
things then it's like
well we're the experts
where you know if you
still get stuck we
are here and we can
support you on it so rather
than be you know a
course a bit like what
we're doing with the
website so it's like
okay we can teach you
all this stuff even when
you teach people
they're still not ready
to go but yes we can
still as a community we
can actually come
and help you in your
organization to actually
execute this as well so
i think if we if we
think of it like a almost
like we'll call it
like a lead flow or
pipeline type of thing
so i think we should be
um we should think how
we we craft this all
nice so um uh i just
want to get to the
next demos as well
thank you everybody
that's uh looking
forward to the uh to the
updates and hearing
more about how that all
evolves and brad
you'd be able to share
the links for uh and
when the next meetings
are that kind of
thing with the yeah
i'll i'll get the
link and post it image
i'll post it in the
chat thank you amazing
thank you uh so we
have nolan nolan's got
something that he
can demo for us today
hey nolan how are
you? Hey, great, Rob.
Nice to see you. How's
it going, everyone?
Okay, so share
is disabled.
Okay, yep. One second.
We're being, I'm
looking for...
Nolan, I'm glad to see
you're not driving.
Okay, are you ready
to share, Nolan?
Yeah, I'm good.
Okay, go for it.
Okay, let's
see.
You see it?
Showrunner? Yeah.
Okay, cool.
So I've been, I
mentioned this sort
of yesterday on the
call, just alluded
to some work that
I was doing where
I was thinking
about, you know, just
the capabilities
of Claude-flow and
extending it into sort
of other domains. I
think there's a lot
of sort of powerful
features that Claude-flow
exposes from like a
workflow perspective
that um you know it it
opens up the ability
for clod code and clod
flow to be used for
um sort of non-coding
purposes but you know
essentially there's
there's some coding
actually happening but i
uh i recently got
involved in this this
discord uh channel for
this this cartoon series
called uh or this
company called showrunner
and showrunner i think
just got some um an
investment from uh
amazon so they've got
like an ai platform
which is primarily um
used inside of uh discord
um actually let me
just share my change
my share here how do i
my screen.
I'm just doing
my browser. But
essentially, inside
of Discord, they have
sort of commands
and slash commands
that allow you to
tap into the various
capabilities for character
generation, scene
generation, and NLP
to sequence this stuff
together. So, um, I
use this opportunity,
uh, now I need to change
my sharing. One sec.
Where'd I go here? Sorry.
Share.
I use this opportunity to
try my hand at, uh, can
you see my
club or my, uh,
cursor here? Yep.
So I use this opportunity
to work with Claude
Flow and develop an
MCP server that helps
with script that automates
script generation
based on sort of the
characteristics of
Exit Valley. So Exit
Valley is one of the shows
where they're having
sort of community
contributors to create
these shows, and they're
going to vet those and
judge those. And if
one of your episodes
is selected, you
potentially can make some
royalties if the show
goes to air or however
it's being monetized.
So I developed this
MCP server. So if
I just open up a
new terminal here,
Google Cloud, got
my showrunner Discord.
Ideally, I want to
try and tie this
into Discord with
a bot to be able to
use the channels and
the slash commands
to generate the
content. But I have
to talk to their
admins about that.
So I've got a
prompt here.
uh use cloud flow swarm
to generate an exit
valley episode using
the showrunner mcp based
on this script i just
pasted in sort of
like a synopsis perform
deep research on relevant
news topics and
people to improve the
narrative if applicable
uh give it some guidance
someone needs to
die uh it's you know
it's very satirical and
kind of like gruesome
uh lots of swearing and
stuff like that which
is kind of fun for a
cartoon uh also add
a new variation of the
The Crypt Keeper location
scenes also generate
a comprehensive
report in Markdown
format using the generate
episode tool. So I'm
going to let that run,
and that's going to
**** away. That'll show
you sort of the next
thing that happens. So
it generates an enhanced
script in Markdown.
And then what I've
done is I just
take that and I
create a little
Claude flow
project or Claude
project here. I dump
that markdown in and
I gave it some styling
here, but I'll just
show a couple examples.
I'll put these into
the chat. They're
actually quite funny.
Where's my,
i shared one of these
is it runway three
in the background or
what's the what's the
what are they using uh
from a model perspective
um i don't know
can you guys see
discord here yep so like
here's an example oh
my god mark is that
a ******* ak-47 just
sitting there uh yeah
that's um suboptimal
who the **** leaves
that lying around
suboptimal it's a *******
murder machine mark
okay okay let's just
iterate on this no
need to escalate iterate
you're about to get
iterated into oblivion
you algorithmic
**** wait kim let's
optimize this optimize
this you caesar wannabe
piece of **** sorry
for the uh i guess that
one had some swears
and apologies for
anyone who's sensitive
to that but it's uh
it's pretty funny so
like you know inside
the channels here.
You've got different
commands, characters.
You can generate
characters.
You can generate sets.
Incredible.
So it's pretty
cool. It's kind of
weird that it's all
inside of Discord.
Like, I get kind
of why they're
doing it, but they
don't have an API.
So my next steps is I
actually reached out
to support and said,
you know, I'm an
agentic engineer. I'm
also creative and i'm
i'm interested in i'm
building this agentic
essentially script
system because i
can go out in real
like the the way that
the prompting is
working it's just going
out and doing deep
research could be could
be stuff on uh uh you
know current topics
you could schedule an
agent to go and like
get you know real
-time newsworthy
newsworthy facts and
and automate this thing
so um there's a lot a
lot to be done and i
want to see if i can
get access to there
um you remember those
political cartoons i
think it'd be funny
seeing little like just
little jokes like
people would love these
just to see yeah totally
uh here's another
one uh this was sort of
an earlier version of
one um but i gave it
some guidance to sort
of model it off of
swarms and pointed to
that uh um pointed
to that uh quad flow
documentation i haven't
read this in a while but
um it might be actually
no you know what
that's not a good this
one had some errors in
it um here's another
one you know it's
interesting we come to
the concept again so when
you're generating
there's always i love the
no filter stuff but
then like at some point
you might have to do
filtering right so
then the the system of
the prompting itself
has to it's interesting
how it all comes back
together oh yeah
well uh i think that
they're probably using
something in the back
like a model in the
background that um have
some right but you can
kind of go around some
but if you get special
access you get like
like permission to like
play with it without
it but then when you
release it you know
like my script generation
isn't putting any
profanity and whatnot
in because it's using
Anthropic under the
Clot under the hood so
it's you know it's
maybe the clean version.
It's the person, the
person itself right?
Yeah you know
with I could
I could augment
that with other
approaches but
yeah that's Discord
channel it's called
Showrunner oh
yeah we should all
share that to see
hey yeah that's that i
just recently created
a repo with 600 plus
sub agents for all kinds
of things non-coding
i just shared a link
in the chat you might
be interested in reading
over thank you thanks
so current currently
this is sorry go ahead
currently it's it's
you know i've I took
the MCP approach, but
my next step, thank
you for sharing that,
Chris, because my next
step was basically, you
know, I think just the
architecture of Claude
code in combination
with Claude is toast.
It's ******* toast.
Okay. Adam, Adam,
the big, beautiful.
There we go.
That was a quick
reaction. Good job.
Yeah. My next step
is to actually try
and build this more
into the, the cloud
flow dot cloud
folder architecture.
Cause I think I
was listening to a
podcast the other day.
I think, you know,
there's a lot of
opportunity for non
-technical people to
use cloud flow for
purposes beyond coding.
It's just, it's,
it's an incredible
orchestration framework.
That's right. That's
right. john petty was
really speaking to
that a few weeks ago
and i think there's
some that's uh it is a
big uh field as far as
multi-tool orchestration
and how that all
plays out you
should make a fun app
like you could have it
like generate you can
have a comedian go
on stage using it to
first get or just put
a button where you
activate it and talk
to it to generate
your your your theme
and then it just generates
it'll be interactive
like look how you
made us all laugh
yeah very good we
have uh we have
one more
presentation uh from
bensa but before
we get there jed
how's it going on
our androids game
progress update
it's running is the
short answer so um
now we've got androids
i don't know if
it's streaming well
but it works keeps
track of the store
it drives around
we can change the
we can change
the sprites i'm
sure and this
all i think your
volume is a little
low there jed
is it yeah a little
quiet is this any better
yes yeah cool so
anteroids is now working
um it was one prompt
i shared the prompt
earlier in the comments
and in from that
one prompt and And then
the emphasis on making
it darker and making
sure Playwright is
able to visually confirm
that it's working
was able to get the
game working for me.
And now I'm able to
revisit, what is this,
1980s, 1970s arcading?
Yeah, it's 1970s.
You need to be flying
straight up and
reappearing at the
bottom and going
as fast as you can.
Okay. So the
good news is that
everything else
works. You can
drive around. You
can shoot stuff.
so what used to
take developers
maybe weeks to
do this in 1970s
hardware took
me 20 minutes
um and 15 of those
minutes was waiting
i wonder that uh
intro to programming
class where they make
you make a game what
happens now for the
kids like they just
well it's how to
write words that's
what they have to
do write words The
interesting part
is that hackathons
now are very easy to
win, provided there
are no other
agentists also there.
Looking forward
to showing up
at the next New
York hackathon.
There it is. There
it is. That's good.
Very quickly, a thought.
What do you guys think
about how children
should be taught
programming now?
I don't know. the
short answer is they
should probably understand
what a tech stack
is and the components
of a tech stack what
goes in the front
end what goes in the
mid end what goes in
the data layer what
goes in the application
layer but the actual
syntax probably is
irrelevant i don't
write assembly there are
probably three people
in this call who
know a little bit but
definitely couldn't
write a full application
in assembly and it's
becoming increasingly
irrelevant so it's
about architecture
it seems that way i
mean i didn't even give
any specific uh design
direction to anteroids
i even misspelled
asteroids and it's
still i love the misspelling
you could type so
fast misspelling it's
so good so it was now
to be fair the use
case was simple but i'm
of the opinion children
should for those
who wish to enter this
space should focus as
much as possible on
building that muscle
learning what prompts
or what descriptions
what text is most
important to achieving the
outcome they need because
the reality is very
few people here myself
included can teach
it it is definitely
something they can learn
but i don't yet think
it is something that
is readily taught i
love that like young
people the kids like
they like question so
much so i've seen like
this toy dinosaur like
company where they
just have like a voice
you know live streaming
with it and just
imagine how annoying
like i would love to ask
50 questions right but
your parents at like
7 a.m they'll get angry
so if you just ask
it everything and you
just learn and learn
and learn like it's
just crazy that they
have that now you know
like you don't have
any children sebastian
do you no not yet not
yet okay very good
awesome i think maybe
that's why i have some
time you know but yeah
all in time no rush
um bence how you doing
i'm muted yes yeah
yeah yeah i'm here
yes sorry i'm outside
so i'm off cam
for the for the
for the minute okay
sharing is not turned
on yet okay you
ready okay it's
turned on yeah okay
showing my screen
just quickly
here um here's
the entire one
can you guys see it now
yep yep showrunner
showrunner alpha yes okay
so this is the the main
concept that one we
intro kind of is a
mental health application
so it's a reg based
on just 99 hunger
Hungarian documents
collected through 30 years,
like articles about
how to approach
cancer patients
in hospitals,
you know, and relatives
as well, you know,
how to process the
mental burden, what
you've got as a cancer
patient or relative of
a patient. And that's
working in English.
So the language
model perfectly
translates everything
which is available
only in Hungarian
to English.
But the interesting
one is the Indian.
I can't remember now
which language is this.
It's Bangla.
Yeah.
Could you go to
the homepage?
is the home page here.
What I love is
Sarvan AI, right?
What I love is,
I think, Bensi,
you discover
Sarvan AI, right?
Sarvan is a brilliant
language model.
Servant AI?
No, Sarvan.
Yeah, it's a sovereign
language model.
This is it.
Sarvan. Okay,
okay. Excellent.
And they've got orange
orange color as well
which is just coincidence
and interestingly
i shared this with
some of this so so i
said if it depends for
example if you type
there talk to me in
assamese or something
like that so assamese
is a language is my
native language so i
shared with some like
perioperative surgeons
in in assam and i said
guys what do you think
about them and they
gave some very interesting
feedback because
many decision making
happens very socially
in india so the the
cultural aspects like
lots of people want to
know and and healthcare
professionals are
overwhelmed by that
and therefore they were
like they were they
were like really
interested in things like
this which is basically
just quite accurate
like what they they
ask some questions
themselves and the
interesting part of it
is that the whole
database is in hungarian
and it was very
relevant in terms of how
the information was
given in a local language
yeah this is in
hindi yeah gosh any
language so you can see
on the exactly on the
right side that this
is a hungarian original
document all the
chunks and this is in
hindi summarized so
it's a retrieval from
have you played around
with doing photos i
noticed like it doesn't
extract photos text
but like too good
but there's probably
some cool models like
that's amazing yeah i've
got another project
for brand visual
designers a book is
processed and you don't only
get a text response
you get logos and
color palettes as a
response from the api it's
tricky mixing them
right like text and
visual what does that
dance it's go hair um
multi-model it's a
canadian oh yeah yeah so
so they are brilliant
on um yeah oh you
know with text and
images together version 4
and then version
4 embed and then
you can chunk
it up and um use
super base or
any four spreads
sorry um and
how are you the
feedback how are
people finding
the accuracy of
the translations
we haven't tested the
indian translation
accuracy yet the english
is fine and uh the
hungarian accuracy is
97 percent i i have
followed so i looked
through asimist translation
it's perfect actually
perfect really okay
it's very very good
actually so um yeah i mean
if there are anyone
from india here i think
maybe worth um getting
some feedback on
this um yeah yeah how
many dialects are there
in india sorry how
many how many dialects
or written languages
are there in in india so
this supposed 22
languages i mean if you
think about number of
languages there are like
hundreds there's
about 1500 under the
constitution of india that
are recognized or known
so ben sir on that
note just wanted to uh
talk about there's tribes
like tribal language
like south hall and
all that and their
language is not electronic
so there's currently
india's building
the models for those
languages by interviewing
capturing that and
the nuances of the
language the way they use
it it varies a lot
so they're trying to
capture all that would be
good to be able to find
a way to integrate
that because that's
where the lack of
accessibility is you know
about this social decision
making around medical
mental health or
medical nature uh so it
would be a huge uh huge
asset to i think that
kind of geography and
africa as well the
same thing is happening
in africa yeah big
opportunity for for
these guys um they are
working on with the
indian government i guess
yep
all right thanks guys
that's really
uplifting to see the
technology being
put to those kinds
of those kinds
of projects and
tools where that
can go my goodness
so we're
if there's anyone else
that would like to
show or demo we've got
a little bit of time
yeah I can go
go ahead how you doing
can you hear me all
right oh yeah can you
hear me all right yeah
there we are oh John O
'Hare yeah that's right
hi John hi how you
doing so I've literally
been throwing this code
up the stairs as people
have been talking
uh so it's in a sorry
state but I think I
think you know that's
the vibe isn't it so I'm
just going to go with
it uh because you only
live once uh and see
where I end up so the
whole of screen two
that's fine have you is
that oh wait is that
now sharing so this is
not how it's supposed
to be clear uh i'm i'm
live debushing sorry
sorry my apologies john
you got to share again
oh okay two seconds
that's not your bad
that's my bad how
is is that working
yeah yes perfect good
okay oh neat okay
cool right so what
i'm going to do
very very quickly so
this i started this
a year ago this is,
is there many coming
across LogSeek?
It's like Obsidian,
it's open source.
It's just knowledge
management. So the thing
with knowledge
management is the Spring
Force stuff is next to
useless because it's
very confusing. This
is my baby graph. This
is the public graph
that's published online.
You know, I'm into too
many things and it's
just this information
fire hose, which got
much worse with the
advent of AI. So I
started pivoting to
trying to manage my
knowledge with this. And
then I got very heavily
distracted 12 months
ago with this. So my
background is in human
-scale telepresence,
so large-scale
visualization systems,
holodecks-type stuff,
which is the things that
you see there, in
which there was a bit
of kind of data
manipulation in 3D spaces.
So it's mixed reality,
telecollaboration,
working with other
people, working with now
AI agents, I mean, so
distributed systems,
kind of protocol-level
stuff. uh it's just
very it's a wild moment
right so i i started
trying to put together
a a way to deal with
the um the incoming
firehose of stuff just
for my own information
management purposes so
this i mean 12 months
ago just vibe coding
whatever you want to
call it at the time
managed to stand up
listening javascript straight
away this just takes
the ***** the data
off github re-springifies
it turns it into
something that's crockable
in a 3d space and it
just worked straight
away in ar and i was
like well that's very
gratifying and i thought
well why don't i do
it multi-user in rust
that was a mistake because
i'm not a programmer
and i didn't realize
how difficult that
was going to be so i i'm
now a hundred thousand
mines of code 12
months later kind of
become a labor of love
in a way uh and it's all
you know because because
code code it's all
very well documented
and stuff the the system
now is uh spring
solving on a gpu uh for
multi-user so it's
got a single source of
truth so you can connect
multiple clients to
it it pulls the information
from github which
is sourced in the log
seek stuff that you
saw which is the
knowledge management stuff
and then it re-indexes
it through rag and
microsoft graph rag and
uh other things it has
a voice-to-voice layer
it has a obviously
it's got the agency
layer and this is what
really what the crux of
the of the demo here is
you know there's all
kinds of interfaces and
off and that's all
well and good but the
thing that i've suddenly
started to add in
which has made everything
false multiplayer 10
times as good is the
is the the thing that
just suddenly makes it
you know the the can
do anything jarvis
knockoff so i mean i'm just
going to type the word
test in here because
we don't have time for
that but so you can
you can spawn up a hive
mind uh on the data
that you have access
to here and then it
brings in all of the
uh the monitoring stuff
which is based on agentic
flow uh and i'm not
really sure how any
of that works because
this is how it goes
with this stuff you know
um i was trying to
use a much cleaner mcp
interface over the over
the existing port because
everything obviously
is dockerized and
speaking to everybody
else's points about
getting these things to
do anything i've been
getting it to do things
that are right outside
the domain of um of
coding so like a full
air circuit board for a
uh preamp like a preamp
with a bit of character
which somebody
told me to make so it
created the circuit board
in my docker i have
all the latex tools all
the rust tools all
the usual tools that
you'd have all the
electronics tools uh all of
the um just whatever
you can think of that
you can digitize slap
it in the docker connect
it to the visualization
system voice voice
go and make a thing
deliver the thing when
it's done and there's
a this is kind of the
opportunity that i'm
seeing when i'm talking
to other people here
is that they want to
see something that's
a bit Like Andy, they
really don't want to
look at a CLI interface.
And showing people
that it spits out a
circuit board with four
layers of checked code
and a bill of materials,
and it's $120 for
this preamp, it's just
wild. It's unscrewing
people's heads. It's
passing the circuit
analysis checklists.
It's giving you a
bill of materials. It's
a four-layer board.
My first degree was
electronics, and
since I've been doing
these things, So
I've been kind of
ranging around all of
these different
specialisms for years.
And suddenly all of
them can just be stuck
in a Docker container
and you can stick a
knockoff Java's
interface on it. And, you
know, how much are you
actually getting out
of the performance
optimizer telling you
how much CPU it's using
at a given moment?
Not a great deal,
but people do feel
strangely comforted by
this stuff. And so that's
good. So this is
working through my space
mouse, which is why
it's kind of woozing
around a little bit.
but all of these things
are parts of my
information corpus and
they'd normally be
spread out in a much more
attractive way but
all of this works in
AR and all of this
works multi-user and all
of it has infinitely
tunable everything.
But the main thing
is that it voice-to
-voice connects to
ruv-swarm on the back
end now and can just
do anything, connect
to a robot, print
out a circuit board,
do whatever. It's
wild. So exciting.
And you say you're
not a programmer.
No, not at all. I've
never really touched
code. It's 100,000 lines
of Rust, Cuda, PTX,
TypeScript, Docker,
Docker, Docker, Docker.
I've got 12 Dockers
here now because there's
the, you know, there's
the Whisper. It's
all local as well. All
this will run local.
So there's Whisper.
There's the local
infancy. There's the local
text-to-speech, speech
-to-text, the RAG
stuff, the Swarm stuff,
the interface stuff,
Docker, Docker, Docker,
Docker, all the way
down. And just keeping
that secure, it's
very hard to get Claude's
flow to talk across
Docker boundaries
into other code bases.
It gets very confused
about where it is.
So there's been
a lot of kind of
struggling with the
container side of
things because it's
all local. And I
think this is just
partly my ignorance.
That is by design.
Yeah, no, totally. I
mean, I have a box that
I lock it in with as
many tools as it could
wish to have so that
it doesn't get greedy
and try to get out
of the box. So everything
that is, you know,
it's a very big Docker
container. It has
all the electronic
stuff. Oh, yeah, GIS
stuff. So it'll, you
know, go and make a 3D,
go and find that bit
of the Lake District
into a 3D model straight
off. And it connects
to Blender and it
connects to rUv. And it
connects to, so, you know,
I've had it the other
day make a 100 shuriken
swarm in Blender
over MPTP from its own
Docker into another
Docker that it can get
screenshots from. and
it's just whatever you
ask for it's just mind
-blowing but then yeah
the obviously the
main thing is putting
this interface on it so
that people can feel
like they have some kind
of enfranchised interface
where they understand
what's going on and
that's not necessarily
true but you know
paul roddick would
probably love this
he's been working on
visualizations of the cloud
flows forums as well um
that so if i'm if i'm
hearing you correctly
john uh voice-to-voice
interaction and if
i want to describe an
idea for uh a new piece
of um musical circuitry
yeah that uh this
system has enough
understanding of the
requirements and and inner
component interactions
and rule sets that it
can actually output in
a way no it's just it's
just i think people
aren't people who are
coders are not noticing
how far it can push
itself it would happily
go and download all
these things if you
say go and download all
of the toolkits that
are used for this stuff
the the gis stuff i
was training somebody
at the university where
i've been doing some
work recently and i'd
already because i knew
the gis stuff because
of you know previous
years doing doing
immersive vr stuff i
i'd already gone and got
qgis and and connected
up the mtp and connected
to blender and done
it all the hard way he
literally just asked
claude to get him some
data for the local
area. And it went and
got QGIS and stood up
the MCP server and did
the things. Because,
of course, that's what
it does. It's just that
we think in a... Well,
I'm including myself
in programmers here.
The more constrained
your language is and
the less flexible
your language is, I
think the less that
you allow it in a way
to go and find, to
explore these things.
I didn't... I haven't...
I mean, my first
degree was electronics,
but I haven't
looked at the kind
of formal validation
for circuit board
stuff for years. I
just said, just go
and find whatever is
the current thing,
download it, put it
into the Docker. You've
got pseudo access,
go for your life.
And it pulled in a
load of stuff that's
command line based.
And that stuff did its
own internal checks.
But I've since looked
at the board and
the board is fine. The
bill of materials is
fine. I had to do
a bit of massaging
afterwards. But it's,
you know, I've run it by
the guy who asked me
to make the preamp and
it looks fine, right?
Whether it is or not,
another matter. But
it's all, they're all
the kind of boilerplate
chips and specs
and all that stuff.
a bit of character I
don't know what that
means so whether whether
or not whether or not
you choose to build
it or not but you
know I think there's a
there's an iterative
process with these
things and I think this
is this applies to is
it GIS is it space
science is it molecular
biology I don't know
how far you can get
just asking it to
go and download the
current crop of tools
as long as you're in a
safe environment
phenomenal is this is a
private tool is it open
source oh no no it's
I'll push the GitHub
up into the chat now.
What was that
last? You said you
had a big sack
and then some
of the tools of
a breakthrough,
your voice dropped off.
Well, in terms of
the tools that are
in, so that's also,
I mean, my container
is here and you
can see what's in
it. It takes so long
to compile because,
I mean, it's a
multi-layer Docker.
It's taken me weeks.
It's probably taken
me longer than
anything else that I've
done. but of course
it's got full latex
in it because it
turns out if you give
Claude Flo
full latex then
it suddenly it can write
hundreds and hundreds
of pages of document
you know go make a bid
for an internationally
significant theme
park in the north
of England What does
full latex mean?
Latex is the kind
of the academic
coding markup language
from the 1970s
that academics use
in order to change
Mathematical formula
yeah yeah yeah exactly
it's an old and very
well established but
also hideously stupid
and annoying markup
language with it does
yeah i mean it does it
does as you say it
does it does equations
it's very good equations
but all of the archive
archive the website
with the academic
papers on that's all
latex these these llms
have chewed through a
lot of latex they all
talk a lot of latex so
that they they assume
an academic voice
when you make them use
latex so you don't end
up with the the default
boilerplate voice
from them so if you
if you force everything
through the lens of
latex and make it
recompile and recompile
and say look over here
is the over here is
the branding material
in the elsewhere in the
docker it comes back
and it's 500 pages
doesn't it doesn't
matter it'll do it it'll
talk to itself for hours
and it's fascinating
to so the knowledge
management side of
things the everything
else side of things the
you know go and go and
research this electronics
whatever else uh
side of things that
isn't coding is the bit
that I'm trying to kind
of ease out into and
I'm finding most of
the successes are coming
from just giving it
its head and just making
sure that it's nice
and secure and doesn't
want for more tools
and then it's fine
so yeah I can put
the links in there
Do you have to give
it guidance to tell
it to use latex?
So I let it know in the
docker that I have
it in I append it to
the Claude MD saying
you've got a full latex
environment that's
the preferred way of
uh of making files
it it's better to use
markdown uh internally
for itself you
don't want it running
off it it can spend
hours trying to trying
to get it gets as lost
as any academic in
latex it's a it's a
real pain in the ***
you know it'll be
integrating it and
deintegrating it forever
and trying to sort out
the indexes and the
citations and the
bibliography and all this
stuff so you you want
to keep it mainly in
markdown until you
get to the point where
you've got what you need
and then you just kind
of push it off into
latex and say this is
your preferred this is
your environment you
have all the tools
you need if you don't
you've got pseudo so
it's fine that's what i'm
trying to do with the
researching like the
filtering because like
it's going to go through
the web and find
all this other stuff
but also if you have
multiple at the same time
doing it and then like
having them talk to
each other to like
filter or like all these
because that's what the
thing is like you're
saying you got them
doing so much things
at the same time and
then how do you know if
they're all when they're
doing at the same
time they have to kind
of work together it's
hard to do is that
interface so hopefully
hopefully when you're
in ar with other people
because it is multi
-user hopefully somebody
can see what's going
on i have absolutely
no idea how to keep up
with this stuff it's
it's hard enough simply
keeping the docker
environment together
i don't know i think
this is so cool to
research because like even
with the google's genie
thing with the video
generating it must be
some sort of mathematical
or like like a like
an autonomous kind
of like program that
somehow can keep like
uh order or be correct
like and just validate
it like a verifiable
yeah i mean i'm so
fascinated by verifiable
our brain is too
yeah there's there's
a real there's a
there's a real stretch
goal around this stuff
for verifiable uh
compute and stuff that
that is mathematically
this stuff does exist
i can't just really
hard and it's just a
dead easy job because
it's a grind job but
whether or not people
want to be i mean
now that the cost of
this just falling so
fast to have an agent
that's over there
saying, can I make this
into a verifiable thing
that has no security
holes because this
is passing all of
those classic academic
checks. I mean, it's
another thing to add
into the stack, isn't
it? It's fascinating.
It just goes all
together. That's so cool.
John, question
around Latex stuff.
Have you tried
to write stuff
using Latex? Does
it do it well?
Yeah, that's what
I'm saying. I've done
multiple 500-page
documents with it in one
shot. like we just
went out my friends who
haven't seen for ages
got drunk uh said said
just give me give me
give me a thing that's
a problem in two
lines and 550 pages
later it designed a
bunch of course material
and done a load of
research written some
python scripts because
of course they have
been it went and got
all the ceos of the
of the things then it
compiled it in that
images that's what we
should do to awesome
i'm going to do that
to the research thing
and then that's what
i want to do train it
together like train
it and like just see
what how we could it'd
be cool to see what
it comes up with yeah
yeah yeah everything
everything you do with
this stuff it spits
out cool stuff unless
it doesn't unless it
just gets lost but
it's like i mean yeah
that's what the logo
for the infinity feels
great because we're
just like in a black
hole we're just yeah
all just i mean it just
just i honestly i'm
spending most of the time
just trying to lock
down the docker more
it's it's it's just so
and the docker's docker
communications and
this is where i start
to get a bit out of
my depth because once
it once it once it's
out of the context that
you're in once it's
locked in its box you're
like i don't know
how to help i'm gonna
have to fall back on
gemini i'm so sorry i
wonder if it does have
a robust networking
stack john so it is
possible to chain multiple
docker containers so
yeah i've got the same
i've got i've got a
private docker network
so that's got all 12
on it and it is aware
of them and it can
see it and that's fine
so i've got it
constrained into a docker
network on my local pc
and this is the because
I'm leveraging a lot
of GPU, unlike the...
I've been considering
going out and using
the dev containers
that you're on, because
it's clearly a better
idea in a sustainable
way for this stuff.
But then the other
path is just to stuff
loads of kind of
high-bandwidth taxing
tools into a very capable
GPU-connected Docker
and just stand it
all up in their old
bunch of Dockers, which
is just kind of the other
route on this stuff.
And that's where most
of the personal tax
is coming for me, is
just trying to keep that
uh kind of web of
dockers going in a way
where stuff doesn't
break all the time which
is why i was fighting
it today to try and get
it going again but i
mean it's fine it's
just it's just the next
thing to do really what
i need to do is get
it just good enough so
i can start solving
real problems with it i
would then suggest
that you point your
collection of docker
containers powered by cloud
code to research
declarative infrastructure
yeah yeah yeah and
i'd like to see this
project combined with
that with whatever braun
is building that post
that he had or that
message that he had in
the whatsapp group where
he said he's like
passed to the other side
like the the whole
the whole agentics one
so all of the all the
telemetrics that comes
out that was in the
one that uh was was
demonstrated in the in
the uh in the branch that
had all the telemetrics
and there's a lot
of it um that's all in
this one in principle
so i've ended up
standing up in another
server inside the swarm
container because it
just i couldn't get
enough out over the mcp
channel and now i
literally have no idea
what's going on in
that corner of the code
base now it's it it's
it's working but i don't
know i don't know how
much uh telemetrics
is coming over it seems
like there's quite
a lot of it and you saw
when i when i zoomed
into the green blob
and that's just like
that's just the hive
mind instance that it
had stood up for that
particular thing and
i've got a suspicion
that you were looking at
mock data there because
that in any given
moment the whole thing
is either working or
not working you know
like a jagged frontier
of horrible unknowns
but i've seen it i've
seen it pulling stuff
live and i've seen it
pulling quite a lot
of stuff live i just
don't know what sometimes
it'll get there i
have a question do you
what do you ever think
of naming it or want to
ask it it's currently
****** jarvis because
it's It's obviously
***** garbage. I don't
know what to say.
It has other
names. But I think,
I mean, the way
it is, because,
I mean, as you
can see on the,
there's the bland
name on the GitHub,
which is ARAI, whatever,
logs it contend.
And then just, I have
a bunch of different
website endpoints
because it receives
Cloudflare. So you can
just, you just, the
dev endpoint that
I've got running here,
you just recompile
it the other way
and it just takes
in the Cloudflare
tunnel and it just
stands up straight
away on the web.
So it's dead
easy to run and
push out to the web.
And then it's got Nostro
authentication. so
you can have different
levels of privileges
and the whole thing
will distribute as well
so i've got uh i've
got local containers
and distributed uh
stacks as well so most of
the work that i do is
on uh distributed uh
protocol all that other
stuff so that that
stuff kind of uh is to
come uh i've been kind
of working on the
core bit in the middle
so every time every
time i stand up a new
front name so which is
fine you know so name
it per whatever the
whatever the domain is so
this is the domain
of the knowledge base
that i have been
accumulating that i was
fighting to deal with in
the hailstorm of ai and
that's my knowledge
base and all my rag
stuff and whatever books
i load into it but it
could just be that it's
just a legal interface
and it's just a
medical interface or
it's just it's just
whatever your local domain
corpus is for whatever
company you are
which is where it starts
to feel like it might
be a useful product
because you've got you've
got a couple of you
stood in there and
what what i didn't even
say is that the spring
system that you can see
there is is designed
uh with springs and
weights so you grab
hold of the nodes
and depending on the
depending on the metadata
in the the connections
and the weights of
the metadata for those
nodes which are the
the information buckets
you get um you get uh
as you drag it around
it drags other stuff
around at differential
speeds which allows
you to leverage this is
kind of my research
background which allows
you to leverage your
ocular system to see
what moves the most so
you can see what the
connections are using
the bit of your brain
that's good at that
stuff you know the spring
and a spring and a
ball thing so you can
you can go in there
and very intuitively
drag stuff about and
say that's not important
because it's not really
moving anything and
that's kind of why these
knowledge why these
spring systems exist
there's a whole load
of research that i've
got to go and bring
in later to to make that
more visually appealing
and less like it's
just a big ball of
string but all that
stuff already exists in
academia so that's fine
i can do that we've
done it before but the
whole point is that
you can go in there and
and leverage not only
your voice and and and
kind of the proximity
and the spatial
dynamics of other people
in the space with you
but also the information
should be spatialized
in such a way and
also physically embodied
in such a way that
you can figure out
what's going on without
particularly digging
into it but then of
course if you double
kick it you can dig into
it as well or ask it
about it or ask it to
update it honestly this
is such a cool engineer
like you actually
built like such a cool
like system all around
like that's actually
it's really interesting
i love learning from
you more it's just like
that's awesome like i
i love how you deeply
composed together like
you know the systems
between the indexing
and all the different
like you're saying the
structure is not visually
uh the back end uh
different deployments
it's just every time
i knew every time a
brilliant new thing turns
up i just kind of
smash it in on the side
and then my attention
wavers and i wander off
but all of the yeah
yeah totally this is
it and there's so much
there's so much candy
about you can just you
can smash it together
and as long as long as
it as long as you have
like a through line
and like a golden path
that allows you to
see that you're not
wasting your own time
with it like rag is a pain
in the *** but but at
the same time you know
sometimes you do want
to have a local corpus
of microsoft graph
rag organized uh cross
-linked books that
only pertain to your
organization so there is
probably a through line
there am i using it now
of course i'm not am
i am i looking at anything
am i even updating
my own data which
is the thing i was
supposed to be doing in
the first place no i'm
not i'm just wrestling
with docker containers
anyway i've talked
for ages i'm sorry for
the folks not familiar
somebody mentioned in
the comments there that
it's latex l-a space
t-e-k no it's right it
is t-e-x yes yep okay
and it's it has weird
capitalization because
of course latex yeah
yeah yeah so if you
if you look at if you
look at uh archive you
know we've all we've all
read papers on archive
.com you can only
submit those as latex
and then it compiles
it on the back end to
produce the pdfs so it's
latex spits out pdfs
and that is all it was
ever supposed to do
but it's like it's 1970s
vintage it's proper
***** as you'd expect
uh you know if you want
to put a pound sign in
good luck and i wrote
my phd in it which
was just the wrong
decision massive no thank
you yeah having done
that i'm like oh it's
cool seeing you have so
much fun with it you
know it's worth it like
yeah it's great it's
really good and it's
nice to present as well
so thank you for the
opportunity please do
like a little page doc
for us to like why
not like you know like
apply it ourselves we're
learning a little bit
more i'd love yeah
well i mean if you so
in principle the
documentation is almost up to
date so if you have a
look at the link the
link that i put in
there uh that what i've
had to make sure is
that is that it gets to
100 000 it doesn't even
fit in the gemini big
contacts window now
so so i'm starting to
lose the ability to rock
it in one go no matter
what tool i use at
the minute so the the
documentation should be
completely up to date
and some of the some
of the mermaid diagrams
code have slipped
behind a bit while the
debug goes as i go
along so if you want to
dig into the the that
container or the container
that i've made with
all of the different
tools in it then those
are the two links that
i put up there so
you can have a have a
kick around and yeah
just just do by all means
do ask them in the
discord and the whatsapp
super john thank you
really fascinating there
was a bunch of folks
working on different
visualizations but
uh that one is uh is
fully integrated right
with with everything
else which is fascinating
um uh nick i saw
that you had your hand
up there how are you
nick i was just uh
some applause for for
john's effort there
right thank you i haven't
worked with uh personally
i haven't worked
much with obsidian
yet so that being as a
base uh that sort of
grew out of that's yeah
that's really fascinating
we're past the
hour and uh i could
go for a few minutes
yet if there's uh Some
topics or, funny, I
haven't heard anybody
talk about GPT-5 yet.
Do folks have
some observations?
Have you plugged
them into your tool
set? I just did
something this morning.
I asked it to create
an app to compare terms
of service and privacy
terms for AI-based
systems so when you log
on and it says terms
of service and privacy
everybody just clicks
through because it's
too complicated to
read and the tough things
to watch for and what
you ought to watch
out for. It gave me
back a useful app, but
I didn't copy it and
paste it in. Well, it
supposedly paste it in.
Yeah, I got an
echo of some kind.
Is that still going
on? I'm going to
mute some other
folks, just make sure
we're okay. Okay.
Sorry, John, continue.
And then I asked it
to compare loom and i
think firefly and it
came out with some
interesting stuff but i
asked it to do it from
its interface so i think
it just went out and
compared them kind of
sequential sequentially
as as prompts but
i'll play with it a
little bit more and
maybe uh sell what i've
got afterwards because
i think these are the
kind of apps that i'm
interested in i'm not
interested in getting
any kind of certification
at my age but i am
interested in being
helpful to people
and i think in this
organization, I come back
to who are we serving?
That's right. And
if we're going to
have a PhD level kind
of a thing and go
to a university
model, I understand we
all come from our
backgrounds. I just
don't know who that
serves, except maybe
some big tech
companies, ultimately.
And so it becomes a
hiring and an employment
agency, which I think
for a lot of people
is just not interesting
at all. They want
to get the information
so that they can save
time in their lives
and be creative without
having to learn coding.
So I'll come back
to my bandwagon, who
do we serve and why?
And another point that
I'd like to raise,
which is somewhat
troublesome to me, and I'm
not going to name
names, is that there is
some question about dues
that have been paid.
And people are
wondering, where is that
money? I would sure
feel a whole lot
better being involved
in the organization
if there were some
accounting done
of that. And rather
quickly, I think
if you're going to
go to people and ask
them to donate money
as a nonprofit,
and it comes out
that you took money
and nobody knows
where it is, I think
you got a credibility
problem and you
might have a much
more serious problem.
So I would make that
priority number one.
Absolutely. So there is
a board of directors.
We do have a treasurer.
That treasurer is
Brad Ross. We have a
volunteer who manages
all the accounting.
That is Eric. He's a
chartered accountant.
The management meetings
on Mondays at 12 o
'clock are open. So all
members are welcome to
attend. And all board
meetings are also open.
And everyone is welcome
to attend. So it's
full transparency all
the money is accounted
for it's all set
good good the whole
thing is professionally
structured wonderful
yes and as we port to
the new membership site
um that's i mean the
whole intention there
is for all of us to be
able to contribute to
ensure that there's
as much value coming
in collectively because
it's the it's the
strength of the size of
the membership that
can contribute across
all spectrums because i
totally agree with you
john i want uh i
would love to have a
browser extension that
checks and and and
highlights anything
crazy in user agreements
before i click yes if i
have a quick way to scan
all those things and
compare them to best
practices I think
that's one of the really
great, truly powerful
aspects of artificial
intelligence today is
that it gives us the
ability of transparency
and accountability
because we can pierce
through these horrific
documents written
purposely to obfuscate,
right? And all of
that fades away and
we can bring out
those things that
are really egregious,
both in law and
legislation and
also in, you know,
day-to-day consumer
interactions where
we don't realize
we've signed away all
of our data for the
privilege of creating
a document more
comfortably. So I agree
completely, John.
I think you're on
all notes. Your
precision is excellent.
Well, as soon as
I got something
working with Claude
Flow or Claude itself,
I'll come back and
demonstrate it.
Well,
anecdotally, I booked
a flight some time
ago with not a first
-year airline. And in
their terms of service,
they mentioned,
or the contract of
carriage, they did not
guarantee that the
plane was airworthy.
I have no idea if
there's any actual
precedent or if
that clause is even
defensible. But I've
noticed a number of
operators are starting
to use that kind of
language, I assume,
to avoid liability.
That's crazy. So
I agree, John,
this sort of work
is necessary.
And it's always
fun to see what
other attempted
carve-outs exist
so we can make
fun of them later.
Well, there is the
whole concept of
lawfare, which
is the oppression
of peoples and
democratic processes
through contracts
and agreements.
I shared that in my
community, a data
center was going,
three data centers were
planned and actually
had been approved.
And all under the guise
of NDAs, we weren't
even allowed to
know the name of the
company that was behind
it. And fortunately,
it had to go to
another entity for
final approval. And
the community just was
up in arms when it
came out. And that was
defeated unanimously.
So these are
important, important
processes that have to be.
There's got to be a
balance back between
wealth and power and
government and the
person who is is
being constrained. It
just has to be. So
that's what I'm up to.
We appreciate
it. Fantastic.
your discussion gave
me an idea for nolan
you know nolan you
showed us the um i forget
the name the lovely
cartoons right so if
you find i think we
can generate original
content by taking these
uh contract clauses
like the carriage
airworthiness etc and
creating lovely lovely
jokes and that's a great
idea let's do it
that'd be very nice we
create a channel on this
yeah everyone shares
it and then like it's
just fun and it's
true it's like a like
the political memes
before the newspapers
before it was like you
know a fun message that
everybody shared not
too harsh but it was
a theme that we all
shared and that would
probably be a nice
like way to translate
your your spirit of what
you your your goal
is which is very nice
yeah one more thing
i think based on what
john mentioned it also
gives me the idea because
it help us in pushing
our whole donation
sponsorship thing so
maybe I think we should
consider showcasing
like how and where like
I know this is all
that content and I have
seen it but can we
maybe create an app to
make it really public
so it's all the spending
etc so we can use that
as leverage to say
we are doing it we
want to do more of this
and therefore we want
this so it's like it
becomes real like in
terms of rather than
explaining to the people
because people ask me
all the time like what
is a gentix when i go
and ask for sponsorship
and all this stuff
i think we can just push
it out there and just
do a community outreach
through linkedin
or whatever to do more
of what we are already
doing and show the
evidence of how the
funding has been used
and what value it has
created etc yeah i think
that i mean i think
well two things um
absolutely so that's a
conversation to have at
the management level and
at the board level and
with council in terms
of exactly how that's
properly conducted.
And then I think the
emphasis really is on
the foundation and all
of us collectively to
put our efforts into
ensuring that that
community.agentix.org
site has a stream of
populated value and
everybody is, we have that
structure is unfolding
beyond just the lives
the lives are i mean
these are wonderful
it's the heart of it
we all get a chance to
talk face to face um
but as john was saying
serving the public at
large uh is also about
non-technical non
-engineering uh skill sets
and coming into contact
with the technology
so non-technologists can
unleash more creativity
and insight so it's
a it's a combination
of the too, certainly.
So again, just so
everybody is aware, on
Mondays at 12 noon is
our general management
meetings. In the
evenings on Tuesday
is when 8 p.m. Eastern
Standard Time is when
we meet primarily with
Asian chapters and
members that are in Japan,
Malaysia, New Zealand,
what have you. So to
help orchestrate and
support their efforts.
But those are open and
everybody is welcome
and uh they're all
recorded so there's um
uh yep that's the spirit
of the entire thing
i have one one announcement
to share broadly
speaking so we have
had confirmation i
will do the formal
logistic confirmation on
monday that we i'm
sorry can you turn your
volume up a bit or a
little closer to the mic
is it any better now
i'm on my phone sorry
about it i just wanted
to mentioned that
we we have had confirmation
as of yesterday
that we would be speaking
at the CISO London
summit as a keynote
and also probably
conduct some workshops
it's in October and event
that Joe, Mark,
Dirigik and I have been
working on so that's
now confirmed I and I
am going to work on
the logistics so again
it's a security focused
session I'm happy to
say share the synopsis
of what we are thinking
of and if members
have thoughts would
like to contribute
to that please do so
obviously we'll acknowledge
the contributions
in those workshops and
sessions and if anyone
is attending around
the uk area the cso
london tlc summit um
then please let me know
we can coordinate efforts
wonderful in october
excellent thank you
mandri well we're
closing up on the hour
any uh uh last i think
folks are asking for
the meeting links uh
rob so if we can get
oh yeah absolutely
this is you know martin
is the best one to
share these because when
i share them they're
always difficult
getting uh uh i had a
question yeah um i
remember it was mentioned
about the nvidia maybe
try to help the the
agency with some gpu
power is this something
that will be happening
or if it's happening
how are we going to
share that power to
the community or is
it i know it's a long
project question but i
think it was i haven't
heard anything on it
yet jose okay and i
mean that would be that
would be nirvana right
yeah exactly we can
get access to some
you know that's the
problem that's the problem
with uh flow now i'm
thinking in nirvana
every day yeah that's
right yeah um and
certainly that's that
that's the goal i know
uh those conversations
are ongoing so as soon
as there's something
concrete or tangible
then for sure all
righty thanks yep so i
just i just shared
the zoom link for the
mondays at 12 because
the calendar link is
through the eugenics
.org calendar you got to
subscribe to that
calendar right so you and
you can subscribe to
that calendar but by
the time we get through
those nuances you're
squarely in martin's
domain not mine right
my day's 12 o'clock
eastern standard time
all righty
everybody uh so jed
your asteroids
game still playing
well done i already
took it down but did
you zero shot it was
a one shot i had to
write the prompt but oh
yeah created the game
it was a browser
browser-based game work
with my keyboard i
could probably prompted
to work using your
phone's accelerometer
so instead of swiping
on your phone you
have to rotate the
whole device um it might
be fun i don't know
if that's worthwhile
sure but i think
we'll close up in the
next three minutes
or so unless someone
has any questions
and then move over
to the discord if
anyone wants to follow
up on those
conversations isn't there
yeah very good it was
very fun everybody
thank you everybody
for hanging out
have a good rest
everyone take
care okay guys
good weekend bye