here we are we're on
august 15th time's
flying by we've got
a great uh episode
show what do we
call this anyway i'm
not even sure the ai
hacker space august
15th we we're excited
today we've got
a a variety of
presentations um lined
up uh rob who do we
have lined up today
We've got a few
folks, really great.
First of all,
Brad Ross, long
-time OG member. He's
going to be sharing
with us something
he calls Dr. House.
It's a CLI agent
for brutally honest
code reviews.
Oh, nice. Yeah,
it should be good.
And then Sandro,
Sandro Pasquale.
Sandro is an
AI native web
developer, and
he's got a system.
It's sort of like an
upgraded GPT UI for
egenic workflows.
So I'm curious to
see what he's cooked
up there. So that
should be nice. And
then, of course, we
have Ken Carter, who's
joining us today.
Wonderful to
have you with us
there, Ken. Really
great to be here.
Yeah, we'll get to
Ken in a few minutes,
but Ken is helping us
form our legal committee,
Gentex Legal. He's got
a massive background
in the space, working
at some of the
biggest tech companies
on the planet in some
of the biggest battles,
I might add. so
it'll be exciting to
sort of dig into that a
little bit but let's
start with the the
interesting news of the
day of of course a little
bit of a battle this
week for me in in
i think it was um paul
graham of y combinator
came out earlier uh
i think it was like
monday and said basically
he met with someone
who was creating an
amazing 10 000 lines
of code in a day which
you know for For the
folks who watch us on
these weekly calls,
10,000 is like nothing.
We do that in like
10 minutes on one of
these coding sessions.
And so that opened up
debate. And basically
half the world and
all the sort of AI
pundits that don't know
what they're doing came
up and said that
it's spaghetti, it's
garbage, anything that
is at that scale can't
be good was the sort
of discussion that was
had. Like there's some
kind of like linear
or exponential component
to code that says
that if you create
five lines of AI code,
it's good. But if you
create 10,000 lines
or 100,000 lines of
code, somehow it's bad.
And I countered that
in the sense that
when you look at
like a human creating
code, let's say
you're hired at
Microsoft and you're
working on the Windows
operating system.
You're not looking
at 10 million lines
of Windows code.
Now, you could, I guess.
You're never going
to understand all of
it. You're working
on a very small, modular
part of that code
base and making sure
that whatever it is
that you're doing is
optimal for the job
and the problem in
which you're solving.
When you look at
these agentic systems
and agentic coding
systems, you're not
going and saying, tell
me everything about
Linux and give me
every line of code
and then I'm going
to figure out how to
insert my particular
addition to Linux.
And that's probably
a bad example because
Linus would probably
not want AI-generated
code but regardless
you're working on small
parts of it so this idea
that there's somehow
some you know you know
linear more is worse
sort of approach just
doesn't make sense and
structure also is
really important and if
you look at a lot of
things that we're showing
you it's all about
the process it's all
about the architecture
it's all about the
guidance that's why you
need identic engineers
and so the rant and
i'm sure a few folks
will probably join and
tell me i'm full of
it. But the idea that
you're working on everything
all at once, it
doesn't work when it
comes to these types
of coding environments.
So that was the debate.
That's where I stand.
I'm obviously extremely
biased towards
the development process.
So let's take a look
at some of the stuff
that we did this week.
Yesterday, for those
who didn't have the
chance to jump in and
see our live coding
session, the Vibecast,
always trying to build
the craziest things I
could possibly build.
And thanks to, I'm
not sure who it was,
but I know Bents sent
me a link to some
research about whether
or not you could
use, and this was
legitimate research
that was done out of
a university somewhere
that basically
looked at whether or
not you could detect
alien signatures in
terms of communication,
like actual
extraterrestrials,
using language models.
And if, Bents, if
you're on, let me know.
What was the takeaway
from that uh yeah it
was interesting because
i totally forgotten
i asked claude.ai two
years ago about this
i don't know where the
inspiration is coming
from but you know
this can come from my
brain as well and how
aliens communicate
via language models why
not and then strangely
i found one guy who
had a research paper
in the same topic but
it's not peer reviewed
so it's just speculation
But there are
there is a very niche
kind of researchers who
are doing this, trying
to find and hunt
down signs from
another planet or other
intelligence that are
messaging us through AI.
And maybe they want
to get in contact or
maybe they just research
on us. We don't know.
So there are practical
applications here
beyond looking for
extraterrestrials. So this
is also looking for
anomalies within the
structure of a language
model. You could use it
for guardrails. You
could use it for lots
of, you know, less
crazy things. But this
particular application
was interesting. So we
built this yesterday
in an hour and a half,
and I wanted to do two
things. I want to show,
well, I want to learn
about Go. So this is
using essentially a Go
-based middleware that
will do analysis of,
you know, enthalpy,
linguistic pattern
recognition, cryptographic
analysis, temporal
correlation, all kinds of
crazy things. So you
can take a look at
this. I'll pop it in the
chat here for you guys.
And this is, I don't
know the exact number,
but I think it's
somewhere around 20,000
lines of code, both
front-end and back-end.
So, you know, 20,000
lines, it's functional.
this is what you can
do in roughly an hour
and a half for those
that don't believe
anything is possible
you can dig through it
and just as an fyi the
you'll need to vibe
the uh the front end
a little bit so i i
only i stopped after
an hour and a half so
if you want this to
connect to the back
end you're going to
have to point Claude at
it so it's not quite
done but the the
interfaces are are almost
there again i spent
this is an hour and a
half so if you go to
the documentation
folder, you'll see here
that there's a bunch
of information on how
to use it. There's
the CLI integrations.
I don't think this is
a startup, but if it
was a startup two years
ago, this would have
taken quite a bit of
time to do. This is
not an hour and a half
worth of work. You can
also see that it's
mobile friendly, all that
kind of stuff. It's
a fun little project.
I'll give you a link
to that as well.
But that opens up
another interesting
point. There's been a
lot of discussion around
this idea of, and
this is also Paul
Graham, I think, the
idea of a billion-dollar
startup that is run
by a small group or
maybe a single
individual. And I'm not
saying that this is
going to make a billion
dollars or anything,
but it got me
thinking, what does a
billion-dollar individual
startup actually look
like and how would
it actually operate?
Like what would it
do? Would it be SaaS?
Would it be some
kind of self-service
software that you
could sort of point at
and operate against?
This has been particularly
lucrative for me
anyway. And this is
something I built actually
on a whim after one
of our AI hackerspaces
where people are like,
we should do some
kind of neural trading
system based on some
of the work that I
was doing around roof
swarm and other sort
of micro neural nets so
that's what that's
what i ended up doing
about a month and a half
ago and it's actually
done particularly well
and i've been swamped
with with people who
want to basically
deploy these kind of
neural networks and in
the most simple terms
what this system does
is it allows you to
basically point clod or
in clod flow at a sort
of pre-built series
of trading components
right so you see here
that i've got various
types of components
here like simulation of
trades portfolio i've
got sports betting
i've got polymarket
components and i can train
each of those to work
in correlation to one
another so for example
the polymarket can
can make predictions
on just about anything
to be honest and then
you can you can train
the neural net to
see how those correlations
relate to other
things will a stock go
up will a crypto go down
should i short should
i go long should i
have a momentum or
mirror trading strategy
and you can go in here
and you can test all
those strategies. And
as the system operates,
it learns and adapts
and gets better. So
basically to start,
and after about a month
and a half of doing
this, I've done a couple
dozen of these
deployments at this point.
What I've discovered
is what most people are
doing is they're
essentially running a kind
of paper trade. They're
pointing it at the
flow of information,
whether it's Bloomberg
or Alpaca or whatever
the source is. And then
over the first week
or two, its training
based on the sort of
criteria but based on
how aggressive they
want to be how they want
to you know what kind
of money they want to
make whatever it happens
to be once they're
comfortable when the
kind of paper approach
then they switch to a
kind of paid or money
based approach where
they're going from fake
to real and it's been
fascinating to watch
so this so what i've
done is i've created
and initially it was
just a web or sort of mcp
interface so i've been
working on creating
a web-based interface
you can tell it's got
my favorite sort of
hacker style going here
but let me show you
the back end a little
bit and this is the
part that's really cool
um and anyone that's
actually interested in
in doing this themselves
and don't want to you
don't want to spend
the money i haven't
given this away just to
be clear i don't give
away everything but if
you want to actually
build this yourself and
i i might do a version
i give away here in
a week or two. But
you can basically go to
my Reuven fan project
and basically say,
build this. And I'm sure
it'll build a rudimentary
version of this
pretty quickly for
you. But there's a few
things you're going to
want to see here. So you
see that I'm using
Claude and components.
And you can see here
that I've got my MCP. So
I've got 68 different
tools here. You can
see all the tools I was
showing you earlier.
And I'm using Reuven
to show you this. You
got the fantasy system.
This is like a sort
of pseudo sports
fantasy kind of thing.
But the interesting
part, and this actually
is applicable to
anything where you
want to sort of use
Claude as a kind of
front end to something
that's adaptive.
So let's say I want
to create or come up
with a new strategy.
I have a series of
agents and commands.
So when you go into
the neural trading
folder, you see here
I've got all my various
momentum trading.
And then I've got
different types of agents
as well. So if I want
to run an agent or
create a new agent, all
I need to do is choose
the various things.
So in this case, I do
slash neural, I got to
spell it right, neural.
So you'll see here I
got my various neural
agents, a neural
momentum trader. So I'll
choose that one. And
I'll say something like,
create a strategy that
optimizes based on
current market conditions.
I'm just making
it up. Market
conditions or something.
Conditions.
So there's two
ways I can evoke
this. Right now,
I'm invoking the
agent directly, but
I can also invoke
things based on
a slash approach.
So I'm going to do that
in another terminal,
but I'm going to
run these things
concurrently. So in this
case, I'm going to go
here, and I'm just
going to let that start.
And by the way,
we ran into an
interesting problem
yesterday with
Claude, for those
who are using it.
Claude 77 to 80 doesn't
work. So if you are
using Claude currently,
make sure you upgrade
to version 8.1, or
the agents won't work.
i'm using eight one
you'll notice here the
color is a neural
momentum trader that
indicates that it's
using the agent now i've
given all the the sort
of guidelines for how
the agent will work
you can see it's it's
doing it's doing the
analysis it's using the
the neural network
components it's it's sort
of figuring out what
and how it should
optimize i gave it a
really rudimentary sort of
guidance here so now
i'm going to jump here
to another one and i'm
gonna i'm gonna i'm
gonna go DSP, so I
use my quick little
aliases. So, DSP,
dangerously skip permissions.
Now, in this case, I
can use slash commands.
So, you can see I've
got lots of different
slash commands. I'm
going to go here
and use a neural as
well. So, you can see
I get neural evaluate.
Let's do backtest.
So,
optimal trading scenario,
something like that.
So now this is invoking
the command itself.
And again, all this
stuff is customizable.
So a lot of what you're
seeing here, and this
relates directly to
the code base. So when
we go here, you'll see
that there's, let me
show you the SRC folder
quick. you see i got
my gpu i can deploy to
fly i can i can deploy
to various environments
i've got it's
modular so i got trading
canadian trading crypto
trading sports betting
all kinds of stuff
polymarket integrations
so basically what this
is doing is invoking
all these through the
mcp which you see right
here so this isn't
is a it i don't i can't
find anything online
or anywhere that's a
neural, a micro neural
network, MCP based
Claude flow based real
time trading system.
And you can deploy this
to the cloud. The last
thing that's really
interesting, I'm going
to stop this for a
moment, is if you want
to invoke this remotely,
check this out. You
can use Claude flow.
So I'm going to do MPX
Claude dash flow at
alpha. And you can
create run a backtest.
Literally, that's
all I need to
run. And now
what I'm going to
do is I'm going
to evoke this.
Oh, I forgot the swarm.
So I can use hive mind
as well. I usually,
you know, for this,
I usually use swarm.
Now I'm skipping
the user interface
itself and I'm doing
a direct verbose JSON
output. And what's
important about that
is that's how I can
get the user interface.
So now you see that
I'm getting, I'm
invoking all this
same information, but
I'm not using the
actual Claude interface.
You can see here,
this is the task,
it's doing the
various things.
If you look
closely, you can
see the types
and the messages.
So essentially,
to create a user
interface that
looks like this,
I'm taking the
direct output from
Claude-flow and
I'm basically just
formatting in a way
that looks nice and
pretty, right? And
I can invoke the
same basic structure.
So I'm using
Claude-flow kind of
like a LLM endpoint,
which is pretty
neat, I think.
You can see I've got...
and by the way, I
built this little
dashboard initially in
Lovable. Then I, then I
connected my Lovable to
my GitHub. Then I, then
I brought the Lovable
files into this
project. And I basically
said, make the dashboard
work. Literally,
that's all I did. Um,
and then that's, that's
how I got these sorts
of things, right? It's,
it looks pretty good.
I think, you know,
I get my little filters
and it's yeah that's
so back to the billion
dollar one person
startup you know this
this dashboard took me
a couple hours you
know but um the overall
project's been coming
along really really
well i think it's pretty
cool the results have
been pretty amazing
like the the the people
are using it are doing
surprisingly well
i think a few of the
folks in the call probably
were help support
this. Thank you, you
know, for supporting
me and my crazy ideas.
And not every idea has
to be an alien detector.
So this looks like
it's doing some things
here. Now, what did
this one come up with?
Let's just take a
look here. So based on
this one, based on a
comprehensive neural
backtesting across
multiple models, it came up
with some kind of
mirror trading strategy.
It's interesting. The
mirror trading strategy
works really well.
Like the number one
strategy that I've seen
other than people doing
like random sports
betting in the in the
third quarter or looking
for a baseball home
run is actually just
pointing it at like random
U.S. senators and
saying do whatever she
does and that that's
been the best result I
mean we can do those in
under 10 milliseconds
with this system so
basically just you can
monitor the stream so
in the same way that
you see this output
we've got an option here
in Claude-flow that
allows you to do stream
analysis I'm going
to show you that
quick we don't have
a lot of time and
I'm almost out so
So we got alpha and
then we've got, I
think it's screen.
I don't remember
what I called
it. I'm gonna need help.
So let's do
that for a sec.
And there, where is it?
See, I got, oh, I got
a bunch of new features
too, by the way,
this, I created a
verification system the other
day that basically
looks for truth and
helps validate whether
the system is actually
working in the way
that's expected. I'm not
gonna go into that right
now. And I think Brad
might have a similar
presentation. So I'm
going to let him go
into that, but we have
stream chain. So what
the stream chain does
is allows you to do real
-time stream introspection.
So you can get the
stream output from
like a live stock
trading algorithm or the
news or Twitter or
whatever. And then you can
correspond that directly
to whatever it needs
to make action on. So
in this case, I would
do something like
run an analysis and I
can monitor the stream
output from, let's say,
the New York Stock
Exchange and correlate
that to crazy things
the president might be
saying, and then make
stock trades based on
that in real time in
under 100 milliseconds.
It's crazy.
That's it. I'm
out of time.
Thank you.
All right. Quickly,
does anybody have any
questions? I know
that was a brain dump
really fast. Hopefully
that all made sense.
and uh bentz thanks
again for the inspiration
for this week's uh
podcast cool yeah
that was that was a
neat concept to explore
yeah wonderful my i
showed my kids that the
other yesterday uh
you know and they're
like you're you're nuts
right well you never
find it if you didn't
look right yeah
that's why you're here
to be nuts right yeah
yeah that's right i'm
sure the uh the stock
trading system is
probably more valuable
but the uh alien
detection system is more
interesting yeah it's
actually interesting
um yeah i think 60s
70s there was this
conspiracy that kgb
uses newspaper headlines
to communicate so maybe
you can extend that
to the lm right like
so you just replace
aliens with what would
be like kgb or like
whoever other various
organizations so
womenati and they
communicate for like a modern
like facebook posts
well it's open i i i
hear you point that
at create a branch and
and uh do a kgb uh
or whatever the the
modern version of that
is a detection system
um let's so let's let's
jump we don't have
a lot of time today
so and we got a full
uh full dance card
we've got ken carter who
i met a couple years
ago and he's he's
really uh doing some
great work and what we've
i think it was two
weeks ago we we had
a conversation i think
with john and a few
others they pointed
out we really need to
be doing more in the
sort of legal space
and the you know the
the what i just showed
you probably has
several legal variables
that we need to discuss
but we won't get
into that right now but
the the idea of agentics
and ai and the
the sort of legal
ramifications of it you
know when when we're
creating code with ai
itself there it's not
patentable as far as
i can tell there's
there's a lot of you
know discussions around
copyrights and fair
use and all the things
that we're using and
like for example the
other day when i posted
that comment about
creating millions of
lines of code someone's
like well it's not
legal or something like
that i you know i have
no response that i
have no idea so the sort
of legal elements that
we're doing here are
probably particularly
uh concerning um
before we do though ken
i know you you spent
some time at google and
and uh cloudflare and
others maybe you can
give us a little crash
on your background
and what what what
leads you to the agentic
space so um i'm at
JDMBA was most recently
general counsels a
company called Bitmovin,
a company before
that, Cloudflare,
which I assume
you've heard of.
Before that, I was
head of public policy
for Android and Fiber
at a company called
Google. I don't know if
you've heard of them.
Before that, I was a
senior consultant at
a company called the
Wiesenschlafteges
Institut für Infrastruktur
und Kommunikation
Dentist. It's practically
a household name.
and I started my
career as a senior
attorney in the Office
of Strategic Planning
at the US FCC where
I was an expert
in Part 15 rules and
IP interconnection.
I recently, about
two years ago,
started a company
called Ozeki
based on my experience
as general counsel.
And here's the
observation.
Contracts are the
fundamental building
block of all economic
activity right nothing
happens until you get
to a contract right
the legal standard
for the creation of
a contract is offer
acceptance consideration
and meeting of
the minds and it's
really hard to get
to a meeting of the
mind when the other
side has lost theirs
I've spent thousands
of hours negotiating
thousands of contracts
over my career.
And all
negotiations just do
is destroy
economic value.
And I'm wondering
if there's a way
in which you can
use the negotiations
to generate
economic value.
And that's what
we're building
at Ozeki. We
are next week
launching our free
NDA negotiator.
lets you create
and configure and
negotiate NDAs in
seconds because they're
the worst kind
of contracts and
I want to make life
easy for people.
And we've already
launched our core
product, which is
an AI negotiator for
contracts, helps you
develop a strategy,
and you can delegate
that strategy to
an agent. That agent
can be carbon-based
or silicon-based
if you're choosing.
Fascinating. So, yeah,
the NDA is interesting.
Everyone always wants
me to sign NDAs.
Like, is there any
point to an NDA, really?
Like,
so is someone going
to come back and
say that I had a
conversation that
I shouldn't have?
Like, let's dig
into that a little
bit for a moment.
Yeah, so I spent
most of my career
misunderstanding NDAs. In
fact, about two or three
months ago, I put out
a blog post called,
I've been getting NDAs
wrong my whole life.
And when do you
need an NDA?
Well, when you're
going to exchange non
-public information that
you want to share with
the other side, but
you want an assurance
that they're not going
to do anything that
would let that public
information get out.
and then non-public
information get
out to the public
or use it in a way
which would come
back to harm you.
So the litigation
of NDAs are rare,
but they can go seriously
sideways for one
of the parties if the
other party fails.
So I always used to
think the objective
function in reviewing
an NDA was how
fast could I get to
a yes or no decision?
uh that is the wrong
objective function i
mean sounds cool but
it's it's not uh the
question is is this
fit for the purpose
that i want i want
to use it and if you
think about this there
are two strategies
inherent in negotiating
an nda there's the
informational
strategy and there's a
jurisdictional strategy
let's let's get rid of
because it's really
easy so what law
governs this contract
if we need to interpret
it and if we have a
dispute where do we
settle that dispute.
That's really
straightforward.
The informational
strategy is
actually the bulk of
the work. And that's,
what am I going to
use this NDA for?
And if you think
about it this way, my
sales team, well, it's
one guy, he blabs.
He's going to talk
next quarter about
all the deals that
he did this quarter.
Close this company,
close that company.
If we have NDAs in
place with them, well,
he might be
breaching those by
telling his
future customers.
All right, so I want
to set the NDA up
so that it is as
hard to breach as is
possible. I want very
narrow definitions
of confidential
information, very
loosey-goosey usage
restrictions and
disclosure restrictions,
and a very short term.
But this is the other
way. It's my finance
team, and they're going
to make disclosures
to a software vendor
about how much money
we're making and how
much we're spending.
I want that NDA
locked up tight.
And so the strategy,
the informational
strategy then
becomes, like,
how restrictive can
I make this NDA?
If both sides see
the NDA the same
way, there's nothing
to negotiate.
If you have a
difference of a view
of what they want
to use the NDA for,
what its purpose
is. Well, now we
have forces to trade
and logs to rule.
We can make exchanges
within the contract.
I will give you
on the term if you
give me the choice of
law, if you give me
a non-restrictive
definition of confidential
information. So
we can optimize to
get to the best
intersection of what both
parties want in
seconds and for free.
What it's a
contract that states
trust between two
people, basically.
NDAs are trust building
exercises, right?
So as a consultant,
everyone basically wants
me to sign NDA. And
it's always, I see these
and a lot of the work
I'm doing are kind
of similar to one another,
right? I'm an agentic
engineer. So most
likely, someone's coming
to me and looking
and saying, I want to
create some kind of
agent AI system of some
sort. And they're all
kind of the same at the
end of the day so you
know so the it's always
a trick for me it's
like well it's obvious
what's confidential
it's some kind of thing
that the company's
doing as a as a primary
way that they make money
that they don't want
me to disclose but it
but when it comes to
like the agentics
part of it i disclose
everything i share my
code i'm not sharing my
client customer's code
but i'm certainly sharing
my code that is
generally being used in
the methods and approaches
and architectures
are being used so
it's it's it's i don't
care because as you say
no one ever litigates
them so i don't have
much thought about it
but should i care is
should i be more concerned
i never negotiate an
nda i can't think of
a time i've ever negotiated
an nda in my life
no let me just jump
in here for a second
yeah yeah could you
speak for a couple of
minutes on the difference
between a unilateral
and a bilateral
nda because i think
most people here
are interested in
technology solutions
So it would be tech
to tech rather than
finance or, you
know, the other
example that you gave.
I think most people
here want to know how
restricted they
are in doing other
projects when they sign
an NDA and conversely,
how much of
proprietary information
they have exposed to
the public by signing
the NDA. Tom
Smeddinghoff, who's a guy
I know and respect a
great deal, did a lot
of work on NDAs. And
I've done a bunch
of NDAs in my personal
ones for myself.
But I think those two
points are critical.
I think, Reuven,
you don't have
them sign the NDA.
They present one to
you and you take it
or leave it is kind
of the way it's
given to you. You
don't restrict them
on your end, do you?
No, I couldn't care
less. Yeah, that's a
unilateral one. That,
in my experience, is
dangerous only if you
get into a lawfare kind
of situation, which is
a big problem today.
If you get somebody
angry at you
who has a lot
of resources and
just wants to
smash you down,
that's where they
could come after you.
Unlikely, but that's
the exposure you have
personally, I think.
But maybe Kenneth can
have something more
that he can add to
that. Yeah. Let me
tackle the unilateral
versus the mutual
really, really quickly,
because it's actually
a very true concept.
Yeah. So the NDA
says you have an
obligation to not
tell anybody and not
use this information
in a certain way.
Now, that
obligation can be
incumbent on both
parties equally.
Or just one.
And it doesn't
matter whether
it's unilateral
or mutual.
The other side can come
after you just as hard.
But if it's unilateral,
then you have no
claim, well, you know,
no counterclaim. You
took my confidential
information and took it
to the park and posted
it on the lamppost.
um so um people most
people look at a mutual
nba and say it
comports with some sort
of playground notion
of fairness and equity
and if you're bound
by this and i'm bound
by this well you wouldn't
do anything stupid
to yourself um and i
i don't think that's
the right analysis
i think the analysis
is where's the flow
of information are you
a net discloser or
are in that recipient.
And you'll want to do
things differently if
you're giving away
your information or
you're receiving somebody
else's information.
To the other sorts
of questions, what
does it protect?
Well, that's actually
specific in the
language of how you
define confidentiality.
There are NDAs,
which I won't sign,
that says, anything I
tell you is confidential
information.
and that's insane
because if i say i'm
hungry and roof gets
on linkedin says oh
ken's ken i'm gonna
send ken a sandwich
he has breached that
nda that's a stupid
*** nda right um i
will not sign that
um so you want to
tune the definitions
and the use restrictions
for your particular
need we want to
talk about something
that doesn't appear
in a lot of ndas
but for programmers
it's kind of handy um
it's called residuals
and the residual
clause just says whatever
is in your unassisted
mind without
looking at anything
without refreshing
anything that's not
confidential information
you do what you want
and that's a particularly
dangerous clause
um now i had them
for one of my clients
i had them in every
single nda we we
did why because my
senior programmer
was a savant and he
could reproduce code
from memory so
anything you showed
us we can reproduce
from this guy's mind
uh and it would
not trigger the nba
so i'm looking at
rube and yeah he wants
residuals at all okay
that's that's a really
yeah that's a really
not legal advice etc but
that is a good point
anything i see i can
pretty much bill like
you guys know that right
and with with relative
ease at this point
so that that that's
really interesting i
know we're almost out
of time on this segment
but we're going to
be forming a uh legal
committee um and then
for for those that don't
aren't familiar with
the agetics foundation
we have basically
autonomous committees that
form around focus
groups and areas you
know marketing or code
or in this case sort of
legal ramifications
so what if you're
interested in this type
of discussion and you know
we're going to be
we'd like to do these
on a sort of weekly or
bi-weekly cadence where
we set up a recurring
call and and then
ken and others will
come on to the this call
and say this is what
we've been working on
these are some of the
ideas a lot of this is
probably going to
revolve around policy um
as a kind of i call it
antithesis to some of
the work that the
larger corporations and
governments are doing
as a kind of practical
you know working
group of sorts geared
towards our profession
of agentic engineering
i'm really honored to
have ken sort of leading
this effort for us
i'm excited to see
where it goes maybe we
touch upon maybe some
open source licenses
as well which i think
probably plays into
and um yeah any final
thoughts so i'm also
ridiculously allergic to
ndas and the main
reason was that I didn't
want the liability of
having to protect other
people's secrets, which
I think is a problem
you have there. And
I never really liked
the fact that it was
very symmetric because
the other side controls
what they define as
confidential. And now
it's your liability
to try to protect it,
which is also the reason
I like open source
because the idea is I
want this open source
and also Creative
Commons, it's open game,
right? So in your case,
which is also what
I'm doing right now,
that says everything I
talk about is Creative
Commons and open
source and I don't send
NDAs. And that just
simplifies the whole lot.
You can put that
into your NDA
negotiator and make
sure it's in there
every single time
so you can give the
other side some,
you know, you're
entering in trust
building exercise.
And if you say,
I need to have
this as part of
my philosophy and
part of my
business practices
and they don't want
to agree to that,
well, actually you
started doing the
trust building
exercise of getting
the NDA by saying,
look, I'm fair and
reasonable and
willing to compromise
on certain things,
not principles.
The craziest thing,
I know you guys
might remember that
law GPT I created
about two and a
half years ago that
went crazy viral.
And eventually
there was a lawyer
in New York using
it. I think he got
disbarred for not
actually checking
the hallucinations
of the thing,
which is funny because
right now, I'm going
to admit it, when I
get an NDA, what i do
is i pop it into like
clod and basically
say is is this is
there anything crazy in
this thing that i
should be worried about
that's it that's
basically my entire review
of an nda and sometimes
it says well you
should look at this this
or at the other thing
but generally it's like
this is boilerplate
yeah look most most
nda say the same
thing let me just talk
about the committee
for two seconds uh so
here i want to i envision
working um with
industry groups with
Individual developers
with civil society, a
long background in
government relations and
public policy, doing
this sort of a two
-pronged approach. One is
improving the practice
of law, making life
better for lawyers
and improving outcomes
for their clients.
And two is
addressing public
policy issues such
as market power.
there's a professor at
columbia whom i used
to work for by the
name of ellie gnome
and he's done extensive
research on market
concentration and
suggests that the average
market can support
about two and a half
uh competitors so
once you move the
needle past two two and
a half and how do you
get a half competitor
wave entry and exit
you have adjacent
competition like wireless
competing with
wireline. It's not a
perfect substitute,
but it's close enough.
And just making sure
that the market is
protected from
monopolization or at the very
least delaying that
as late as we can.
So I hope you'll join me.
I'll be pulling on
a listening tour
for the next two
weeks figuring out
what are the most
salient issues.
So it's not
just my ideas.
I hope you'll join me.
We're excited to have
you. we'll probably be
creating some kind of
discord or whatsapp
channel for those that
are interested um you
know what you hang out
the logical places i'll
probably post it on
social media once we
figure out where where
that place is and uh
you know like like
everything else we are
meritocracy so if you're
interested and excited
you're in um thanks
thanks ken i really really
appreciate you uh you
know giving us your
your time and insights
it's gonna be great
my absolute absolute
pleasure who's who's
up next i know we're
running running a little
long here but uh yep
who we got absolutely
uh so we've got sandra
uh let me just check
sandra pascali are
you are you with us oh
yeah uh let me change
my name once bulldog
and fisk yes that's
right yeah Sandra. Hi.
How are you? I
got my camera.
I'm good. How is
everyone doing here?
Great. Great. Yeah.
All right. There we go.
Okay. So can I
just go ahead?
Yeah, absolutely.
I'm working on
various products.
One of them involves
creating a studio
for the generation of
content that uses ai
so what i'm going
to show you it looks
like a kind of a gpt
clone kind of thing
with some extra
features but there's one
aspect of it that i
think it relates to this
group and i thought
i'd want to run it
by you and just get
your kind of general
thoughts it's it's
essentially philosophical
although there's
technical stuff behind
it so let me show it
and then hopefully
this will make sense
um you should see
the share button down
at the bottom Yep.
I think that's it.
Yeah. You see something?
Yes.
Okay, great. So
as you can see,
it's like, you know,
you can do stuff
like add, you know,
say something,
you know, doesn't
really matter.
This is not really
what I'm going to show.
But the key thing is
that these, what I call
exchanges, the prompt
and response, and
it's this chain of
thought, you can edit them,
right? So you can you
can go in and edit
them. Right. And what
I want to talk to you
about is just run one
of these. So these are
these are this is
ultimately a tip tap
editor, which is if it's
a type of browser based
editor that's built
on top of Prozmirror,
which you may also
have heard of. It's
been around since
for like 30 years. It
was one of the first
the guy that wrote
Eloquent JavaScript
made Prozmirror.
and um anyway it's an
editor and so what i'm
creating is this
number of uh tools that
people can use to modify
the content of the
conversation uh so
so translate it um uh
convert it into a different
uh uh for a different
type of user uh go
in there find all the
the things of a certain
type change them to
something else right
so uh actions uh that
can be performed on a
um a block of text so
if i run one just to
kind of this is a good
one because this shows
kind of what's going
on oh i don't know
acceptable of course i
have a bug uh let's
see demo gods yeah it's
just it's like i mean
like i'm sure rUv as
like uh for the last
two months this has
always worked and then
today it doesn't right
like you know what i
mean like um let me try
it again uh yeah okay
this one's working.
And it's, you
know, it's running
some enhancements.
I'm going
to do table
generation again.
Yeah, here we
go. Okay, so this
should actually
work. Okay, so it's
generating a table,
it's filling it.
And so this is the
API for Prozmirror and
TipTap that I'm
running, and this is pre
-canned. But, you know,
you get the idea. You
can do kind of really
dynamic modifications
of content. And so
what I wanted to run
by you is this notion,
like this is JavaScript
running in a browser,
and I have the
JavaScript is kind of
in the code for this.
But what I actually
want to do is send the
text content to the
backend, and then we're
an agent, we'll look
at this, and then
based on my user
profile, we'll perform
various actions. I have
some ideas here, but
you can imagine it can
be anything, right?
Again, the examples
I mentioned, maybe it
looks through there and
maybe there's a question
in there and it answers
the question and
adds it and enhances
the text in some way.
And then how do
I put back the
response? Well, the
modified content,
well, the agent
could generate HTML
or something and
then send it back.
But that would break
the technical flow of
this just because it
would be a sort of a hack
to make that work. And
also kind of tricky,
Like, you know, how
do I send it? How does
it, then I have to
write the processor that
will go into the,
essentially the mini DOM
and then find things.
And I have to write
my own logic for that.
And that's not what I
want to do. And
that's really not the
responsibility of the
backend. So what I actually
want to do is ask the
agent, okay, now write
me a TipTap script
that uses the TipTap
editor's API to make
these changes, right? And
I want to test if
LLM can generate the
scripts I'm running on
these sidebars that are
now canned and apply
them. So essentially,
the client is a proxy
agent working on behalf
of the backend, which
sends instructions
in the form of code
that the client runs in
order to make modifications
to what it sees.
And so I was wondering,
really, I don't have
much more of a presentation.
I was wondering
if that is something
that makes sense. And
if you have done
anything like this, like
where you sort of
proxying an agent to run
on the client based on
instructions from the
backend and the client
itself and the client
agent could also maybe
have its own mini
logic as well that can
do certain things. Maybe
it takes certain tokens
or kind of summarize
instructions and kind
of unpacks them on
the client for maybe
optimization reasons.
But that's it.
I just wanted to
ask you about this
notion of having
backend agents
generate code,
dynamic code generation
to be run on clients.
And if you've worked
with anything like that
or what do you think
of the idea or if it
makes sense or you
need more information.
In terms of what's
the specific
problem you're
trying to solve?
That's a good
question. So in the
traditional sense of
a kind of engineering
problem or a user
problem I want to solve,
this is this is you
know the age this is
the ai question right
like the the the ai
will read my profile
so in the back end i'll
have my stuff all the
other conversations
i've had all of my data
etc and i'm doing a
bunch of you know i'm
building this kind of
memory layer that allows
me to compress you
know who i am and then
that will essentially
form the context for
the llm but going to
decide how to solve
to make my experience
better right and for
example if it knows that
i speak swahili right
and the prompt is in
english it might just
translate it i'm not
telling it to look
for people that speak
different languages and
then translate i'm i'm
giving it the chunk
of text and i'm saying
based on this user how
could this information
be presented in a more
useful way. And so
if it's a 10-year-old
and there's a concept
of some complexity, it
might have a little,
it might generate,
tell TipTap to generate
a pop-up that has a
simplified explanation of
that word, right?
So my answer to your
question is, I'm not,
that's not my responsibility
anymore. It's the
responsibility of my
agent, right, to
understand my customer and
help them achieve their
goals, whatever they
may be. And I'm going
to assume their goals
have something to do
with text that I've
sent. Does that make
sense? Yeah. So what this
sometimes is referred
to as context
engineering, right? Where
you're providing the
dynamic creation of
contextual relevance to
whatever the query is,
right? And, you know,
in prompt engineering
of static, right? You
know, the first iterations
of GPT, you'd create
this long form prompt
and then that would
sort of execute a
series of, you know,
thought processes or
whatever. And what you're
describing is the idea
that the context of
the question should
directly relate to a sort
of dynamic output of
some sort that that
can contains a combination
of previous history
of the conversation
and the context of
those conversations and
and other components
which is really
interesting i think context
engineer or you know
contextual engineering
is actually a really
exciting area to explore
now what i would look
at if i were you i
would look at whether
or not that means tool
use, meaning when and
how do I invoke secondary
applications, like
you said, code
development. So if it's
coding, you might want to
look at something like
an E2B, which is an
environment where you
can sandbox and run
code quickly and easily.
Or do you want to get
secondary information
like MCPs? Do you
want to interact with
secondary agents like
A2A? and or maybe all
of the above and lastly
the rag process in how
you get that information
is is it semantic
like are you doing a
natural language query
or is it explicit
like two plus two equals
four yeah and another
another way i'd look
at it is uh if we
actually want to believe
and actually build an
ai first future that we
need to start thinking
about uh this this
interaction of information
with the the individual
the recipient
and right now like
we do a lot of things
manually and we we buy
subscriptions to certain
services that help us
understand the current
the news of today or
whatever it may be
code um what our ceo
just said what our boss
just put in a memo
that we don't fully
understand and uh you know
we can you know noodle
on it ourselves we can
use services We can
ask our friends. But
what if we're in a
world where the AI is
actually a broker, our
representative, that
before information gets
to us, it's been
filtered and prepared for
us, even for my immediate
needs? Like, I just
had a big argument
with my wife. So how
does it present information
to me in that state
versus a state where,
let's say, I'm happy
in some sense, right?
um i'm assuming i
would be unhappy after
an argument with my wife
so um the uh the notion
here is that it's
not so much um and it
is context engineering
but it's more what
if i always have an
agent filtering information
for me and and that's
what this is kind
of hinting at where
there's no specific goal
right it's just this
information has been
presented to me i don't
fully uh understand
it so before it gets
presented to me i'd
send it to an agent and
the agent creates
instructions for it to be
updated to better satisfy
my immediate needs
so it's kind of a
philosophical idea yeah
but everything you said
technically is correct
yeah yeah i mean this
sounds almost similar
to like the concept
of how they have the
uh ai glasses and you
have those on and kind
of a heads up yeah right
and they're constantly
watching the world
around you and what
you're saying is uh the
things that i ingest
run them through an ai
to give me some kind
of insight on these
things is that true
yes yes and then the
next step then would be
the you know the the
llm the output is is
modified to to reflect
this but that requires
that the the llm then
starts um uh kind of
rewriting text
rebuilding the output it
creates and that then
creates a kind of templating
and kind of text
processing problem because
now we're increasing
the complexity and
the risk profile for
what an element produced
because who knows how
it's going to interpret
that i want to
better understand say
location it maybe creates
a map but how does it
represent a map and
its output and does my
ui actually understand
what a map is and and
and so on so you're not
talking about You're
talking about retraining
an existing LMM.
You're talking about
you have an LMM
that exists, and
you're adding on
to that already
trained LMM. True?
Yeah.
Yeah. With this kind
of agent, yeah. I want
to bring it to a
close, but I see, Guy,
you were trying to get
a question in there.
Is that right, Guy? Yeah.
I think that ChatGPT
projects is something
you should look at.
It's actually pretty
cool. You can put a
custom context. you can
drop files in and it
keeps all the queries
on that topic it
understands the past history
but some of the
things i think you're
trying to do here
you could do um using
projects i think this
adds something on top of
that but definitely
definitely helps a lot
guy are you able to
put a link into that
in the chat i'll uh
yeah i'll just it's in
chats gp core i'll
do a screenshot chain
projects you're a scholar
gentleman thank you
so much all right
thank you sandra thanks
very neat uh we just
got enough time which
is great uh from
hey brad how are you
you've got hey everyone
dr house gotta be
a little quick do i
no no no we got we
still got 10 minutes
to the top of the air
okay so you have
four minutes in the q
and a hey thanks a
lot and really nice to
meet you. I can look
forward to working
with you. Super excited.
And also, Sandra,
thanks. Thanks for
your presentation.
Actually, I'm going
to put my coder
hat on, haven't
had my coder hat
on for a couple
of months here.
So what I'm going
to talk about is
Dr. House, I've been
doing a fair bit
of research on more,
don't like to use
the term AGI, but
I'm go and say AGI
research with a deep
dive into personas
and those kinds of
things. And I really,
when Roof had the awesome
cloud flow, it was
just Roof's programming
is a little different
than mine. I'm very
documentation first
type person. I need
to understand what I'm
doing and go through.
I just don't have the
Roof's level of expertise
to be able to pick
and choose the exact
agent. So I needed
something that was a
little bit more suitable to
me. and my biggest
problem was um i i always
had um the mum effect
so when i write
something i would have
a code analyzer and it
would always say yeah
great 100 or some other
**** like that and
in all reality it was
like broken and ******
and wouldn't validate
anything so i just
kind of combined um the
inspiration from from
what rube had and then
my background with
personas and created really
a doctor house I have
a full suite that
I'm releasing I'm
actually having my agents
update update each
other right now what I'm
showing is a an older
version but it seems to
be working out okay
so again my style is a
little bit more verbose
where I like to have
heavy on the
documentation I like to to
review stuff so so I'm
going through and really
inspired greatly by
my cloud flow so i've
created dr house where
gone through and um
really provided half
my new version is uh
quite a bit shorter but
i had to go through and
assess different code
and end up creating
an agent for it so
it's quite a bit more
verbose this one the
new ones are are smaller
and i'm finding
typically i would have it
output bash commands but
being a little bit more
explicit just because
that's the way i
code is i need explicit
i need more deterministic
uh so it's just going
through when when
i identify um parallel
execution execution
to have this doctor
house persona where it's
brutally honest i i want
it to provide certain
i wanted to have
some friends that are
other agents so i i'm
very prescriptive in
saying this is here's
your friends that you
actually use and what
their capabilities are.
So as you go through,
and I don't know why
the language detector
works better than
just straight bash,
but it seems to work.
My theory, and I
haven't proven this
because I just
created this a
couple of days ago,
and they've improved
themselves quite
significantly,
is if you're
analyzing, say, Python
code, if you use
the Python error
detection, it just
seems to flow more
natural when you're
in cloud code.
again i haven't tested
it it's one of those
ship fast and fix later
but it seems to be
working pretty good so
going through it does
all the tests um uh
here i'm going to jump
to the description because
it goes and follows
through really the
different steps and the
main thing is when it
analyzes everything
i use the approach and
this is what i teach
in one of my classes is
rather than just asking
for an assessment um
create a rubric on
an evaluation criteria
and this seems to be
one of the major
advancements that i'm finding
for any ai coding if
you're just a newbie
or if you're an elite
engineers have a rubric
to compare to so
this is one of the
advancements that i find
is quite quite useful and
as you go through um
it's a it's longer
agent i created a nice
marketing one uh because
i know marketing just
just works so So I
created a marketing one
with the inspiration
from Roof, Braun, and
the Gentix Foundation.
Nice, pretty image. And
it really just describes.
So a lot of this
is, yeah, is it
vaporware? Does
it actually work?
Well, I'll show you.
I'm not going to do a
live demo just for time
purposes. But I had
one. I'm working on
this one, which is an
Epic Planner. so I like
to create ethics in
in github and I like
ethics to be in a
certain format that I
understand and it seems
to be very it's really
purpose built for the
way that I like it very
very verbose step-by
-step that I can I can
review it I'm a teacher
um part-time so I
like to I like to see step
-by-step so I understand
all the code so I
looked through here
and said okay let's
analyze this epic planner
at a base level and
it's like oh yeah mom
effect the overall score
is pretty good gives
me some gaps some
areas for improvement
and it's not not too
bad usually I would copy
paste this into my
cloud code and say yeah
fix it now the difference
is if I even just
copy and paste without
using the framework
where it's really designed
to be in framework
and work with a spawn
or with a swarm so
my brutal Dr. House is
made to be part of a
swarm it actually does
work as a standalone
not near as well but
as part of a swarm it
works incredible but
even even just this copy
and pasting that code
that i just showed
you from the the github
repo you go through
and here i said act as
this persona and then
really this is the
difference in in the
output so this is the way
that i personally code
and this is the way
that i review code for
others and i like to
see. So I like this
kind of format. It's
much easier for me as a
coder to understand.
So this is just one
example of a little bit
more going the, I guess,
anti-pattern of narrow
and tight agents.
It's just my personal
preference. Yours
might be different is
I like a little bit
more verbose and
very structured and
deterministic. So this
is the way that I like to
use code. Dr. house
outputs it very brutal
you can see i only
got a 12 out of 25 for
this epic planner
needs a whole bunch of
work and then it
provides all the extra
information so the
content's fairly similar
um but the style and uh
oh the fruit i forgot
the big thing is it
it will not allow you
to do unsubstantiated
claims if you have a
claim it actually is
built in to go to your
actual code it will
not trust any claim
whatsoever so it goes into
your code and brutally
destroys you for
having false claims it
brutally destroys the
why i wanted it is the
the fake tests if anyone
ran into the the mock
test where you know
what every single test
passes this will not
allow that to happen
i've and it does seem
to work so in my case
i went and anti-pattern
based on my coding
style and it works for
me i'll probably i'll
paste the link right
now i only have the one
agent they're all
improving themselves um
right now so i'll be
posting a whole bunch
more i think i have
night i'm keeping it down
to about 19 that act
as a swarm and um heavy
props to braun and rube
thank you very much
this looks this looks
great by the way brad
and uninstantiated uh
claims is my specialty
so i could definitely
uh i could definitely
use this so is this
input and output so
like after you're done
the project does it can
you run it to say
like is it actually do
everything that it's
claiming to um i have it
built in in my my
coordinator one of my main
coordinators is after
any time you uh do a
feature or an epic or
an issue from github
it actually has the
brutal honest valid with
my validator friend
go in and validate all
of your all of your
code that's a mandatory
requirement before you
have before it passes
an issue or an epic
so i i actually have
this built in as part
of the process to always
always run as with the
validator as and the
optimizer as my final
steps as a workflow
as part of the workflow
so we're at the top
of the hour this is
the after show thanks
for everyone who uh
presented today ken sandro
brad um we we're we're
gonna keep going um
so if you have any
questions for any of our
uh presenters now is
your now is your chance
or if you want to
just randomly rant or
talk about or show this
is the open mic portion
of the uh event if
you will this is this
is your chance to to
uh do whatever you like
so just raise your
hand or whatever if you
want to pipe in um can
i start by making a
comment on the on the
sandro stuff which is
one of the areas i
worked on and and my
observation is that i
think there's a ridiculous
amount of power in in
the idea of creating
uis customized to
particularly users and i
spent a lot of time on
the personalizations the
the the economy there
what I think is super
important is to make
sure that you have
very, very strong APIs
to code against. So one
of the things I've
found is I've found that
the LLMs are very good
if you give the very
explicit APIs, ideally
strongly typed. And
then you could say, if
you want to communicate
or transform, in this
case, the UI, you
can use that. So it's
almost in this case,
Sandro, you can get
the server side LLM to
write almost the JavaScript
or the Python code
that will then be
executed in the browser.
That will then create
a reply for the browser
yeah absolutely yeah
and the coolest thing
these days the reason
i mentioned python is
you can use pyodite
right so you can actually
run python code this
is where my security
brain goes what the
**** and everything else
is like this is pretty
awesome right because
you can actually run
python code directly
on the browser right
which is really cool
so you can actually
write so you're almost
going to have the same
apis if your python is
back end you can
have the same sort of
standard tests if
everything else is there but
then you could send
Python code to the client
which then will render
and recreate that
environment based on
that client preferences.
Isn't that the promise
of Jupyter Notebook?
This sounds like Jupyter
Notebooks on
steroids AI powers.
I think it's different.
I think Jupyter
Notebooks is a great
way to describe kind of
what you do in a
programmatic sequential way.
What I'm more talking
about is the ability
to communicate to the
client in language,
but more importantly,
in an API,
right? And this is where
you don't want open
-ended. So it's almost
like you don't want
the backend to write
just raw Python code.
You actually want to
give it almost the API
for that code to
call. And that
way you can control
a lot more of
the user experience
and you can
control a lot more
the capabilities.
And maybe a variation
of this is if
you feel there's
a feature that
doesn't exist, then
you can have a separate
loop to create
that feature to
add that API, and
then you can rush.
And that's what
I've ran into when I
actually used, I actually
ended up alternating
to Jupyter Notebook
because I found those
same limitations in
the PyDOT environment.
How often is that
environment updated?
Have they done
anything to allow like
node scripts to run
or anything like that?
What do you mean,
Jupyter Notebooks?
The PyDOT environment
specifically, not
Jupyter. Because when I
was still working with
OpenWebUI and they
released the Pyodide
environment where you
could run code snippets
inside the browser itself,
I always found that
there were certain
packages that the Pyodide
environment could
never install. But if I
popped it through a
Jupyter notebook, it always
worked out. So I was
wondering maybe if
I was just using the
Pyodide environment and
incorrectly. When was
the last time you used
it? Because I used it
by like six months.
And it was ridiculous.
They even have NumPy,
they had mat.lib,
they have requests
already, they've added
a fix to do requests.
It's ridiculously
powerful. It almost
felt like there's
this, and then you
can bring your own
Python code, right?
Wow. So yeah, it's been
longer than six months,
so I'll have to give
that a check. Thanks
very much for that.
That's awesome. I kind
of give it up on the
Pyodide. I mean, the
problem with it is, so
it actually runs Python
inside of you, like
WebAssembly inside your
browser. but the web
assembly things they
don't have like experience
to the outside world
so they that's why
they need the little
bridges like so if
actually it needs like to
like how they hack the
requests so numpy is
not a problem because
numpy it doesn't actually
talk to it just its
own in its own box like
but if you want to use
request it actually
has to tell the whatever
shell in the browser
says hey i'm making
the request that it
has to do it on its
behalf collect so in the
same for ui and everything
like so if you try
to bring random
unsupported package that is
uh so if it's some
machine learning like if
it's pytorch numpy like
tensorflow that would
always work but
anything that tries to
talk to outside like for
example sidekick learn
has ability to load
data set that actually
needs a little bridge in
the piedide environment
that will do it for
it yeah but they
added that so you can
actually use requests on
it so they the problem
no but if you try to
do something unusual
they added requests
right so now everything
using requests is okay
but if you uh create
your own http library
call it like for example
there is htps right
yeah that is not anything
relies on that it's
not going to work
until somebody goes and
builds the bridge for it
okay so it's everything
possible but it needs
bridges basically
and uh vati you had
your hand up there
too oh yeah i had i
just wanted to share
some experience i even
chimed in linkedin
so this week i
think it's the first
of my week i made
20 000 lines of code
right so i guess for
you it's a joke but then
when actually like
the way contributed to
that ridiculous conversation
on linkedin than
people so i discovered
a few things so i
started on a tool i was
thinking it's going to
be 200 lines now it's
like at 20 000 and a
few things i did i
never done before so i
started i tell it right
the kubernetes like all
the cicd workflows
because the projects i
work with they not
isolated they actually
have to run within like
corporate environment
with other people's
databases everything so
i started i told it
makers kubernetes like a
world job basically that
we want to contribute
so i always had it
running in production
even if it was doing
nothing and then the
problem why it's taken
like four days versus
like two hours is my
usual one it's because
people's documentation
and sort of understanding
like how the data
actually what it what's
in the databases and
all this integrity is
it's uh the documentation
only like what's
the time is wrong and
even people understanding
like what's actually
is because these
things are written by
15 different groups of
people so what I did I
found very beneficial
I asked Claude to
write a little debug
tools that actually go
into production databases
and fish out records
and that actually
it can look and reason
about them and I found
that I discovered
all the things but
basically it's wrong
with the existing systems
but I think we've had
this experience and
another thing I always
have to yell at Claude
I even put a lot of
guidance files is sometimes
like not to do the
mocking tests because
I think the previous
speakers said like
so what Claude does a
lot of times like if it
goes elastic search
it says oh let me make
the the mock elastic
search like client
right and like this is
like the what it should
be sending and that's
like I'm going to
write all my unit tests
against that and make
sure code and that
works perfectly but the
moment you point it
to real database like
it fails so i basically
found beneficial to
and i kind of live
dangerously because like
it's kind of a
dangerous way except
permissions but
not within the
isolated environment
so like i'm kind of a
little bit scared but
but i found like i can
leave it to run
because these are like
super annoying problems
i think it would have
i would have actually
without claude i would
probably give up a long
time ago and hacked
something quick and
said that it works
but i actually leave
claude to investigate it
took like sometimes
two or three hours to
actually go in different
data sources so we
can reason about it
and um awesome so i
even had to switch from
100 unlimited plan to
like 200 you had to do
the upgrade hey take
the plans finally yeah
i got kicked out by
them some auto wonderful
so i'm not sure i
just want to pivot
i want to make sure
everybody gets a chance
there's a few hands up
uh blood so is there
a final thought there
fati you're you're muted
there fati it appears
okay i can't hear you
can anybody hear fati
no no no audio we'll
come back to you fanti
then so you had your
hand up there yeah just
a quick one to brad uh
you made this *******
house uh agent and
i was inspired by it
and i started to do
my ui you know teacher
um strict teacher on uh
looking at typography
on sizes white space
on a page and i
generated with this agent
with a code itself but
what would you um you
know in your experience
as you develop this
system what what
would you what would
you um suggest how to
start because it's not
really working you know
it's scraped online
sources from different
uh famous designers
in the past like eric
speakerman and others
from germany uk and the
us but it's a mixture
of uh you know
contradicting
opinions about um
different typography
masters and white
spaces so how did you
make make it consistent
um i i usually have
um doc i'll be very
brief i usually have
this agent he's he's
friends with usually
two other agents when
they analyze something
uh so in your case uh
either a documentation
uh specialist or a
front-end specialist so
i usually i usually
send out uh swarms of
three agents with um
with the doctor house
being one of them for
late stage mentioning
i i i have the the
brutal honest along with
the optimizer and the
validation agent to
go through so that
that's just the way i do
um i'm also a newbie
i usually call you and
i have uh front end
questions um but i i i
do i start with usually
either cloud or um
lovable or i find a
site and just say create
a veet um part of my
system i have starter
packs so most of the
time i just get started
but for evaluation
my recommendation is
find two two friends
to go along with an
assessor are you using
playwright as well bram
um i have um i'm
not i haven't
i just rebuilt
it um while i
was on vacation
last week so
yeah yeah yeah it
was very interesting
because it started to
be very minimal like a
real strict teacher in
graphic design class
you know removing all
the colors yeah Every,
you know, gradient,
everything is just
a bare minimum, like
Vignelli from New York.
He was the fan of
minimalism in the 70s.
And Claude scraped
some sources from, you
know, typography
books or design books.
And it's not the way
how we do it. Yeah.
Thanks.
One thing I'll
quickly note, when
you're running
agents, they seem
to work better
in odd numbers.
uh for whatever reason
three is better than
two five is better
than four um and i i i
think that has to do
with some kind of like
consensus mechanism
where you need some
kind of you know a you
know majority three
out of three out of
five kind of thing or
whatever it happens to
be so just as an fyi
try to try to use odd
numbers neat potty did
you get your mic back
on yes i did so i
have 49 agents would
that work yeah the prime
numbers were great yes
so so anyhow um i've
been working on this
project similar to
uh brad's uh i called
it a code governance
sentinel system so
it's basically policing
or like uh house sitting
the um the Claude
but when it deviates
from you know what you
wanted to build it
often marks the tests
like claiming victory
like you know really
like really jumping
the gun all the time so
even when I you know
use the system this CQGS
it does go around
and it does claim you
know it does have you
know false claims so one
solution i found is
to open you know is to
start another you know
cloud instance from
the scratch with you
know fresh memory so it
will have no uh you
know memory of what it
has been doing and it
does work in that way
only so um i'm i'll be
very happy to collaborate
if anyone or you
know uh like i guess
i should directly ask
this to uh the brad if
you want to uh you
know take a look at it
i'm not um very uh
skilled in a coder i only
took uh classes when i
was in college so i'm
not as good as a roof
either so i mean yeah
that's what i what i
wanted to share we've
got a coding group
on both whatsapp and
discord where we have
exactly these conversations
um if you're not a
member you know join
and share and and i'm
sure you'll find your
cohort thank you thank
you thank you wonderful
nick how are you nick
i'm well just want
to do a quick introduction
nick spizak longtime
engineer and architect
new been listening
the last few weeks
to the community here
my question was more
just more generic i know
a lot in this audience
is very familiar
with the architecture
of claude flow and the
underlying my question
was more as the agentix
foundation is starting
to build up the
community i'd love to
contribute both the time
and um on the finance
side for hey how do we
become members of that
if claude flow has
already some existing
learnings that are
around there i found
a lot of the different
architecture but i don't
if anybody else in this
call is also newer and
kind of picking some
of those pieces like
hey i could use these
with some of our b2b
clients um just looking
to see if there was
a if you guys already
had not even a getting
started right it's a
very technical audience
but the what's the
already existing
patterns that are there
and we could bring
those to future sessions
for hey here's some
use cases that we're
looking in our
existing businesses so
that was my open-ended
question not sure
what you guys kind of
had thoughts around
that. There's two parts
to that. We'd love
to have your help.
And I've been a little
overwhelmed with the
amount of interest
in it. And part of
what I've been trying
to do to make it a
little easier to navigate
the ton of stuff that
we've created for
it is I've been
working on a wiki here.
So the wiki is where
I sort of, as I'm
building the various
parts of it, you can
go and explore. For
example, you'll see here
that there's a bunch
of CloudMD files.
These CloudMD files
are kind of how
I modify it. So
when you're doing
the init command
for Claude-flow,
you're essentially
getting a kind of the most
generic version of it.
So when you're going
and you want to build
something specifically,
you should probably
go and take a look at
some of my examples.
Like here would be a
Claude-flow for AIML
projects, right? And this
explains how it can
use the various agents,
how they're spawned,
and it gives it a
guidance. One more
thing. A couple of people
mentioned that
sometimes these
systems, specifically
Claude, loses sort
of context after a
while, you know,
specifically when it kind
of condenses the
conversation. You can do
hooks. And the hooks are
a particularly easy way
to sort of remind it
what an original intent
was. And so there's
two predominant ways
that I've been doing
it. One is I inject the
ClawDatMD back in when
it's about to do the
chat compression or
whatever they call it.
And then that reminds
it what its original
intent is. And the
secondary thing I'm doing
is using all the various
agents. So the agents
allow it for a secondary
context. And so if
you're relying on a
sort of the sort of
multi-agent flow, then
the overall ClawDatMD
becomes a little less
important. Now, the last
thing, I want to go
quick here. We've been
talking about verification
a ton today. I've
rolled this out on
Wednesday. There's a new
verification system
that is intended and
would be perfect for
Brad's approach. I'm going
to take a deeper dive
into what Brad's doing.
but basically what
this does is it creates
what I'm calling a
trust or truth and is
enforced but not assumed.
A lot of the sort of
let it run for an
hour or two, you know,
and then it builds
something crazy is a problem
we all run into. So I
was working with Chris
Royce on sort of a way
to sort of validate
and have that sort of
run and have different
validation modes. So
the system can not
only validate, it can
learn what's right, what's
wrong. And the more
you use the system,
the smarter it gets
and the less it it
hallucinates so when you're
looking at me and and
the reason i can develop
things so quickly
and effectively is
because i've been training
this thing for for
almost two months on the
way that i like to
build and then it knows
kind of what what makes
sense and then and
then i also have a kind
of rollback mechanisms
so lots and lots of
features that that you
can dig through check
out the wiki there's so
much stuff it's almost
hard to sort of you
know understand it all
the wiki is great yeah
we could probably
create groups dedicated
but just parts of the
app and um anyway yeah
hopefully that was
helpful perfect thanks
for that on nice to meet
you nick welcome and
we are welcome join our
join our discord well
now the biggest thing
to add on nick is
once you have Claude-flow
running in cloud code
you can ask cloud code
to analyze the source
code of Claude-flow off
of github to explain
what it does that's
the fastest way i was
able to onboard to
what was supposed to be
happening and making
sure that what was
actually built matched
what I was trying to do.
Perfect. Thanks,
Jed. Appreciate it.
I'll try that as soon
as we get off here.
You can also point
it at, if you do an
NPM install, you can
point it at the NPM
node modules and say,
tell me about all
the things. I actually,
by the way, I did
that for Claude Code,
and that's how I
discovered the background
running process
that was undocumented.
So just as a
quick FYI, if you ask
Claude Code to run
long running sessions
in the background,
it'll automatically
invoke the control B
function and it'll
run forever. Now,
once you've got that
running, you can do
stream analysis on it.
So let's say you're
running a WebSocket
and you're getting
real information in
real time. You can
just run that in the
background and do an
analysis every 10
seconds or something.
Fascinating. So would
that be like a use
case for that might
be having that small
team that does a
playwright verification
of the working
components? Exactly.
So it's constantly
checking. So, so dead on.
So when, so for example,
let's say you're
running NPM run dev.
And while you're, you're
running, you know,
your site, you're,
you're visiting it and
there's errors, it can
automatically monitor
the run dev console
output and as a
background task, fix the
problems as it occurs
without you having to go
and copy and paste
those issues. The second
thing you could do,
Playwright. So Playwright's
really good at
getting the browser
console output, right,
where you're getting
client-side errors. You
can directly feed those
client-side errors
back in the Cloud Code
using that background
process. And you can
run many background
processes concurrently.
You can then allocate
each of those
to an agent. And
each agent is only
looking at a
particular class of
problem and solving
those on the fly.
Is there a cap to the
number of background?
No, I ran like
100 the other day.
And you'll see, and
once they're running,
you can actually
do the slash bashes
command, and you can
then monitor each
of the agents using
the bashes command.
And you can see the
real-time view of the
console, and then you
can click escape, and
then go back and look
at the other, and it
gives you introspection
to all the agents.
So you can, earlier
I showed you that
option where I did the
Claude flow swarm and
it did the direct
output using stream,
you can evoke the
agents using that and
then run them as
background processes.
Anyway, it's so much.
Good discovery.
The way I got that
is I told Claude to
basically document all
the undocumented parts
of Claude code in the
NPM modules folder.
anyway it's pretty
cool right i'm putting
i'm putting that that
uh exercise into my back
pocket forever who's
up next we got marcos
hi guys um i just had
some kind of questions
because i i finished
reading nathan b jones
article last night
about chat gpt5 and how
it's both in his words
It's both the smartest
AI tool and the most
difficult to work
with, because it sounds
like from what he's
how he presents it is
that chat GPT five is
almost like an open
router or like a router
to many different models
behind the scenes.
And it dynamic not only
does it dynamically
choose based on
what you just typed
in and asked it or
prompted it which
model to choose. But
in some cases, it
kicks off several in
parallel to analyze
your question and
compares notes among
its own committee
of experts that it's
assembled to come
back with the answer.
So I guess what I
mean to say is that it
sounds like Roof's awesome
cluster swarm concept
that he implemented
last month was
prescient of this idea.
In other words, rUv
implemented it himself and
came out with something
that's working even
before ChatGPT did.
Am I getting
this correct?
Is that the model?
Well, it's a rudimentary
implementation of
a, you know, agentic
swarm style gateway,
right? So when you make
a request, there's some
kind of heuristics
that basically gets
deployed that basically
says, is this something
that needs to think
longer or is this
something that needs to
use a particular model?
and then it allocates
it to it the issue
that i and others have
with gpt5 is it is it's
built for the lowest
common denominator it's
built for people who
don't know how to
prompt engineer or ask
the right questions
which i guess is 99 of
the world but for someone
who actually knows what
they want and knows
how to ask for it it's
several steps back
and so i i get why they
did it you know not
everyone's going to be
a an expert in agentic
engineering and
knows how to you know
structure their memory
and prompt engineering
the the all the settings
within chat gpt but
what they did is they
broke all that stuff
that i spent the last
two years optimizing
and now it's garbage and
and i've been fooling
around with it for
the last week and it's
still garbage so i i'm
i see myself moving
to claude because claude
is smart and capable
and and works in the
way that i like it
to work yeah yeah
interesting on providence
and i don't uh you
know mean to like um uh
be be a sycophantic
here but if for
those of us who have
been around for the
last year uh Reuven
had uh through
recursive and reflective
uh chain research
and built deep
research research, four
months before deep
research came up,
and the multi-agent
swarms, or multi-agent
systems, and that kind
of mixture of experts,
I remember seeing a
demo on that probably,
well, fall last
year as well.
What we see, and
please let me
know if anybody
here disagrees,
it feels like typically
the curve that
we're on here in this
community is about
two to three months
ahead of what
we're seeing emerge
out of the big tech,
right?
I wanted to throw in
one thing, though,
is I think you're
referring, there's a
difference in what
you're referring to here,
because chat GPT-5
is an MLE, mixture
of expert models, right,
model that integrates,
it integrates, I
think, 16 expert
models, right, and
that we're not... As
opposed to agents, yes,
that's right. We're
not doing that,
right, in the Agentex
Foundation. We're
not developing large
models like that. And
it's a different concept.
There's two parts,
just to be clear.
The MOE probably exists
within the structure
of the GPT itself,
right, the GPT model that
they're running under
the – and then there's
a gateway component
that's allocating the
request to either a
test time or reasoning
-style model or an instruct
-style model, right,
That the Instruct
style model likely is
some kind of mixture
of experts structure.
It's probably some
incremental better version
of GPT-4. And so I think
what he was referring
to was specifically
that gating process,
not the gating process
within PyTorch or the
neural network itself,
but some first step
that makes the request
and decides whether it
should go to pro or
thinking or Instruct.
Yeah, that's true.
In a normal MOE model
environment, you have
what's called a router.
It's the first model
that intercepts and takes
in the token stream,
the conversation, and
has to figure out very
quickly what model
within its mixture of
experts that it needs to
route this particular
stream of tokens to.
And that's the router
model. And there's
a lot of complicated
technology that goes
into routing. It's
got to do it very
quickly and make a
decision very quickly. I
think that's what
you're referring to.
There definitely is a
router model that sits
in front of the
other remaining 16
distilled, you know,
highly distilled models.
We have one more hand up.
Jotham.
Yes, sir.
Thanks. Thanks. Thanks.
You guys can hear
me fine, right?
Yep.
Excellent.
So I want to go back
to the hallucination
problem. I know
probably a few months
ago, Reuven had this
thing around symbolic
AI, and I thought
that worked pretty
well. But as of today,
I see PwC and AWS
coming up with the
automated reasoning
to help with the
hallucination problem.
So I'm wondering
what's your take
on that and if that's
going to affect
or have any impact
to the corporate
world as it relates
to how do we
mitigate the risk
of hallucination?
I know there's various
ways we've tried
to kind of do it, but
just your thoughts.
there's two i've got
a lot of opinions on
hallucinations so
there's two schools of
thought here on
hallucinations one if you're
creating net new novel
things hallucinations
are a critical part
of the creativity
of a language model
right it's it's not
a negative it's a
positive this is what
allows me to create
you know an ai that
tries to detect aliens
and whatnot right
it's crazy it's new
it's untested it's never
been done and allows
us to invent in ways
that were never quite
possible before.
Now, in the inverse
part of the spectrum are
non-declarative types
of approaches that
are discriminative.
They're explicit in what
they need to do. So
when you ask an AI what
two plus two is and
it tells you it's six,
that's obviously not
a good hallucination.
When you ask an AI to
come up with a novel way
to reimagine mathematics
in using a combination
of things that have
never been done
before, that's a great
use of hallucinations.
So by removing the
hallucinations from these
models, you're essentially,
you know, cutting
off the primary
value proposition for
most of the applications
that I use them for.
And lastly, that's the
point of things like
top P and temperature
settings, you know,
top K and other things
is to adjust the
parameters of the model
to be more or less
probabilistic. So
this idea that they're
suddenly going to
create a model that
gets rid of hallucinations
by 90% is crazy.
The reality is the
reason why GPT-5
hallucinates more is
they've mucked around with
the temperature and
top P settings and made
a generic sort of
value that is trying to
be encompassing
everything for everyone.
What they should do is
have a gating mechanism
that automatically
adjusts the temperature
value based on the
query being made.
right which makes sense
but what about for
right regulated industry
like the financial
services compliance
legal staff because
what aws is saying
they have these uh it's
gonna work within i
think bedrock it's it's
automated reasoning
using math it's probably
fine-tuned somewhere
it's fine-tuned yeah
against some well from
what i understand chat
gbg it does self
-tune and dynamically
adjust its temperature
like if uh if you ask
chat gpt5 a medical
question it'll think
longer and turn down the
temperature because it
being correct is more
important than being
created but if you
ask another type of
consequence of the
system prompt if you look
at the system prompt
that was ripped out of
gpt5 uh it had it it
does mention some sort
of importance ranking
to determine the
quality or the consequence
of being wrong as i
assume it's part of
the safety We're almost
out of time, guys,
and I got to jump. We
got one hand up. I'm
going to let you be on
the final thought, our
security guru here.
I was just going to say
that on hallucinations,
and from a security
angle, since we put
it in, I think the key
question is you need
to bring your own
content, right? You have
to see that LLMs are a
compression of what's
there, and the LLMs
don't know when to stop.
So if you bring your
own content and you
put some graphs on it,
on top of it, you start
to have very strong
deterministic. The
problems occur when you
ask the LLMs to retrieve
content. And I agree
with Rube that the
hallucinations, in a
way, is what makes it
special. The key is to
play to its strengths.
Yeah, I totally agree
with you, Dennis.
One of the big things
about hallucinations
is that models are
generally trained
on very publicly
unknown data. And if
you're in a narrow use
case or an industry
that's very secure
and an LLM's never
seen that, it's
always going to be
inaccurate about your
data set. And so you
should apply your
data set to help and
ground the model. And
it's more than that.
Roo, here's my
request to you,
man. I would love
to have a model
that has reasoning
but no content.
That's what I want.
We have that. that we
built we built that
when you look at the
roof and models that
is exactly the purpose
of the model so when
you look at the micro
neural net concept
what i'm trying to
do is create a blank
narrow neural network
that's explicit for a
task in which it needs
to exist for i don't
need it to i don't
need it to be trained
on all content that's
ever created yes it's
just that yeah that's
brilliant by the
way and that's one of
the few the case you've
done that i think
is the micro models
and i'm i'm a big
allergic to fine-tuned
models but that i think
is beautiful micro
tune again from a
security point of view i
was saying almost like
a frontier model that
has the capabilities
and maybe the
engineering a bit of it
but with no content so
you have to give it
content just you have
no problem yeah but
how do you how do you
train a model that has
no content you got to
give it data to train
it. No, you don't.
Well, no, no, you
don't. So I think what
you're really saying
is we need to move away
from language-based
models for everything.
Language is fine as
an interpretation of
what the information
means in a way that's
verbally meaningful
to me. But for most of
the things that I'm
doing, like when you
look at the trading,
the neural network
trading system I'm
doing, the language model
only acts as an input
and an interpretation
of the output. But
But what's happening
under the scenes is I'm
trying, I'm attempting
anyway, to create
these little tiny
models that understand
how to trade these
stocks slightly faster,
slightly better, and
then over time get
more effective in that.
Make me more money,
right? And I don't
need a language
model to do that. I
need a mathematical
model to do that.
Sure, time series
or data series
specific, right?
I get that.
But I just don't
know how you –
Yeah,
I was just going to
say, Dave, I mean,
my when people talk
about hallucinations
and accuracy, my
response is maybe an
LLM is not the right
business solution
to the problem you're
trying to solve.
I mean, not we
don't have to solve
everything with generative
AI that, you know,
I can give you some of
that. Yeah, I agree,
Sandy. There's an over
-reliance on language.
And if you look at
the cutting-edge work
happening in Meta around
JEPA and VJEPA, they're
saying that it's
like we shouldn't be
using language models
for everything. Language
is just one way that
humans learn. We need
to be using lots of
other mechanisms. So
there's an over-reliance
on language for sure.
all right guys i'm i'm
running late i gotta
go i love this
conversation as always my
fridays are my favorite
time of the week um if
anyone that that's
interested in joining
some of our committees
we got the the legal
one popping up next week
you know we'll we'll
put put an announcement
around that and
we're also creating other
committees for anything
you can dream up so
if some if you want
to get involved in some
of our micro neural
net stuff there's a
small group of us maybe
reach out to jed
who's been a vocal and
active member of that
committee or we can dream
up new ones let's
create a whole new breed
of models that we
haven't even thought of
we can hallucinate our
way into that space um
yeah discord.agentix
.org yeah thanks everyone
until until next week
okay bye guys bye