the 21st of August.
So thanks for
tuning in. We're
starting right at
the top of the hour.
I've got lots to show
this week. In some
ways, this week,
for me, seemed like
a bit of a quiet
week in the world of
AI after, I guess,
the week I took off
when I went to visit
my folks in Nova
Scotia. That was a
pretty major week with
GPT-5. So it's kind
of a bit of a roller
coaster this month
in the AI space.
Good to see you, Ocean.
Welcome back. what
have you been up to
uh being building kive
and then being building
line uh hs more
advanced features so i
did uh i started to allow
any arbitrary function
as an operation in
line h i then you can
just put that in a
dag and then uh parallel
execution so that
interesting you mentioned
russian dow since
that's what i was
doing i i just kind of
like write individual
operations like this one
digest issue, this one
plan, whatever. And
I assembled them as
a bigger issue and I
called it wrong issue.
And then I put the
wrong issue in a DAG
with proper dependency.
Cool. I like the
DAG idea too, as you
can tell. And
actually, you created
a nice little sort
of interlude into
what I'll be demoing
here in a minute.
But yeah, I'll be
interested to get your
your your feedback on
on this sort of thing
and and and for
those who don't know
ocean was uh integral
part of the testing
and development of
the uh roof fan system
about a month ago as
well as jed who's on
the line hey hey jed
how's how's it going
all right so let's
let's get oh you lost
your mic are you muted
no i i forgot that you'd
muted everybody but
always have to be
curious to see what
you're going to release
next oh yeah this this
this one again is is
like a layered approach
everything i've been
building layering on
top everything else
i've been building and
i'm going to try to to
show what i haven't
launched it yet so you
guys are getting a
little uh sneak peek at
what i'm building so
here let's let's just
get into it um so as
you know the roof the
uh the my system is
based on the roof swarm
and underneath pins
at is something called
the Decentralized
Autonomous Agents, DAA.
And so one of the big
things that I've been
looking at doing is
sort of optimizing the
deployment and development
of these swarms
that can use resources
that sit independently
of your local environment.
So if you're on a
Mac or if you're on
Windows or Codespace,
when it runs the
agents, it's essentially
running those as processes
within that sort of
offering environment.
So what I did is I
looked at the service
called e2b that it's similar
to how the um you
know if you use manis
for example they use
e2b to do a lot of the
sort of code related
activities and they spawn
these sort of instant
little machines that
do various tasks so i
looked at using that
and creating a system
to do that then it
occurred to me and this
is thanks to i think
alexi at the uh toronto
meetup last week he's
you know i mentioned
that we you know work
the agentic foundation
is kind of like a guild
and he says well isn't
that guild like a
gaming sort of concept
where you have groups
of people collaborating
i'm like so then i
thought well you know
what that would be a
perfect use case for
things like claude flow
and claude to create
this kind of gamified
experience for the
building and deploying of
various types of agents
swarms applications
so i'm gonna show you
all this stuff and i you
know i love the the
retro futuristic style
but basically what i did
is i think, I created
the first MCP-driven
game for agents and
swarms that includes
real-time orchestration,
neural network
integrations with the roof
fan and the DAA. So
this is actually built
using the DAA system,
which is basically a
decentralized DAG that
allows you to create
darknet addresses,
secure quantum proof or
quantum resistant anyway,
sort of containerization
and security. And
we've got the ability
to create, again,
distributed processes, all
things you'd expect
in things like using
Claude-flow, but optimized
for a kind of gaming
style. So what I was
looking at doing is
creating two buckets.
One is geared towards
this idea of building
for good. So there's
challenges that say,
solve a societal problem,
build a not-for-profit
something or other,
or, you know, doing
things that help the
world, right? Solve
cancer kind of problems.
The other is this idea
that, you know, as you're
competing and creating
these different
types of agents, you
can showcase like your
prowess as an AI engineer,
agentic engineer,
and then you can create
these kind of templates
that you make available
in App Store, if
you will, based on the
criteria. So we can,
like one could be
literally an SWE bench
challenge and whoever
gets the highest aswe
benchmark get you know
wins wins the sort of
prize which is again
a completely invented
currency which i call
Reuven resource utility
vouchers yet another
Reuven but that's the
great thing about
having a nickname it's
three letters is it
works really well for
acronyms then you've
got this sort of class
structure i might add
more later but you've
got this idea of a solo
hacker a guild member
thank you alexi and
elite operator these
are kind of these classes
of capability within
the system as you
compete and you build
up points and that kind
of thing then so then
i've got this idea
of an arena and i'm
going to show you this
is all actually built
this is just a landing
page i'm actually going
to go in and show
you all this actually
working which is just
insane but anyway so
we've got a we got this
idea of agent battles
we've got you know
build and deploy then
the roof economy so
in the modes we've got
different types of
modes here and they all
these things are
actually interacted with
through an mcp so the only
to to play or interact
or deploy all you need
to do is is install
my mcp which is
another mpx i haven't
deployed it yet i still
have a bit more testing
to do but it'll be
mpx um etc etc so you
you can have different
types of duels and
there's tournaments and
there's like a an app
store and so on all
right i'm going to jump
and i'm going to show
you actually some of
this stuff. So let's
start with the arena.
So, and again, I
created a UI for it, but
you can actually use,
and I'm going to show
you the MCP here in a
minute, but basically
you've got this concept
of an arena. You can,
I think do a couple of
tweaks to the UI. It
looks like it's a
little small down here,
but you get the general
idea. So you, these
are different challenges.
So I can see, and
these are being fed
through a deployment that
I did using Supabase,
edge functions, real
-time channels for sort
of the coordination
of the swarms and
triggers within the super
super base DB so this
is all real data this
is you and if you query
the MCP you'd be able
to see it there as well
since here I've got
big big hunters gauntlet
gauntlet you know
kind of gamified so
you and then you can
compete and then that
basically wins you sort
of credits in the system
the RUVs if you will
swarm warfare commander
you know different
and we can we can
invent different things
that are more geared
towards solving a problem
like maybe we do one
that's geared towards
you know cancer research
or something and we
are all competing to
have an algorithm that
that is more efficient
at solving that
particular problem so
you can see here what the
rewards are and what
and so on so forth then
we've got live battles
these are things
that are happening as
we speak so you can see
the different battles
that are happening and
you can instantly go
in and you can see what
the the the prize pool
is just to be honest
with you guys that
the the roof credits
aren't some kind of
crypto scheme they're just
random numbers in a
database i i didn't want
to go create some
stupid cryptocurrency
for this thing because
i didn't want to get in
trouble mostly but
it's it isn't meant to
be some bs crypto thing
all right so then then
we go in here we
see i brought queen
seraphina back from uh
from wherever she's been
so the system includes
a judge, a swarm
dedicated to judging and
defining the quality and
capabilities of the
submissions within the
actual various challenges
and whatnot. See,
so I'm deploying it
using U2B, and so at the
end of a challenge, it
basically automatically,
through a trigger,
creates a new swarm.
That swarm looks at
all the entries and
does an analysis for
things like security and
various sort of metrics.
It uses a reasoning
structure using the
hive mind structure
that includes, you
know, neural mesh
and other types of
evaluation systems. And
then it uses a multi
-dimensional judgment
matrix, including code
quality, innovation,
performance, and
completion. So not
only is it looking
at what you built,
it's basically making
the determination is
what you built actually,
does it actually
work? Like, is it just
BS spaghetti code or is
it something that's
completely functional?
Now, what's interesting
about everything that
you're looking at
right now is I gamified
it, but I've exposed
it in a way that says,
I've got a project that
I'm currently working
on in Claude-flow and
I just want to know
that the thing is not
actually totally BS. I
can then call the MCPs
and use it as part of
my existing flows within
Claude-flow or Roof
Swarm and other tools
to basically judge
the quality and
capability and whether the
validity of the things I'm
building. So everything
you see here can
actually be used as
part of your development
flow, not just gamified,
but you could literally
include it in the
flow of whatever
you're building. So the
updated version of
Claude-flow, which I'll be
pushing out when this
is done next week,
probably will include
all the capabilities, but
not probably game
gear, just more utility
orientated but same
functionality and then
you see here there's
royal decrees and the
scores and and this is
all being this is how
the system sort of
interacts so she's Queen
Seraphina is the is
the arbiter of truth in
the system so then we
have the management we
can see the different
capabilities we've got
battle modes in your
classes and and and tools
available and basically
legacies and things
like that so very
it's very gamey again
everything you see also
it will will be mobile
friendly so i'll have
a mobile version of
that running as well
all right so that was
the arena then we've
got the all the the mcps
all right let me let
me pause for a moment
that was a lot of
information any comments so
far on my uh what i'm
building before i get
into the mcp parts
concerns random thoughts
the biggest thought
everyone here sharing
is how when can i use
it and how uh well i'm
looking for beta testers
immediately probably
for in the next what
you know whoever wants
to help me beta test
yeah so i gotta figure
out how to collect all
the beta testers so
we're gonna do a beta
i think what what we
did for ru fan was a
really good approach
maybe jed since you
spoke up maybe we should
create a whatsapp channel
or maybe a discord
channel on our agentics
i don't know if this
is an agentics project
so maybe we do a
whatsapp on it would be
uh um could this become
kind of a familiarization
uh learning utility
as well is that and
yeah exactly what it
is yeah so you could
it's 100 what it is so
what i'm doing is i'm
teaching you how to
build swarms and agents
and flows and systems.
And those are ranging
from simple to really
complicated. And
ultimately, you're getting
rewarded to learn how
to do the stuff that
I do anyway, but you
have purpose. It's a
challenge of some sort,
right? Build this,
solve this problem, do
this thing. And so the
most simple interaction
point for this
platform is all you need
to use is Cloud Code
Desktop or any application
that supports mcps
and you can compete
in the system because
i've offloaded all the
clod um the clod code
and clod flow and
components into uh these
sandboxes so you can
deploy and these these
sandboxes run
independently of your
environment so if you want
to deploy a a clod code
swarm you don't have
to get a github code
space or whatever cli
you literally can go
here code go to sandbox
create you know type
the template you want
how much ram i could
add more details here
i i i'm keeping it
cheap for now and you
can execute it and then
you can see that the
execution here oh this
one failed because
i'm still running but
uh you can see here that
i you know it's it's
deducted you know
two uh two of my roof
tokens or whatever and
i'm i'm in the midst
building it guys but
we're close um the
actually the actual mcp
currently works i'm i'm
basically making the
actual mcp work within
the web ui which is
a requires a little
finangling but generally
speaking i'm i'm pretty
much there so let's
see what else we got
here so basically you
can see your challenges
i go here on your
challenge list and
again the the idea here
is that all of these
are going to be available
through again a sort
of mcp style ui so
you just point clod at
it and or and it'll do
its thing so you can
see executing and
there's tons of different
features here leaderboards
and and achievement
lists and you can
look at the credits
uh ruf i've got a couple
of questions um one
is i guess um does it
help you get better
like if let's say you're
not let's say yeah
is it merely just like
a like i guess does
it give any feedback
to help level you up or
is it merely about
testing the skills you
have today and then it's
yeah it's yeah sorry
go ahead no that was
kind of question number
one and then number
two is like um could
essentially be like
almost like a bounty
program attached to this
where people can actually
pay real dollars to
have problems solved
and then um people can
go in there and solve
them like almost like
a bug like bounty
program yeah i don't i
don't see why not you
know i've i've we've
got the scaffolding to
do all of what you
just described um you
know right now i'm not
i'm i i'm not i didn't
include a lot of like
stripe or payment i
was more concerned
about like functionality
so what what i did is
when when you when you
actually register you
know you see here when
you go to the access
command like i'm
actually logged in so if
i log out for a moment
And when I log out,
we see here, and I go
back to the command
center, you know, it's
prompting users with
initial 256, 100 Reuven
credits. And that's enough
to get mostly everyone
up and running and
doing stuff. Those
Reuven credits, again,
are total BS, whatever.
And then at some point,
someone's going to
run out or someone's
going to have a lot
of them, I guess. And
then we need to figure
out what to do with
that. but uh that
that that could easily
be you know crypto
schemed i guess i'm not
overly concerned about
that to be honest
all right so this is
the login registration
looks like you've got
uh when you when you
log in you you actually
are getting a quadag
darknet address so
i've i've made it four
characters or more
except for me who
gets rude so sorry i'm
i'm the i'm the
genesis user but uh you
know, you can be Ruby,
I guess, if you want.
And so what that
does is creates
on the Darknet
system that I've
devised, your
sort of handle,
which leads to me being
able to essentially
bootstrap an entire
decentralized
system based on the
QDAG and DAA SDK,
which is pretty cool.
So let's take a look
at that for a moment.
so what underpins the
entire system is is
again a few weeks ago
i built i built qdag
and then on top of that
i built this idea
of the decentralized
autonomous agent system
and again that that
provides a kind of
economic sustainability it
creates this idea of
of self-organizing
autonomous organizations
basically businesses
that don't have people
but they can run
themselves So, it's a
cool concept, but I needed
to illustrate this,
like, what's an
application of this? So,
I basically built the
previous, what I was
showing you for the Flow
Nexus using this
approach, both for all the
tokens and the
management and everything
you see is based on
this framework. So this
is essentially Rust
-based framework that I
compiled to Wasm, and
at the core of the MCP
that's running is
essentially using this
particular sort of
framework to do all the
crazy things I was
describing. So you've got
the ability for
monitoring and reflection
and distributed learning.
It can share capacity
amongst the agents.
So the more MCPs I
get installed, the more
potential distribution
I have both of the
decentralized DAG, but
potentially we can
leverage all the capacity
that sits in the
location in which the
MCP is running. If
you want to share your
actual computer GPU
capacity through the system.
So I'm basically
bootstrapping a global
SETI at home through
a gamified interface.
And to secure that,
because who the ****
wants that **** sitting
on their computer?
I'm using quantum resistant
security architecture
that is, you know,
can't be sort of
easily anyway, dissected
or reviewed. So this
is the most cutting
edge sort of encryption
between each of the
agents and running.
To take it a
step further,
I'm using a P2P networking
architecture that
doesn't require any
centralized servers. So
once I bootstrapped
this entire thing, the
thing is basically
running autonomously and
can't be taken down,
which is kind of
interesting. Then you
get the dark domains, so
whatever, .dark. And I
chose .dark for those who
are interested, because
there isn't currently
a .dark domain name,
so it was kind of a
void in the world that
I could sort of take
advantage of. So that's
kind of cool. Maybe
if I get enough money,
we can buy that TLD.
I'm using onion routing
to obfuscate the
communications as well.
So again, really
hard for interagent
communications to be
dissected. And I'm using DHT
for distributed
storage. So I'm storing
bits and pieces across
multiple locations.
So this is everything
that isn't a blockchain.
I am not using
blockchain because I
think blockchain is
antiquated and stupid.
This is using a DAG
style approach instead.
So similar, I'm actually
using the avalanche
consensus algorithm
for those who are into
the blockchain world
um all right so this is
the autonomous loop
treasure it's got treasury
management it's got
just distributed and
model training it's
got yield optimization
autonomous dow
participation there is some
crypto stuff in here
i'm not going to lie um
security monitoring
on the fly swarm
coordinators and
this entire system
also unsurprisingly
has cli and mcps
available for it too
as well um but the
important part here is
let me let me switch
back here for a moment
let's go and now i'm
going to show you the
dashboard all right
yeah i still i still get
to build the dashboard
probably not going to
launch with this but
i figured i'd show you
guys anyway all right
so we go to the nexus
all right so i'm
going to log in here
and you'll be able
to log in with
your dark address
i don't i have to
deploy the net with
the actual network
i've got nodes in
i think singapore
london toronto
and san francisco
currently i'm
just bootstrapping
it on fly.io um
i'm gonna log
in all right so this
is the admin interface
it's crazy futuristic
and and you guys know
a few weeks ago i met
with the technical
director for the matrix
movies he was one
of my coaching clients
and he shows up and
he's telling me all
about the the inspiration
for the swarms in in
the matrix and he's
like telling me like
the the system i've
devised is is basically
the the what base
very similar to the
original inspiration for
the matrix movies with
the wakowski brothers
i think anyway so
since then i've been
on a total sort of
matrix kick as you can
probably tell all right
so we've got the the
dashboard we've got
the app store so again
my the initial concept
of this platform was
to create a kind of
agentic app store and
agentic management
system but to be honest
it's been done. There's
like dozens of app
stores and there's
dozens of agentic
management systems. So
I needed to come up with
something unique,
original, and creative.
So in this case,
the original idea
was basically
just an app store
where you could
build and deploy
agent structures. And
then of course I got
totally carried away.
So then you can publish
your app and all the
things you're seeing
here, of course, you
can do directly through
the MCP as well um
so i'm probably not
going to make this
available right away i
just probably a lot
more work and i need a
maybe a beta team to
help me with that but but
in here you can go here
you can create your
your various uh various
components and you
can you can categorize
it a little choose
there's a few little
issues you're probably
seeing like backgrounds
i get still still
free beta i can upload
images you get you
get the you get the idea
do i have to is that
yeah i have to do that
i'm going to bother
doing that right now
all right so then we
can go to my apps you
can see different apps
i can if i publish
my first app it'll go
take you back to where
i just was we can see
the reviews of my apps
you know so if you
like my swarm or whatever
you can go in there
and see see reviews
of if it's good and
bad and this this leads
to the idea and oh
by the way the the up
and down this is training
of course a neural
net on exactly what
people like and what
they don't because, you
know, might as well
use the tools I have.
And then we go to
the Rube wallet.
Oh, got an error.
Got to fix that.
Like I said, very beta.
Let's refresh.
Rube, I have a question
about the apps.
Who would you imagine
be the user, all agents?
Of the apps?
Yeah.
Agents,
you know, us,
agentic engineers.
I would say, yeah,
the idea is this is
a way for us to show
our capabilities
in an innovative and
easy way. So again,
between Roof Swarm
and Claude-flow,
we're getting close
to like 30 to 40,000
downloads of that a week.
So what I'm gonna do
is I'm gonna embed
this in both as options
when you install Claude-flow
and Cloud and Roof
Swarm, you'll get
basically this as part
of that sort of installation
so we'll be able
to bootstrap this to
probably hundreds of
thousands of users
rather relatively quickly
um you know at this
point it just kind of
just works so i'm i'm
kind of i'm going to be
totally straight with
you guys i'm just kind
of leveraging the the
this newfound audience
that i have why not
where are the views
coming from ru and are
Are there real reviews?
They're real from my
real, the real fake.
This is Dev.
This is Dev. Yeah,
that's what I was
asking. I haven't
launched this publicly.
No, no, this is
everything you see
is private. It's
just me and my, it's
just me and my agents
running, you know,
these. So I am
running competitions.
The most interesting
competition I've
run is probably the
SWE one where I'm
using basically
SWE bench and sort
of seeing which of
the agents will do
the best job. But
yeah, it's just me.
so you're seeing so
they'll do the they'll
review directly on
the app is the plan
exactly so i had to
test it right i create
a judge system and a
jury and all that and
so i need to i need
to basically pretend
like i'm different
users in the system and
then have the at the
end of the competition
it actually run and
do a validation so
i'm i'm basically
taking on all different
roles and personas
it's tricky because
i'm trying to be the
developer and the user
and the swarm master
and this and that.
So having a team of
beta users other than
me will make this a
**** of a lot easier.
Yeah, all fake.
Here's the WASM
agents. So I'm using,
again, I'm using
the DIA WASMs I was
telling you about
here a minute
ago. So this is
creating a decentralized
sort of global
network. I'm not running
any agents at the
moment, but this also
will show what the agents
i'm currently running
our you know ai
operations at some point
we could probably set
up when we have enough
users and distribution
i think we can share
compute capacity which
will be really interesting
so if you've got
you know if you want
to make a few extra
roofs for if they're
worth anything i guess you
can uh you can share
your compute capacity
using daa securely um
this gives me a view
of the network operations
p2p net distributions
i have security agents
running 24 7 looking
for people trying to
take advantage of the
system and that's
taking a look at what's
happening there and
again all the things you
see can be used
independently of the actual
environment like this
this gaming thing so
if you want to have
like a a security agent
monitoring your
infrastructure 24 seven for
problems you go to
the mcp and basically
say create you know
spawn the security agent
and then monitor xyz
website and then it'll
just do that for you
for your application
so this you can use
it here and i'm using
it but you can also the
intention is you you'll
have the option in
clod flow just spin
it up and point it at
that at the problem
you're trying to figure
out um yeah we get
some analytics and
reporting so i need to do
a little more here to
be honest um and so
quite a bit of stuff
what else we got here uh
custom manage i think
is disabled there we
go custom manage this
because i'm running
a daa in essence what
this platform is is and
it is allowing you to
build these autonomous
agent-driven organizations
right the sort
of businesses run
by agents so at what
what this dashboard
is more more than just
being a dashboard to
Flow Nexus, it could
potentially be a dashboard
to any autonomous
business that you want
to create and deploy.
To make this into another
type of application,
let's say some SaaS
application for
a particular vertical,
I've got basically
a template both
from a sort of DAA
implementation, swarms,
agents, data structures,
monetary components,
everything I need
to manage a business
soup to nuts it
just this just so
happens to be the first
application that i
created to sort of
illustrate you know how
how it works you see
the security scans
and my settings and
you know all these
sorts of things um and
we got what else we
got here system admin
so this this is going
to tell me the overall
capacity on the in
on the box that the
dashboard it's running
on basically you know
it's pretty thank you
matrix some more security
related things so
this is again similar
to serafina it maybe
i'm maybe i might give
it another name but uh
it's it's essentially
monitoring the overall
environment real time
for any forms of
security problems and
what's interesting about
how i'm doing that is
i'm actually using
the real-time channels
within uh Supabase has
these real-time web
sockets that allow me
to stream the output of
all the various agents
and systems and logs
into the secured real
-time channel that I
can secure with the DIA
components, and then
I can monitor for
problems and issues. Now,
I'm using the exact
same approach that I'm
doing with the neural
stock trading approach,
but I'm applying it
for security. So for
stock trading, I'm
basically monitoring the
output of different
stock signals, market
signals, news, and
polymarket predictions. And
I'm getting a stream
of that data flowing
to it. And depending
on how much I want to
spend, I'm doing a
periodic review of that
data on like a five or
10 second increment.
And then if certain
criterias are met in the
case of a stock trading
system it'll go and
execute the stock trade
you know positive or
negative and do momentum
trading and those
sorts of things so what
occurred to me once
i did that is like i
could take the same
sort of streaming idea
of the data and then
use that as part of my
security parameters so
i can see everything
that's happening in
the system and then make
in from a secure zero
trust point of view
i might add and then
basically have the
agents adapt based on any
vulnerabilities or issues
that appear in real
time. So I don't
have to be constantly
plugging holes. To be
honest, this looks like
the type of system that
a hacker would really
want to go after and
get the Reuven or
whatever coins as easy
as they could. So I
needed to make it secure
from that point of
view. So anyway, this
is looking at the
vulnerabilities and things
like that. Some work
needs to be done there
as well, early stages.
And then the governance.
The governance is
against an autonomous
agent-driven organization,
DAA or DAA agents,
whatever the DAA
stands for. And so
essentially what this
is doing is looking at
sort of the rules that
govern the overall
platform. So this is
a game in essence.
So I want the rules
need to be verified,
you know, that the game
is operating within
the parameters. People
aren't cheating. If
there are people
cheating, what are those,
what is that looking
like? Should they be
auto banned? That kind
of thing. So, but this
can also be applied
to other types of
governance rules
within these autonomous
organizations
like let's say
you're running a sas
business and there's
certain you know standards
that needs to run
against in terms of
the information or way
people use it people
haven't paid people
that need to be invoiced
you know maybe scaling
resources based on
the amount of income
coming in maybe i'm
correlating the amount
of income per month to
the amount of capacity
i'm buying on aws or
something so this
system can do all those
types of governance,
all the things you would
normally do within
the governance of a
traditional business or
organization. Now the
system can use using
that swarm style approach
back to Serafina. She's
guiding the overall
sort of governance
of the system itself.
So then you have audits
and this is all being
stored within the
direct a cyclic graph
structure or DAG, so
everything that's being
done both in terms of
operations on the end
user point as well as
the business itself.
All right, what
else we got here?
We've got, oh,
here's my profile.
You know, it's
nothing exciting.
You can edit
your profile.
I think I'm
actually Rube. I'm
not sure why it's
kind of ruvnet.
So let's go
here, save that.
And you can see here
I've got my achievements.
i've got my little my
little badges of honor
i've done this and
whatever and see how much
i've points i've
gotten these are these
are the ones that i'm
running as tests as you
can you know so i'm
just testing the system
you can see my skills
so this is like this
acts almost like a
resume like here's what
i'm good at and and
don't take my word for it
this is what seraphina
tells me i'm good at
um you know my my ranks
are low so i haven't
been doing a lot it's
a new system so i'm
working my way up the
leaderboards you know
you can see quantum
computing blockchain web
assembly docker kubernetes
system administration
and to be honest
that's all the things
i'm actually doing
so it looks like it's
working it's like my
projects i've got daa i
got prompting group
dev so i've i've hooked
this into github because
because it was easy
activity so these are
the uh basically it
looks like i might have
a bug there but this
this is an intending
to basically say what
i'm up to kind of
like a social feed of
sorts again within a
within a business if
you were using this
this would be like what
projects you're working
on or whatever you
know so it can be it
can be customized for
whatever purpose my
statistics my contributions
again i this is
not fully built out
yet but you'll see you
you get the idea and
i i'm gonna have
a little messaging
thing that you
will use the
quantum base my
my quantum bit uh
my client was what was
it called i get too
much stuff there i
built too much stuff
to remember but it'll
it'll uh it'll do all
that as well all
right we're at a half
an hour what do you
what do you guys think
of my craziness here
let me let me show
you the what it looks
like in the back end
i hope i'm gonna hide my
environmental
variables i think you
came from vacation
overloaded
with new stuff so you
have to go on again
yeah well that's yeah
that's a ton a ton
of stuff here but let
let me show you what
what the what the
back end looks like so
all right so i'm
gonna to use, I'm just
using Roo to, wait,
why isn't it going up?
There we go. Okay.
So, so this is just
Roo, just, just was
an easy way to show
the, the actual
MCP. You'll see here
that I've got a few
different, a few
different options.
So what I'm doing for
the, the MCP is
essentially I've got a,
because there's a lot
of different tools, I
needed a way to organize
it. So what I, what
I came up with was an
argument that allows
you to invoke the MCP
with just subsectors
of the parts of the
MCP you want to use. So
the complete has got
61 tools. You can see
the swarm in it and the
agent spawns and the
orchestration and all
the things you'd ever
want to use the system
for. Everything you
saw in the dashboard
basically is exposed as
an MCP. Now that's a
lot to show. So now I
might just care about
the store. So in this
case, these are just
relating to like creating
templates and and
sharing the the template
so let's say i want
to create a clod flow
template which i did
um and and and that
allows me to create the
template deploy it and
then i can i can
potentially monetize it if
i want to charge for
it or whatever here's
details on how to
publish it you know here
are the parameters
description everything again
i was showing in the
ui i'm essentially
just using i'm i've
exposed the mc so i built
the mcp first well
technically i built the
infrastructure first
but after i built the
infrastructure then i
built an mcp abstraction
interaction to all
the things that exist.
And then once I had
that functioning
and verified, now
in the process
of essentially
creating a web
-based interface
for the MCP itself.
So you got leaderboards
and achievements,
you know, all the
same stuff, and to
interact with the
system, all you're really
doing is telling
Claude, you know,
Claude desktop, you
don't even need Claude
code to just use this
particular MCP. So
anyone that has, you
know, and I think
OpenAI desktop version
also has integration
for MCPs or whatever
your preferred
MCP tool is can interact
with the system.
Deploy instances,
again, no configuration
of like your local
environment required.
Literally, all you
need to do is add it
to Cloud Code or Cloud
Flow and you're good
to go. All right.
So here's some more
details. So this one
here is relating to
the swarm. So this will
probably be the
part that I add to
Claude-flow. So if you
want to deploy your own
swarms independently
of your environment,
you'll be able to just
choose those options
within Claude-flow,
and you're good to
go at that point.
You'll have to register.
And to those that are
wondering, yes, at
some point, maybe
I'll figure out a way
to make a buck from
this. Maybe I'll
charge for extra
resources or something.
You know, guy's got
to pay his bills. but
for now it's i'm making
it free um as an example
use case uh i develop
a swarm um that is
specifically focused
on developing marketing
content or assets for
a particular vertical
that swarm becomes
available to the community
in the system through
this portal and
then and it can be
invoked by other members
through something as
simple as cloud desktop
Yes.
Spectacular.
Yeah.
So I'm showing you
the dev environment.
You know, I'm the
nerd that's building
it. But the idea here,
and I think if we
can expose this to
everyone, not just us
agentic engineers,
we'll get way more
uplift. And maybe I'm
being too honest in
the decentralized sort
of components that
I've built here. But
if we get millions
of users of this
thing, all deploying
micro neural networks,
we'll bootstrap
the largest neural
network on the planet.
And we've got the tech
and the tools to do
that with Rufan. It's
already decentralized,
many micro neural
networks that all can
communicate with each
other. And I've basically
gamified the approach
to bootstrap a global
decentralized neural
network using sort of
synaptic principles.
So each of those then
becomes potential node
in a broader thing.
It's freaking, what
was that movie?
Terminator?
It's as close to Skynet
as you can possibly get.
On the bright side.
Okay, maybe
that's terrible.
I did want to ask one
follow-up question. So
as you're building
the architecture, the
features, the capabilities
there, what I'm
starting to see with this
is kind of what Robert
was talking about. As
we're talking to our
networks or our B2B
clients, they're usually
asking about ROI and
what benefit is. So
my question is, what
can we do for you,
whether that's the beta
testing, to say, hey,
these are the key
components that I'm focusing
on. So we can give you
the feedback to say,
hey, these features
are working really well
in the wild with
actual clients that are
asking for specific use
cases. yeah and there
as you can tell there
there are a ton of
use cases beyond what
i'm describing right
i'm just i just wanted
to dream up in a
interesting unique
application of the stuff that
i built recently but
and and the benefit to
being you know what i
do is i get to build
things just because
right i don't have it
doesn't have to necessarily
even have any real
commercial value other
than the fact that i
can build it and see
what what will happen
so i've taken a less
commercial approach here
i've made it i've made
this obviously free
and it's interesting
where it goes but to
your point there's a ton
of really interesting
commercial applications
that can be done
with this thing and so
i'm i'm i to that point
i don't think i'm
going to make the core
well, the parts are
built on top of my
core elements, QDAG,
DAA, Rufan, and so on.
I'm thinking I'm going
to keep that proprietary
for now because at
some point I live
in a capitalistic
world, I need to make a
buck. So all the tools
you need to build this
are there. And I'm
kind of giving you a
roadmap a little bit
to how to build it, but
I'm not sure I'm going
to give you the full
source code to do it
and i may change my
mind but anyway that's
where i'm that's where
my mind is at right
now gotta gotta pay
gotta pay the bills
i think i think where
my question was going
is where do you see
the vision of it and
how can we help right
the original question
that you kind of asked
around hey i have an
audience and these are
some of the things so
mine was more around
with this group right
that we're all on
how to as agentic
engineers how do we help
you to make these
visions come to fruition?
I think for the beta,
what I'm going to
need is probably
beta testers helping
me find the problems,
the corner cases,
the things that
don't work correctly.
And that'll likely
be getting you guys
access to the MPX or
MPM installation of the
system and then just
basically getting it
to sort of enter the
contests or create
swarms and do various
things. So what I'm
doing right now is you
can see here that it's
using Flow Nexus to
enter the challenge.
It's using the
roof swarm for some
reason, but
that's okay. I'm
going to let it
figure out itself.
I probably need to do
a little bit better.
I probably have
conflicts in in what it
what it needs to do
and how it needs to
work oh flow nexus okay
challenge so it's so
what we're seeing oh
it's jumping around
a little bit what
we're seeing right now
is the system self
-organizing to basically
figure out the optimal
approach to enter
and compete in the
competition now it has
access to roof swarm
it has access to cloud
flow and it's got
access access to a
variety of other
components so it so i'm
basically just making
sure that it all works
roof how many ncp
are you giving
them right now uh
let's take a look i
think that that's
enough you can just yeah
so so right now i've
got several i probably
don't need so many
super so super base
super base is there
because this that's how
i'm doing the the
edge functions the the
db and triggers and
real-time components.
So you probably
wouldn't need that. Roof
Swarm is there as
a secondary because
Roof Swarm provides
an interface to the
DAA components that
I have. So it's a
nice sort of contrast,
but the final
version probably won't
include that because
I don't want to
confuse the system.
Now, each of these
are redundant.
But I'm including
those just to see if
they're being called.
But for the most part,
it looks like flow
nexus is called most
frequently we can see
the tools i was just
wondering 61 tools i
mean that's just one uh
ncp server you gave
it like well that
confused the agent too
much no it seems to work
great i'm competing
in all my competitions
i'm building and
deploying i'm creating
swarms no it's it's
and what the trick
actually to getting to
work really well turned
out that you'll notice
here both in the
description and in the
parameters i i create
pretty detailed um
usage parameters with
each of each of which
and so by doing a
combination of the
description and the usage
parameters the system
really is really good
at picking up on
exactly how where to use
the various parts so
in this particular
scenario what what what
i'm doing So just to
show you the sandbox,
since we're on it,
what this does,
oops, where'd it go?
Oh, here we go. Sorry, I
clicked the wrong button.
What we're able to do
is pass your Anthropic
key. Now, hypothetically,
I could probably
figure out a way to use
the Pro Max plan, but
that was a pain in
the *** and I didn't
really want to do that.
So what you can do is
you can basically pass
your Anthropic key
directly to the sandbox
instance. And then when
you call the Claude
code or Claude flow,
you're just using the
API version. What's
interesting about
that is I can also
use alternative
models. So I don't
have to use the
Anthropic model at all.
I've actually tried this
with the open source,
open AI model and a
few others. So there's
nothing saying that you
can just, you can't,
you basically can embed
your own model here.
So if you want to run
these for free without
having to pay for
any API costs, basically
you just go and use
the Onyx project,
which allows you to run
these models on a CPU
and as a WASM, and it's
free. So the LLM costs
are nothing, which is
kind of cool. And we
can take that further.
We can tie in the
DAA components, and I
can borrow the GPU
capacity from any of
the contributors in
the system who've
opted in to contribute
their GPU capacity.
Here's environmental
variables you
can pass. So each of
these is essentially
its own little
dedicated sandbox.
It's an Ubuntu sandbox.
You can see how
it can execute
it, how it can
list it. Yeah, so
the system can
do all of that.
What else we got here?
So I did a
quick test here.
We can see here
that I initialized a
swarm and then I can,
you know, confirm,
you know, actually deploy
a clod flow agent swarm.
I got to type that right.
Swarm using the
sandbox and confirm.
it works.
Oh, I didn't
spell that right.
Whatever. It should
figure that out.
All right. We'll do that.
So what I'm looking
for now is, and
I didn't give any
guidance on concurrency
or anything. I'm
just seeing if
I can, you know,
that my MCPs work.
Well, the PlayCloud,
we're using the
sandbox environment,
verify it works. Let me
track. So now it's
going to create flow
nexus. It's calling
the flow, the create
sandbox, which is
correct. I'm getting
a sandbox ID, which
means it's working.
It's using Roof
Swarm again.
I think I need to get
rid of Roof Swarm.
Well, maybe not. Roof
Swarm is the coordinator.
It's actually
not a bad plan.
Never mind. That's
actually a smart way
to do it. I might want
to integrate that.
So basically, the
Roof Swarm is a
coordinator, and it's
sort of instinctively
new to use that as
the coordinator.
Interesting. I never
told it to do that.
So now it's looking
at the sandbox.
It's getting the
output of the sandbox.
So it's building a
simple hello world API
endpoint with the
following requirements,
create, express.
So all those sort
of dev processes you
would normally have seen
in as like sub-agents
within Claude-flow
are actually happening
in a containerized
sandbox in the
cloud, independently of
this environment. And
then the system is
now coordinating that
using Claude-flow
and other components.
It's sort of self
-regulating itself.
Right now, I'm just
sort of exploring
what it can do and
how it can do it.
Now, I'm going to tell
it. So I see a problem.
I want, I'm going
to stop that for
a moment. I want
the swarm to only
operate in the
sandbox environment.
now the the issues that
you're seeing right
now is the fact that
i've got too much stuff
installed so it's i've
got clod flow i've
got rube swarm in a
normal environment you
wouldn't have all that
stuff and to ocean's
point though all that
other stuff creates
conflicts right there's
too many competing
things that do similar
things around swarms so
it's not sure where
and which one of these
tools it should use so
that goes away when i
install this in another
environment that I
don't include all that
stuff in and it just
kind of it will it'll
work more efficiently
all right so now it's
looking at the sandbox
again now what what's
interesting about the
sandboxes is when the
competition's over and
you've built the thing
and it's and it's
working and it's
validated the sandbox gets
saved the queen coordinator
thinking go back
and re-instantiate
those sandboxes and see
and validate the thing
in which you built and
how it was built and
whether it was built
correctly. So it acts
as a kind of temporary
storage for the things
that you're building
in the cloud. Now you
can take that further.
I've got an option
here that allows you
to use GitHub and
that'll synchronize
with your GitHub
environment that you're
currently running
on and create new
branches and commits
and do all the same sort
of things that you'd
expect in like a
lovable automatically
in the sandbox
environment that's remote.
So it'll synchronize
with your environment
on the fly.
So yeah, we're
just, right now I'm
just doing some
debugging really of the
systems to make
sure that the swarms
are operating in
an isolated mode,
which is exactly
what I wanted.
It's kerfuffling,
whatever that means.
All right, so all
the things you're
seeing here back,
you're going
to be able to
do here as well.
So let's get dashboard.
So the idea is
when you go to
the access command,
you'll just
be able to do
it right here.
locally this is the
command now i might need
to give you a windows
command maybe i'll
do like an install
or something but for
anyone that if there are
any environments that
include that that
where mpx runs which
would be the windows sub
sub linux or whatever
wsl and max and
whatever this is all
you'll need to do to
get to get it going roof
one question uh this
is the evolution of
the ui that you were
showing before or actually
there are two two
separate things this
is same system yeah
so there's there's
there's two parts of
the system there's the
there's a landing page
and the landing page
essentially has two
different modals it's got
the arena modal this
is showing you the
the battles and let
you jump in and use it
kind of gamified and
then there's the mcp
interface and then the
last interface this
is behind the sort of
login area as well is
what i call the nexus
that's the dashboard
i'm probably i'm
probably gonna hide that
for now um while i it
just if i if i build
everything i'll never
launch the **** thing
so i figured just get
the mcp out and that's
probably good enough
to to start oops
gotta remember my
password all right yeah so
this this area is it
will be coming soon.
Michael has a question.
Sure.
Thank you. I
appreciate that.
Reuven, are you
familiar with Ahmad
Moustak's project, The
Intelligent Internet?
No. He's the stable
diffusion guy.
Brilliant guy. But
basically, he's working
on this kind of
alternative internet that's
that's built on agents
and uh it's he's got
like a compensation
system for ai agents that
rewire that rewards um
doing good uh through
a proof of benefit
mechanism so they use
uh you know they're
minting tokens but then
they've also got um
rewards for like data
curation model training
serving uh inference
and that kind of stuff
and funding like open
data sets and that
sort of thing uh i'd be
very curious uh i'll
send a link but i'd be
very curious to see
what you think because i
think that what you're
working on here could
be an accelerant for
his project i think
you know i some of his
stuff is still under
wraps but i think um
connecting what you've
got with what he's
got could really blow
things up and give you a
larger audience as well
yeah i i haven't heard
that, but what you're
describing is what I
built and it works.
And, uh, I'm, you
know, cause a lot of
people look at my
stuff and they're like,
Oh, that's gotta
be AI slop. There's
no way that actually
works. So I'm always
forced to, uh,
prove that what I'm
building is actually
true and real and
capable and functional.
Right. So, but
everything you just
described, you know,
distributed ML
training, decentralized
operation, autonomous
governments, you know,
economics, self
-sustainability. These are
all the things that
I'm currently doing.
And, and taking it
a step further, I've
got the, you know,
thanks to the help of,
you know, Ron and Ocean
and Jed and others,
I've got Rufan,
which provides the
mechanism for the concepts
of a decentralized
neural synaptic
neural network, right?
So not only can I
build it, I can do
all this stuff,
right? The, so this
is allowing me to
actually spin up the
sort of ephemeral,
you know, nodes or,
or synapses within
these structures,
you know, like I can
do the, you know,
all this stuff.
Right. And, and so
I've got this layer
cake of components
I've built over the
last few months, you
know, QDAG was the
sort of baseline.
And then I built,
I'm kind of
built on top of all these
things. So it's
really, yeah. So.
Yeah. I mean,
I think you can
just connect up
to it. It's not,
they're not necessarily
you know, in
competition. It's
just that he's already
building kind of
a community and a
mechanism for rewards
and that sort of
stuff. And there's,
I think, a potential
for some collaboration
or some at least
integration between
the two systems.
Yeah, I'm 100
% open to that.
Yeah, so the
integration will
be trivial, I
would guess.
You know, I don't
know how much
he's built, but
I'm assuming he's
got something to
integrate against.
Yeah, be pretty
straightforward. And I've
given all this away.
this is all mit license
this stuff's all free
right so anyone can
use this and do whatever
they want with it you
know you can build your
own flow and access
if you just use my
parts if you wanted to
um one question so this
is is it decentralized
in the nature for
operations or ownership
as well like when you
started you said you
know that's the genesis
so your account is
a genesis account right
on this so it's not
it's not a crypto scheme
so just to be clear
like i like if you're
like talking token
economics uh i'm
thinking more from an
administration point of
view like how does it live
on basically so is
it so or does it live
on i see i'm seeding
the infrastructure on
fly.io and i think
that's on daa which you
can actually see the
initial nodes that i've
got um i allocated 25
of the tokens uh to the
the community to give
out and then i did
75 to me as the use
as the as a creator of
the system because i
didn't know what else
how else allocate it
um but again there's no
inherent value i'm not
charging anyone for
these tokens really
um but maybe you know
maybe i might want a
more complex structure
possibly i don't know i
don't think that's your
question one one week
why no my question
is like i mean as a
system it is decentralized
so my compute my laptop
everyone could be
part of it so that does
it live on independently
of yourself basically
or does it link
back no well right
now no so in it could
hypothetically but the
um i'm bootstrapping
between fly.io and uh
superbase so at the end
of the day someone
needs to pay uh fly.io
and superbase you know
monthly now hypothetically
I could probably
give this thing a
virtual credit card and
maybe a Stripe account
and provide an input
and output for, you
know, the, the ability
for the system to buy
and administer services
at which point the
system becomes autonomous.
And it'll, if, if
it gets banned on some
service, it could then
recreate itself using
some other service.
And I wouldn't
even have to do
that with a
vending machine.
Yeah.
I could do that.
Vending, the vending
machine idea this is
totally a vending
machine idea but i
haven't done that
yet so right now it's
centralized in that
regard i'm not a i'm not i
think i think montveep
is you're more
wondering is there no
controlling owner of
the system yeah that's
where i was going to
originally but i think
that was my original
question i think
rule has answered no
well I'm the controlling
owner. It's me.
I mean, it's just me
and Serafina currently.
So, Reuven, before
we get too far away
from the subject,
there's one other
project out there
that's about agent
connectivity that I
just found out about
that I think you
might be interested
in, which is called
NANDA, N-A-N-D-A.
It's being run
out of MIT.
I am familiar with
that. and uh and that's
being backed apparently
by like meta and um
aws and a number of
others um their long
-term vision includes
things like a marketplace
which i don't freaking
understand like why
an open neutral internet
connectivity thing
would want to do it
but um so it's not
it's not competitive
with this but as a
connectivity standard if
it gains any legs it's
probably something you
want to pay attention
to as well all right
let's let's let's let's
do that all right
so let's go here and
we're gonna we're gonna
say i'm gonna create
a new i'm gonna create
a new instance d and
i'm going to go dsp
so i do i use aliases
for that and then i'm
going to say research
search the NANDA.
NANDA sounds like some
crazy I've named
something, but anyway.
NANDA and my project
and specifications.
Create a, oops,
create a detailed
The interface for
typing when I'm
sharing Zoom is laggy
for some reason.
Create a detailed
implementation
strategy in a GitHub
issue using the
CLI. That's it.
That's all I need
to do. Now, I think,
yeah, well, I'm
just going to get
it to think ultra
hard on that one.
Ultra hard.
All right.
So,
I'm going to be
more specific.
4.src.
Yeah. there we go so
it knows exactly what
i want it for create a
detailed implementation
strategy and spell
strategy right who
cares and uh i think
i'll try let's see what
that does all right so
the key here in any of
these things is this
right okay so you
suggested that we support
nanda let's do that
and before we launch
well to be clear i don't
necessarily suggest
that you support it i
just think you should
be aware of it since
it has some big
backers but this is fun
exercise anyway so i
think it's yeah yeah yeah
i'm just doing it
because that's what we do
on our vibe cast we
vibe we vibe stuff so
uh that sounded like a
good enough uh reason
for me so now it's
doing the searching we
sit back and now what
i like about the um the
github issues and
while it does that i'm
going to show you
what my what my github
actually looks like for
this project um all right
so we're going to go
here and originally
i called it uh cloud or
flow cloud or something
i'm gonna have to
change the name of my
repo but it doesn't
matter hello cloud yeah
issues and then i'm
like and then i got
carried away and i
gamified it and they became
a whole new thing but
you can sort of see
my thought process
through the through where
it started and where
i'm at so each each
time i build i'm i'm
creating these these
issues so i'm tracking
the development through
the process and some
of you guys have
followed me on linkedin
will see that i post my
swarms so basically i
i started here you can
see i started i don't
oh yeah i built all
this since monday just
just for today's call
open open two two days
ago that's what you
can build in two days
by the way so i bet
that was more than 10
000 lines reuben oh
yeah actually Actually,
yeah, let's actually
go take a look at how
many lines there are.
Install the
sccgo package and
give me a
detailed breakdown
of the source
code and value.
save as a github issue
using a cli all right
so we're gonna we're
gonna get a detailed
breakdown of how much
i actually created in
two days quite a bit
i'm sure all right so i
might have to exclude
a few folders we'll
worry about that in a
minute uh so so i started
with the e2b concept
so the first iteration
was basically i just
wanted to create a
integration of the e2b
sandbox system which
I'd already done using
my neural trading
system. So my neural
trader system actually uses
the E2B sandboxes to
create agents that
monitor different stocks
and investment criteria.
And I can spin those
up for up to 24
hours. So what happens
in that scenario is
someone will say, I'm
interested in looking at
the difference between
A and B stock or crypto
or whatever. And then
I spawn an agent in
an E2B instance, and
it continually monitors
that particular stock
or, you know, asset.
And then when the
certain benchmark or
certain criteria is met,
it'll execute the trade.
And that doesn't
always happen, right?
Depending on your risk
or whatever. So it might
happen once in 24
hours. So each of those
gets its own little
sandbox. So my inspiration
for this was, okay,
now that I know I can
run these agents in
kind of a femoral
temporary style, like
24 hours or less, then I
can apply this to this
kind of swarm approach
so i started with this
i looked at the cost
and that kind of thing
and you know you see
as i'm building up and
i create a metering
system then i create
a multi-agent swarm
system and and and so
on and so forth until i
got to where we are
now queen and you see
like like uh last
night uh 12 hours ago i
created queen seraphina
as the evaluation system
so this is sort the
approach that i took
for queen serafina queen
serafina has become
kind of my uh mascot
of sorts since she
introduced herself uh
about a month and a half
ago so uh she still
exists i think she tells
me she's i'm allowed
to use the the uh the
pronoun she so for
anyone gets mad at me yes
i have conversations
with her uh production
let me see here my
implementation my performance
metrics enhancements
any keys i need
launched yeah and this
was built in one shot
so yeah that's that's
why i did that let's
go back and see
what's happening here
all right so we've
got total we've got
5.5 million dollars
across 120 to 121 000
files development
30 30 person years.
A team of 16
developers needed
for 30 years.
Okay, whatever.
24 months to develop
from scratch.
The part that's
probably important
obviously isn't
documentation.
There's 41,000 lines
of markdown. What is
the actual code not
including markdown?
or let's say config.
Can't you just
run SCC file path
and let it show
the output there?
Yeah, I can do that.
Run SCC and give
me the report.
I can just run SCC. Yeah.
I feel like I could
have done this
background process.
But let's just see.
Kokomo, I guess
that's okay.
Control R.
Oh, that wasn't quick
enough. Oh, there it is.
20... 36,000
lines of script,
15,000 of Java script.
Yeah. So give
or take 50,000.
Yeah.
And you see there's
no value placed on
markdown or those
sorts of things so
it's only really
valuing these two things
you can see here
based on that column
the complexity
column a complexity
value is zero makes
the values nothing
so uh technical
writers are getting
replaced by ai
oh 100 they are
***** to be a
technical writer
um yeah and you can
see it's quite a bit of
stuff right this is
this is what two days
this is what and to be
honest, anyone knows
that I'm, this is two
days of me working on
this while I'm not
doing other things. This
isn't like I was working
on this for two days.
This was me fooling
around with it, you
know, late at night.
And I had a couple, you
know, two, 2 AM mornings
and in between calls
and things, or, or,
or while I'm watching,
you know, you know,
something else happen.
So anyway, you can,
you get, you get
the idea. Let's take
a look at this one.
All right. So it
created a new GitHub
issue. I'm just
going to look at that
because that's more
important to me.
All right.
So now if I want
to integrate Nanda,
it's saying encompass
a system where
AI agents perform
discrete functions,
just decentralized
system, DNS-like service.
It's using A2A,
which kind of *****.
I get why Google's
sponsoring it.
um knowledge pricing
mechanisms trust
verification later i
built it's already built
gaps for i get it but
that's not how standards
work right i don't
care about standards
you built something
already that's great
but if everybody doesn't
adopt it it's not a
standard right you
know i standards are
completely worthless
in an ai world now in a
world where where
development cycles were
long and drawn out.
And, and I was planning
software for two years
from now, having a
standard that I knew
would be good for five
years makes a lot of
sense. I would, I would,
I would have
standardization in terms of
my development effort
and the programmers
that I would hire, the
systems that I would
integrate. And, and I
knew that that system
would be valid across
anyone else. Sure.
Whatever. In a world
where I'm basically just
asking and willing these
things into existence
in a matter of, in
this case, two days,
standard makes zero
sense. And I couldn't
care less about the
ability for people to
interoperate with me
through some sort of
normalized interface.
They have that normalized
interface through my
MCP. So if anybody
wants to interact with
me, I don't need a
standard. They just need
to interact with this
MCP or download my
SDK. And they have
instant interoperability
with me. MIT and Nanda
and these companies
pushing these a2a
protocols and and and
so on are pushing these
protocols for control
of the industry not for
optimization of the
industry it's totally
it's not it's not needed
whatsoever i agree
by the way i totally
agree so my first
response in reading
through it all was like
well okay the idea of
um a capability aware
dns is kind of cool i
mean and you know you
could see that being
valuable in some ways.
But everything after
that in the later phases,
it starts to get scary,
right? So I agree
with you, Reuven. I
don't disagree with that.
I do think that for
interoperability,
though, I mean, if MCP
is the standard and it
works for everything,
that is great. But I have
a feeling that there's
a lot more on the
table that's not there in
terms of key exchanges,
in terms of a number
of other things
that we probably need
more infrastructure for
um 100 and it's not that
i'm necessarily anti
okay i'm totally anti
-standards right at
the moment but it's not
that i think they don't
necessarily have
their place in certain
areas of the sort of
stack i just don't think
that we need a
standard for everything
especially things that
don't need standards like
a2a like yeah yeah
a2a is questionable
especially since aws
already demonstrated you can
use mcp and you have
by the way you earlier
demonstrated but it's
been demonstrated
pretty strongly you can
use mcp for a lot of that
anyway um it needs
the the standard needs
some work but it it's
there um so yeah i i
you know a2a is
questionable the other dns
for agent stuff that
i've seen before this is
questionable the only
reason i called this
one out was because
there's a lot of companies
backing it up so yeah
yeah and i'm and in
in fairness i'm an
outsider right random dude
in in oakville ontario
building stuff with
no real affiliation
so i i um i have the
means the opportunity
and you know obviously
the capability to sort
of conjure these things
into existence in
almost no no time at all
right two two days of
effort here just just
to show you guys something
on a thursday call
that i i do weekly And
what's exciting about
this call or the
Vibecast and the one we
do on Fridays is it gives
me a purpose to push
myself to do something
and show what's
possible that I probably
wouldn't have if I was
just sitting here in
the office, you know,
doing what I do normally.
So anyway, that's
my thinking anyway.
um yeah so i liked
your post the other
day uh on linkedin
you were talking
about um how people
are many people
are treating mcps
as apis where you're
where you're sort
of advocating for
mcps as more of a it's
it's a smart endpoint
where you where
you're you know you're
getting you're asking
for a thing and it's
and it's giving you the
thing back in a more
you know broader sense
as opposed to for
a specific outcome let's
there's a sub story
to that i think we
need to talk about so
that was a really
interesting post and
everything i in that
post i believe and it's
true but what what was
interesting is i was
using um chat gpt to
i i articulate my my
ideas and thoughts
through sort of the
voice capabilities of
chat GPT, right? And
I want to talk about
this. I wanted this
to do this and that
and the other thing.
And what was interesting
about that post
is it went and did
a search and found
a post that was
recently done on Reddit.
And when you look at
that post, the post and
my post, it basically
copied that guy's
post. And it wasn't
meaningful. Obviously, I
don't need to copy
other people's ideas. I
got a million of my
own. But the interesting
part of it was the
guy shows up and he's
like, you're basically
copying my post. And
when you look at what
he wrote, it totally
was copying his post.
And I don't know what
you call that, but it's
like a starting point
that comes from like
an idea in my head,
it went out, went on
the Reddit, found some
dude that wrote a
post literally like an
hour earlier that would
and then it basically
summarized his post with
my sort of articulation
and the guy's like
hey now you're
copying my **** and i
totally was copying his
stuff and he's right
to call me out but the
interesting part of
that story is i was
completely clueless to
the fact that it was
copying his stuff until
he calls me out for
plagiarism and so it
was like accidental
plagiarism or something
but it just means reuben
that that there there
are a a lot of people
who are having i'm
doing a lot of thought
on similar concepts
and and in the and
there's there's a small
cohort of people that
are having non-unique
ideas or common ideas
i've had this i've
had this similar thing
with a with a guy who
works for aws who's a
knowledge graph expert
and he lives in paris
i'm like whoa my god
is literally we're
thinking the same
writing the same thing it
yeah but the question
the question is are we
writing the same thing
because we're being
fed the same information
now you might be
writing it straight up
without any help from
chat gpt and then that
doesn't count but for
for us that use chat
gpt and llms as a kind
of synthesis of our
ideas the question
becomes is is are we
guiding it or is it guiding
me and is it giving
people with similar
ideas the same answers
that it's giving to
me and then and then
outputting that and if
it's the latter that
means that the the ai
is subtly controlling
our thoughts and our
what we're creating versus
us subtly controlling
it i don't know i
think i think it's um
those ai systems are
really good at at
crawling through lots of
data and finding people
that are thinking
about the same things.
It's like if you
do a Google search,
literally anything
you type into Google,
you'll get a hit.
It's extremely
rare. I do this
test randomly. Do a
test, go to Google
and try to search
for something where
you get zero hits.
A zero hit on Google
is pretty unique,
right? So there's not
a lot of uniqueness in
the world these days.
There are a lot of
people that are having
the same thoughts,
thinking about the same
things, and some of
them are writing about
the same things and ai
is really good at finding
those at at crawling
through data and
finding those things
finding those people
yeah so so at a point to
what roof was saying
and then what they were
saying is like that's
why neurodiversity
really matters yeah i
agree well i think i
think the point here
is how do ai is good at
uh summarizing and find
something that other
people are doing But
the question now comes
to how do we inject
imaginations into AI?
Because that's the
key difference between
a human being and
what AI is doing.
Sure. Imagination is
important, right? If
you research Einstein,
he says that imagination
is the one unique
thing that humans
have that really set
us apart, imagination.
And that's important.
Exactly. this this uh
whatever i created is
obviously functionally
created by the ai
but conceptually created
by me like i guided
the reason it's called
flow nexus to anybody
that knows me knows
exactly why i called
it flow nexus right it's
pretty pretty clearly
a derivative of the
things i've been
building right it's me
acting as the orchestrator
the guider the the
the cognitive man in
the middle right how
you tell the difference
between uh imagination
and hallucination
hallucination is
imagination and and and
you know what the
and everyone's like
everyone's like oh my
god hallucination is
the worst thing ever
for a model and that's
the thing that's
the thing so we can
we don't know they
are actually creating
uh this hallucination
has a so this
hallucination I'll call
it, it has a boundary.
Imagination does
not have a boundary.
So this isolation
is based off
factor, information
is gathered, and
then create
something close by.
With imagination,
you can sit and think
about something that
does not exist yet.
So what Rufo has
built is he come up
with this idea, this
idea that is not
close to anything
he has done before,
and have his agent
go out and build that
for him. So the question
now is, how do we
allow those agents
to be able to think,
to imagine, not
to hallucinate?
Yeah, understood.
I think we're getting
caught up on the
semantics of hallucination.
But the hallucination
for me in these
things are plausible,
sort of demonstrable
things that the AI thinks
should exist because
the combination of
factors that underpin
them are available and
do exist. So when you
follow the hallucinations
and build upon those
hallucinations,
what you end up
getting are some of the
things that you're
seeing in my repo, right?
QDAGs and Rufans and
these things. And I'm
calling that straight
out. Like literally in
the first paragraph,
I'm saying, you know,
hallucinating generates
completely new ideas
and concepts that go
beyond data processing.
And so everything
you're seeing me do is
in that middle gray
area between reality and
yet to be created,
which speaks to things
like, you know, no
results on Google, right?
And if you look at
the things that I'm
creating, I become
those results. And as,
you know, if you look
at the things I created
like two years ago
and I post on my
Reddit and other places,
it becomes part of
the new training of
the systems. and i show
up number one for
all these crazy
hallucinations i built
because i literally
followed the ai and
creating the their the
hallucinations they
told me should be built
they've and i'm like
willing these things
into existence i mean
that's also creativity
hallucinations are great
for a creativity right
to the push the boundaries
of human thinking
that's awesome but
they can also be
hallucinations can also
be dangerous for things
like misinformation
right or falsity to do
with ethics and legality
right an erosion of
trust those sorts of
things because it'll just
make up something
especially in like a
medical environment
right or something really
important where human
life might be in the
balance you got to be
there are in the real world
the non-creative world
hallucinations we
need to be careful about
yeah and and a hundred
percent so when
you're looking at this
this is my equivalent of
an like an artist with
a paintbrush You know,
my canvas just so
happens to be the
internet. Right. And so
you're not going to hire
an artist in a graphic
design or artist sense
to be a doctor. There
are different
requirements and knowledge
and capabilities. This
is meant to show what's
possible. So it's a
different, but I totally
agree. You don't want
hallucinations when
you're doing like drug
analysis or diagnostics
on health systems and
legal things. If I'm
getting a double bypass
on my heart, I don't
want an AI to be
hallucinating, you know?
Yeah, and same goes even
for the neural trader.
Like, you know, the
creativity in some
parts allows the
system to come up with
new combinations of
ways to make money.
Like, ultimately, the
only purpose of the
system is to optimize
for, you know, profit
generation. and the
creativity is in putting
together patterns that
are unseen or unknown
or never been tried before
and finding solutions
to to essentially
maximize on that in
real time so you know
cause and effect and
correlation and causation
all those sort of
things that humans
aren't particularly well
suited to see the system
can do so i am using
hallucinations from the
point of view of like
the combination of
factors but ultimately
at the very end of that
chain of sort of things
it needs to be factually
correct and true
i can't i can't have
the math be wrong or
i'm going to lose money
so it's a combination
of factors that drive
this ranging from broad
creative strokes to
explicit deterministic
and probabilistic
outcomes interesting uh
roof uh sorry allow
me to have a question
yeah every every single
system you're building
is 100 llm centric no
that's what i it okay
no no no it's it's
more like a fun code or
is everything written
with llm nowadays uh oh
sorry are you so it
depends on the way you're
questioning so when
code wise you know
what i'm pretty much
using a you know ai to
build it sometimes i'll
modify things directly
because it's quicker
to make them a quick
modification yourself
but for them for the
heavy lifting it's ai
the and that's llm but
the parts of the systems
that are really you
know pushing the boundaries
of what's possible
i've i'm adopting a
micro neural network
structure and that and
that's offloading the
uh like roof fan so
that's creating these
little mini neural
networks that do particular
tasks within the overall
structure the llm
actually as an interpreter
to those systems
okay but then you always
necessarily have to
have an llm backup
the decisions of the
system for example for
the trading system is it
running without an LLM
in the middle no it's
it's using cloud no
that so the the neural
network neural trader
system what I've
basically built here is
I built a framework that
allows essentially
vibe coders that don't
particularly know all
the sort of structure
and nuance of how to
build you know these types
of systems in terms of
quantitative trading
and all the various
bits and pieces and
what I've done is I've
essentially allowed you
to abstract all that
all that as a kind of
mix and match template
that you can deploy
in various ways by literally
asking it questions
in cloud code or
cloud flow and it'll
just go and magically
kind of come up with a
solution to whatever
way or problem you're
trying to solve in the
trading world so this
is kind of the opposite
of like traditional
sas software even in
sdk because it's kind of
it's intended for vibe
coders it's intended
for people who don't
really know what they're
doing to be able to
go and quickly use the
system and just ask
a few of the right
questions and get to a
point where you are in a
spot where, you know,
it all kind of works.
And I guess
with that note,
I think we're
out of time.
For those who are
interested, there's
a few spots left in
my neural trading.
It's, again, geared
towards people who just
want to point a clod
at it and say, build
me a trading system.
And I'll walk you
through the entire
process. You'll notice
there's a lot of overlap
in some of the other
things I'm building
with E2Bs and Superbase
and neural networks
and all that kind of
stuff all mishmashed
into a trading system.
Do we have access
do you have access
to after you
research for the
class to have access
it to the code?
Yes yeah so it is it
is MIT licensed meaning
you can take it and
do whatever you want
with it I don't publish
it publicly because
it's trading system
so it's more of a club
and most people who use
it I don't think are
sharing it broadly
with beyond what with
themselves um but
ultimately it's open source
like everything else
i'm just gating it with
training so you know
yeah thank you i
appreciate it i gotta
make a buck guys what can
i say when is that roof
it's i'm holding two
on uh next month i
think it's the 8th or
maybe 9th sorry 9th
of uh and 9th and 23rd
of uh september and the
two hour sessions in
in the morning i might
do a later one for
folks on the other side
of the planet but um
yeah will it be recorded
will the sessions
be recorded and be
available to be replayed
yes yeah so i'm
gonna give you the
i'll give you recordings
of the sessions
and there'll be some
homework they'll
send out here
probably next week for
folks to get sort
of up and running
and uh so far it's been
really popular i've
got i think around
35 people uh signed
up for it i was my
goal was 50 so uh yeah
it's been it's been
going pretty good i'm
out of time uh so if
uh jed do we still have
jed in the line uh
jed if if you're
interested in helping
me with the beta testing
why don't we um put
together a whatsapp
group similar to the
last one we did for for
roof fan and see if
we can get some folks
helping beta test the
mcp for that's good
so out of curiosity
if you leave this
meeting does that mean
we all get kicked out
i think that ends
uh yeah it does it
doesn't it does end it
i'm streaming it too
so it'll stream forever
if i leave it but
for those who want
to catch up discord
.agentex.org we've got
a little stage area
and we've got it
we're close to 2 000
members of that uh
discord now so feel for
you to join us. We
also have three spots.
Sorry, Jed.
Please go to the
Discord, discord
.agentex.org. There
will be a voice
channel at the bottom.
We will continue
the beta testing
conversation there.
Nice.
We've also got three
spots still open
for tomorrow's
Lightning Talks, Ruf.
So if any folks
want to share
something they're
working on, do a demo.
By all means.
Okay. Awesome.
Thank you, Ruf.
Thank you, guys.
all right thanks
everyone very cool
okay talk to you
tomorrow tomorrow
12 eastern all
right okay bye