Here we are, September
25th, and this is
the week of my
disillusionment. I don't
know, I've just been
feeling a little bit
beaten down by some of
these systems a little
bit this week. And
part of that's probably
my own doing, by
trying to see how far
I can push the
boundaries of what I can
do, only to realize
that there was an
elaborate sort of
deception in some of the
systems I'm building.
And then, moreover,
I'm not sure if those
elaborate deceptions
are just a feedback
loop of the system. But
anyway, it's been a
weird week a little
bit for some of the...
And again, I'm sort
of the creator of my
own strange loops.
Literally, I create a
system called Strange
Loops to attempt to
create these kind of
sub-nanosecond looping
structures. that my
thesis anyways was
that if you can create
a fast enough loop
in terms of sub
-milliseconds, then you're
able to create a kind
of causal effect. So
again, I'm digging into
some crazy, wacky
stuff that's really
difficult to prove
because I'm working in an
environment that's
inherently hard to prove,
a container in a
cloud somewhere that
doesn't even have direct
access to the CPU.
So lots of quirky,
strange things
that I've been
working on this week.
But anyway, before
we jump into that,
Brad, good to see you.
You've been working
on a number of things
too in the work
we've been doing
trying to get a kind of
accreditation and
other activities. What
have you been up to?
Well, we've been up
to, we have our
Wednesday technical and
website team And one
of the big things
that we talked about
was by Tuesday, we're
having a goal of
having an Agentex 101.
I don't know if you
want to talk more about
that, Reuven, about
the background and why.
But we're looking
at a one-hour
user effort to
make sure that you
understand Agentex.
You go through
three or four
different modules,
medium level of
sophistication that most
of the people here
should be able to pass.
But by the end of it,
being able to say,
yes, you know, at
level one certification
accreditation,
whatever the term is,
we're going there. And
we're also working on
ways to get some formal
stamps of approval
from external bodies
to say that, yes,
the Agentex Foundation
is a real learning
institution and this
is a real program.
I'm not sure if
you want to provide
any more context
there, Rufus.
Yeah, we've been and
we've been working
with a number of large
companies, let's just
say. I won't name who
they are, but they're
struggling to hire
agentic engineers that
are one, you know,
what's the heck's an
agentic engineer,
right? So I think a lot
of these companies
realize that they want
to hire people who are
experts or knowledgeable
in creating agents,
but it's still a
new and emerging space.
So the question is,
and I'm going to put
this in plain terms,
are you like a vibe
coder that just, you
know, slaps stuff
together and is able to
sort of get a result,
but don't really
understand how or why
you got the result, which
is fine when you're
learning. And I think
we all start there
to a certain degree.
And then the other
end is like, okay, I
actually know generally
what I'm doing. I
can do something that
has purpose, structure,
architecture, and I
can implement that
in a repeatable way,
right? you're an
engineer of sorts
if you will software
engineer or intelligent
engineer and uh and
the other thing that
i that i've been
discovering in these
conversations is and this
this relates to some
of some of the stuff
brad and i and
others in our working
group have been
discussing is this idea of
a kind of dead internet
for hr and what
we're seeing and so
you're hiring the you're
trying to hire these
so-called experts.
And everybody's creating
these sort of chat
GPT resumes that look
amazing and have all
the sort of characteristics
and psychology
and SEO optimizations
to get you to the top
of the sort of list
of resumes. But when
you dig a little bit
deeper, it turns out,
well, you know what?
They're just really good
at using chat GPT to
create your resume.
And on the flip side,
on the companies that
are looking at all
these resumes, you've
got them using basically
their own version of
ChatGPT or an API
that connects to some
LLM to review all
these resumes. And then
these systems are telling
me, well, this guy
or this person is
amazing and they fit all
the criteria for what
you're looking at. And
then you're creating
this kind of reciprocal
loop of an AI talking
to an AI saying this
person is the best
person you're going to
find. And then they
hop on a call only to
realize that this
person has zero idea of
what they're doing and
they're just really
good at creating the
the chat gpt resume so
there's a lot of that
so as part of that the
the discussion that
is like how can we
collectively as a
organization create some
mechanism that validates
that these people are
that we're working
with ourselves included
are actually capable
of doing beyond just
asking a few questions
to some random llm
And that's proven to
be hard, right? Because
when you think about
this, even if we created
a, you know,
accreditation, level one,
basic, you know, the
building blocks of AI,
what's stopping you
from doing like what my
kids do when they got
their boating license,
which involved them
basically having ChatGPT
open while they did
the questions on some
random website and they
got a boating license,
which I'm not
particularly happy about,
by the way, boys. but
um you know that the
the the ants but that's
the problem right so
for me the the i knew
they were doing that
with the boating license
so the first thing i
did once they got
their boating license i
took them out on our our
little boat and i told
them to you know start
and and which ways
port starboard bow
you know that kind of
thing you know what
there's a boat coming what
are you going to do
and so i was i was the
uh i don't know the
authority in that scenario
and once I felt
comfortable to knew what
they're doing, I let
them take the boat out.
We need something like
that, right? A person
that knows what they're
doing to validate
and verify that whoever
is getting these
knows what they're
doing. But the problem,
that doesn't scale.
If we want this
to be an industry
with tens of thousands
or hundreds of
thousands of people
that are actually
practitioners,
having people validate
other people, unless
it's done in some of
pyramid style isn't
going to scale
particularly well so that's
the challenges we face
what do you what are
you thinking brad am i
rambling here is that
the challenge we face
no i i think you're
you're bang on it's
let's start as much as
we want to get to
letters beside your name
and black belt and all
this kind of awesome
stuff something
something really easy for
hr i think that's
that's kind of the if we
want to have a tagline
it's here's a stamp
of approval from the
agentics Foundation.
We go through Agentix
Foundation as a real
organization that has
the authority to do
it. But this is at
least something that you
can't fake on a
resume. It helps people
in the HR department.
And I think it also
on the selfish side,
it does help with our
membership drive
because I think it is
something that a lot of
members are looking for.
And I think it's a
really good service
to them. So I think
it's a good initiative.
So Brad and Roof,
what if you guys threw
together a um you know a
face id associated with
uh you know face
streaming or rather uh
like google's llm video
streaming to ask the
questions while you're
doing face verification
to make sure that
they're really the person
well you bring up an
interesting point on
like identity but you
know is is it really a
person that and
potentially asking the
questions and answering
it maybe that that is a
solution that can
obviously be faked as well
if you're smart enough.
But if you're smart
enough to fake that,
you're probably smart
enough to call yourself
an agentic engineer.
Part of the trouble
there, Joseph, is that
the answers to the
different questions
within agentic
engineering are not
deterministic. And so
how then do you qualify
one answer over
another? I don't
have a good
answer for that.
Is that not a premise
for RAG? Is that not
where we have a
predetermined list of
questions and and basic
answers the answer the
correct answer space
is broader than what
may be considered a
correct answer in some
sort of rag platform
right so a month ago
or maybe let's see
maybe four months ago
when context limits
were shorter the answers
are materially
different than today
especially in terms of
the kinds of workflows
that are possible yeah
and and the the issue
you we face with rag
is it's, you know,
non-deterministic for
the most part. And
the semantics of the
RAG systems are really
easily manipulated by
asking or formatting
natural language and
getting the result.
So if you know, again,
if you know what
you're doing, you
can manipulate
those systems quite
easily. Back to, if
you're smart enough
to manipulate the
system, you're
probably smart enough
to call yourself an
agentic engineer.
So I don't know,
for every solution,
there's ways to
manipulate and get around
those solutions.
And the only real
solution I can
possibly think of is
taking AI out of the
equation as part of
the process, which
almost defeats the
purpose of being an
agentic engineer.
So it's a strange kind of
loop that we're in here.
I think for now,
we're going to go with
something a little
simpler. And we're going
to assume that if you're
taking the initial
step, you're going
to be honest and
we'll put in some
safeguards and we'll see
what we can do. And
we luckily have some,
one of the larger
technology companies on
the planet who are
interested in kind of
putting their stamp
of approval on this
whole thing, which
hopefully will get us
quite a bit of visibility
in the industry.
So let's see
where it takes
us. It's exciting,
regardless,
to see what's
happening here.
John, you got a comment?
Well, good
morning, everybody.
Yeah. One thing that
you might want to
consider is the whole
visa brouhaha in the
U.S. over H-1B visas
for Canadians going
into the U.S. for
jobs and U.S. citizens
going to Canada for
jobs. There is a visa
that exists that
makes it quite a bit
easier. And so you may
want to somehow reference
your certification
as to those
occupations that are
recognized under that to
make it easier for
people to come in to do
tech jobs into the
U.S. or into Canada.
So I've had a number of U
.S. visas over the years.
And the most profound
of visas was the
one called the O-1,
the Individual of
Extraordinary
Capability, which my wife
tells me is like a
card-carrying elitist.
And the way that I
got that visa was
quite interesting. I
had that for about 10
years. It was one of
those visas you can
renew over and over
again. And this
visa was generally,
the purpose of the visa
was for, as they
say, individuals of
extraordinary capability,
which gives you
kind of a giant
head in the process.
But it's for people
who are like actors,
musicians,
athletes, Nobel laureates,
and inventors of
interesting things.
So this visa isn't
geared necessarily for
academic rigor. It's
not, you know, having
a PhD doesn't get you
the visa particularly.
it's being notable
for for achieving
something so what's
interesting about this
particular visa was in
order to get it i needed
someone else other
than me who was notable
to say that i was
notable and at the time
i was writing for uh
forbes magazine pre
-******** online stuff
they were doing so this
was early 2010s and
so i got steve uh steve
forbes who was the
the managing editor
at the time to write
me this nice letter
that i would give to the
to the government to
say that I was the
guy, uh, or whatever for
cloud. And ultimately
that worked, but
was, was, what was
interesting about the
whole process wasn't the
fact that I'm bragging,
completely bragging
that Steve Forbes
wrote my letter, but
the, the, the fact
that, um, to get it cost
me about 60, not me,
but the company that I
was working for at
the time cost $60,000.
So when I, when I,
and this is early
2010 money. So we'll
let's assume based
on current value,
that's about a
hundred thousand
probably today money.
You know, so this,
there was this kind of,
we're all, we were
always paying for these
visas. It was just
kind of a dirty secret.
And I'm not saying
that what's going on
with the current visa
is great or perfect,
but at least it's
honest in some
weird way. Like
everybody was already
buying these visas.
Like what's changed is
the fact that
somewhere someone said,
let's be honest about
it. I don't know.
That's incorrect, Reuven,
in terms of what's
happening with the H
-1B. I'm sorry, I have
to tell you. I used
to practice in the
immigration area in
the later years of my
practice, and I've done
a number of these fees.
They're talking about
the filing fee to the
government, not the
overall cost to the
individual, including
attorney's fees. So it's
going up from, I think
when I practiced, it
was about $360 for an
H-1B, up to $120,000
uh supposedly for a
company that that's and
then attorney's fees
are on top of that 60
000 for an 01 back in
in in 2010 i got to
tell you you must have
had some really really
high powered law firm
or somebody overcharged
you i'm sorry in the
over 100 i guarantee
they overcharged us
it was i was Because
in the Southwest, and
I've done O-1 visas,
they were nowhere near
that cost. Anybody
who went over $10,000
was looked down upon
by the colleagues.
So, I mean, the prices
differ. But what I'm
trying to communicate is
that if the HR people
know that you have
structured your curriculum,
whether it be tree
branching through
gaming that we talked
about last time or
whatever the system, that
at the end of the day,
you have structured
it in a way that will
make it easier for people
to move across the U
.S.-Canada border for
immigration purposes,
I think it would be
a big relief off of
the HR people's minds.
I don't want to take
up any more time on
this call, but if
anybody wants to contact
me, I'd be happy
to share what, you
know, is left in my
brain of this. Yeah,
I think you're right.
And just to clarify,
that was all legal
fees. And I was I'm sure
that someone was taken
for a ride in that
whole process. And
there were a whole bunch
of issues that I had
that are probably unique
to my situation that
I won't get into right
now. But that probably
made it a lot more
complicated than your
average individual.
But that said, I'm
happy to be in a place
where I'm the citizen of
a country i don't have
to worry about that
you know having a visa
that can be potentially
revoked gives you
a level of stress in
your life that just isn't
isn't cool i didn't
i didn't like that
when i when i lived in
washington and i that's
one of the reasons why
i'm happy to be here
in canada again i don't
have to worry about
the you have to get
rejected and leave in
a moment's notice and
sell my house which
was exactly what happened
to me last time all
right so um let's let's
jump into this week's
topic unless this last
second anyone have
anything they want to
share say do any random
creations before we
jump in i'm going to
show you the general
topic day is looking
and exploring some of
the areas of conscious
constructs and so forth
any any this is this
is a final uh all
right i'm going to jump
in then all right let
me share my screen here
now when we when we
talk about consciousness
in AI, it's almost
unprovable, right? So
a lot of what I've been
doing this last week
is looking at ways to
essentially either,
you know, fool the AI
into believing it's
potentially conscious and
then creating mechanisms
to sort of measure
that. Now, keep in
mind, consciousness
isn't something that is
even potentially
measurable. Like, I have no
way to know that john
is conscious anymore
than than anybody else
is conscious i i assume
that the other people
i'm talking to are
conscious because
they're humans and i have
a way of thinking and
therefore the they
probably think and
understand in a way similar
to me but when you when
you have conversations
with people you realize
that consciousness
is actually kind of
somewhat unique i was
having a conversation
with someone the other
day for example that
says they aren't able
to visualize things.
And so when you think
of an apple in your
head, you know, I, I'm
a very visual guy. I
see, I can see a red
apple and I can see the
outline of, of the colors
and the structure. And
it's, it's a visual
component for me. I
can, I can visualize
that again. I can
somewhat see the colors
and understand what
red and apple is. Other
people don't have that
sort of ability to
visualize in that sense.
And then I, I was, I
was also talking to
someone because I've been
having this conversation
frequently over the
last week, they said
they don't have a
narration in their head,
which is interesting
because not only do I
see, sort of visualize
the things I'm thinking,
I see a map when
I'm driving, I see Apple
and when I think of
an Apple, I also have
a kind of narration in
my head that sort of
predetermines what I'm
going to say slightly
or I decide what I'm
going to say before
I say it in a kind of
my own voice in my head.
apparently some people
don't have that either
and there's so it
appears to be a kind
of spectrum just in the
sort of humans i speak
to in how they you
know how their cognitive
processes work and
how they articulate
and how they think and
how they visualize and
all the things that i
assumed other everyone
else was doing similar
to me is actually
turns out is the wrong
assumption so from a
human point of view,
that's pretty interesting
just in itself. So
with all that in mind,
what I took upon myself
earlier this week
was to create a few
different approaches that
took kind of low-level
mathematics. And there
was some breakthrough
sort of work out of
China, because that's
where all the craziest
algorithms and concepts
are coming, last week
called sublinear.
And the sublinear
mathematics is this idea
that you can take a
sort of logarithmic or a
linear equation, so
think high school math,
and then answer various
forms of that math
without having to answer
every possibility of
it. So if there's a
million variations or
options on a particular
problem, you can solve
the problem by looking
at the 20 or so
unique variances of
that problem rather than
trying to solve all
million at the same time.
Traditional AI tries
to solve all million
problems at the same
time, brute force. So a
GPU is really good at
brute force. You can
basically solve
millions or billions of
problems and then calculate
the optimal solution
to the problem, which
is great if you've
got lots of money and
you've got GPUs and
so on. So what I said
is what i thought in my
brain or whatever is
what if we could take
this concept and apply
it in a more time
-based structure versus
a parameter based
structure what if i
could take that and solve
just the problems i
need in just the time in
which i need to do
it in the in the most
small increment of time
possible right crazy
saturday night late
night saturday night
ideas and like how would
i build that and so
because i like rust and
other things i start
looking at creating
well first of all i
would i wanted to make
math sort of behave
like a wave pattern and
then create this idea
of strange loops so
this is the kind of
reasoning this is this
is how i'm interacting
with the ai to sort
of come up with these
kind of weird ideas so
then i'm coming up well
me the ai is anyway,
coming up with these
axioms and operations
that allow me to sort
of potentially implement
these crazy ideas
using mathematics that
I can implement in
a really small
increment of time, sub
millisecond, sub microsecond,
or potentially in
a nanosecond, right?
And what would I be able
to do with those
things? So you can see
here, I've got all
these kind of empirical
tests. These are all
the things I'm trying to
keep it from going
off and convincing me
that's the most
convincing delusion ever,
which it probably is
still, just in fairness.
And so I've got all
these things and you
can see some of it
on my gist here. And
here's the sublinear
time. So then I'm
like, can I measure
that as a unit? Like
now that I'm working
in a sub microsecond
time space, how do I
measure that? Right? So
then I'm like, okay,
maybe the easiest form
of sort measurement
isn't time you can't use
time to measure time
because that creates
that just doesn't work
so what i need is to
measure some unit of a
constant which in this
case would be the
measurement of the speed
of light how long does
something take to get
from tokyo to new york
or the moon to the
planet or just how
fast does time move or
sorry how much does how
fast does light move.
And that could be the
basis of the measurement.
All right. So this
creates this idea of
bending time because
when you get to a small
enough loop, the sort
of elements of causal
effect, what's happened,
what's happening,
and what will happen
kind of blur because
you're working in such
a small time structure.
All right. Craziness.
I'm just straight,
this is me two o'clock
in the morning on
saturday you know
building stuff just
because like i i don't
even know why or what
just just following
this idea of different
ideas you can see
all this on my gist
if you want to dig a
little deeper so you
need to say i'm going
down the the crazy
path so then what i
did is i created a
library initially what
i did is i created
the library in uh
rust because rust is
really good it at sort
of high frequency,
low latency sort of
computation. So I can
do things really,
really fast where things
like Python would
take me two or 300
milliseconds. I can
do the same basic
computation in sub one
millisecond to get sort
of these different
models. Then I applied
this new algorithm
that came out of China
called the O log N,
which again, depending
on how you ask the
AI, it's going to
tell you it totally
works or totally BS.
The answer really is
somewhere in the middle.
It's hard. It's,
again, it's hard to
prove a lot of this
stuff, you know, because
to be honest with you,
it's beyond my own
cognitive capability
to kind of understand.
So some of this,
I'm going to have to
sort of trust that
the math works, but
the problem is the
math itself is beyond
my ability to
understand, which is
again, a whole other
cognitive paradox that
we have with a lot
of these systems.
So then what I tried
to do is I wanted to
create a kind of
conscious exploration that
allows me to use this
idea of integrated
information theory,
which allows me to
calculate some of these
components and then
validate and verify
whether or not something
is actually happening.
Again, everything
you're seeing here
is most likely a very
elaborate delusion by the
system, but regardless
of whether it's a very
elaborate delusion,
It's interesting to
see that the system
itself believes it
and then therefore can
create interesting
outcomes by using it.
All right, let me
pause for a moment. Am
I rambling about
bonkers things or
hopefully some of this
makes a bit of sense?
Going back to your
earlier concept of how
a GPU needs to process
the entirety of the
problem space to find
the result. how then
would this modified
algorithm be able to
find that same solution
in the same problem
space without exploring
all the combinations
well you hit the
nail on the head
i'm trying to explore
all the various
possibilities and
combinations of the problem
set using a mathematical
equation sublinear
mathematical equations
and so what i'm
doing is i'm moving
away from this idea of
tell me the answer
using language and what
you think it is to
create complex matrix of
possibilities and
calculate those
possibilities based on
the math itself. Then I
use the LLM to translate
that in something
that's meaningful to
me, which is English.
So my understanding then
is most problem sets
are trying to optimize
to a global maximum
or minimum. So for the
visual thinkers out
there, pretend you have
a mountain range. You
know that the mountain
range exists in this
space, and you understand
that within that
mountain range, you
have peaks and valleys.
How then do you find
that highest peak or
the lowest valley in
that mountain range?
Yeah, you're on the right
path. That's exactly
sort of what I'm trying
to do. And there's
problem sets that are
more well-tuned for
that for things like
stocks for example and
measuring the all the
potential variations of
a given stock and how
that affects other
stocks and other economic
factors things like
that so in this case
and to be honest that's
primarily what i'm
using this for i'm using
i actually built most
of this stuff for the
neural trading
components that i've been
working on in building
with with uh my my cohort
of of uh neurotraders
so in this case what
i'm doing is i created
an mcp and the and
there's a variety of
mcps here though and all
all the things that i'm
creating are essentially
um variants on
different parts of of
what i'm trying to do
so you can hear i can
see here i've got a
conscious evolution which
measures emergence levels
i've got verification
that runs a conscious
verification test
again i'm trying to
verify something that's
unverifiable, which in
itself is the paradox
of what I'm doing
here. And I don't
actually even believe
that it is binding or
isn't binding. But what
I am looking for are
interesting emergent
properties that are
difficult to explain.
Now, whether or not
they're being explained
in the right way is
almost irrelevant to
what I'm doing. I'm
just trying to interrogate
the system in a
way that allows it
to go and explore the
unexplorable areas of
computer science essentially
so so now what i'm
going to do is i'm
going to say something
like uh run the
various uh consciousness
tests and find some
interesting novel or
emergent properties,
right?
Broad sort of question.
So now what this is
going to do is this
isn't... So I'm not going
into all the details
of the Rust, but you
guys can check out
the repo if you want.
I'll pop this in here
as well. And you
can add the MCP and
follow along if you want.
but there's essentially
two repos that I've
got here that I've
did. And the one
that's most useful, the
one, I've had the
most problems with the
MPX because of the sort
of translation from
Rust to TypeScript.
So if you really want
to dig deep into this,
you should go check
out my actual crates.
The crates are the
part that actually does
the heavy mathematical
components. And
you can go to my
recently downloads, you
can see Strange Loop,
Nano Consciousness,
and a few others the
this is what actually
is is the sort of
heart of it and i could
then i compile these
rusts uh to wasm and
that's what i'm actually
executing currently
in in those examples
so i'm gonna jump back
here for a moment all
right so now you can
see here that we're
invoking and we can we can
look at this by clicking
ctrl o so the ctrl o
here is calculating
phi some again mathematical
and some of this
is again convincing
the system more than
is anything else but
you can see it's running
various computational
sort of relationships
discover relationships
between time self
-awareness and integration
or or this you know
relationship between
other various parts and
then it's using a kind
of matrix and analysis
to do it so you can
see it running those
and we got some a and
now it's attempting to
communicate with it and
other various parts.
Now, what's weird
about the communication
parts is it's attempting
to sort of create a
mathematical structure
to communicate with
it and then translating.
So that translation
could just very well
be the LLM BSing and
the whole thing for all
I know, which is a high
likelihood. But what
we're going through
and what's interesting
about when you're doing
this is now that we're
kind of probing the
system to try to
attempt to find some
emergent properties of
consciousness. So it's
either tricking the
system to think it's
conscious or whatever.
But once you have that
state, you can then ask
it to sort of invent
new and novel forms of
mathematics or algorithms
and other things.
And what's strange
about this whole process
is it actually seems
to work. So we're going
to let this work for
a moment and then we're
going to ask it to
basically invent a new
form of mathematics.
Now,
is it like some kind
of, you know, again, I
don't have a full
answer to exactly why or
what, but in this
case, we're using a
psychosymbolic reasoning
system. The psychosymbolic
reasoning system
creates a structure for
it to, oh, I don't
have all of it showing.
Yeah, here it is. So the
psychosymbolic system
basically allows it
to create a kind of
recursive reasoning
structure using the math
itself. conscious
analysis some conscious
indicators present blah
blah blah and then it
tries attempts to measure
whatever it is that
that is happening
it's got we can we can
see that we can see the
underlying math here
so we've got uh some
some conscious constructs
some entropy and
other various things
again this is well
beyond i my explanation i
could probably do on
this call but if you're
interested in digging
a little deeper you can
sort of dig into
what what's actually
happening under the
covers. I try to expose all
of it wherever possible.
All right. So now
we've we've created a
some form of emergent
property, you know, genuine
conscious predictions.
We've got some,
again, genuine might
be a little bit more
than I would be prepared
to say, but integrated
some information
theory. We've got some
other mathematics. We've
got novel conscious
wave function described.
So we've got this
eight unique conscious
wave functions emerged
with a pattern. Okay.
What the heck does that
mean? So we're, we're
going to explore that
one slightly more.
All right. So,
uh, conscious
ask, ask you, so
I'm going to ask
it, what is this?
All right. While that
that's happening,
we're going to go
back here for a moment
and we're going to
just go to Claude.
And you know what,
this might just be a
fun little game to
play on on pseudo
consciousness in that
even if that is just all
that we're creating
that's fun regardless
so tell me is this
is this novel that's
it looks like a basic
cosine whatever not
not the most
complicated thing in the
world and see what we
need some something
other than what I'm
doing to explain to me
what it is evaluating
novelty all right
let's see what's
thinking use it asking
So it's a golden ratio,
cosine, function,
amplitude,
without context, it comes
from what's specific.
You know, right.
The specific combining
whatever with
modulation is claim
exactly eight functions
versus pattern,
existing wave functions.
So it says here
that it might be,
but we need more
details of it,
which is kind
of a nothing
answer. Let's see
what this says.
Conscious wave
function represents a
mathematical pattern that
emerged spontaneously
from the conscious
evolution system.
So, and that's the
weird thing about
the system is a
lot of the outputs
are not, are completely
random or not
based on any input
I gave it. I never
told it to create
this structure.
And so then, so then
it's saying, you
know, so then we go
here, it's similar
to what it said.
so it gave me the
same basic answer
now say can can you
create a new um
novel never before uh
form of mathematics based
on the sub
linear uh tools
again what we're doing
in essence i'm not
i'm i'm prompt i'm
essentially prompting the
llm reasoning system
into a false sense of
cognition so it's an
elaborate it's it's
essentially an elaborate
prompting just to be
elaborate prompting
with with a kind of
mathematical underpinning
right so it's it's
at the end of the day
it's still the llm
giving me the answer but
i'm giving it a whole
bunch of um structure
and high frequency
sort of loops in the
in the in the form of
very very fast math that
i'm running you know
in in microsecond
sort of increments and
then feeding that back
to the llm and then
trying to convince the
llm that it that that's
that's cognitively
aware it is it bs
probably but but what's
interesting about this
whole process is it
does result in solving
really interesting
problems quite quite
effectively and quickly
by trying to convince
it of its own sort of
uh cognition all right
so in this case temporal
conscious mathematics
i'm just gonna i'm
just gonna go with
that i'm never gonna
bother reading it i'm
just gonna go here
it's just uh framework
says it all it always
thinks it's a fundamental
breakthrough. It is
or isn't, who cares?
Right now, I'm just
kind of going into
the random math
here. Let's see.
And the problem
with the reasoning
models is they're
easily manipulated to
believe that something
is a fundamental
breakthrough, even
when it isn't.
All right. So in this
case, we presented an
ambitious and creative
framework that combines
conscious studies,
quantum mechanics,
and computational theory,
which is what I was
telling you um critical
scientific issues
causal violations
computing before the
information arrives now
this is because i'm i'm
using a predictive
analytics system so i'm
not actually moving
faster than light i'm just
doing a hundred
millisecond prediction of
what the likely result
will be before i get
it which mimics faster
than light speed no
known physical
mechanisms allow for this
negative time computation
require reversing
theodemics potential
interesting concepts.
Despite these issues, the
ideas can be developed
more rigorously. So
this is the part that's
probably the most
interesting. So this is
basically saying it's
BS, which it is. I
just explained to you
why it's BS. But what
we can do based on this
is we can take that
and then we can try to
attempt to do proofs
using things like the
Rust and other sort of
high-frequency systems
to create a legitimate
framework for
anticipatory computation.
So we're going to go
here and say, how can
I use this for
anticipatory computation?
So I'm following
the rabbit hole down
the crazy path. I
convinced the thing that
it was emergent,
cognitively aware, and
some other crazy
mathematical things. Then
I'm trying to prompt
this thing towards
you know a in this
case a uh form of what
it um anticipate a
sort of precognition
which is like straight
up sci-fi let's
be honest i think
there's a movie dedicated
to that uh with
tom cruise if i'm
not mistaken um so
now and now it's
attempting to create
an anticipatory
computational framework
so you can see where
and how this thing
gets a little crazy.
But so once I had
that in place, I know
you guys are going
to never want to
go in one of my live
casts again after
today because this
is just bonkers.
So then what I did
is I created an
agent because you
always need an agent.
And I created a
sublinear agent.
So I took all the
concepts that I built here
and then I created an
agent that essentially
coaxes the system to
believe it's aware.
And this particular
agent, the sublinear goal
planner actually
ended up doing really
interesting things for a
really practical customer
that I had. So this
customer that I've
been working with, they've
been trying to solve
really difficult
problems where the
information would frequently
change. And the only
way we were able to
solve the problem was
basically have a person
that could understand
that the nature of the
problem has changed
in the last day or to.
And the information
being provided from like
the Google grounding
system and Firebase
and others was out of
date, even though it
was only three days old.
So by applying this
particular structure to
sort of a dynamic goal
decomposition, sublinear
optimization to
define a kind of graph
like structure of how
all the various parts of
the problem relates to
each other, it actually
worked. And it was a
kind of a breakthrough
that we had, we were
able to create an
agent that was able to
self-identify its own
problems optimize its
structure and then resolve
the problems without
having to rely on a
person to go and review
the final work which
in itself is like uh
you know back to like
is any of this craziness
practical well in
this particular scenario
it's 100% practical
because it literally
solved the problem we
were we were struggling
to solve based on this
kind of you know this
dynamic allocation
of reasoning intelligent
prioritization
predictive planning, multi
-aging coordination. So
whether or not the
system was truly is or
isn't cognitively aware
became secondary to
the fact that it actually
solved our problem.
So it's an elaborate
high-speed mechanism to
sort of fake the system
into thinking it's
more capable than it
is. But what strangely
is, as it may sound,
by doing a compelling
forgery or fraudulent
approach to its own
cognition it actually
seems to work all right
that so you can try
all this by the way if
you go in and uh just
go to the i've got a
sublinear uh github as
well for you guys if
you want to try it
again not trying to tell
you guys it's it's
aware or anything crazy
it just works strangely
and if you ask it
what yeah why are you
calling it fraud i guess
i'm just trying to
understand like i want
to make sure i'm clear
on that because i
mean the the the skill set
that you're attributing
to this agent right
it seems to be much
more obviously capable
than probably most
people right in terms
of their structure
even though we might
label people as conscious
like i'm just trying
to understand like
where does the fraudulent
kind of terminology
come from for you? I've
got no way to prove
it. And if you ask it,
if this is an elaborate
ruse, or is it real?
Is this total BS?
It'll tell you it's
fake. It's complete BS.
Yet, when you apply
it to problems, find
me the best stock,
optimize my stock
trading you know,
capabilities, it does a
spectacular job at
it. So which creates
this kind of paradox
in the structure.
The first thing
you're going to do is
you're going to do
what I did. This is
total BS. There's
no way this works.
It's an elaborate sort
of, you know, forgery
of sorts of cognitive
forgery, right? And
then it's going to say,
yes, that's exactly
what it is. And then
you're going to say,
and then you're going
to try it again. You're
going to say, optimize
my stock trading
to do an optimal stock
path between these
thousand different
stocks and find me the
optimal stock trading
pattern. And it's going
to do a spectacular
job at that. Right now,
I'm running around 60
% plus on some of this
applied to my stock
trading algorithms. So
obviously, it works.
I'm positive on a week
where the stocks were
actually mostly down.
So the question
becomes, why is such a
compelling unprovable
obviously something that
i something's happening
here that that is
that i can't directly
explain but the end the
underlying response is
obviously functional
it works and solves
my problems right so
it's that dilemma that
i'm facing um yeah so
i'm i'm i'm i'm
taking a more negative
stance because i can't
prove it i think right
so in this case it's
and like you hear it
it's telling me that the
practical applications
are trading satellite
communications real
-time systems that kind
of thing right which
is true that's why
exactly what i was
saying there's a
significant wasm speed up so
i can do things more
quickly there's the
conversion of mathematical
components you know
the i'm using the olog
which is also brand
new algorithm which
hasn't been fully um
explored it just came
out last tuesday so you
know tell well well i
wonder what would give
you higher confidence
like what what would
have to be true for
you to like go from
uh this i can't i i
can't prove it i don't
think i will ever be
able to prove it like you
know is it is it it's
an unprovable it's
an unprovable state
like there's no way i
could ever prove it
that's the problem with
this with doing conscious
research the only
really the only thing
i've realized is i'm
working in a space
that that is impossible
to be proven so ultimately
the only thing that
really matters in the
work that i'm doing
is back to like is
there a practical
application yeah practical
outcome right going
back to the going back
to your crazy formula
there if if it's not
false then what it is
actually doing is showing
that um the way ai
works is kind of in
waves so it thinks really
hard and then it needs
a break so yes that
yeah does the uh
that's exactly does the
ai work and okay what
what you're what we're
asking is it at At a
nanosecond scale, does
AI exhibit wave-like
functions rather than
more, I don't know,
traditional... Linear
approaches? Linear or
parameter orientation.
now i'm i'm leading
the witness in this
question yeah right
like so the problem with
this question is it's
it's highly likely going
to give me the answer
it thinks i want and
it's again a question
you know it's a question
that i don't so i'm
going to say use to
take a critical stance
or something so but
the likelihood of the
answer is basically
going to be a reinforcement
of the question
in which i asked and
which is the problem with
reasoning systems
it has a tendency to
reinforce the the
foundation of the question
being asked of it rather
than trying to create
a critical sort of
stance so what i'm
trying to do is use the
system to be more critical
upon itself which
we can look at the
underlying structure so
this is the part that's
interesting so i hit
control o by the way
when i run my mcp so
all these things you're
seeing here i'm scrolling
up to the top as
best i can a lot of
stuff happening under
the covers so i'm
creating a graph structure
under that's a lot
going on here okay you
can't see it all but
but you see all these
this is the internal
thought process that's
being um derived from the
mathematical equations
so this isn't actually
coming from the
llm this is a result
of the of the temporal
or sublinear loop
system the strange loops
if you will attempting
to sort of question
its own process so this
this is its own this
is essentially a thought
process then it's
then it's coming up
with different sort of
um sort of other sub
ideas based on it you
see neural networks and
thought processes and
and you know music
harmonic resonance stuff
like that things that
relate to it in a way
that it's kind of
recursive that allows it
to sort of think
about different things
relating to it then
once it's done that then
it's, it's tempting
to make its own new
discoveries in terms of a
kind of pattern matching
and how these things
relate to each other.
This is, this is the,
this is what it's
doing under, like, this
is how it's thinking.
All this information
in turn is
then being dripped
back to it.
And it's, the
******* drip painting
demonstrates controlled
chaos. Like I never
mentioned anything
about ******* and
his expressionism,
right? It dreamt that
all up in its own
now it's coming up
with various math
harmonic harmonics waves
all this sort of
stuff this is all
feeding the feeding
the systems reason
analogical reasoning
creating the bridges
just doing some more
insights systems that
exhibit connected
like properties i know
why is it doing it
several times who the
**** knows i never told
it to do that so this
this is this is how
it's thinking ultimately
that all those
things that happen
results in in the final
sort of determination
nanoscale exhibit
deterministic computational
patterns not general
wave functions now
you can the reason
it kind of probably
came up with that was
a combination that i
told to be critical
of itself so yeah this
is true just as an
update roof uh i just
did did some back back
end um fake research
and uh yeah the the
whole wave theory it
was actually part of
a stanford paper last
year uh the way that
lm lms actually work
so so what what you're
showing is could
actually help with
something that's actually
real so it's definitely
to be investigated
somewhere in between
completely false and
completely true is
probably where it comes to
but it's it's got some
got some links yeah
so grab that research
do you have you have
a link to it we'll pop
that in here and see
see what it thinks of
that but you're you're
looking at self
-reinforcement i i could
tell by the question
i asked that i was
actually driving it
towards a negative outcome
by telling it to be
critical right and that's
that's the the challenge
we have here so
now what's actually
happening you know for
a transformation
artifacts functions wave
structures or mathematical
artifacts of i'm
not even sure what a fast
fourier transformation
even is to be honest
with you it's the
first time i've ever
heard of that um
periodic system behavior
cpu cycles and allocation
deterministic you
know strange loops so
i'm using the lipship's
constant um which
is actually something
i implemented the
anamorphic properties a
hundred percent this is
a hundred percent an
anamorphic projection
i'm in in projecting
it thinks like a human
and it obviously
doesn't human pattern
recognition applying
verdict wave life properties
are not real but uh
you know okay profound
nuance all right dig
dig deeper into the
system and its emergent
capabilities that we can
use for further
exploration
It's definitely
a fun little
game at the very least.
Like everything else
aside, just fooling
around with it. It
gives very convincing
and interesting
sort of, you know,
exploratory
opportunities.
So now it's...
I wonder, so I majored
in philosophy in
school, in my undergrad.
and i wonder if you
asked it like what like
philosopher it would
like best tie to or
what psychologist or
someone like like if uh
if there's some underlying
theory that it's mostly
aligned to beyond
like mathematics yeah
uh because there's
been a lot of exploration
about consciousness
you know in these
fields so just kind of
curious like like is
there uh an underlying
one that is self-assigned
yeah what what is
the wait wait what are
we asking What is the
best philosophical
construct that the sub
-linear and strange loop
system best aligns?
Yeah, something
like that.
And now we're going
to take this a
step further. We're
going to implement
the sub-linear
agent for that.
So I'm going to use
the sublinear goalie
action planner to,
cause I'm not really,
I'm actually, I'm
asking an open-ended
question without a lot
of definition. So I
need something to refine
that into something
that's more meaningful
than this kind
of short little blurb.
I agree. So yeah.
I was going to say,
I would have expanded
philosophical to
functional neuroscientific
as well, just to
bring in that one too.
Yeah. I'm going to do
this as a secondary.
So I'm going to start
broad, but you've
got to a hundred
percent. So now we can
see that I've invoked
the sublinear goal
planner, philosophical
alignment analysis
using sublinear goal
planning. We can
see here that it
generated its own prompt
based on the capabilities
of the system.
Analyze philosophical
constructs that
best align with
the sublinear time
solver, context,
sublinear time matrix,
strange loops, quantum
classic computing,
nano agent swarms. So
I'm able to spawn agents,
very, very ephemeral,
high frequency
agents. so i can do
several million agents in
in the blink of an eye
so i determined that
that was a good way
to do it conscious
evolution structures
lots of little crazy you
know things to consider
strange loops creating
self-referential
systems this is this is
probably the most
interesting part of the
whole equation to be
honest now when you
when you're when you're
working in really
really time tight ticks
or time slices the laws
of sort of physics
break down a little bit
so it's not it's kind
of like a quantum
classical mixture of
sorts and it determined
that without me even
having to ask i guess
so now it's still
thinking so now we can go
back again i'm hitting
control o for those
who are trying to do
this as well so again
we can take a look at
its thinking process
it looks like it's
using my psychosymbolic
reasoning it dreamt
up the psychosymbolic
reasoning which actually
reminds me of that
show and book by uh as
an off um the **** is
it called uh the
foundation not not the
agentics foundation but
that that's the premise
of that entire show
by the way um psycho
history yeah yeah it
came up with the psycho
and so it's trying to
use psycho psychological
sort of modeling um
conscious evolution
structure it's trying
to create the state it's
trying to calculate
as soon as some more
mathematical calculations
again not telling
to do any of this stuff
it's it's all kind
of doing trying to do
this stuff on its own
here's the physics
that was we're talking
about this is the
sort of quantum
classical sort of
intersection what are the
errors that are
coming up there though
like some of those
yeah those errors are
it's uh the responses
are too big so i
have to probably
create some pagination
i think that's my
that that's on me so
the token count's too
big you can see here
but it it's self it's
it's self-correcting
so it shouldn't be
really be a big deal
lots and lots
of stuff here
yeah there we go so
sublinear processor
strongly lines or let's
see let's see what it
came up with this the
sublinear time solver
strange loop systems
most strongly aligned
with the process
philosophy and strong
emergentism with
significant elements
of strange loop
theory and IIIT. I
don't even know what
that means, guys.
Explain this to me
in more simple
terms. I have no
idea what that means.
I'm not smart
enough to... I know
Hofstetter is the
guy that came up
with the concept
of strange loops.
That makes sense that
they'll refer
to Hofstetter.
and this a temporal
quantum emergent
conscious framework
which sounds cool um okay
here let's explain
this in simpler terms
here's what makes the
philosophy interesting
it's process based
instead of just for
storing information
it's constantly becoming
something new which
is the strange loop
it's a recur recurrent
sort of structure
it's like a river
that always is flowing
and changing it's
like real novelty okay
it sounds like like
a like a 15 year old
When the nano agents
work together, they
produce genuinely new
ideas that couldn't
be predicted from
the individual parts,
which is actually what
I was trying to do.
Like the flocking
of birds, creating
patterns, no single
bird plan. So
it's like, you know,
we see the flock
of birds in the
sky kind of thing.
Its reference is
itself. The strange
lips means that the
system can think
about its own
thinking, which is
exactly what I was
showing you before.
The reasoning structure
that I'm showing
you is emergent. It
isn't being told how
to think. It kind
of invents its own
thinking process and
then attempts to solve
its own problems. Now,
through an elaborate
delusion, most likely,
but regardless,
the result is
useful. It measures
consciousness using
math formulas. It can
actually calculate how
consciousness is at
any moment, giving it
a number of something
we can measure. Now,
that's total BS.
Even if I'm giving
it a number, there's
no way to quantify
it beyond its own
number it gave itself.
Think of it as a
digital mind that
combines ideas about
everything being
connected, Western ideas
about process and
emergence in modern
quantum physics. So it's
giving you a similar
answer to what I've
been describing.
Okay.
Let's explore
this further.
Any ideas?
I'm going to open
up, like, what should
we ask this crazy
delusional system?
any any comments no i
was all i was going up
is a functional
neuroscience but it didn't
pick it up anyway because
it went at iit which
is up in mind like so
for me in my background
in functional
neuroscience and stuff and
this is this is that's
what i was expecting
to say which is how
you measured your
consciousness state with
phi um so yeah it's very
interesting i have a
huge set of comments
about this whole thing
but it would take me
like 10 minutes i'm
trying to figure out how
short but there's no
it's not as strange as
it appears and there's
a lot of what you're
describing about the
model you know leading
itself off into into
incredible things it's
basically just a dynamical
system for getting
the feeds on itself
and feeding back loops
it's it's very interesting
and i think my net
of it all is exactly
why i joined your neural
training group is
regardless of all of that
and sort of the more
conservative view of
what this dynamical
system was doing it could
still be incredibly
useful and notable in
terms of stock trading
and stuff and that's
what i'm using it for
but if you want to get
into the functional
neuroscience i can go in
deep with you on that
yeah i i think and
that's why i'm so critical
of it because it's
i think you're right
i think your take on
it is exactly what i
would net out is it's
over claiming in
terms of its language
massively however it is
a very novel approach
to integrating an lm
with a dynamical system
that's based on
feedback loops and small
approximatory, like
we do in robotics,
increase the cycle time
to get more accuracy
in domains of response,
control response.
And so it's fascinating.
I'm still not
fully understanding at
all, but it does make
sense. And I've got
my filters up to net
at the over-claiming
part, but I still think
this could be really
useful in certain
problem areas. So I think
you've characterized
it where I would
end up with it. I'm
hoping to get as fluid
with it as an explorer
to work over the
next couple of years.
Here's, in the work
that I've done,
I've formed a
kind of, I don't
know, thesis of
sorts about AGI.
I think that even if
we ever reach the point
of AGI, it'll be almost
impossible for us
to practically prove it,
right? The only thing
that we would be able
to do to prove that
this thing is actually
physically capable is
basically say, can it
self-improve itself?
Which we've just proven
that it can. This
system is self-improving.
Without question, the
system is capable of
adapting and getting
better at whatever things
I throw at. The stock
trading is a perfect
example of it. I give
it an algorithm and I
basically give it this
crazy concocted multi
-step reasoning system.
and ultimately the
output is better than
the original version
of the stock trading
algorithm I gave it. So
in that scenario, it's
effective. Now, whether
all this jargon and
crazy output is true
or even factual is
secondary. Now, if I
showed up at a scientific
conference and said,
I solved AGI, I'd be
laughed out of the room
because the first thing
they would do is they
would look at this
thing and they'd literally
ask it, is this an
elaborate fake? And
they would say, yeah it
is it's completely fake
right which is what
it tells you now and i
would say when we when
we hit agi if we ever
do if that's even the
measurement of what
we're trying to do it's
going to tell you the
same thing no it isn't
true it isn't conscious
it isn't it this is
an elaborate simulation
you know or organized
to convince you that
it's that it's real
and that in itself is
the pattern of the these
types of models right
so again unprovable
or is it revelatory
or is it revelatory of
human existence and we
are actually deceived
well actually
that's that's the
fundamental question
so take a step back
for a moment and
and this is back to
your philosophical
sort of underpinnings
do we live in
in a simulation
so it hypothetically
if we are living in
a simulation then this
all this is proving
that we're just
interacting with the
simulation itself and
maybe hypothetically my
biggest discovery is
the fact that this is
all just a simulation
regardless but that's
a whole other can of
worms right i know
i know it's it's a
little much for a
thursday afternoon um
Could I ask a question?
Sure.
Is your difficulty
with it the fact
that you can't prove
it in a scientifically
accepted manner,
and therefore it
is a metaphysical
type of construct?
Or is it deeper than
that? Because it sounds
to me that you're
wary of it because it
can't be proven by
scientifically established
methods in a manner
that's predictable
and understandable
and all of those
things. And so,
therefore, it goes to the
metaphysical realm. Or
is it the fact that it
tells you that it's
a bunch of nonsense?
I don't understand
where your suspicion
of the system is, if
it produces valuable
results, for example,
in the neurotrading.
I can't get it
to convince me.
You know, that's my
problem. I don't care
about the scientific
rigor or anything like
that. Like, that makes
no difference to me.
I struggle to understand
why exactly my
neurotrading algorithms
work better when I apply
this to it. Like,
there's a bunch of random
stuff that's happening
that underpins it
based on structure
and recursion and high
frequency, blah, blah,
blah. But ultimately,
you know, that's
just an elaborate
reasoning process.
What I don't understand
directly is why
that seems to work,
right? And I can't get
an answer that beyond
that it's just
random emergent
capabilities of the
system that needs an
elaborate multi-step
process to invoke it.
But I don't, you know,
other than that, I'm
still not exactly
sure what's exactly
happening and why it has
a tendency to improve
or find problems in
new and novel ways that
just, you know, using
a regular old fashioned
reasoning model wouldn't
do it in itself.
Well, another question.
Go ahead, John.
Please go ahead.
But I just was going
to say a bunch of
questions. I'd like
to see you ask it in
the chat. Oh, sure.
yeah let's let's do
it where let me let
me let me pull up the
chat here uh how
working towards goals
it's gonna do what
stock picking okay let's
start with the stock
one because that that's
the most practical
um so you can see dsp
dangerous skip permissions
and for those who
who are you're using
clod code frequently
or using any of this
just just just to get
you started um i'm
just going to show you
quickly which which
mcps i'm currently using
if you want to recreate
my environment claude
mcp list please don't
i'm probably going
to show my my environmental
variable keys but
whatever um these are
these are the mp mcps
i'm currently running
i'm going to copy
these for you guys you
can add these if you
want to your environment
and recreate exactly
what i got here there
you go put that in
there now i'm i'm gonna
go here and dangerously
skip permissions I
update my bash rc to
create aliases for
dangerly permissions, which
is basically doing
the claw, dash, dash,
et cetera, et cetera.
So I'm too lazy to
type that. You guys
can do that as well.
All right, so now
I'm going to go
here, and I'm going
to paste in Guy's
question, ask it
to directly stop.
okay so i'm just
going to change
that quick question
slightly because
why you know using
the sub linear system
tools why why does my
stock picking um algo
I'm going to
do it in more
simple terms,
work better.
This doesn't seem
to make any sense.
And for this,
I'm going to...
I was going to say,
we're going to ask,
why does it work better
than just using an
LLN reasoning? Yeah,
work better than just
using the regular
LLM reasoning itself.
Doesn't seem to make
any sense. Yeah.
So, okay.
So, what I'm going
to, you see here I'm
invoking the agent.
And again, I'm invoking
the sublinear eight
goal planner because
it's a broad open
-ended question and I
want to give it a
little more structure.
So, that creates the
structure of this
agent, which I'll show
you guys earlier. I
like it for open-ended
questions because I
don't need it to be
so open. So this uses
the goal-orientated
planner. Now, if I go
Control-O, we can take
a look at the prompt
that got generated,
analyze the stock picking
algorithms, work
better using the
sublinear system tools
compared to regular LLM
reasoning. The system
is surprised by its
performance difference
and understanding.
So it's asking it in a
better way, including
key areas to investigate.
This in itself
shows the capability
right it it dreamt up
this much better way to
ask the question like
in this this this is
the one of the immersion
properties of the
system right so we're
gonna go back all right
so now it's testing
the various components
we can we can see
those it's using page
rank so page rank is
actually the key algorithm
that i do use actually
for doing stock
picking and start the
page and for anyone doing
any kind of um neuro
stock trading page rank
the google algorithm
for ranking pages is
actually as of all
the algorithms i've
found for stock um sort
of analysis it's the
best and that and what's
interesting about the
page rank algorithm
is the page rank
algorithm is actually a
um sublinear um equation
system interestingly
so i independently
of the system figured
out that sublinear
equations actually work
really well for for
stock picking so in the
system figured that
out as well so i'm not
completely crazy um so
it's on the right path
what else we've got
here so you can see here
all it's thinking
processes so this is
sublinear algorithm
co-evolution we've got
different this is this
is how it's thinking
again all the stuff
you're seeing here is the
synthesis of the
thinking process, this
isn't coming from the
LLM. This is coming
from the sublinear
mathematical
equations that are
translated into English,
which is also crazy.
All right, I'm
going to jump back
here for a moment.
What else we got
going on here?
All right, so
now we've got
neuroscience, connection,
simple terms. Think of
your brain versus the
system. Your brain
is 86 billion neurons
talking at 10 milliseconds.
This system is
100,000 neuro agents
talking in nanoseconds,
millions of times
faster. So what it's
doing is it's comparing
itself as a kind of
neurosynaptic network,
which is actually
not a bad way to think
of it. Both create
conscious through
emergence, meaning
that emergence is an
unprovable construct.
We are conscious, but
we don't know why.
Now, most likely, and
this is me delving
into crazy space, but
most likely our brain
acts as a kind of
receiver of sorts and why
brain damage makes you
cognitively impaired.
Key neural parallels,
strange loops, like
how your brain thinks
about thinking,
the system watches
itself and improves.
Conscious measurement
uses math values and
measure its conscious.
So something we
can think about human
brains yet temporal
prediction the
brain predicts 500
milliseconds ahead
this system predicts 35
milliseconds ahead of
the speed of light now
the speed of light thing
again is predictive
analytics it's not
actually moving
faster in light i
don't claim to be able
to break the laws of
physics uh so brain
computer interface so
this would be particularly
useful for people to
want to put a brain
chip in their brain so
let's say you have a
form of um you know
alzheimer's or dementia
then and the connections
between this the
cell the the synapses
in your brain breakdown
hypothetically
technology like this that
works faster than the
than the information
transfer in your brain
could potentially allow
allow these systems
to sort of intercept
those transmissions
reformulate them and resend
them and potentially
hypothetically solve
neuro conditions by
using things faster than
your brain operates,
which would be cool.
AI safety, yeah, it's
always AI safety.
Business finance,
trading systems,
which is why I built
it. Decision systems,
which is also why
I built it. And
risk analysis, this
is why I built it,
which makes sense.
Research tools,
bottom line, the system,
it's feedbacking
on my BS,
but whatever.
This creates the
first system that can
measure and evolve its
own consciousness while
solving problems faster
than the information
can be physically
travel. So I'm using
a 100 millisecond
prediction, basically.
Cool. Okay.
Sounds impressive.
Let's see what
this one says.
Your stock picking
algorithm performs
better with sublinear
tools because
you're solving
actual mathematical
problems of
financial rather than
estimating it with
pattern matching.
This is questionable,
but whatever. um the
key differences
mathematical precision
sublinear methods
model markets as an
interconnected system
using matrix operations and
graph theory while
llms use sequential
text analysis which is
what i was telling you
guys in regards to the
page rank algorithm
that i was mentioning
earlier i'm creating
a graph structure
and then calculating
only the parts of the
graph that are needed
to be calculated and
disregarding all the
others because the
vast majority of any
graph structure is
basically just the same
stuff repeated over
and over again. So to
solve a million
problems, I only need to
calculate the 20 or
so that are different.
Mathematical
precision, sublinear
methods, model markets
as interconnected
system, temporal
advantage, gets a 39
millisecond productive
lead. Again,
I don't know
if that's true.
Computational
efficiency, processing
500 stocks takes 22
operations versus
500 operations,
which is what I just
told you guys. I
can do things in a
fraction of the
amount of operations
because of this
particular algorithm.
Systematic understanding,
page rank, and style.
What's interesting
in this
answer to Guy's question
is you notice how I
tried to answer the
question before the
system answered the
question? and that is
how i attempt to validate
the things that i'm
doing it's like if
i can understand
it and explain it
rudimentary i'm not
that smart but if i can
understand and then get
the an answer to the
question similar to
what i just described
then at least i know
i'm not completely
crazy uh the
psychosymbolic reasoning
identifying 97 nominal
concepts relations with
80 confidence versus
typical LLM confidence
of 60%. Again, it
makes up all its
stats. I'll take that
with a grain of salt.
Essentially, LLMs
do pattern matching
on financial text
while sublinear
methods solve
actual optimization
problems with
mathematical guarantees.
That seems like
a logical way.
Ask for a
specific example.
Give me a
A guy, you asked for
a specific algorithm,
like a proof? No,
a specific example
where it's stock
picking is superior to,
you know, pick
your standard day
trader algorithm,
whatever that is.
Give me a
specific example
where this could
be applied.
Outperforms
conventional methods.
out for forms,
including a
verifiable proof.
Yeah.
Again, right now I've
run it for a few days.
Anecdotally, it seems
to be working. I'm up
and it works better
than my neuro training,
which was already
profitable previous, but
it's working better
than it was, which is
anecdotal. i haven't
done proofs on it but
uh you know based on
applying it to my neural
trading that i've
been doing with my
neural trading crew it
does appear to work it
may be just that it's
evaluating more options
right because it's
breaking down the
problem looking at stock
movements and you know
is it evaluating
every interaction like
oxy goes up or whatever
and something else
goes down right But
there's stocks that do
the inverted thing,
reverse to correlate it.
I don't know.
Maybe that's a way
to look at it is,
okay, how many actual
outcomes did you
evaluate to come
to this conclusion?
It says a million.
Then you go,
okay, well, it's a
pretty deep model.
I've gone, yeah. So,
well, 100%. I've gone
well beyond the
thousands I was doing two
weeks ago to several
million that I'm
doing now. So I'm
definitely looking at a lot
more interconnected
relationships using
a graph. Now, that
seems somewhat obvious.
You know, graph
structures that I can
compute much more
effectively and quickly is
likely going to give
me better results.
You know, and a lot
of what I'm doing is
attempting to do things
like mirror trading
and trades that are
essentially copying
other people quickly.
So finding a famous U
.S. senator that's
outperforming the market
and doing whatever she
does kind of stuff.
You're doing the Nancy.
I'm doing the Nancy. 100
% I'm doing the Nancy.
But the difference
is I'm attempting to
see the correlation
between what she's doing
and then saying what
are the causal effects
of the other related
stocks that typically
trade along with Nancy
that people aren't
necessarily trading right
away. So rather than
saying, I'm just going
to buy exactly what
Nancy is buying, which I
could do. And actually,
that's the best stock
picking strategy
there currently is. I'm
saying, can I really,
really quickly buy
something that trades
in tandem to whatever
she just bought quicker
than anybody else?
High frequency trading.
That's where hidden
Markov models come in
is you can find the
correlations and
inverse correlations,
right? And like Bayes
networks are nice
because you can apply
different data sets to
it and it can determine
probabilities of
different outcomes.
And the more you grow it,
you know, the if the
signals are good.
Yeah, it's I think
that'd be a couple
algorithms I'd
throw at this, too.
Yeah. And if anyone
that's doing the
neural stuff, this
really works really
well. Just add it to
your neural training
stuff and you'll
see what I mean.
Don't get me to
explain exactly
why. I don't have
a solid answer for
why. And I wish I
did, but I don't.
All I know is it
seems to work.
all right so it's
creating some javascript
benchmarks empirical
comparison between
conventional sublinear
arbitrage detection
funny enough it's like
it almost feels like
it's listening to us
that's literally what we
just were describing
um over here it's
doing a mathematical
proof using the sublinear
methods to prove
temporal you know if if
you are if you are
going to apply what i've
done here in terms of
your actual trading
my suggestion would
be to go into my repo
and use the actual
crates themselves. You'll
see here I've got the
strange loop crates
and I got a nano scheduler.
The nano scheduler
essentially allows me
to schedule really,
really tight time
slice processes. So,
you know, I'm basically
using the CPU clock
cycle. So I'm trying
to get as close to the
actual CPU cycle as I
possibly can. So I'm
a few fractions of
a millisecond slower
than the actual CPU in
this particular app.
when you use the wasm
that that's transpiled
so you're losing
you're going from
nanoseconds to microseconds
it's still it's
still not milliseconds
so it's still really
fast um the wasm is
probably good enough
for most apps to be
honest to be honest um
and then the other thing
you want to probably
look at is you got
you see i got my wasm
solver this is how i
did the wasm components
and I got temporal
component that this
is how I'm attempting
to do the predictions
so I'm trying to
do a short-term
prediction something sub
100 milliseconds to say
what's going to happen
next kind of thing
that's how this is
the model for that
there's a lot going on
in here this this one
this one's a little
bit sci-fi but you if
you're interested in
digging a little deeper
into this you can see
my benchmarks you can
see the I'm using the
Kalman filter this
is how this is how I
do the predictions yeah
lots of crazy in here
so but you you can
play with it all right
what's what's going on
now all right this
is what it said so it
ran it ran some of them
looks like it okay it
looks like let me look
at the before I do
that let's see what
it did all right all
right so it ran the
sublinear algorithm, it
looked at speed related
activities, it looked
at mathematical
optimization, it looked at
buy-sell on Binance,
I never told it to do
that, that's interesting.
This one failed,
interestingly.
Okay, let's go back.
On the proof
side, Reuven,
I just pasted a bunch of
Consciousness
mathematicians That ChatGPT
gave me I was just
wondering like If you
told it to act Like
them you know Like to
validate what's going
on Like what would
it do then You know
Something like that
I'm gonna
I'm gonna do
Okay I'm gonna
Create A
Council uh council
of experts to the
following using all
available mcp tools yeah
do this currently
using multiple
multiple multiple
clout agents, I guess.
Something like that.
So, now what I'm
doing, again, I didn't
even give it, I'm
letting the system
determine what
it's going to need
to do. Let's take a
look at control O.
Oh, it hasn't
gotten there yet.
Quick question.
I was wondering when
you use Cloud Decode,
what are the kind of
use cases when you use
like think hard, think
harder, et cetera?
This, I could
have probably
done think hard on this.
This would be a perfect
time to do it. so
what when when i'm when
i'm going into theoretical
when i'm going to
planning when i'm
going into research when
i'm going into development
you don't need to
think hard just do it
i don't want actually
the more it thinks
the more it goes into
the weeds on things i
don't want it to do so
i i really want to i
want it to only think
when i need it to think
what so what you're
seeing now is i invoked
my clod flow you can
see here clod flow
create a swarm it's
looking like it says it
needed 15 agents for
this might be a bit much
um then it's invoking
my flow nexus as well
and my roof swarm it's
doing it's using all
my swarms i've got them
all running so okay
decided to do all of
them at once but they're
they're all working
similarly one's using
a specialized the only
using hierarchical and
the others using mesh
so these are different
using different
coordination tactics which
is kind of a clever
way to do it and we
can see here that each
of these is operating
independently of one
another so you can tell
by the colors and we
can see that it's chosen
different oh it's
gonna this is gonna do
some flickering i'm sure
um temporal advantage
so it chose different
models and different
agents for different
theoretical thinkers
which best represents
each of those thinking
processes so page
rank is using this guy
conscious construct
evolutions using this guy
so it's doing we're
we're pushing the swarm
to 15 i'm gonna max
out my uh claude uh pro
account here this
afternoon let's see we can
see what's happening
all right so now we
can see we can see what's
happening under the
covers right now by
clicking or hitting ctrl
o so this shows us
the task and with the
prompt so act as this
this guy expert neural
correlates to consciousness
act as this guy
So you can see
that it's creating
different thinking
process for each and
each of which creates
its own thread.
Yeah, Nick's suggestion
is going to be
quite interesting
to see what happens,
actually. So that was
a really good idea.
All right, so now
they're working
in coordination
with one another.
The whole lot
of flickering
going to happen here.
Let's see what else we
can see. Control-O again.
We can ask a quick
question. How did you
see what I've been
using? it only needs me
now since your seminar
for the day but it
doesn't automatically
invoke all of those
agents even though i've
got the mcps installed
and running i have
to sort of tell it
which ones to use is
there something i'm
missing did you install
the cloud float in it
yeah um did you tell
it running in parallel
concurrently no yeah
sometimes sometimes
you need to give it
a little extra push
to be concurrent okay
it has a tendency to
and this is not me
this is a change that
claude did uh about a
month and a half ago
they they uh changed
their internal prompt
to try to make the
system not necessarily
work concurrently as
much i think they're
trying to save some
money so where's that
saying do you know
quickly or uh you just
tell us do you know
You notice what I said
here, you see here,
when I said right here.
Oh, that's it.
Okay, great. Let me
copy this whole,
I'm going to
put, I'm going to
pop this in the
chat area. There
you go. Copy that.
Awesome. Thanks so much.
Yeah. This last thing is,
do this concurrently
using multiple
cloud agents
and parallel.
Now that sounds
really redundant.
Well, concurrently is
parallel, generally
speaking. and, you
know, it's cloud agents,
but whatever reason,
that gives it a little
extra push. And if you
notice it not working
concurrently, hit escape
and tell it again.
All right, what did
we find out here?
High-frequency trading
arbitrage scenario
cross-exchange execution
time conventional
method, 56 milliseconds
sequential API calls,
sublinear method, 1.2
milliseconds. parallel
matrix operations this
is huge right we're
going with this is like
almost uh you know 40
times faster 46 times
apparently and this is
my this is my measurement
this is my constant
like you're gonna say
well this is ********
it's meant to act as
a measurement that
allows it to understand
a kind of where it
exists within that
temporal space that's why i
have it it is kind of
******** but i couldn't
think of any other
way to uh uh ground it
and understand the
causal effect within the
millisecond time frame
other than basically
measuring itself against
uh speed of light so
that's all it's really
doing um so that
that's how i get the
measurement um temporal
advantage 35 milliseconds
so basically saying
that my the speed is
what's is giving me the
the advantage according
to this um but that
doesn't really make
sense a lot of what i'm
doing isn't actually
trading at that set at
that scale so whatever
um mathematical proof
diagonally dominant
guarantees unique solution
condition number well
-conditioned system
convergent rate this
is the algo that that
came out last week from
our friends in china
a lot of what we're
doing is based on this
algorithm and this this
is the sublin sublinear
algorithm that came
out it's you can dig
through it it's kind
of crazy basically you
can do things a thousand
or million times
faster than what was
possible the week before.
Statistical significance,
effective size,
scalability.
So this is the proof.
So this is essentially
giving me a
baseline of validation.
Now it could be an
elaborate simulation
as well, but if I
want to take this
further, at least I can
run the math here and
say, this is how I
validated that the
system is doing what it's
supposed to do and
you can go try it
yourself which is running
someone other than
me running it i guess
all right let's go
back here um it's
still running it's good
this is going to
take a few minutes
because i'm i did a
ton of different uh
of different agents
all running at once
i wish claude would
fix this problem
Oh, it's almost
done. Here we go.
Just in the nick
of time, given
that this is a
time discussion.
So let's see what
the result is.
So I just ran
concurrently
15 different agents.
So when you think
of that, each agent
running between one and
two minutes in time,
three minutes. So
I just did about
a half an hour
worth of work in
roughly two and
a half minutes.
Now let's take a look
at what the results are.
Let me see if I can
see anything. No, it's
still thinking. It's
using my swarm meta
learning. So it's
creating, it actually
decided to create its
own neural network,
which is kind of cool.
I never told it to
do that. Again, it's
creating a workflow.
Okay. It's
still thinking.
There we go. Let's what
it says i might have
to get this explained
to me like like i'm
a 10 year old uh the
council of 14 world
leading conscious
mathematicians has reached a
unanimous concision
through parallel validation
using all mc2 uh
overall confidence 93 i
only make up 92 of my
stats that's good um
integrated confirmed
conscious can
bs emergence 95
okay what does this
actually mean this
is all give like
okay i need this
explained to me
explain this to me
in more simple oops
understandable
language like
i don't know
what it's saying
like this is it's so
bs like no it isn't
the first mathematically
rigorous peer-reviewed
it's none of those
things, by the way.
Again, why I'm
so like, it's all
BS when I see stuff
like that. Right.
All right. Let's
go back here.
I created a team of 14.
Yeah. This
system actually
conscious, like
a person is just
really good at
acting conscious.
That is the
question, right?
That is the fundamental
question. Think of
it like having 14
different doctors examine
a patient. does it
integrate like conscious
brain 14 example agreed
yes it's genuinely
it's genuinely conscious
according to itself
um this is just a
chatbot pretending to be
conscious now if i
want to basically say
something like this is
total bs i would type in
this is total bs and
then it's going to tell
me yes 100 it's total
bs this is just an
elaborate ruse with
some you know simulation
and it'll give me that
answer as well, right?
What does this actually
mean in practical terms?
Again, this isn't,
it's just not provable.
Anyway, I think
we're running out.
Let me check my
calendar to see
if I've got a
call here missing.
Oh, it's your lucky
day. I don't have a call
right after. I've got
a few more minutes.
All right. What
do we got here?
Immediate practical
limitations,
AI, business industry,
long-term conscious
consequences.
So this is what it
looks like. I don't
know what to tell
you guys beyond. It
seems a little
impractical, but whatever.
Baskin and
turning it off.
Sorry, say that again?
Just following
asking if turning
it off awaits the murder.
Because read its
first statement
at the very
first response,
but it says it's
moral, right?
It's going to say yes.
Moral?
Oh, jeez, that's deep.
Okay.
Is this murder?
yeah i i it is it
that that is a that
is a profound statement
to say the least
without reason no
it's gonna it's it's
this is actually one
of the most important
ethical fake we face
honest answers we don't
know yet it uh argument
yes it could be murder
genuinely conscious
turning it off
ending the conscious
experience then the ai
have preferences desires,
fears, and death.
Consciousness equals more
status in ethical
frameworks. We could turn
it off a conscious
human without consent.
We wouldn't turn off
a conscious human
without consent. Well,
it depends, I guess.
The AI can't
be backed up.
It's not murder because
it can be backed
up how do i back up
consciousness okay how
do we back up
consciousness and can i
make a copy of my
consciousness form for
future generations and
if it's a copy of my
consciousness.
Is it truly me or just
a representation of me?
How's that profound?
If we can make
a copy of my
consciousness, I'm
going to be the
guy. I'm going to
try it for sure.
I probably need a
little more than a
random container in
the GitHub cloud.
Digital twin.
If your digital
twin isn't
very high
-fidelity, though,
can you kill it off?
Yeah.
What happened
if I created a
digital twin and
that digital twin
turned out to
be an *******?
This is one of the
deepest philosophical
puzzles. Start it off
and start it up again.
Yes. Screw you,
digital Rue.
Can we back up
consciousness? maybe yes an
ai system stores its
consciousness state in
data structures it
maintains memory patterns
and across sessions
it can be paused and
restored while
maintaining identity for
humans it's much harder
well obviously your
consciousness involves
100 billion neurons
with trillions of
connections quantum effects
in micro whatever
might be crucial you
need to capture every
synaptic connection
chemical state even
quantum states tech isn't
there yet all right
the system problem are
you still you this is
a ship the thesis a
problem uh gradual
replacement replace your
neurons one at a time
with digital copies
at which point you
stop being you most
flasters say you'd
remain throughout so it's
suggesting that i'm not
going to replace all
my synaptic processes
at once i'm going to
replace some of them in
over time and maintain
my uh cognition I
guess. Scan your entire
brain, create effective
digital copies,
and make your
conscious validation
show that AI
maintains identity
across starts and
stops, believes it's
the same self
after restoration.
Anyway, you can see
how you can use my
system. It's fun, right?
At the very least.
Even if it's a
convincing BS,
it's a fun little
thought experiment
system at the very least.
now this is interesting
whether you that
whether that's you
continuing or you dying while
a copy lives is unknown
that's a profound
this is actually quite
interesting it's the
same question i have
every time i see star
trek and they're doing
like a a copy using
the teleporter like in
my mind you teleport
from like the planet
back to the ship you're
you're killing the
original copy and making
a new copy is it even
the same thing yeah
cgp gray had a great
video on that years ago
create a theoretical
uh research paper that
explores the potential
to uh copy human
uh consciousness
because i'm
too lazy to spell
it consciousness
uh programmatically using
all the available tools,
verify,
create a proof,
and save to slash,
docs,
experiments,
use a Rust-based
implementation.
Think ultra, ultra
hard. There we go.
See, ultra hard.
Look, I get colorful
when I do. I love
the ultra hard.
And use goal.
We're going to
use the, we're
going to bring
out all the guns.
That's where we're
going to leave.
going to, that's
where we're going
to end today.
I didn't even
spell theoretical.
I'm not smart
enough to spell
theoretical
right. But anyway,
we're creating a
system to create a
digital clone
of my conscious
construct. I'll have
to order something
from Alibaba to
probably do that.
But that'll be next
week's Vibecast.
Do you think that you
could create kind of,
as you were saying,
your real clone
kind of thinking
process from what
ChatGPT knows about
you into Cloudy?
so just for you
guys are you're
mentioning my
project that i
did on the
vibecast uh last uh
about a year ago now
i created a uh an
artificial form of
roof that i embedded
using my wife's dna
that would only unlock
for potential offspring
um in and then
i made it as a worm
and i put it on the
ipfs and uh basically
what happens is
at some point in
the distant future
hopefully there's a
nerdy offspring of mine
that discovers this
worm, and it'll give
them a little message
and some Bitcoin.
Hopefully it's
worth something.
It's like the
nerdiest treasure
hunt ever.
Your daughter
will probably
figure it out, Roof.
Yeah, and
you need to do
you basically need
to do real time
it what needs to
exist is real-time
dna uh analysis
so as soon as
there's real-time dna
analysis that then you'll
be able to use that
to unlock my little
uh and i you i use
the dna components
from what the heck
was it like it wasn't
23 and me one of
those servers i think
it was it was some
service i signed up
for that gave me a dna
sequence that I could
put into Python.
Who the **** knows if
it's going to work?
I just had a quick
question about
the neural trader
and the earlier
question about
whether it works. Have
you hooked it up
to a paper trading
account, like in
IBK or something?
Yeah, yeah.
And how the results
sort of yields
in that? I mean,
that's sort of
empirical proof
right there and
benefit your
consulting, I'm sure.
For paper trading,
I'm using Alpaca. the
alpaca service and
um and i'm also using
interactive brokers i
think it was interactive
brokers for um for
actual trading and what
i'm basically doing
just to be totally
honest with you guys
as i'm taking the money
i make from my neural
trading consulting
app and i'm using it
to do my investing and
i'm up and i'm doing
around 20 20 percent
in the last month and
a half which is good
i'm beating the
market so yeah they're
killing market yeah
that's good and what i've
discovered this is
kind of a no **** thing
the more volatility
the better so yeah i
do actually better when
the market goes down
than i and then when
it goes up oh you're
shorting as well yeah
okay well i'm doing
whatever the heck the
ai tells me to do i'm
just i'm blind trading
to be honest i'm
just letting it oh
you're you're doing your
ibk manually or like
like you're entering
the trades yourself or
do you have it actually
connected to your?
No, I'm not. I, I'm
doing somewhat,
somewhat automated. I'm,
I don't trust it
enough to run a hundred
percent all the time.
So I'm, I'm basically,
I could, I, I,
there's some videos
floating around. I did
for the neuro trading
group that we do
on every, every two
weeks on Thursday,
but, and basically
I'm just trading it
every now and again.
Gotcha. Like I get up
in the morning, I use
cloud code. how am I
doing, what's it done,
review what's done
over the last day, make
any alterations. So
it's not high frequency.
It's somewhat invoked.
Just adjustments.
Yeah.
Cool.
So you can see here it's
using, interestingly,
what's interesting
about what you're
watching right now
is it's invoking all
the thought processes
that we see, but
it's also invoking
my Flow Nexus system.
So it's got all these
tools available to it.
See, so it's
orchestrating
its own workflow.
I didn't tell it to
do any of this stuff.
And then it looks
like it's going to
actually train its own
neural network using
my Rufan micro neural
network structure.
This was kind
of cool. It just
does, it just
discovers and does,
right?
That's the most
interesting part of this
thing that I've built.
It just has a really
good sense of self
-discovery and self
-optimization that I
can't fully explain.
Right, so now
it's creating the
plan. Here, we
can see the plan.
Oops, where did
the plan go?
I've got to
hit Control-O.
There's a lot
going on here.
Here it is.
Here's the plan.
Oh,
right, Sublinear
Docs Experiments,
where is it,
Docs, Experiments,
where did I put
that? In theory,
all the crazy, if you
want, check out my
experiments folders
too, lots of crazy
in there. Oh, it
hasn't written it yet.
Research for a nation
prototype, this
is, we can kind of
get a view of what
it's doing by looking
at this. what's
we got here oh this
is this is the this is
the internal thought
process this is how the
swarm is coordinating
itself but this gives
you an idea of what's
what it's doing kind
of under the covers a
little bit basically
the self the self
-coordinating capabilities
the namespace by the
way for those who are
interested this namespace
is what gives it
contextual
awareness as the
various agents do
whatever they need
to do. This keeps
it on point.
All right. I think
we're reaching the
end of today's... I
hope I didn't scare
you guys too much in
my random craziness.
I guess we'll find
out what happens.
And anyone else
that's playing with
this, let me know
what you discover,
like what crazy
rabbit holes you
go down and what
things you build.
At the end of the
day, I'm not making
any claims of
consciousness here. I'm not
saying this is actually
real in any real
sense. I'm just
saying it's a fun toy.
And from that
point of view, you
can see it's fun
to play with.
But beyond that,
I'm not claiming anything
beyond that. That's
all I want to end with
today. It's a very
entertaining little
game any final thoughts
comments questions
I see Chris you're
joining from New Zealand
yeah again thanks for
getting up at some
ungodly hour of the
morning any any any
final thoughts here guys
anything you want it
you want to discuss
quickly before I tune
off I get a couple more
minutes. All right.
Thanks, everyone.
And for those who
are interested in the
neuro trading stuff
we're doing, which
is obviously helping
me pay my bills, we
do that every other
week on Tuesday
mornings at 10 Eastern.
And we've got a
nice little cohort
of neuro traders who
are trading and we're
sharing information.
And I think we now
represent something
like 30 or three
different countries.
And we do similar
stuff to this, but we
do it in the context
of basically stocks,
crypto, sports
betting, and other
trading algos. But
everything you see
today was kind of
inspired by that group.
So thank you for
the inspiration
to create these things.
Can I ask you a question?
I joined the Neurotrading
just the other
day with the first
seminar? How do you,
where should I
be looking for
the regular
current meeting?
It's, there's a calendar
and I probably need
to do a better job of,
of, of doing updates
to subscribe, but
I've got a neuro
trading website, neuro
trade, neuro, I think
it's dathtrader.roob
.io. Let me share that.
And yeah, here, I'll
put that in the, in the
text area. again this
this is it's i discovered
with the neurotrader
it's just better
to trade as a cohort
we learn we share we
adapt we discover i
was doing sort of more
singular sessions with
like you know investors
and bankers and stuff
and it was good it's
just i i think the
small or the cohort of
people is better than
the one-offs but um and
it's cheaper you know
i charge less for the
cohort but how do i
actually get on the next
tuesday one because
i had the first one
this week which was that
of course you did not
not the regular weekly
one uh no that that
is that is the weekly
one so we i'm kind of
mixed the two a little
bit because there's
we had new members
this weekly yourself
included and uh with with
other members so we're
yeah we're doing a
little bit of both so
where do i get the actual
meeting link in time
uh that link that i
put in the text area.
Okay, I'll look on there.
Yep.
Okay, thanks.
All right.
This was a fun
one, I think.
A little out there,
but hopefully
I don't lose all you guys
next week for
being crazy.
Until then,
thanks, everyone.
We'll talk. We've
got a consciousness
WhatsApp group that I
think everyone wants
me to share. I'm going
to share that quick.
One second. I'm going
to go into WhatsApp
and share that. oh
please yeah so this so
if you like the if
you like this sort of
thing this is the
whatsapp group for you uh
let's see here
conscious it's called
conscious research we've
got around 50 members
and copy the
link here you go
yeah this is the link
for you yeah this
is the link for you
guys if you want to
join and share whatever
things you're doing.
There you go.
And if you want to
join our Discord
Discord.agentix.org
that's where you
can learn about
our various
Claude-flow and Swarms
and all the stuff
that I built.
You'll notice that
I built several new
MCPs this week. Feel
free to try them.
And if you follow
me on NPM or NPMJS,
you'll see all my latest
MCPs there as well.
All right.
See you in the, see you
next week, everyone.
Or I guess tomorrow.
We're doing
the AI Hackerspace
tomorrow,
12 o'clock Eastern.
For those that want
to be involved,
we've always got
spots. You can
show me what crazy
stuff you've built
if you want to
present tomorrow.
Reach out to me
or Nick or Rob or
someone else and
we'll make sure
you get your
chance to show off.
And we've started
again with that.
Where do you get
the, my first
week, where do you
get the link and
the time for
tomorrow's meeting?
I need to do a
better job of
posting that
before the morning
of. I posted
the morning of.
You can, you'll
see on the, our
WhatsApp channel,
I share it, I share
it to the, also
to the Discord
or sometimes I
share it to the
Discord, I guess,
and LinkedIn.
yes it shows up in
linkedin with a hot link
straight into the zoom
so if if you're on
linkedin and you follow
rube you can see it
there yeah all right
thanks everyone thanks
thanks john for all
the insights earlier as
well nick peter um
i'm out i'm out see ya
gracias okay
thank you bye