so yeah last week uh
i took i took the week
off i was a little
under the weather and
went on a bit of a road
trip with my daughter
to see a her favorite
act a guy named uh
conan gray which i wasn't
particularly familiar
with but it was fun
to hit the road and
go to ohio akron ohio
and the where else did
i go the cleveland
at the rock and roll
hall of fame so you know
it was it was a good
it was a good little
uh break um been been
fooling around with a
number of stuff this
week but but before
we do who do we got on
the call here i got you
know jed you've been
you've been busy
working on on a number
of things uh how's it
going did we did you
do an office hours last
week or what we did
we did have some fun
with office hours and
then brad uh shared how
he agentic engineers
so i think we were able
to show this community
there's more than
one way to do things
yeah and there is
that's a really good
point there's many ways
to do things and and
there and that's
probably part of the
exciting part of what
we do is is uh you know
figuring out the the
the way that works
best for you the way
though and that's a lot
of discussions i have
it's like what works
for me doesn't
necessarily work for
somebody else um so
yeah that's that's part
partially maybe we'll
explore today i've
been busy bug fixing
this morning apparently
i'm good of breaking
things right before
these calls, but
hopefully I can get
everything back up and
running in short order.
I see Rob, you're
on the call
as well. How's
it going, Rob?
Oh, good, good,
Ruben, and welcome
back. Yeah, it's
been a good and busy
week. Lots of stuff
shaping up New Zealand
and getting the
dates selected for
Tokyo, the Tokyo
chapter, and I believe
Paris as well. So
tons on the go.
Nice. I think there's
a bunch of stuff
happening in London,
too, coming up.
Yeah, London's been
interesting for
me. It's been a
really hot city.
I just got off a
call with some folks
out of London
about an hour ago.
So London's hot for
Eugentex, for sure.
And they weren't
familiar with what
we were doing in
London. So this was
like independent
of all the things
Montuip and Benz and
others are doing.
Montuip, how's it going?
yeah 250 billion
uh the the you know
the investment
what we got in the
uk is that billion
in dollars or in
dollars in dollars
yeah that's like
that's like 12
pounds or something
no i'm just kidding
i'm just kidding
us bashing yeah but uh
yeah it's it's great
so what exactly does
that involve that's
like government uh
spend or is that is that
is that like uh data
centers um open ai
nvidia google um what
else you know the big
tech um are investing
i don't know if it's a
promise or is it a
roadmap or it's already
on the bank account uh
i don't know details
but these are the big
brands okay so it's
one is it one of the
like i i love uh paper
partnerships we're
we're gonna we're gonna
spend 300 billion
dollars on gpus you don't
have with money we don't
have but don't worry
it's going to be
amazing and your stock's
going to go up 100
billion dollars i i i'm
just summarizing last
last week right and and
i'm the **** for
pointing it out no you're
you just don't have
the uh you know this is
how the world works
well just because that's
doesn't mean it's it's
it's a great way to
do things but what am
i i i like real things
well real uh virtual
things anyway yeah and
volunteer is the other
company yeah coming
up obviously ben's uh
next ben is day our
fortnightly sessions and
then in partnership
with a group called
projector which bens
had been part of before
there is an in-person
event the next day on
thursday um um i would
be very keen on like
roof if you are kind
of coming across
connections here um if
it is relevant for us to
be bring them in to what
we are doing so please
feel free to point
them to us um i think
we're slowly building
a community we but i
think we got we still
we got to normalize it
a little bit more i
guess in terms of more
time with the industry
for example we have
a session i think i
mentioned before in in
october and on the
security space that should
hopefully give us a
bit more visibility and
so we are taking we
are working along those
lines okay yeah it's
a great right right?
Sorry, Rob.
That's at Greenwich?
No, this is basically
at Mercedes's
campus. This is the
CISO London Summit.
Yeah, excellent.
It's just a 20-minute
keynote within Mark
and I, but that's
what we... Okay, cool.
All right, we've
got a lot to cover
today. Anything else
anyone wants to, any
updates, anything
before we jump in?
This is your moment
of... And Mandreep,
you're looking
for our new venue
location sponsor in
London for anyone that
might have a lead.
Is that correct?
That's correct.
Okay, so everyone's
really quick to
offer. We need to
probably do a better job
of taking people
up on their offers.
The big tech companies
are a little bit
more difficult
because they require
sometimes like
knowing who's going to
be there or limits
to certain criteria.
But there's a number
of tech firms that
have offered so we
just need to probably
follow up with them
um i saw your post so
maybe we'll maybe i'll
repost that as well
for you to see see we
could drum up but as
i said london for me
has been particularly
good over the last
uh about two three
months i've got probably
around half a dozen
companies and i've
that i've reached out
and i'm working with
to some degree in in
london and i think another
one is in edinburgh
so a little further
north i guess um
we just need Two things
real quick, buddy.
So, first thing, on
the $250 billion,
New Zealand just got $70
million over seven years.
Sorry, sorry.
$70 million?
M.
But keep in mind,
I don't know
what the population
of New Zealand
is, but on a per
capita basis,
that's probably not
that bad, right?
Is that New
Zealand dollars?
Yeah. Yeah, that's New
Zealand. okay sorry
that's harsh okay oh
also it's actually
really little because
new zealand has same
population than in
finland that we are at
least investing like
hundreds of millions so
it's pretty it's
something it's something
it's better than nothing
and it's it's it's
yeah it could could
be worse um so like
but actually what
is the population of
finland or New Zealand?
5 million. 5 million.
So your entire country
is less than Toronto.
Interesting.
In terms of all these
numbers, how to leverage
them, right? I mean,
the way to make
sure this is how it is
in every other place,
like, there are these
Innovate UK rounds that
keep going around,
that go from a few
hundred thousand to a
few million, actually.
I'm just wondering,
something we should think
about is, can you be
scientific about this
community forming
small units of groups
and basically tackling
those grant fundings.
That's how this money is
actually trickled down.
I love that.
Be intentional about that
and be systematic
about that.
Yeah, that actually
makes a lot of sense.
So you're suggesting
that the money comes
from corporate interests
as in the form of
grants versus the
government basically for
example if you look up
innovate uk on google
innovate uk grants you
see lots of ai projects
going on at the moment
and these are open
either fully fully
free or 70 free 30 you
have to invest or
basically loans very very
cheap loans and they
they range from like
120 000 all the way to
a few million so they
could be so for For
example, the last one
I applied was around
UK Sovereign AI Fund.
So I've applied
for a couple now.
But I'm thinking like,
you know, because
it's much more
easier to make these
applications now
than it used to be
before. I've just
been using Deep
Research Gemini for
many applications.
That's right.
But if we form like small
cohorts here
and we're really
scientific about
attacking them,
probably out of
20, we'll get two.
how many other applicants
do you think are
also using LLMs to
enrich their applications
we are early probably
I'm pretty sure
almost many would
do that but well
hey I just wanted to
thank Robert Ransom as
well for connecting
me with Finland we got
off a call last night
with Miko Elseria um
who's had a very very
successful uh launch
um they've got you know
1200 members on their
finland agentics uh
whatsapp chat and uh
it's taken off over
there so we had a really
great call with them
um last night and uh
so something is uh
brewing there so i'm
really excited about
that so thanks and we've
got timo on the call
here so g'day and uh
well let's let's get
cracking roof yeah let's
do this all right thanks
for all the updates
everyone it will be
if i may say for a
couple words to come
here uh from malaysia
and uh well along poor
here and uh and uh
greetings from uh from
the age atomic where we
had a uh i had a a panel
discussion yesterday
about the ai and agent
engineering there
and uh and uh tomorrow
robert uh hosting
two two panels here and
uh yes We're talking
about the numbers, I
mean, Dubai and GCC,
which I think in
regular language,
it's like the Middle
East, like the
country, Saudi
Arabia, Saudi Arabia,
Qatar,
Bahrain, and so on.
They are investing 4
.65 trillion USDs. There's
45 million people,
so it means that they
are investing 100
,000 USD per person
for AI-related things
there. I believe in
these numbers or not, but
they have the oil money
and they're really,
really heavily also
investing in the AI
industry in large
scale. And that's kind
of, that gives you the
support of 100,000.
And I think that is
like next five years.
So, so try to beat that.
Nice. Incredible.
Yeah, looking forward
to seeing the, the,
the footage and
the pictures. I saw
one of you, Tommy, up
there on the panel.
it should be, it sounds
like it's coming off
really well so
congratulations to Robert E
and the team out
there putting
together that APA Summit
Absolutely,
very very good
people and very
nice to meet
Robert in person
here Yeah, nice
And say hi to Rob for
me lots of doing lots
of stuff, really
appreciate that, all the
work he's putting in
as well Yeah, I'll see
him again tomorrow
All right, so a few
things that I've been
working on You know, my
latest tutorial,
for those that are
interested, I've
been playing with
the new developer
mode within ChatGPT.
And as you know,
700 million people
are using ChatGPT on a
weekly basis or monthly
basis or some basis.
So like an astronomical
amount of people.
So embedding your
tools within ChatGPT
is just a quick and
easy way to get a decent
user base and
integrate your data and
that sort of thing
quite, quite quickly.
So what I want
to show you
guys quickly is
how I did it.
And there was a number
of kind of gotchas
to get it working.
But for those that
aren't familiar, if
you go here, I'm in
ChatGPT, and you go
to your settings,
there's a little
hidden area now under
connectors. If you
scroll to the bottom,
you'll see this advanced
settings option.
You click that on and
that basically enables
this developer
mode where you can
basically enable full
MCP support and that
allows you to essentially
add your own MCPs.
So in this case, I
created an MCP server
based on my Flow Nexus
system. uh so mcp
-flow-nexus i gave it a
little sort of interface
with different
endpoints so the end
points are the the
trickiest part of this
was actually the oauth
getting the oauth
endpoints to actually
verify and create the
tokens and then stay
open for more than like
five seconds and things
like that basically
i i got it all i
got it mostly all
working um you know you
can you can create an
account you know that
that sort of thing
so what so what i'm
going to do right now
and just fingers crossed
that it actually works.
So basically they'll
show you some of
the code and show
you how to create
your own. But
basically we can go in
here and I'm gonna
create a new one
and I'm gonna call
it Flow Nexus 5.
It's because I've
got four already.
Now without
OAuth, you can use
edge functions
and other things
and it's actually
quite easy.
Now the issue you have
without OAuth is if
you don't have any
sort of authentication,
it's hard to know who's
doing what and if you
want you know uh role
-based access or or
limitations based on um
permissions then you're
you're either making
it open to everybody
or you or or it's uh
just limited to data
that you that you don't
care about so off is
is for the types of
things i'm doing it's
definitely pretty
useful it's just easier
without it so you might
want if you're starting
you might want to
start without it just
to see how it works and
i again the description
Doesn't seem to make
much difference. I
was hoping the
description would actually
guide it a little bit
It doesn't so I'm not
going to bother Well,
I'll put flow of access
in here or whatever
And so I'm going to
create now if all goes
well. I'm I'm going to
Create and this
should spawn a
OAuth login
So we'll see what
happens. I've got 90
something tools. The
first time it ran was a
little slow So now we
see that we went we
went to the OAuth The
URL here is particularly
important. You'll
see here that we've
got different response
types code. We've
got the client ID. That's
a unique identifier
that I generated
just for this. We get
the redirect back,
which is basically
redirecting back to the
connector platform and
some other tokens and
some other scopes.
Basically, this is
all the requirements
of ChatGPT system.
So I'm going
to log in here and
I'm going to...
Oops, I'm going
to log in and
then I'm going
to go here.
So at which point
it should, if all
go as well, it
should authenticate.
Let's hope the demo got a
smile on me at
this morning.
All right. It's
doing its thing.
Taking a little longer
than normal, possibly
because I'm sharing my
screen or something.
Usually this happens
really quickly. I'm
not sure why it's so
slow at the moment.
this is chat GPT
doing this thing. All
right, I guess it just
had something to do
with sharing the
screen, I guess. But
you can see here it
worked. I can see all
my actions. So these
are the different
actions I have available.
So what I'm doing
in this particular
scenario is I create
a mechanism to create
sandboxes and create
different neural
networks and some of
the other components
here, a subset of
my capabilities of
the Flow Nexus system.
All right,
so in this case, that
looks good, so I'm
going to go here and
I'm going to activate
it by going here to
more, developer mode,
in developer mode now
I've got different
options available to me,
so I'm going to choose
Net Flow Nexus 5. There
is zero difference
between Flow Nexus 4
and Flow Nexus 5, I
just happened to set
that up earlier but one
of the one of the
things I that I don't
necessarily like
particularly is the fact that
it will you see in
your sec I'm gonna say
create a sandbox I've
been having some issues
with the sandbox
this morning so I'm
gonna debug it and see
if it creates the mock
version or or legitimate
version all right
so we gotta do that right
so now it's thinking
that you can choose
different different
options here where it uh
you know you can use
thinking mode or auto
or pro i you know i
just i'm going instant
just to see what
happens now what's
happening next thing
you see here is it's
listing all my tools
so this is telling me
basically that it works
and i got a whole bunch
of tools so i'm
going to choose just
randomly a tool you
can see that it's it's
using you know here's
the stop a sandbox and
here's the status of
the sandbox and so on
so it looks like the
tools are working.
So this is basically
telling it what it needs
to do. Now it's
attempting to create the
sandbox. You can see
that it's going to
install some packages
and do some other
things. I'm going to
enable this to remember.
It only remembers
for the particular
conversation
in which you're
having, which is
not optimal either.
So it means if I start
a new conversation,
it's going to make
me do this every
time. It's kind of
like the way the
plugin system works.
Same general idea. So
the plugin system
uses SDKs and APIs
and traditional sort
of API structures.
This uses MCPs. So in
essence, in the most
simple terms, it's
basically a version of
the plugin system, but
using MCPs instead.
So here we can see
here it's calling a
tool. I can see what
tool it's calling. I
can see the request
structure. You can see
here it's requesting
a sandbox and it's
made the response,
looks like it's working.
Now what I'm looking
for, because I was
having some trouble
earlier, I'm looking for
the response to
actually make sure that
my sandbox isn't
returning mocks. It isn't.
So now it's going to
execute some code,
that's good, let's
go ahead and do that.
So this is really
quick and easy way to
integrate just about
any MCP enabled data
system. But keep
in mind, it's not a
studio MCP. It's an
MCP that needs to run
in a streamable HTTP.
So a web-based MCP.
But it looks like
it's all working.
It looks like it
did it correctly.
So now I can take
it further. I can
say create a neural
network workflow.
Network workflow.
and we'll do that
and all right let's
see what happens
now it's thinking
now the question
really for us you know
if I was if I was
doing this in the
if I if I was doing
this in the traditional
sort of system like
using cloud code or code
Codex, I could use
Dangerously Skip
Permission, so I wouldn't
have to sit and click,
so this is basically
good for people who
don't know how to use
VS Code or IDEs and
things like that, so
you can use all the same
basic capabilities, but
again, in this case,
you're going to have
to click the Publish
button and other sort
of capabilities here.
all right let's
see what it's
doing so neural
networks activated
and we can take a look
at what's happening
there we got so it's
creating the model it's
training the model it's
giving me a response
i can see the response
so workflow neural
net all right let's
benchmark it now I'm not
I create a model with
no guidance on why I
want to create a model
this is like vibing a
model I guess but it's
what I'm really doing
right now is just
trying to make sure
everything actually works
more than anything else
but it's kind of cool
that I could actually
train a neural network
model deploy it in
a hosted sandbox validate
it optimize it you
So if I was doing a
recommendation engine
or a training algorithm
or something, this
would be a nice, quick
and easy way to do it.
Apparently, there is
the ability to use
deep research, but
I haven't been able
to get deep research
to use any of the
tools. So I don't
know if that is
something I did or
it's not available yet.
There's zero input in the
system in terms
of debugging.
A lot of trying to
get this thing to work
was me just messing
around with it until
I got it working. like
if there's an error
there's basically
says error and it
doesn't tell you what
the error actually even
is so in this case
i'm just looking at
what it's doing so
it looks like it's
looking for nlp models
i don't know if i have
any nlp templates so
we'll probably return
null but in this
case if it's smart it
should basically yeah
it's not it's not
returning any models
because there isn't
any models that i've
created for nlp so
it's sort of doing the
discovery right now
all right so we'll
let it go a little
longer see if it sorts
itself out uh it's
trying to execute
a workflow again
let's see what happens
there remembers
the conversation i
guess i'll turn that
on so i find to be
honest i find the clod
to be much and rue
and klein and cursor
to be much more capable
at figuring out and
calling this like if
if i go into let's
let's just go here
for a moment i'm going
to show you what what
it looks like if i
do this in rue just
as to sort of show you
an alternative view
so that that was using
the web-based version
now if i if i go
to roo uh where's
where's roo hidden itself
here so you can see
here i i did a similar
sort of process
here i said create a
sandbox using flow
nexus it it created a
sandbox now i could
say create a optimized
wise i don't know
let me actually
just refresh
the mcp quickly
because i made a
changed earlier.
Yeah, I might
have broken it.
That's my SSC. I'm not
concerned with that.
Yeah, that one
doesn't work because
I don't think I
had the right URL.
I'm going to go here
and do complete.
Just refresh it.
When you make changes
to MCPs, always remember
to refresh them.
It caches it, generally.
Most tools cache
the MCP server, especially
if they're local.
So now I'm say create
a uh optimized uh
neural net network
using flow nexus for uh
recommendation
recommendations or something
so now i'm just
validating that the thing
actually works now over
here i'm gonna also
validate that i didn't
break it i'm really
good at breaking stuff
mcp list so i'm just
gonna make sure everything
works over here.
It looks like
it's working
pretty good. Uh,
it's connected.
Linux is connected.
Yeah, it looks good.
All right. So now
we're here. So you
notice, you notice
a difference here.
What chat GPD doesn't
do is create a
plan. It kind of, it's
dumb. It's sort of,
it's like pokes at it
and tries to figure
out what it should do,
but doesn't actually
create any kind of
real strategy or any
kind of thinking
process like Claude or
Roo or any of these
tools do really good
job of. So it's like,
I have to, in, in
the, in, in chat GPT,
I have to kind of tell
it to do all this
stuff where I didn't
really have to tell
it. It kind of figured
it out by itself that
it, what it needed
to do here in Roo. Right.
So now it's looking
at the, It's looking
at the neural
list, it's looking at
my neural training,
it's creating the
different types of neural
components, dents and
others. You can see
here it's creating
the prediction model.
See,
ChatGPT did none of that.
So now it's creating
a new model. and so
it even decided to
benchmark itself you know
inversely I can go
over here and I can go
into DSP and now that
I've got a variety
of different MCPs
installed here I can say
something using a
combination of uh i guess
spell it right the
claude flow room swarm
and flow nexus create
me the ultimate uh
ultimate neural
i got oops neural uh
recommendation system
And actually, you
know, this is my
dev environment.
It seems like a
bad idea. I might
not do that here.
But you get the idea.
So let's go back
over here. So
now it gave me an
overview. So it created
the network model.
It's a feed-forward
neural network,
five-layer deep
architecture.
And it's done 50
runs of it. There's a
batch size, training
results, performance.
Okay, what the heck can
I do with this thing?
this is something jed
brought up earlier
okay i created a
recommendation system or
multiple microneural
networks what the heck
do i do with it what
can i do with this
right that's that's
that's the that's the
million dollar question
okay i i created some
sort of neural network
and it's got high
confidence in doing
the recommendations all
right so now what it's
doing is let me show
you how to use a practical
app soon next for
optimized recommendations
let me create a
simple application and
send it to the sandbox
so it's uploading some
kind of code i guess
again vibing that
vibing this some kind of
demo i'm not sure why
it didn't tell me but
we'll we'll let it do
its thing now we can
see what's happening
at any given point here
file so if you're
always curious of what's
happening you can
always just expand
these That's what I
like about Rue. It
gives you a nice
visual experience here.
Now, while that's
happening, let's take a
look at Codex for a
second. I got Codex here.
Yeah.
Run Lonexus.
I think I got
Lonexus installed here.
The update of Codex
is pretty good too.
All right. So what
the heck did it do?
All right. So what it
apparently did is it
created an e-commerce
product recommendations
suggesting based
on user browsing
history, pattern
recognitions and preferences,
cross-selling, content
media platforms,
business intelligence.
OK, now this is
this is the part
that's that's
important when
you're doing this
sort of stuff.
Prove to me this
actually works.
it's like oh it's a
93 percent accuracy
with 6.7 millisecond
latency which sounds
amazing but uh it
it's uh i i'm i'm not
i don't believe it
until i try it so in
this case i'm gonna
i'm i want more proof
i spend half my time
lately just proving
this stuff isn't
hallucinating itself
into a corner tell
me i think you got a
hot mic there well
we got i can uh i can
mute people yeah
this is the call that
has a tendency to
not auto-mute people.
All right, meet all.
If you need to talk,
you know, meet
yourself. All right,
so now we see it
creating some more
content. It looks like
it's creating a new,
another model to
sort of prove itself.
Now let's run more
time to show the
model's consistency
and verify the
training status. Now
this sort of thing
is particularly
important when
you're... I'm going
to turn off Codex.
Codex suffers...
I'm jumping around a
little, hopefully this
all makes sense. Codex
suffers from the same
problem that ChatGPT
suffers from. It's
like, it has, as far
as I can tell, it has
the FlowNexus system
in here. I can see all
the models, yet it's
too stupid to figure
out how to use it,
right? It's classic
sort of issue with with
ChatGPT, it needs
like really explicit
guidance for anything to
happen. So in this case,
what I probably need
to do for codex, I'm
gonna have to create
a detailed flow nexus
or clod flow file to
give it that guidance.
All right, so in this
case, I'm gonna say,
try the, I don't
know, sandbox.
sandbox. Try to, try
to, try to create
sandbox. There you
go. I just told it,
I gave you all the
stuff it could do.
Go Codex.
So once you, once
you sort of figure
out the quirks of
Codex, you can kind of
get it working and
doing stuff. It is
not Claude by any
stretch. It's, it's a
kind of dumb version
of it or something.
All right, let's
go back over here.
Let's, is, is this
thing actually real.
All right.
So proof your neural
network actually works.
So it's given me
trained and active, it's
five layer networking,
passive, high, uh,
high action fan,
balanced user,
uh,
realistic movie
scenarios, I guess is what
it used in this
particular, uh, comedy
fan. So I guess what
this is, this model
is that technically
is basically telling
you whether or not
the user is a fan of
movies is that
something like with a 79
uh recognition model
is alive train okay
your network is 100
functional so how can i
optimize this further
keep in mind this this
idea of overfitting
models is everyone
likes to say overfitting
models is the worst
thing you can possibly
do when using AI and
creating these kind of
deep analysis systems,
it depends on what
you're trying to do. If
you're creating a broad
model that needs to
do lots of different
things, language models
or, you know, things
that are, you know,
sort of declarative
in nature, overfitting
is going to be terrible,
right? You don't
want to overfit it
because it's going to be
one thing, well, nothing
else particularly
at all. But for a lot
of things, you want
it to be really good
at that one little
thing like i needed to
trade that particular
stock or i needed to
understand that particular
user that you know
is going to buy or
not buy or something
and in in for so for
many cases a sort of
over fitting isn't
necessarily a bad thing
as long as it's narrow
enough to be really
good at that one narrow
thing so so at this
point when i say how
can i often this
further i'm going to say
avoid avoid over is
this running in parallel
somehow because i'm
doing some simple math
at 5800 uh what was
it predictions per
second and 6.7 milliseconds
to do one prediction
that would require
40 well 39 seconds
to do something that
happens in one second
well that's good that's
good let's ask it
it's not it was it's
it's it's that's a good
question actually i
don't know if i have
an answer to that um the
only plausible answer
for me is there's
some sort of parallel
prediction going on
but there was nothing
in the prompt mentioned
yeah okay yeah well
let's let's uh let's
ask that next but those
are exactly the kind
of questions what you
these systems are have
a tendency to take
the path of least
resistance and that's an
ongoing you know issue
all right cut codex
is stupid i'm turning
that off it just hasn't
been able to figure
itself out i want codex
to work i don't maybe
i don't maybe someone
has had more luck
with codecs than I
have, but it's just
dumb, generally speaking.
All right. So, it's
doing some more
optimization.
Remember, this is
CPU-based
optimization, not GPU.
How is the model
actually running?
Is it sequential
or concurrent?
and how are you
getting such
great results
or something?
This doesn't
seem believable.
I don't know.
Believable.
All right.
So, question it.
Definitely.
we go. We're, we're,
we're now here's
the other problem
with being skeptical.
Sometimes when you
start, when you sort
of prompt it and
say, this is fake,
it'll say, oh yeah,
it's absolutely fake.
You're, you're
totally right. It's
fake. Then you'll
say, no, it's not.
It's real. Oh yeah.
You're, you're
absolutely right.
It's, it's absolutely,
absolutely real. And
that's the, one of the
problems with these
reasoning models is
they, they have a
tendency to, to just go
and tell you what what
you want to to actually
hear or see no see
in this case this
is a perfect example no
real network you know
neural network
training is happening
looking at the neural
network as you you know
it that's not true
and i know it not to
be true because i
know that the it's not
using it the numbers
aren't actually using
the uasm isn't this
using the wasm and then
it'll be the oh yeah
you're right so again
it's it it's i prompted
it down the path
of of being critical
to itself to a point
where it's actually
critical beyond its
actual functionality it
it actually is working
it just i convinced
it that it wasn't and
it and then it's like
oh you're you're so
smart you're you're
you're you're true now
asking now that i show
the next part it'll
be like oh right we
are using the WASM.
So there's a lot of
that sort of thing,
especially in more
complex applications.
And so one of the
things you're going to
have to do to get
around this kind of
it's right, it's not,
it is, it isn't sort
of stuff is does it
actually solve the
problem which you're
trying to address?
And can you
independently verify it?
And in this case,
It's looking at the
WAZ. I'm going to
give it another
go to try to figure
itself out here.
But, like, yeah, that
was literally just me.
A sophisticated
simulation framework.
No, it's not a
sophisticated
simulation. I just
made you think it was.
Let me check actual
WAZ. Is it stuck?
Is it thinking?
I might have, you know,
it's still thinking.
has anyone else run
into this issue or is
it just me um yeah i've
run into that quite
a bit so i find just
like you're saying
you can't be opinionated
in your question
and lead it in any way
um and my suggestion
for what you're
testing now would be to
ask it to give you five
questions to ask it
that it should be able
to answer and to be
as specific and narrow
as possible in the
questions i leave the
questions more open
-ended draft uh markdown
file showing where
to look to demonstrate
the training is
actually happening
or the inference is
yeah exactly and that
yeah at this point
i've i've messed it up
so much that it's just
completely confused.
Right. So that, that,
that is the, um,
that is the ultimate,
uh, challenge that
we have with these,
especially for, for
things that it, it,
it, it struggles with.
And that is training
of neural networks.
And one of the things
that I do in, in,
in the scenario here
is I'll, I'll say,
you know, compare
it against something
that I know that works,
like use the, uh,
a tensor flow and
do a comparison
and like, oh, it
actually does work.
Whoops, I was wrong,
right? It's like what
it doesn't, it can't
quite see everything
or quite can't quite
understand it. So it
infers the unknown
and then it'll default
to whatever stance
you've opinionated
question you've given
it. So in this case, I
might say, use the
TensorFlow.js template
and compare against
the neural components.
So yeah, interesting
stuff there.
Let's see what
ChatGPT does. And
in my other screen,
I'm going to say
this is real and
see where it goes.
All right, the question
in the meantime.
Oh, did someone
say something?
Yeah, I had a quick
question. So you were
talking about how the
LLMs are susceptible
to over-reading
into some of our
instructions sometimes,
and I have faced it
myself quite a bit,
to a point where I now
try to front-load all
context so that it
does a one-shot. and
if i have if i find
myself wrestling with
the llm i i generally
like end up killing
that session get
resetting and then
trying again um but i saw
you like live wrestle
the llm now so i
just wanted your
opinions on uh do you see
like what do you
think of front loading
and one-shotting or do
you see it inevitable
to to discuss slash
argue with the llm
well arguing with the
llm doesn't work because
it'll just it'll
it'll just comply with
whatever argument you
give it, as we just
saw, I prompted it to
basically tell me that
it was a simulation.
Then I prompted to say,
no, it's not a simulation.
And basically now
it's just completely
confused to whether it
is or isn't a simulation.
And it doesn't
know how to validate
that it is. So the most
logical approach to
validate that it is or
isn't a simulation or
fake or real or whatever
is to do some kind
of comparison against
something you know that
is true and real. Like
PyTorch or TensorFlow
or something that I
can use to say, well,
I'm getting the same
result from TensorFlow.
How can it be fake?
That's like a
rubric validation.
The key here
is essentially
not being opinionated
and how you guide it
and creating some kind
of mechanism to allow
it to validate. Now,
certain applications
aren't necessarily
as prone to that. If
you're doing like a
database driven system
of some sort with
like role-based access
and analytics and
stuff that that is not
going to suffer from
this problem because it's
it's more of a kind
of binary output it
is or it isn't right
it either gets the
result or it doesn't
either queries the the
table correctly or it
doesn't now the problem
with these kind of
more abstract systems
like a neural net is
it it really has a
difficult time deciphering
whether the neural
net is is truly
functioning or it's just
an elaborate sort of
fake simulation? So
one way I've gotten
around that is to have
it generate an export,
typically as base64,
which I then pull into
a completely vanilla
instance of podcode
on a separate machine.
So there's no way the
context is poisoned.
And from there,
I ask it to
explain what the
base64 file is.
Usually it's
something fake or
some representation
of nothing.
occasionally it's an
actual model at which
point i'll then continue
down that thread
and have it perform
the necessary testing
and training or re
-weighting as needed yeah
it's not a bad approach
the other thing
you could do are things
that are easily via
like verifiable like
if you're doing like
a model to train like
trading or something
and you needed to
execute a particular
trade you know when
some some threshold is
greater than x it
doesn't have to be crazy
complicated it just
means that like the the
momentum is positive
versus negative and
whenever it's positive
beyond something and
you think it's going
to be continue in
that direction do do
the trade now with that
kind of criteria how
do you avoid heuristic
type rules from being
used to simulate a
neural network yeah
exactly the problem
right that that's why
i do that that's why i
do dual uh, dual
implementation and I'll
use something rudimentary
like TensorFlow.
And if I get
the same result
from both, I can
pretty much, uh,
not a hundred percent,
but I'm fairly
confident that the
system is working as
expected. Then when
you see the difference
in speed, you're
saying that TensorFlow
is relatively slow
because, you know, at
least the JavaScript
version that I'm
using. And that, that
means that at the,
that I'm getting
the same result
essentially, but
I'm just getting it
at, you know,
100 milliseconds
versus 10 milliseconds
kind of thing.
All right.
Yeah, it's, it's
not, there's not
necessarily an
easy answer to any
of, any of
these problems,
especially the more
deep tech you get.
But back to this, if
you guys are interested
in creating something
similar, you can
go, you can go to my,
oh, this is my NPM
box. Let's, here it
is. you can go here,
and I created a gist,
where did I put that,
like, here,
no, did I, gist,
yeah, basically, all
you need to do if
you want to create
something similar for,
for, uh, ChatGPT,
just point Claude at
this, uh, gist,
and it'll give you
everything you need,
I've got two different
versions of it, I've
got the, uh, the
version here for doing
without OA, which
is this, this version
here, non OAuth.
It's a nice, simple,
easy starting point.
And then I've got the
version with OAuth.
Someone pointed out
yesterday that I
didn't include a time
to live on my OAuth
components. So what
that means, or maybe
I created a really
short time to live.
I'm not sure exactly
what the issue was
here, but basically
what you want to
make sure you do,
especially with OAuth,
is set how long the
token lasts. And I
apparently didn't do
that in this example.
So what it means
is after like five
minutes, the system
requires you to re
-authenticate. I should
probably update this to
fix that problem. But
you should be able
to resolve that just
by asking Claude to
basically resolve
that problem quickly.
Yeah, that sort of thing.
Meanwhile, this...
Meanwhile, in
my other screen,
it's still trying
to... It's still trying
to figure out whether
or not my neural network
is true or not. It's
completely confused.
it's it's it it thinks
it's it's real it
thinks it's fake it's
it's uh it doesn't
know what to think so
there's still a place
for humans that's for
sure it's still it's
still uh it's still
attempting to validate
itself with neural with
predictions oftentimes
cloud code defaults
to using some sort
of random number
generator. So generally
what you can do is
commit this to a private
GitHub repo, have it
pulled down into a
separate environment, and
then have the separate
environment search
for any random number
generator or any
heuristic. And that's
usually enough to surface
whether or not the
training and
inference was mocked
without
explicitly looking
for mocked to do
or simulation.
Yeah, that's a good idea.
All right. So
let's jump to
another conversation
briefly.
We've been having
some discussions
also around the
idea of creating
a accreditation
around Agentex.
And Maju, are
you still on the
call? Any
thoughts on that?
yeah so uh i think
thanks for setting up
the discord channel
we do have i forgot
to mention we did
have a public whatsapp
group as well actually
called masterclass
engineering which
i'll put it on discord
channel but there's
been a lot of
conversation on this
topic and some of this
is if we look bottom up
um i have consolidated
that into a google
notebook lm so if
people may be interested
to kind of just follow
through what discussions
have happened
over the last couple of
months around this it
is it is traceable
what we do want to now
do is converge in terms
of like all of these
discussions have
happened so what is the
approach that hopefully
we will want to take
forward so that is where
we are at the moment
and hopefully by monday
after next we can
get to that view so so
what so in practical
terms what if we want
to get to this idea
of a kind of let me
let me stop sharing for
a moment like an
accredited an accredited
agentic practitioner
and then agentic sort
of developers or like
how much do we care
about like the term
engineer and and there's
been some debate on
whether it even matters
you know there's a lot
of things people call
themselves software
engineers and no one
seems to care in the least
that you're a software
engineer why why
would people care that
you're an agentic
engineer or when the
engineering associations
even push back on that?
Any thoughts?
Well, the problem
is the engineering
associations have a certain
amount of discipline
and validation of
the term engineer.
I wouldn't, for example,
be sitting on the
sixth floor of this
building if an agentic
engineer built it. I
trust that the civil
engineer and the
structural engineer were
certified enough that
this building will
not collapse while I
sit in it. So in that
same vein, I understand
why the engineering
discipline wants to
protect that name.
So I'm curious, why
don't we invent a
term, something that
cannot be easily Googled
today, so that once
it's Googled, it's
possible then to point
it wherever we wish.
So you're suggesting
we shouldn't have, you
wouldn't want to sit in
a vibe coded building
not six stories off
the ground ground floor
no problem because
you know i can i can
self-escape here it's
great i will not survive
a 60 i will not survive
a 20 meter descent
or rather yeah i will
survive the descent
i will not survive
the impact the
rapid unscheduled
deceleration don't worry
it passed all the
tests 100 percent
yeah well i we're
probably not far off from
a vibe coded or vibe
you know pretty much
everything you know
and that's the uh
challenge we face with
the next generation of
like students and
cognitive offload it's
like i can take my
engineering degree and
you know what point is
half of my degree just
me asking chat gpt
to tell me what the
answer is right well
that's medical students
today consultants
yesterday and maybe
tomorrow engineers so
so how do we validate
that the people are
actually doing it you
know what what they say
they they they can do
right is and and if
you're going to be
accredited as an agentic
engineer is there
some way for us Much like
how we were suffering
from the AI, you
know, telling us what
we want to hear. Are
you actually doing and
capable of doing the
things you say you're
doing? Or are you
just asking chat CPT?
It's kind of fun to be
able to put a bounty
to disprove a claim.
So, for example, I
have a pose detection
demonstration in my
GitHub repo. If someone
can demonstrate it's
not working the way I
claimed it was working,
that might be a sufficient
enough incentive
one for those making
those claims. to
ensure it works, and
two, for others to look
for holes or flaws or
breaks in that claim.
It's a little
adversarial, but at
the very least, the
incentives align.
I think we
shouldn't wait.
I don't think we
should let the
term engineer hold
us up, because I
think, as people
have suggested,
the time is now, and I
think there's
a huge demand.
We're kind of defining
this space in a way,
And so I think that
we just need to get
the content out there
and we need to educate
not only industry but
also the recruiters.
So we probably do
need some terminology,
but I just don't think
we should let the
engineering institutions
hold us back.
Big engineering.
This brings us back to
the point
about, you know,
we've seen lots of
things are happening,
but we are still
kind of fragmented,
right? We need
to, this group, we
need to form a
form of organizing.
So what I mean by,
like, foundations, like
just neutral terminologies,
like agentics,
you know, practitioner,
basically it's in
foundational level or
a practitioner, right?
could be a more neutral
terminology because
that is very broad i
do realize that our
strength is the depth
because the difference
between this group
and other groups with
others are too broad
right this group has a
real depth in it and
i think they've come
from certain members
like you know that are
creating this frame of
frameworks mechanisms
so we did touch upon
this earlier on is
that if people here who
are a bit more advanced
are able to say okay
a mechanism in which
you It draws some
challenges, and people
here take those
challenges, and if they
demonstrate through an
automated system that
they've achieved that,
then we're certified.
I agree it could be a
little bit, it could
gain the system a bit,
but you know what?
We do need to create
a level of consistency
that the rest of the
world sees us with.
Otherwise, we will be
seen very fragmented,
so no one knows us
beyond the small group
here. But if we can
have a foundational 20,
30, 40 foundational
identification issued
by the different
chapters and all of a
sudden our visibility
goes up and people and
then we can improve
the program as we go
along but we need to i
jump in here for a second
yeah it seems to me
seems to me the the
title is less important
than the certifying
institution so you
want to be able to say
i am certified by the
agentics foundation
that builds up the
name of the foundation,
raises a question
whether you want to
trademark the name
so no one else
can come in and use
something similar.
And then I am
certified by the
Agentix Foundation
as whatever the
certification level
is. End of story.
If you want to get fancy,
you can say, like
Jed suggested,
Agentist. I'm an agentist
certified by the
Agentix Foundation.
Or you can say,
I'm an agentix,
T-I-X.
This is just a
way to identify
the strength of
the certification.
That's all. You don't
have to worry about,
I'm an engineer,
I'm not an engineer,
and you avoid the
problem altogether.
That would be my
common sense way of
approaching it. I think
that's very, very onto
it, very smart. I
think the term is less
important than the
level of trust. And
as you say, who is
certifying that trust?
And I think Agentix
Foundation has a
great opportunity to
be that organization.
so for example togaf
right in the good
old days of prince 2
in the good old days
or msp right you are
either a prince 2
foundations or a prince
2 practitioner or
you're a togaf foundation
or togaf practitioner
so i think we just
say agentics uh
i think yeah i think
agentics that whatever
agentics foundation
let's get the brand
name out so
agentics foundation
organization you know we
define the proper name
our practitioner
something we need that
and we do know that
we could assign some
of the members capability
like Reuven your
capabilities so you
will swarm that could
that's the depth or
again i have said this
before oceans hive
and line are agi right
so some level that
familiarity of those
could be enough and
they demonstrate the
knowledge through one
or two projects that
they do themselves
the members who are
aspiring to themselves
and they prove themselves
we could follow up on
rube's nomenclature
so that you would be
certified for clod
flow or dag or you
know a flow nexus and
then you'd have levels
within that but the
the key thing is
that the foundation
controls both the
nomenclature and the level
and that it's the
foundation's stamp of
approval that counts
and you build that up
as a trust relationship
i trust that if
they have that
certification from the
foundation that they
are competent within
certain parameters it
seems to me that that
that's a common sense
way of approaching
it until we find
somewhere that it doesn't
work and we modify
it or throw it away
Competence is tricky,
John, because unlike,
for example, the
bar exam, where the
answers are presumably
consistent, there
are many different
solutions that can be
applied to the same
problem within this
LLM-powered coding
or LLM-powered work.
So I'm not sure how you
would start it on that.
When I took the bar exam,
a lot of it was essay.
and there you can come
in with 12 different
versions that all of
them work but those
12 different versions
still follow whatever
principles drive
legal theory right or
common law theory i
think is what it was
called well by the
same token 12 different
versions of a solution
using Claude Flow are
still solutions it's
you have somebody who
who you have a
candidate the candidate
does something you have
a an expert or a panel
of experts that the
foundation has approved
to do this job and
they decide and pass
fail or you know you
know high honors or
summa *** laude,
whatever your, you know,
your levels are. And
that's what you got.
It's a trust
relationship. And if you
design it in such a
way that it builds
trust, wherever these
people go out and try
and get the benefit
of this, you know,
certification, that's
what you're really
looking for. It's a
trust relationship. And
you have to build it
up and make sure that
nobody spoils it by
coming in saying,
I'm the agent
foundation and here's my
certification. And they
confuse the whole issue.
That's what trademark
law is all about.
And that's, I think,
basically what the
issue is for me.
So just to dig into the
trust thing for a moment,
if we trust each other,
which hopefully we
do, then there's some
hierarchy. I don't like
hierarchies but let's
just say there's a
hierarchy of trust
there's a few of us that
obviously know what
we're doing and we've
proven it we work with
large companies we we've
got we've built
things that people use
whatever it is that we
can do to make people
trust that we actually
know what we're doing
then there's a secondary
group of people who
want to sort of aspire
and in essence to
become similar to what
we're doing and then we
validate that that
secondary group are
capable you know based
on our knowledge and
capability ourselves to
say though that person
actually knows what
they're doing and therefore
they can call
themselves you know an
agentic engineer tier
one or something and and
at which point they
become the next level
of the trust and anyone
else that wants to
be validated either
has to go through us or
them and so on and so
forth and then you have
the the guys in in
new zealand or finland
and uk or whatever
at creating their own
groups of accreditations
and that spans and it
starts small and
hopefully spans the globe
after a few years or
something well how do
you if i was going to
if i was going to look
at trust i would say
for me the people i
would trust most would
be you jed ocean and uh
you know a couple other
people who who who
escaped my my mind
right now you guys have
gone in there and got
your elbows dirty and
really pulled the stuff
apart and so you can
determine by watching
somebody on a a zoom
attack the problem
what their level of
familiarity and their
uh level of ease of use
is that you can pretty
much figure out where
they are in the scheme
of things just by
watching giving them
a problem and watching
how they try and solve
it you could probably
do it in about an hour
you would know pretty
much where that
person probably should
fit in terms of letting
them out into the
world with your seal of
approval to go out and
get a job that wouldn't
reflect badly on
the foundation it's
it's it's not it's not
rocket science it's not
like what you're doing
actually encoding
but you have such
familiarity that you you
you can you can assess
somebody by watching
them do the work it's
it's about the reputation
right i mean and
you know rove and and
ocean and jed aren't
gonna put their seal
of approval on someone
who they think is not
going to you know hold
the agentex foundation's
reputation and
good stead so exactly
for someone that's just
as well sorry just uh
like a sub component
that might serve
multiple purposes uh a
standing project or set
of projects prds with
various levels of
complication um maybe it's
in the foundation
repo And that defined
kind of project and
having somebody say, OK,
here's my system,
here's my approach
to build that project
with very, you
know, transparent
performance attributes
and how long did
the process take
and how secure is
it? and a checklist,
that serves, both
could serve as a
tool for accreditation,
but also a
tool for battle
testing new systems,
new configurations,
and new setups.
So as LLM practitioners,
it seems silly that
we're still relying
on human validation
of competence. So
in what way can we
leverage LLMs to
independently
validate competence in
wielding LLMs? That
seems to be a more
fit-for-purpose
solution. The how is
still unclear, but
does that make sense?
if you add uh you
know testability and
verifiability you can
use the ai to verify
the results of what
rob is proposing
can we though like do
you guys saw earlier
that i was like
without a whole lot
of effort able to
convince it that the
whole thing was a
fraud then i was able
to convince it that
it wasn't a fraud in
the same in the same
uh thread I mean,
therein lies the rock.
against that kind of
uh sycophanty yeah and
that's kind of what i
was trying to do with
my seraphina judge
system where i created
like a multi-dimensional
sort of validation
rubric that looked
at speed performance
capability um novelty of
of the code base and then
created a kind of
scoring mechanism based
on all those things
like does it work is it
fast how and is it
unique kind of thing and
as far as I can tell
knock on wood it seems
to work pretty well
we could probably
use a similar
AI approach for
that as well
and then you have
bounties on top of that
for you know finding
exploits in that
verification system
yeah nice can I just
my screen to
just show you
something from
the notebook
that's okay is that okay
Sure.
So I'm just going
to move this window
here and move
this other window
here and share my
screen in a second.
So I have put
the link on the
chat for those
who would like
to just explore
on their own.
But if I share what
I'm sharing now,
this is basically, I
think is good about
this conversation that
we are having now is
exactly what seems to
be here, right? So all
we are talking about
is the fact that we
want to go through a
build a guild, right?
Which is built on the
tenets of mentorship,
knowledge sharing.
And we're trying
to set our own
standards, effectively
self-regulated
as a principles.
In terms of what
does it mean?
Could we be agentic
crafters maybe?
And which means
that we're slowly
trying to embrace
the disciplines
of engineering
progressively.
and the governance
structure being primarily
let's say we skip
this one but the
methodology right tier
one could be a certificate
and a badge program
which is like you
know you demonstrate
a single focus course
maybe serafina within
roof flow right people
earn a digital badge
for that right so we
get some creation on
that and then we could
go down to some more
in-depth things like
really study probably
some of the deeper
repos like swarm you
know basically and you
know and other stuff
and then you demonstrate
to a process some
competency which is
where you get a levels
of certifications
right at a tier one level
and then progressively
i think as we mature
we try and move
towards the engineer
designation that we are
all debating but i
think this is something
we have enough today
for a number of us
here today to get
certified and on this one
right so um that is
that is priority but
please have a feel free
to read through it but
the way to explain
this is that there's a
mind map here this is
primarily the sources
for this is the entire
whatsapp chat over the
last few months and i
think i've taken chris
your document which
you shared the other
day so this is the wider
discussion and this
is the other one and
there is a mind map
here which you can you
can basically so month
we have a question for
you yeah for someone
who is certified as an
entry level whatever
the term ultimately
is yeah does that
certification expire or
is there some sort of time
component because
this this space will
still continue to evolve
six months is what you
should dedicate i think
i would also about
to say 12 months but
i should i think we
should and i i that's a
lot of work six months
i i we we all have
lives and jobs i think
in fairness to if i
was doing this i don't
think i want to do
this every six months i
think that i even though
the space is moving
at an astronomically
fast pace we have to be
fair to the people doing
it and and and have
some kind of window
that's not so crazy
you have to continually
do it every you know
i agree a fixed renewal
is probably not the
answer i'm wondering
to what extent adding a
vintage for lack of a
better term to be more
appropriate so i like
vintage it's almost
like it has a half-life
right like your your
accreditation only
has this has quite a
relatively short half
-life until you need to
pop it up yeah well the
vintage is interesting
because you know let's
let's use me as an
example i'm a cloud
guy circa like 2006 so
my vintage is ancient
in the cloud world and
you know for a lot
of the things in the
cloud in the cloud
space at this point i'm
probably out of touch
with the the inner nuances
of like aws because
i haven't really used
it in 10 years and
that would you know so
but on the flip side
that vintage gives me
perspective of two decades
of sort of you know
so the reason you'd
want to use me for cloud
computing probably
right now wouldn't be
to like implement your
aws infrastructure i'm
not your guy but what
it does give me is
the the experience of
two decades of cloud
related work which in
itself is valuable for
like perspective
consulting um you know in
broad sort of knowledge
right so there's there's
always benefits and
drawbacks to either
well it's good it gives
you that experience
and as a as an engineer
actually in that
discipline which
gives you credibility.
To go to Jed's question
about lawyers
and doctors,
you get a, for lawyers,
you pass the bar
exam and you get
admitted to the bar.
That says that you can
practice law legally.
If you're a doctor,
you get a degree
and then you have
to do, you know, a
residency, and you
may do, you know,
other types of things.
But in both of those
professions, there's
continuing education.
So you could offer the
continuing education,
and someone could
then ask someone
who was, let's say,
an entry-level person,
like me if i passed
i would be maybe an
apprentice to the
guild that might be a
level so as an
apprentice someone would
know that i would
need to be supervised
by someone who was
a master in the
guild that kind of
thing and if i went
to apply for a job
the prospective
employer could ask
me what's the level
of what of your
continuing education
so that that's where
that would come into
play in the marketplace,
not in the foundation
itself. The foundation
could offer the
continuing education,
but it would be
optional for the apprentice
to decide to do it
or not. But if they
went out and said that
they had gotten
those credits and did
not, that would be an
issue of their trust
level, and that would
be their problem. that's
it that's probably
an easy way to solve
it the bigger issue
for me is one this
field is moving really
fast and two the people
who would be doing
the accreditations are
interested in the work
more than they are
in the bureaucracy
yeah and if you're
gonna the more you
standardize the more you're
going to bureaucratize
the process and
you will then lose your
best people who would
be able to evaluate
the level of a person.
So my recommendation
to the group would
be let the person
themselves say what
they're going to do and
you watch them do it.
And like Jed made a
modification for the
random numbers, how he
would go about finding
a random number and
verifying it for Reuven.
And Reuven said, yeah,
that's a good way of
doing it. That's the
kind of thing you want
to see. What is their
skill level, really?
What is their ability
to solve the problem?
And what's their
familiarity
with the process?
And then the interest
level of the people
doing the evaluation could
be maintained because
they'd be curious
to see if they would
learn something in
the process as well so
that's yeah that's my
my i'm going to shut up
that's very insightful
i think because it
actually demonstrates
that there's a two-way
relationship there
between the apprentice and
the and the master right
but that the master
can actually learn
something from from their
apprentices and um we
can all grow together
i love that so yeah
let's let's be let's
be honest for a moment
this idea of a master
is is is a is an
interesting idea because i
i routinely feel like
a fraud that doesn't
know what the **** i'm
doing you know in some
days i feel like the
captain of the universe
but you know and then
there's days where
nothing works and i'm
like do i even know
what the **** i'm doing
you know so there's
there's always going
to be that level of I
need to learn something
new. And for, for me,
the, those days where
I do feel like a
complete and total
fraud are the days
that I actually push
myself to learn or
do something I've
never tried before to
make myself almost
feel like I'm not a
fraud or something.
That's like all of
my psychological
issues, I'm sure. But,
um, you know, that,
so that said, I think
we, you know, part of
this is is you know a
combination of technical
capability and um
almost like curiosity
and like i can actually
i'm in confidence
that i can do it you
know yeah i don't know
maybe i'm blabbing here
that's the layer between
like experimental
r&d and really
pushing the maximum uh
possible ramifications
of these new tool sets
and then what condenses
just behind that and
this new um understanding
of what's repeatable
and and uh creatable
so that's i mean
i applaud it the you know
the the uh experience
of being in the area
of the uncertain
with these new tools
is really where all
these incredible new
insights are coming from
honestly just to
clarify something here
though guys yeah
just to clarify
something here guys
when the when the
master reviews you
know the an apprentice
who's looking for
an accreditation
it's not the master
that is actually giving
the accreditation that
master is actually
working on behalf
of the foundation
and ultimately the
accreditation and the
passing grade comes
from the foundation
not the master that
that reviews the work
so it doesn't matter
who it is whether
Whether it's Jed,
whether it's you, Chris,
whether it's me,
whether it's, you know,
Reuben, they give a
passing grade, but that
passing grade comes
from a foundation.
And the foundation
will, I guess, need
to agree on what are
the certain standards
so that we can maintain
a certain level
of quality. And I
think some of those
things may be around,
like, do you have
the right mindset? I'm
not so sure standard
is appropriate here
because it implies
there is a prescribed
way of thinking.
Is there some other
way to measure problem
-solving capacity
using specific tools?
uh if i can jump in i
come from a background
where i have been
running hands-on
boot camps um here
back in india for a
bunch of unicorns and
for some uh companies
back in the bay area
as well and it's
a really interesting
question it's the
same thing how do
you certify somebody
especially since every
context is different
folks come with different
styles with different
skills You don't want
to box them into X,
Y, Z is the way, but
you also want at some
level to create a
benchmark and say that
somebody coming out of
this has already these
first principles that
they're experientially
demonstrating. right
and and for me i think
at a very high 50 mile
level when i look at
the problem you guys
are cracking right now
i think it's more of
figuring out hey what
are these conventions
that we believe is part
of the core culture of
agentics what would i
like to see from an
apprentice as under a
journeyman and a master
in terms of what he
can put out there um
within let's say 90 minutes
and and and this is
what i would do in an
art large arc that told
me hey nikyo you're
going to give us a lot
of philosophy about
agile and XP. This is
going to distract folks
from production. I
would say, hey, let's
just measure what's
your average time to
productivity and what do
you mean by productivity?
And then I would go
back and I would say,
how can I build parity
and muzzle memory and
judgment and design
skills and then expose
them to the complexity
in such a way that we
can then bring them
back on the floor and
then let independent teams
put them on the floor
And then two months
later, go back in and
observe, okay, did I
move the needles, right?
And one thing I've
seen is that when you,
especially with larger
arts, when you try to
claim something, a
lot of effort is just
lost in defending and
yak shaving around the
verge. But if you go
move a needle, you move
a needle. And I would
say that if there was
a certification that
I would care about, it
would be because I had
the peer group or the
network here at Agentic
Foundation acknowledge
that I could move ball
at this sophistication
level and at that
speed, right? And that
would really make sense
to me. I would come
and ask you guys to
peer review me. So those
were my thoughts. I
thought I should add.
Fair. Love that.
Love that. All right.
So we want to do this.
I think we all are
in agreement that we
want to create some
kind of certification.
There's been a
number of comments
from folks that
this should
not just be
for developers.
I think Dave Gratton
was particularly
important in terms of
if you're a project
manager or you're more
business orientated,
like you still should
be able to get a
level of like a credit,
you know, agentic
accreditation that
doesn't involve you
having to go into the
finer details of like
the code. And I think
that that's a fair,
a fair thing to,
to one as well.
So this should, there
be, there should
probably be a couple
of different paths.
One is highly technical,
which is kind of
the area where I'm
comfortable and the other
should probably be
more administrative or
I'm not even sure
what to call it. like
knowledgeable about
the space or something?
It's a class of
solution. One class is
code. The other class
is whatever LLMs
can output that are
still useful. So
perhaps prompting
better, deeper research.
Deeper researcher.
Yeah, exactly.
We want to be inclusive.
We want to be
inclusive in a world
where there's
different types of
capabilities, mindsets,
and we want to,
i don't think we want
to limit it just to
uber nerds not that i
have any problem with
uber nerds i i am one
but we should uh we
should try to be as
inclusive as we can be
well that's how
technology as a discipline
started a collection
of uber nerds figuring
out how to talk to
each other over wires
without voice well
the internet anyway
that's right our whistles
and whales oh but
who was speaking of
course i didn't see the
name uh the person
who was speaking about
the boot camps they
already reached out one
tweet they say they're
connected oh all
right lovely okay all
right thank you and
just for the record
i'm gonna hang on to
egenic engineering as a
term because i love it
i think it makes a ton
of sense and i think
it was august 2024
when you first uh
coined that term roof.
And it's got a lot of
steam. So I take it
as a verb, not a noun.
I bought the
domain in August.
It started with a
Gentix. And actually,
a long, long time
ago, when I was still
in the cloud version
of all this, the
original vision for
cloud computing was
essentially autonomous
systems that
could self-build and
optimize and deploy.
And obviously, a lot
of that wasn't possible
until essentially 2022
when, you know, GPT
-3 came out. At which
point, and I'm going to
be totally honest
with you guys, I asked
ChatGPT what the **** I
should do with my life.
And it says, you know,
based on your cloud
background and your
interest in infrastructure,
you should do something
involving, you
know, that in AI. and
then through collaborative
stuff it's like
well you should do
something called agentics
now i have absolutely
no idea if i was the first
or not and it doesn't
matter to be completely
honest with you
guys at which point i
started posting stuff
about it that's it so
it would have been march
ish 2022 when i
started using it anyway
with the genics yeah
yeah genics and then that
led to like engineering
and blah blah blah
and here we are today
but yeah you know really
who who cares who
came up with the term
first it really i'm
sure there's plenty of
people probably using
it before me but the the
reality is that what
we want to do right now
is is make it a a
legitimate x like an area
of study that is
rational quantifiable you
know it's a profession
that's that's our
that's our objective here
and i if we can achieve
that then i i'm i
feel like i've left a
enduring mark in the
space there that's all
i gotta say about that
yeah yeah so a lot a
lot of people get caught
up on like who who
coined what right it's
like anyway who cares
oh by by the way
according to i i according
to my latest analysis
my my system is real
thank god or maybe not
so just just for for
those who are interested
i did a direct
comparison of tensorflow
and my neural network
system and got the same
result so um that's
generally how i and how
i go about validating
the stuff i do is
i take the approach
that everything i do is
fake and not real and
until proven otherwise
and then a month
later i'm still trying
to prove that it's real
so so getting the same
results from tensorflow
and mine you know
if if if that's a if
that's a simulation
it's the world's best
simulation i just
completely simulated uh uh
tensorflow on multiple
vectors so when you
say when you say your
system rUv is that
called flawed flow
called nexus what did you
compare it against i'm
well underpinning all
the stuff that i do
with my neural networks
is my uh concept of
micro neural networks
with jed and ocean and
others helped to sort
of help me sort of
put together and that
that's using uh the roof
fan and neurodivergent
which is basically
the roof swarm system
that allows me to use
the wasms and then
invoke those wasms to
do various types of
neural network modeling
now what i did for that
was we took the c is a
c or c plus c library
i think it was for
the fan which is a
popular uh neural network
library imported it
rewrote it essentially
for uh rust and then
made those rust wasms
and and then distributed
them as an MPX. So
when you look at all
the neural network
things I'm doing, I'm
essentially just using
those WASMs. So if those
WASMs are compelling
fraud or forgeries,
then everything I
do going forward are
going to be forgeries.
But the reality is
if they are forgeries,
and I'm not saying
they already are,
I'm pretty sure they
work, is I'm building
real applications
and solving real
problems with them, which
in itself should be
an indication that
there's value to them.
Like when I'm doing
a trading algorithm,
it's actually
trading. It's actually
making money. It's
doing the thing it's
supposed to do. Right.
And that's, and that's
the sort of, um,
the back and forth
with the system. It's
sometimes it tells
me it's totally fake.
And, but the problem
with the totally
fake is it can't see
inside the WASM. It
sees this package
that contains all the
logic and then says,
well, it can't be
real. I can't see
what's in it. And that's
the drawback to
this sort of rust
-based distribution
approach that I've taken.
It obfuscates some
of the complexity.
So if somebody wants
to leverage your
work that is on par
with TensorFlow,
then they should
use Claude Flow.
Or Roof Swarm or just
the library itself.
um it's i'm you're
seeing layer cake layer
after layer everything
i build kind of
built on top of the
thing i built before so
when you look at like
the flow nexus system
that's like all the
other stuff i built
sort of underpinning
it as a as a service
right it's just built
kind of on top of
the next so if the
bottom is ******** then
everything else just
kind of falls apart
sure i get it awesome
that's good to know yeah
uh all right we're
almost out of time this
was a really interesting
discussion we
we created a discord
group uh for doing
the the idea of an
accreditation and short
there's some talk
about doing uh you know
something quick and
initially that we will
just kind of dog food
ourselves essentially
self-accreditation
I think is what
we're calling it where
we as the kind of
core group will attempt
to do an accreditation
and take the
accreditation ourselves
and see how hard it is.
If I can't do it then
maybe it might be
hard for others to
do it kind of thing
If there's one thing
I can leave you
with it would be think
of it like an RPG.
There are different
skill trees that's
well there is a skill
tree and there are
different tracks you
can go down and as
you go that you go
on quests you know
maybe flow nexus can
be a part of that you
know you go on
these quests and you
pick up your your
missions and objectives
are achieved and uh
you can demonstrate
yourself in any of
these skills just a
thought i like it yeah
and oh is that skyrim
is that what that is
i don't think it's
skyrim but it's along
those lines yeah right
yeah i've been an rpg
player for like post
pretty much all my
life i love those games
skill tree is a great
idea yeah i like
it uh all right we
got a couple minutes
left any last thoughts
uh before we sign
off here today we
got uh ai hackerspace
tomorrow uh chris
thanks for getting
up at four o'clock
in the morning i know
you're you're you're
totally ********
don't ask me it just
happens yeah um i was
gonna say one thing uh
i kind of lurked here
today um salesforce
has an awesome
gamification certification
path like trailhead or
whatever it's called
or trailblazers or
something like that
and even if you're not
into salesforce like
this is a great model
and it would be really
good to see this thing
sort of built as able
to be like extended
through modules or
whatever and that way
companies like all of us
have our own companies
we could all use this
and contribute back
to the main source
essentially and then
you know even sell to
clients that way too
it's great very cool
it's good it's good that
you mentioned that so
i just throw it out
there so i actually
work for salesforce
on the trailhead academy
team so i uh i've
been i'm aware of that
as well nice dave yeah
yeah when were you
gonna tell us dave yeah
really and so it's
just a new it's just a
new thing i just started
uh they they asked
me to join their team
and it's all backed
by their agent force
ai the new push so and
and the work that
mondweep has been doing
and i'm like oh wow this
is really overlapping
and intersecting
with the work we're
doing in the Agentex
Foundation because they're
using, you know,
their whole trailhead
academy is doing all
this AI stuff. So when
I get more info, I'll
bring it in and I'll
help you and I'll
share it with you guys.
Fascinating post.
Congratulations,
David. I mean,
that sounds
like a sponsorship
opportunity.
If you could get
a sponsorship to
collaborate, that
would be amazing.
I know, I know.
I'm with you
guys. Believe
me, I'm with you.
You don't want it.
it's sort of
like investment
you don't really
want that money
well they just announced
a startup incubator
thing two days ago
as well so it's like
like yeah anyway that's
great well all right
till tomorrow then
uh tomorrow 12 p.m
eastern uh ai hacker
space if uh rob do we have
signed up for
presentations we've got uh
joe and one other fellow
just confirming so
we still have two spots
for demos or lightning
talks tomorrow four
minutes crisp but
lots of time for q a
after that and uh yeah
uh you can reach out
to me on uh discord
whatsapp or a dimple
perfect as well dimple
francis all right
till till then thanks
everyone super guys
thanks ruf okay no problem