How's
it going? Going
well.
How
you doing? Good. I'm good.
Very
cool. Alright, so, what's, uh,
what's, what's happening today?
So, Mac, what, what do you got? And we'll talk about some other things,
but I wanted to give you the floor first.
Uhm, I, I,
I still have a lot of. Work, uh,
to do on my end before I come back with some,
some big questions for roof, I'm kind of just plugging away.
Um, nothing really,
uh, outstanding for me to go, right.
There were a couple of questions I had, but I figured it out.
Okay. So, um,
I think that it, that makes sense to just, just talk through,
through the next steps that we're going to be.
Uhm, and, you know, what, what we want to deploy first,
uh, in the app. So,
uh, so, so Ruv, what, what, what, what. We decided as a business,
and just, you know, getting this thing,
uh, working,
our top priority is. Is one of the features of
the overall app, so, so, Mako is working on a bunch of stuff,
but, uh. . . He basically built out,
effectively, a lot of the, of the user,
the UI, UX.
Uh, for the, the, what the patient uses,
that the practice manager uses,
that a treatment coordinator uses. There's a whole bunch that,
that's built out. And he's, you know, he's tying all that to supabase.
But there is, kind of, one feature that uses a subset,
doesn't use the patient portal, only uses a bit of the practice.
Manager portal, uhm,
that is this AI scheduling agent.
And so that's what we want to release first, and then we want to
add on, and so go through the entire deployment process,
and then add on all these additional features that Mac's been working on.
Uh, so.
You know, so we want to kind of take,
and there's, there's other technical problems that we got to work through
to get that work working. So, for example,
one technical problem is, is actually connecting the app
to the API bridge that's called Next Health that
allows us to. Connect through Next Health multiple different patient management systems.
So, like, how,
how do we go about doing that? Uhm,
that's, that's one thing. And then the,
the, for the AI scheduling agent,
right? It only needs, you know, that, that API,
the Next Health API.
That links to the PMS has a huge amount of functionality in there.
We need a teeny subset of it to support that AI scheduling agent.
Basically we need. To determine calendar availability and
we need to post back,
uh. Uh, when,
when the appointment has been confirmed, uh,
and then, uh, also to send back on.
A little bit of information that's collected during that call.
So what we're thinking about doing is so,
so now there's, there's effectively the. App that max working on.
Okay, then there is the PMS system,
which connects through the API
bridge.
And then there's the AI scheduling agent.
So the first thing that we were thinking about doing just to get something
up and working was before we even.
Build the AI scheduling agent.
We have the app working so that a person can take the call.
A front desk person can take the call, put in the information,
you know, and through the app check availability,
uh, you know, so it connects through the API.
I layer, so that's kind of solve that problem,
and then we add the AI scheduling agent,
and so that the AI scheduling agent.
Our thought is that that would not connect directly to the PMS through the
API bridge, but would connect to the app,
which connects to the PMS. Does that make sense? So the API bridge is
sorry, a service you're using,
or you're using. Using some secondary API,
what do you mean It's a third-party service that we license that basically
has connected. To,
you know, a dozen different separate PMS systems,
and they, they manage that testing.
And those connections, so that we only have to connect to one,
and not all these individual ones.
And, at some point, I mean, there is additional cost that we have to
pay associated with that. So, at some point,
maybe we would connect directly to somebody.
Some of them, so to avoid that cost,
but it, it's, we know other companies that have used that,
that. Sure. Sure. Show me the API docs for that service.
I get what you're trying to do. And. It should,
it shouldn't be too bad, but I just want to understand,
like, show me their website and whatever it is that they're doing.
So this is like a critical feature is what you're saying?
This is a critical feature, yeah.
Okay, so there's two, two critical features. There's something that some sort of agent
that will do scheduling, and then there's some,
some sort of system, the agent will work against this POS system.
P,
PMS, they call it, patient management system. It's like an electronic medical record.
So it's the, it's the system of record for,
or the, Mac,
you want to just share your screen?
Uh, yeah, just share the screen and walk, walk me through this.
And you haven't done any integration against this,
but you do have the API keys.
And there's probably a sandbox of some sort? It
is, uh, when I was testing APIs previously,
it was the only API that, I think it was be- had to do
with not setting up the sandbox properly in the NexHealth portal,
but it was the one API that wasn't connected,
even though we have an API key. Uhm,
and I uploaded these into context 7, uhm.
Uuuh.
And what do you need context 7 for?
Like, why not just point it at this website?
Oh, just in case it was, it was useful, just in case.
Store it
somewhere. Oh, I gotcha. Okay. So you,
you're saying you haven't been able to get this to work for some reason?
Well, well, I, I went through it quickly.
Um, it was just a very quick testing.
Not, uh, I didn't, it was not a full deep dive.
And, and are there specific features of this API you want to use,
or?
Yeah, it's a, it's a teeny subset for this first,
for the first thing we're doing. It's a teeny subset.
And then as we add some additional features to it,
presented the product in the future, we'll use other parts of
the, what's, no, I mean, just be specific.
What parts of this would you like to use?
I need to, there's a spreadsheet that I have that has a list of.
Of all the features,
uhm, I need to find that real
Okay. And, and as for the,
so the, the explain,
better explain to me the agent and how and what it's exactly it's doing.
Okay, so today, like to, okay, so the, the, the. The, the, the problem
of this feature, okay, is patients call in and
if somebody answers the question. The phone today,
they, they can use their PMS system and,
uhm, you know, basically look at the calendar inside the PMS system.
The PMS system has, it has the full calendar of,
of the providers, it has. It has, you know,
payment system in it, it has, it,
it has the, the- So
it's, that's basically what the PMS is. So, it's their system of record. So,
if somebody calls in, then,
the, the front desk will have that, they'll have it always open.
Uh, and they'll just book the appointment in it.
So, what we want to do is to be able to, book the appointment
with an automated agent that can answer the phone 24-7,
even when they're busy. Okay? Okay.
Okay. So, the,
so, so the idea is that that agent would,
in, in, in. We, we actually have an agent that works quite well as
a simulated conversation. It just doesn't have the tools connected to it.
To
be.
Okay.
That's great. That's exactly what you, that's exactly what you need to do.
We simulate it, then we make it real. And so,
a year white. What you're missing is, like, tool invocation.
Like, doing, updating,
editing, whatever, update it somewhere else.
And, Getting calendar availability,
and then, um,
once it has a calendar availability, then it, it's capable of negotiating that conversation.
conversation. Uh, and then,
um, it would, would update back the appointment,
and the idea is that we would, have this,
instead of the AI agent,
just connecting directly to the PMS,
instead- we'd have this intermediate layer,
which is the app itself, because the app itself can say,
here's how many we've booked, you know. And if you need to follow up,
if there's any to do anything else you need to do,
so, so the app has some additional functionality.
Uhm, you know, that Mako has been working on. Does that make sense?
Yeah. Uhm,
oop. Okay. So, in terms of use of our time today,
what would you like to do? You want to set, you want to get
this API working? Sounds like the,
uh, next, uhh, uhh, uh, API thing that you're describing is what you need
next to help.
Uh, Mark,
I do have the repost setup. It's my first club.
I just sent you the link,
but I can share in visual, uh, VS code. I think that, that we'll
have, so there's- actually two projects that are very,
very similar to this. So, the question is,
Mac, are you ready to work on the API?
The next- Yeah, I have a cursor to start.
Okay.
Uh.
Let me explain. This is a different project,
uh, and I'm going to orient you to it.
Uh, this one's a pretty fast and easy one,
but it's also a com- sational voice AI.
In this case, the conversation voice AI is connecting to
a calendar. I wonder. Inside of Go High Level.
Uhh, you're familiar with Go High Level,
it's like a CRM suite. Umm,
and Go High Level. Umm, Go has the ability to see,
it has an mcp, umm,
it has the ability to set the calendar- it's,
in the inside of Go High level. Okay,
so let me, let me explain a little bit more detail. So, so basically,
the client has a list of lee- We eads that they've collected with
opt-in information. Um,
and this, the, the company is. is. They,
they put down flooring, like cement flooring in your garage and stuff.
So they've got a list of leads. They want to use an AI agent
that- It calls those leads, so the contacts are already in high level,
and we'll have the AI- I agents basically make these calls,
and again, we've already built, uh,
a template agent that, that understands the business.
And, so they can talk about the business. Their primary job is just to
book an appointment. That's it.
So, they that,
The calendar, though, of record is in high level.
And high level, basically, it connects to your Google calendar.
Or your Outlook calendar. Uh,
so, but it has some additional features there.
So the idea is that we would connect to that calendar.
calendar. We would take the, take the list from Go High level somehow,
um, to kick off the agent and,
um, then, uh,
have it work its tool is gonna be connecting with that calendar and
then, uh, it, It'll pass back just a couple pieces of
information. It's basically the booking. And then,
from that go-high level,
ha as workflow automation. So go-high level,
it's going to send a follow-up email and send a text message,
confirm it.
So go-high level has some mechanism to do,
uh, bilateral, uh,
you know, at, you know, appointment scheduling of some sort.
. . .
It does. Yeah,
so it has a calendaring system that's kind of like,
it, it, it, it, one of the f****** audience is just like calendaring.
Just like calendaring,
you
can give it a link. Show me that
API for that. How, how we interact with that.
And I'll see you
the
API. So it sounds, it sounds like you guys have done a good job
of sort of finding the services.
And now it's just a matter of connecting up the APIs that- it.
To use those services
correctly. I haven't- we haven't played with the API of high level yet.
We just found out that it's gotta- in MCP,
uuh, but we haven't played with the APIs at all.
Uhh. That's okay.
That's kind of an exciting
event. So,
uh, yeah, Matt, now it's- can tell you what a calendar looks like if
you want to see, like, the
settings. No, no, we- We don't want us- we want to just make sure
we can do it programmatically. Yeah. And I assume that you can do it
programmatically, but, you know, we never want to- really assume anything.
So we just need to make- we just need to confirm that
whatever, you know, cal- the calendar capabilities are actually- .
accessible through the API.
Yep.
So just go to the API docs where those happen to be and find
the API calls for- That particular feature.
Uhh,
you should be some doc somewhere- this looks like it's some- where
they're- where they're main docs.
Non-age-based. Please.
Good.
This is the first time I'm looking
at- Yeah, that's fine. I would do the same thing.
and I just gotta- we gotta figure it out. Now,
uhh, there's- there's a couple ways to do this.
I'm a lot lazier than you guys are. Uh,
I see doctor- just click on the docs. I- I would've just asked,
like, chat GPT or something. But, yeah,
just click on the- yeah. Yeah. Click on the docs. Just click on
the calendar
events. Yeah, there we go. Yeah,
it's- it's most likely, uh, get- Get it.
Okay, put three slots.
Yep. Perfect. So click on that.
Uh, this guy.
Yep. Yep. You Okay.
Perfect. So, let's get.
Now, how does it handle,
. I guess. I guess.
It got to put here. Get
update. Get
delete. Perfect. Okay. So, so. You I'm thinking through this logically.
If it's like calendary, then what it's going to do is it's going to
basically tell you, like, when you register and try to get- a time slot
for me, and to be honest, I should probably use this for- for my
own system. I should-
it's- and there
you go. Yeah, yeah, but, uh,
I get a- exactly what you're trying to do. You're- you're basically trying to
do kind of negotiation between a patient and the availability of the-
of the actual, uh. And that's it
This one's not a patient, it's just a- it's a customer of this- this
concrete pouring service, this- this flooring service.
So. up. It's- it's different than max app.
So this is max- max app into high level,
max connecting to the
app. Oh, yeah,
this-
this would also- It doesn't work really well for max app as well,
right? If anything involves any kind of calendar negotiation.
Uhh,
yeah. Except for we have to, we're forced in that environment to work with
the PMS that the orthodontist has.
So, if
we, We hit, they don't have an API.
In, in this case, the client,
this is a totally different project and the client is using high level and,
high levels calendar system. This is where they have their contacts is inside a
high level.
Okay. Okay. Well, looks- You sold me.
I'm totally checking out my level later.
I mean, I'm
not going to
reflect- High level is calendar. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. High, high level is awesome.
Yeah. It's good.
And instruct me that you would be the last guy in the world wrote
to use high level, because you would look at this and go,
I could build this- in an hour.
I, you know, I use- I
use-
I use- I use- I build what I have to.
I prefer- blue for- for for- for most things.
And, uh, if- if it exists and it's cheap and easy and someone else's
problem- problem. Especially when it comes to, like, money-related activities,
I- I- I like- I'm gonna just use whatever is available.
Like- Yeah. Assuming this isn't crazy.
Well, I'll tell you what, it- it would be a hundred dollars a month,
but I'll give you a sub account. So,
you know,
it'll
be-
But yeah, that's, you know,
you know what I charge, it's
not a huge.
Alright, umm. Alright, so,
yeah, so- You Are you guys signed up for this?
Yeah, yeah, so we have, we have what's called a high level agency
I didn't see it. So we have many clients underneath us
that have their own businesses in high level.
So. So, It's like an individual business high levels like a whole CRM system
plus work law. So think of Salesforce plus HubSpot.
For small business. Okay.
And
you can put up your websites there, like,
you know, you can host them there, like, uhh, like a Netlify.
Umm, it's got a website builder in it.
Uhh, so it's got a whole bunch of really cool functionality.
It's got the calendar functionality is a nice one. I use this instead of
calendly. You can very, and you can sell products on your website.
It's kind of a cool thing or products or services.
So it's got a lot of capability. Uhh,
so yeah, so this is inside,
so what we're doing is we're connecting a calendar inside of-
a sub account, and so you see that it's got a token type of
sub- sub account token, so we- so that's what would change be- from one
client to another. Uhm.
But, uh, yeah, the idea is that- that we'll have this AI agent- it.
1 And it can easily be plugged from one sub-account to another
by just changing that sub-account token.
Okay.
So what do you want to
get? What do you guys want to build? You've given me several ideas.
So what do you want to do today? Okay.
So what we want to build is we want to actually take,
um, the existing,
uh, 11 labs age.
aid. And see if we can connect it.
To this.
So, so,
so you need
it. So before, before you do.
That you need, you'll need to create probably an abstraction,
uh, for this API. I would,
like an edge. Thank much. Function, most likely,
that will authenticate,
so. So, When you, when you make the request,
you're using an anonymous key.
With some form of, of user validation.
So, when you are, when the,
when there's a call between the two, how you handling user settings.
Like,
is there, how do you know who's who? Alright, I haven't thought
that far. For more information, website at www.beadaholique.com
Well it's explain the- explain the workflow.
So, uh, is someone- someone's getting a phone call it sounds like and then
you're- your v- validating somehow or other that they are who they- who they
say they are and then they're- and then they're
scheduling- Oh, Okay, so for this one, we're calling.
out. Uh,
so- so we're- we'll we'll have a list of contacts with phone
numbers and we're gonna call. . . out to that list.
And you're just kind of assuming that if you call them,
they answer and they agree to schedule,
then they are who they say they're.
Yeah, yeah, because they've given us their contact information.
And, you know, if they hang up on the agent or so forth,
we'll- You know, we'll collect all that, but the,
you know, we'll know
they're not- So you're- How do you separate their- their kid or- or
someone that happens to answer the phone, which is unlikely given the nature of
the mobile environment we live in today,
but there's no secondary- questions or validations of identity
or anything.
Uhh, that's a good point.
I, we, we hadn't- It's,
it's, it's actually when you're, when you're calling out, it actually makes sense to
do that in your first message. So let me,
anyone that's calling- any call center validates identity,
even if it's rudimentary, which usually involves me saying,
no, you, you prove that you're real. No, I'm real,
you're real. Or whatever. And, and then there's a back and forth between me
and whatever random person happened to- Try to convince me that they're calling
on behalf of a company. So I'm, I'm probably the worst person to call
because I assume everyone's trying to scam- And
me. But, you know, they always
are, they're always asking for proof of my identity,
which I don't, which I don't give ever on a
phone call. But you can just do, do the name.
Yeah. Um, you know, hi. Uh,
is this, is this so-and-so? This is,
um, you know, blah from,
uh, Spartan floor
covering. Okay, so let's, let's, let's,
let's, let's, let's keep it simple. So we're gonna do a multi,
a multi-step implementation here.
The first thing and the easiest thing we're gonna do,
and, uh, and this is, this is
Krista's screen we're looking at?
Yes.
Okay, and you've got the- the API key for this,
uh, service?
I don't know.
So let's- let's create a .env. Maybe. Let's grab-
let's
get- let's sign in and get the- and get the key.
So it looks like there's a bearer token that's required.
We're going to use a, a,
um, an- an- anonymous key. We'll see you in the approach,
which is going to be, uh, the- the best since most secure way for
you guys to sort of ham, sort of, uh,
interaction with this. We'll- If you guys are comfortable with Superbase,
we'll just use an edge function.
Sure.
So we're going to need your Superbase- Peace.
Uh, access token as well.
Oh, me? I don't, I do not have that.
I
think,
Mac, that you shared,
right? Bye.
Okay,
I have. For some
reason. I can give her a super-vince who creates access token.
And what are you guys- What guys using for a password vault?
Mac. You're on mute.
Uh. you I'm I'm looking for the access key right now.
Okay, just to so if we're gonna have a multi developer agent development.
Helpman. Plan here. We,
we can, we can do it quick and easy by using a .env.
We can do it right if we want to have.
Have a, uh, a shared password vault.
Uhm.
We can do a little bit of both to get, to just, to get
it working quick and then- secure it. Uhm,
but if-if you, me, and Mac,
and some agents are-are-are gonna collaborate,
dotty and these are- hard to go away for collaborative use of tokens,
uh, and-and-and you can buy keys because you literally we're going to create a
file and share that which is terrible. Yep.
Uhm, oh, I'm sorry, you guys don't have access to share?
There you go. Uhm.
. . I just want you guys to be,
I want you guys to be secure, and I'm I'm . . . know,
this isn't the, uh, HIPAA compliant platform like the other,
but we should just build with SOC 2 and HIPAA compliance in mind for
anything we're building.
I totally agree. You Yeah,
uhh,
okay, so. So. So, this is a couple things.
When working with these access tokens, there's a- the reason why you choose never
expire and never choose, man,
ever. . . because if there's leakage,
you'll never know, right? The drawback is,
to using never, to using 30 day or 90 day,
is inevitably in 90 days,
it's gonna stop working. And you're really like, why the hell doesn't it work?
And then you're gonna spend 20 minutes to realize that the token expired.
The benefit to that is, if you have any token leak- the worst case
scenario is 30 days,
90 days, however long that the token is available for expired.
It's expired. For any kind of sock too,
you're never going to choose never.
Yeah, that makes sense.
Okay. So. What should we choose? 30?
Uh, what, how long you guys plan to take to develop
this? Yes. I usually do 90 cause I'm lazy,
but. Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. And I never lay in 90 days,
I forget. And I go th- the whole rigameral every time.
I-I happens enough now that I almost instinctively know that the token's expired.
But,
uhm- You can line them up all the same time.
Yeah, it's-yeah, exactly.
It's-it's always a random Tuesday. Okay.
Uh, yeah. So, give it a-give it a name that- It's usually specific to
the project.
Interesting. Okay. So, this is my first day using this application
and- we're trying to generate a token from
inside of my account with,
uh. Um,
high level, right? So I actually don't know how to do that.
Okay, no worries. The way that I do it is I'm,
I'm also lazy. Lazy in a good way,
I hope. And I, I use umm.
and I use an agent browser and
just
go, and I,
and
I, and I tell, I tell it to go figure it out.
Yeah. Exactly. It's
actually, I
haven't tried the new,
uh, OpenAI one,
which came out yesterday, but, uh, I, I,
I like the, I've, uh, browser extension,
but it looks like you're using something similar. What,
which one are you
using? I'm using a comment, right?
Probably Gemini, I guess.
Yeah, they all,
they all kinda get older.
They're all kinda clones of the same
idea. Gemini is the worst. group. Actually, Gemini is really
bad. Does Gemini control your browser?
Yeah, not very well. That's the problem. Don't. Don't.
Claud, I, my opinion, Claud is the best,
uh, and they've only released it to a few thousand people.
So, it's not available yet. So, uh,
perplexity Internet. Okay, use- use- use
comm- and- or- or we'll just click around. Go- go to settings.
It's always under settings, generally.
Personally, I sent you the super
basic. And then. And then go to API keys in the left hand side.
Yep.
Uhh, uhh,
So, sure you set
up
your- Yeah.
Make sure I set up your- Your two factor off at some point.
Again, suck too. Thank you
so much.
Umm, hmmm, hmmm,
And
while you're doing that, uh, Mac,
you might want- think about which vault service you could use.
There's one by Hat Hashi Corp.
Probably cheap and easy and probably most of- effective for you
guys. Or
if you prefer web- like web-based
and mobile and all that stuff. I I- I use one
password. Oh my god. Okay.
Whatever you use, make sure it has a CLI. I'll see
One pass and uh,
last pass, but I've used both of those,
but let's just use one pass if Rufus uses
it. Yeah, whatever you're, if you're, if you're currently using one,
use that, but
I'm only using the free version of it. Uhh, so.
Yeah, the, the,
the, don't use free software for the stuff that is the keys to your
entire kingdom. And that, that's not the place you save money.
I actually don't have it. I'm not using it in there other than to.
To, to do something with a client
every day. The benefit, just,
just to stray a benefit to using one pass over last pass is the,
the, uh, one pass word is Canadian company.
So you don't have the NSA introspection that you have the last
pass.
Not that it really matters for you guys at the end of the day.
But if, if you are more, you know,
uh, security conscious, you generally avoid American security companies.
Oh, interesting.
Okay. So
we can go with Russian security
companies.
No, Russian's the
worst. Chinese. I
was gonna say, Yeah,
we're all Chinese.
Maybe North Korea.
Yeah, but generally speaking,
the Canadian one is your safest. his back. You're
not
getting the NSA back to her.
She shared me my little bias there, Ruth.
I love you.
That's a bias. It's more matter of fact.
It's more matter of
fact. I'm kidding. I'm kidding.
I'm joking.
Um, so, so all that said- How should I
log in this super bass? I should create my own account.
Krista,
you're a boy. Uhh, you s- You should an organization,
and then, well, whoever has the master,
you know. You know, uh,
you know, uh, credit cards. You create an
org. Mack and I are admins to it,
so. And add, add Krista and myself.
So. As, as, uh, users, and then when you,
when you don't want me around anymore, you can just delete my user.
Yeah.
Mack, can you do that? Yeah.
Let me see something here.
Uh, to add him in to this.
Krista and Ru. . . .
Yeah, and, yeah, that's probably your best bet.
Uh. I
I can do it if you got,
if it's, you're having trouble. But,
you're an admin, so. you.
Alright,
so you can take that key that we saw earlier, pop that into your
.env. Can be?
Or, is that for me?
Of course
I think I saw it. I'm not sure screen is on,
but whoever was sharing a minute ago.
That was a key for next. Oh, hold
on one sec.
Oh, sorry, I thought we- No, I thought.
Oh, this is what you probably remembered.
So this is an old key in amazing-
Sorry. I'm confused. Are we doing next to Daniel or are we doing the
high
level? We're doing the high level right now.
This is high level- and we would have to create to,
I believe we would want to generate a new API
key. Specifically for the Spartan Flooring Company.
So this looks like an old API key. I that was generated in
Go High level by this person,
Ian, uh, over a year ago.
I'll
do it. You
gotta it. You
gotta Okay.
I, I, I, I, it's, it's. So, He inside on the call and it's
the first I've heard of Ian. So
let's go. Oh, he was. He, he, he, he was a.
Uh, very short time.
I'm contractor that.
Guess
what. I didn't know what he was
doing back. This is exactly why you want to use password bolts.
results. 7 So, in the password vault,
you would've toasted Ian and he would've lost access to everything.
In the meantime, Ian's had access to- No,
because he had
a- I gave him a hero forage email that-
You have the API He gives- gives- gives him access to everything.
Yeah, yeah. Wow. Uhh,
this pretty- And
that's the regular capability seems
to be grayed out. It says it's part of the advanced API that is
available in the pro plan. and
Which we have.
Okay, interesting. I wonder if it's-
Me. Who's- Who's the primary u- You I'm
the owner, so. Let's switch to-
Let's switch to your account.
Let's- You share your screen. You go here.
Let's stop. I'm sharing.
Yeah, it looks- Looks like you probably have an- We need to probably- Thank
you. Allocate access.
What would the URL there?
Oh, sorry. Umm,
let me put this in- e what's app chat so you can click on
it easily. That should
prompt you to- I'll bit. log in with your go high level account and
take you right to the API key page.
iform.
And Mac,
while Krista is doing that, can you sign up for the one password?
That's word. And
add all of us. Yes. And
we're gonna use the one password CLI mostly,
but,
um, I don't see if you put anything in the chat.
I don't see it.
Oh, hmmm, I almost I can't.
But,
I got in there anyway. Uh.
It's in the team chat.
Or Mac or
something. Yeah. Yeah,
it looks like we're making, we might not, we might not broke that.
So, subscription.
description. Yeah, it's account.
Is there anything you use, you don't have a CLI tied to?
. . . Is that, is that a principle valuation that
you think about when you conceive of tools?
I want to be able to write You should
follow me on LinkedIn.
I literally wrote a post on that yesterday. day.
Umm, if you haven't,
I haven't included you,
bug me and I will. I'm really bad at like, adding people.
But, um, yeah, basically. easily. For the longest time,
people would mock me for saying, you know,
oh my god, you-you get another CLI.
Now, CLI's are the hottest thing in the world, and every- I'm not on
the planet using a CLI. Um,
but
essentially, it's-it's-I think programmatic.
Whenever I'm trying to interact with services,
I like- I interact with them programmatically, so that's-that means one of three,
you know, points of access. As, uh, as Mark mentioned, M-s-s
C-P usually is a pretty good indication that I can interact with programmatically.
Two is an API, preferably an API that has- both get
post and other sort of,
uh, crud-style components,
you know, create update and so on. And- and the- and the last would
be a data-centric API, which usually is like a graph QL-style
approach. Those are- I my preferences.
Now, I can abstract any of the other previous ones to do kind of
what I want, um, and lately MCP- people.
E is kind of in my go-to because it's kind of a nice,
clean, any abstraction, and it's hot.
So, a lot of companies don't even have a decent API,
but they'll, have an MCP, and I'll just use that.
So that, those are the things I look for. So if you're- looking at
services, you know, that's- those are things you keep in IO4.
The UI is almost secondary for me at this point.
Uh, Ruf,
which email? Uh, what do you like to- A
Ruf- Yeah, R-E-V at R-E-V.net.
You know what I mean?
This,
uh, to our account as I think that- that our- our billing,
like, my credit card has- how to issue with it,
is I think what's going on with it, because we had this account,
so I'm-
I'd like to serve
that right now.
We can, uh, if you wanna- switch to the other,
in the next, uh, health stuff,
we can do that instead. We don't have a whole lot of time,
so I just wanna- make the most of our time today,
if you wanna get some stuff done.
Yeah, yeah, I just, it's kind of where, where Makoah is and- You
Umm, yeah,
Ruv, I'm just, uhh, yeah, making sure,
umm, I have test data, uhh,
setup, process. Properly, uhh,
this is a good point. Umm, just. Let's just
take a break.
Okay,
so you've got your, you have the API key for this service.
In the Any of these somewhere?
Umm,
ehh, yeah. that. Should we? Uh,
yeah. Yeah. It is.
And this is Sandbox?
Uh,
yes, it is, it is, it is the Sandbox. And you today. Thank you
We at the Okay, next
Okay, so let's do a quick test.
So what's the most important feature of the system?
It's connecting to it. So, let's,
let's open up a new, uhh,
a new, uhh, cloth instance.
Remember, always, always start. . .
Umm,
well, I'm kind of at a critical point, right here,
where. . . I was, uh, just making sure,
um, I'm using correct mock data for testing on the
main. Umm, uh,
which, which main
platform? . .
Next to dental. . .
Okay, cray new, cray new. Leave that and do whatever you want with that,
but let's, let's create a new terminal. .
Okay. . . You can work it, no, no, just Brand new terminal.
Just leave that where it is. You can continue with that later.
And, uh, just, you know, DSP.
Yep. And You tell it to
research the, whatever the name of that API was and confirm that your API
key works with With the basic authorization,
authentication or whatever. And use
the, whatever the name is. So that key is next health API
from the .env local. Go
Yeah. Not the exam, but the local, yeah. So. Let's Sometimes it strips out,
uh, yeah, there we go. Uh, research latest version of the next LAPI confirm
that we are able to authenticate using.
Uh, you know, put, put in a set folder slash scripts,
maybe? You got scripts? Yeah. Slash scripts slash- Same with the API.
What about next help?
Uhm,
sorry, can you say that one more time? them. .
Put in .slash scripts.
Slash next. Next.
Help.
No, no spaces. Yeah.
you Health,
and let's make this as a,
this will be, this will be used,
umm. on you uhh,
uhh, uhh, uhh, uhh, uhh, uhh,-n-o,
tight script. Good. Yeah.
So the reason we're using Deno-Tag Script is because we- our intention is to
use this as an edge function on Superbase and- and those edge functions are
built using Deno. So, might as well kill two birds with one stone
and do it in the right form from the start. All right.
What really testing right now is the fact that we can connect correctly.
Umm, and then for this,
Yeah, yeah, we're good. Just do that.
That's it.
So, so, remember, step one always is,
before you build all this crazy stuff, we just want to make sure that
the API works, right? So there's, There's no point of building this whole convoluted,
uh, edge function and finding out that the API
doesn't, work and then debugging the wrong thing.
So step one is just, does it work? Step two,
once it works, then, then the question is, what's the most important API,
And points that we're gonna wanna, we're gonna wanna do.
Most likely you're gonna wanna query and you're gonna wanna,
wanna post, right? So there's a get.
And there's a post. Gets are easy cause they're non-destructive,
right? That means we can just check what's already there,
if anything. Posts are good.
We'll create something new, assuming this is a sandbox,
and there's no worry about it. And then once we have that,
then we can literally say build all the various functionality.
As needed based on some spec that you,
that you'll create. Now,
do you have, you said you had context 7? 7
Uhm,
it may or may not be authenticated.
Uhm, right.
Don't worry about it. Don't, you don't need to- contact seven.
That- that- it's- it's contact seven went out of style as soon as the,
uh, the they included, you know, the web search capability.
ability. Now,
what do you use to make sure you always have the latest and greatest
information on a- ei's tools,
et cetera?
I, they've
been pointing off towards contact seven and then I've heard there's other things that
are- that are leaner. I bet,
well,
six months ago, I was using contact seven.
and then Claude, then Claude Code came out with built
in, you know, web, web searching and fetching capability and now.
now. I just do, I'm doing exactly what Max is doing.
Go look at these dogs. That's why I don't socks. Yes. Don't need context
seven. Context seven has a tendency to be overly verbose.
It's, it's, it's not, it's not- optimal.
So, if, if I need a lot of,
uh, documentation, I've got my AgentDB system now and- and- and
as well as the SwarmDB that's built in the cloud flow,
that I can use to sort of- sort of get the bits and pieces
that I specifically need. Relating to the project.
So I'll actually use my own SQL DB structure and- and basically say,
go get the most important parts. of the documentation,
put it in the DB, and then that's- that's our- that's semantically relevant,
it's lighter weight, and it- and it gets- what it needs when it needs
it, versus this idea of going and getting everything and parsing it,
which inevitably adds this kind of- compacting,
and it just takes a lot longer.
Now, what you're doing is fine. This is exactly the first step,
but then I might say take the- information and save it using the reasoning
bank. That kind of thing.
Time. Well,
hopefully I wasn't too, uhh,
often the weeds on that, but what max do you
have percents?
Now the,
the benefits of using my reasoning bank is the reasoning bank is semantically relevant.
of in ... to the project in which you're working in.
Where the web search parses the entire page,
or It fetches the entire page. You really only need the bits and pieces
that are most relevant to what you're working on, which that doesn't particularly do
well a good job of. I'm also battling
against, like, running out of, uh,
my weekly limit on clods. I'm trying to- reduce my amount of requests.
Uh,
Mac, have you reached? Have you? Thank you. Have reached your weekly limit at
all?
I, uh, not in the past few weeks.
I've hit-
I'll
be. I've hit five hour limit, probably ten times.
Yeah,
I'm I'm reaching the weekly limit, which stresses me out,
but-
Yeah.
I guess,
uh, I could just spend an extra two hundred bucks and have more than
one count. Like, it's-
Yeah.
I'm cheap,
what can I
say?
I'm cheap. Alright, so uhh, update local, I'm using mock. It's- Okay,
it looks like it's building the Dino.
Dino is a nice, this is mostly for Krista and Mack,
but- The Dino is a nice runtime.
It uses explicit, uh,
network and runtime access privileges,
so it's particularly- well suited for sort of secure,
edge-based sort of functions, and that's why it's popular for,
you know, super-based functions and things like that.
Umm, so you can define specifically,
you know, what-what it has access to in the file system or the network,
and you can see it there where it's- that allow read and stuff like
that. So it's- it's- it's an allowed net which allows network access,
that kind of thing. So it's not- it's- So.
So for agents and things like that, it's well suited because you can- you
can have it, you know, work against,
like, uh, like a active mandate.
Which- which the, uh,
my agent DB and other tools can- can utilize. I'll see you guys in
the
so that effectively define the permissions in a sense.
Yeah, cryptographically defined. So you can think- you can think of- like if you're
familiar with the ideas of a smart contract in the blockchain world.
Yeah. So- so smart contractor are cryptographically defined-
and it says, you know, where what it can do and how it can
access information. It's essentially doing that without- All the,
uh, crypto BS.
Okay, that makes sense.
Alright, so- But.
Uh, I've successfully API. Okay,
complete. Great. Perfect. Okay. So now we have that,
uh, test the answer. Real API temporary set.
No, use the real API. I've tested against,
to test, yeah, why would we want to test against a fake one?
Like, come on.
Heh. You But
what it did is, is the- God Bless.
It's logical for a step. It mocked it, then it needs to create it.
But we don't want mock. We want real. You need- Control-O
at any time to sort of see what's happening on their covers. Uhh,
looks like it was successful. Perfect. Okay. Control-O will get back.
You do if there's two above that
had a control-O and you missed it. Can you click on something?
There's- Yeah,
and do
a control-O?
Yep, hit control-O again. And you see that
there's an option of scroll down. Hello, I forgot,
uh, scroll down slightly. Uhh,
there is an option, I forget what you control button, scroll there is I
forget what you control button, scroll up a little bit. Umm. We'll see what,
scroll away, yeah. Keep keep going, keep going.
I think it's like control axe or something. You gotta go faster,
just go to the- Hurry top. Hurry. Oh, slow,
slow.
Okay. And not that big a deal.
I just, uhh, uhh, uhh, I'm still trying to get my head around.
Yeah,
the
waves to dial through the CLI like you do.
Yeah, it looks like this one's showing everything. But sometimes,
after a compact, there's the ability to sort of see what happened before.
I think it's like Control X or something. It tells you what the,
uh, command- Okay. Yeah.
It only really affects after the compact where you kind of,
we
care about compact anymore in the world of plug flow.
Haven't you? I figured out how to,
uh, well, probably take it
all the good stuff and
pack it in
an evergreen.
Yeah, exactly. I have. Actually,
you're my new sales guy. But, uh,
that's
exactly what I'm doing with the Agent DB capability.
So. you
There's all kinds of crazy in that Agent DB system I've devised.
But basically, in, in, in, in simple terms,
I've got the ability to have semantic relevance. So,
regardless of whether or not it's compact or not,
it stays, it has all the information in the DB.
And then, after comp- ax that can refer to that at any given point.
Alright, click control, oh, it looks like there's some kind of,
uhh, it looks like you're having some trouble with- Actually,
control it one more time. Uhh,
doo-doo-doo session phase. You Low-kunette-lobe.
Looks like you might have a sequel issue.
I'm not sure what's going on there.
Umm. Oh,
it's doing something with supervision. super bass.
Uhh, yeah, you may have to reinstall,
uh, Cloudflow. Go,
go into another terminal session for a second, just, let's just invoke Cloudflow.
And just, no, no, go, go,
go into a regular old fashioned terminal. Oh,
uh, actually, sorry,
go, go back to the MCP. Sorry, I'm jumping around a little bit.
Yeah. MCP.
Agentic payments fail. I think I might fit myself dead.
No, that's- It's working. I don't know why it's giving you that error.
Umm, different. Mmm.
Superbase failed.
Yes. Just, just, just go to,
like, open up a new terminal session. Yeah,
authenticate, try that. Sure.
2 3 4 5
Yeah, uh, your team. Yeah, open that up. Good. Good. It's a nice,
neat new feature. It's- it- you didn't- you just need to authenticate.
You're not using a token, you're using the- yeah,
log in authentication, which expires. The- the
using access token is- this- this approach is probably more secure,
just straight up. So just- yeah, just go ahead and do that.
Okay. Okay.
Go back to the other terminal session,
control-o, go back. I'm not- I'm not sure why you're getting this.
It's an error, but that's a different problem. You're,
Umm.
Alright. So now you've got all the errors.
You're connected to that. Now you can start using adding more API
endpoints. Um, you're enabled.
You're connected. So, what do you want to do with it?
What are the most important uh, API endpoints?
Alright.
The, umm.
I have them in a, uhh. that's the So,
we'll take Thank you. We're going
I mean, in a somewhat organized spreadsheet,
uhm, I need to- I think I have- I have that in a document
somewhere in here. I don't have that readily off the top of my head.
Oh, here
we'll just- let's just wing it then. Choose one,
choose some- ask- What the, what the most useful API endpoints are for this
application. For next help,
API scheduling.
followed COVID-19. Agent.
Should we just do it like one feature at a time?
Yes. That's gonna be way easier.
Yeah. A For
now, one at a time. We work- you work your way up to everything
at a time when you're- when you're- comfortable and confident that you can build
things and understand when things break.
But, where- now as you're getting going,
you're- you just need to ensure that the thing you're working on in
order of most of the least important works. works.
Yeah. Simple, narrow,
and, A lot of
the
problems- a lot of the problems we were running into previously was trying to
like- B-B-B-B So, as soon as we went to a more structured section-by-section-of-a-a-a-a-a-a-a-a-a-a-a
approach, you know, Mac was able to crank out that,
uh, patient portal and, like, you know,
a day, right? Now, that was a more targeted- approach.
Do you have
in Doc's Mac the details of this?
And I'll see you
Definitely,
it was there, um.
When we- ehm,
started this code base, umm,
under
product requirements. Yeah. Uh, you cleaned
it up. You probably- you probably cleaned up into a subfolder.
Also why- yeah,
there it is. Also why- why you want to use a reasoning system.
them. 8 So,
okay, so let's just- now that you have that,
let's just- let's do a different prompt.
So, in this one we're gonna- So, to clear,
clear that out, just hit Control C once. And,
and tell it to refer to the uh,
next health API. I mean, Boulder,
you, you, you, you've just shown?
Yep. Yeah.
Hit, uh, hit tab. Remember,
remember not to use spaces in your file,
uh, in your file names, or if- It's nothing good.
Comes from spaces. Um, don't worry about it right now.
Let's, uh, and-and let's, uhm,
tell it to update- Make the reasoning bank to include details of the,
uh, next health API for the implementation.
Thank for being here today. I'm not of the API at a later stage.
Okay, yep,
do that. Next thing we're gonna do, once we've,
once we've sort of, uhm, put the information to the reasoning bank,
then- What we're gonna do is we're gonna create a skill.
Scroll up into your dot cloud folder for a moment.
Yep. You get sk- skills perfect.
So what we're gonna do after this, we're gonna create a skill that's gonna
be your next health, uh,
API implementer. . . That's gonna use a combination of the reasoning components
that we just- that we're certainly feeding into the system,
and- and implement- 7 8 that's gonna help us implement that API.
So that's- that's gonna be more efficient,
and that'll also avoid compacting issues that you- It might run into where,
you know, so it'll, it'll, it'll stop it from hallucinating.
It'll be ground. I'm assuming that that document is correct,
but assuming that the document is correct,
it'll use the information within the- that document to ground it and guide it
in-in-in-in the appropriate mechanism.
Oh, what's the- doing? I hit escape. Tell it
to, uh, tell it to use the,
uh, reasoning bank using the quad code.
Uh, if you clock flow,
uh, uh,
MPX CLI or something. Thank you very much for us today.
And, and PX. Yeah,
Yeah, I don't know what it was trying to do there.
It gives going down a wrong path.
How did you
know that? It's not making- A
directory when there's no directory we needed.
Ah, for
the reasoning bag. See,
you see how it's now it's creating, and now it's using the actual,
uh, reasoning bank, emcee,
you know, uh, guidance.
Unknown. you Okay, it's acting dumb.
It should have started with the help, but anyway. I'll see Here
we go. Now it's- now it's going down the right- direction.
So it- it- it needed to understand what the- the- the correct.
Now it probably- Probably. I could have asked it to use the Reasonic Bank,
um, the Reasonic Bank skill,
but whatever. This is again, we'll get in the same spot.
Okay, now we're
good. Got a rea- reasoning bank agent DB and intelligence?
Yeah, we got all
kinds of stuff. Yeah, all kinds of- stuff. So,
what we're using right now is my default reasoning bank,
which is my state-of-the-art, as of, like,
a week and a half ago. But, uh,
it's- It's for what you're doing, it's more than adequate.
I'm, I'm moving. You guys are skills. Like,
I know that Claude, the
Claude, uh, basically- that you
need. First, when to use skills.
Or you can call them by name. Umm,
do we need to know your skills and call them by name or- Or
will they be inferred? They're
inferred. So yeah,
that's a whole other, uhh,
you can- Once we start getting to the point of using the AgentDB capabilities,
then we've got all kinds of things we can do in terms of training,
inferring, and optimizing.
But for what you need to do right now, this is the approach,
this is the better approach. Yeah.
Looks like
your, looks like your tool hooks are failing. Two for some reason,
control-o. Mmm,
it's taking a while. Okay,
control-o back. back. I can get you to get back. But you can see,
it's like, so uhh, uhh, actually,
control-o one more time. You can,
uhh, you can see what it's doing. So this is what's happening- this is,
this is the sort of reasoning bank structure that defines critical limitations,
the PMS. So this is all the- information that's important to the system
as it- as it will go and sort of start implementing.
I'm going to be using a scroll up.
Yeah, you're- there's something wrong with your cloud flow,
uhm, I can see it failing. I'm not sure why.
It looks like you're a sequel light. It's, It's not installed correctly.
I don't think
it'll-
I probably won't. It probably won't,
uhh. But, really, you probably won't notice because I've got a whole bunch of
fail-safes. But there is- there looks like there is a sequel light issue.
How do- how do you see
that? Where do you see that? Control-O?
Uhh,
I'm seeing- I'm seeing these air. I'll see in the Yeah, I'm seeing your
errors.
Yeah, those are errors. It's,
yeah, it's not working. Looks
like, looks like
you need to reinstall. Cloud, uh, Cloudflow.
You wanna just
exit and reinstall? Yeah,
I
gotta jump in my next call- Oh, guys, I apologize. But what,
what, what, you're, you do, you do have next health API working.
So now I'm- The Reasing Bank isn't working because there looks like there- it
looks like Cloudflow isn't installed correctly. Umm,
just good. Okay, go quick, a new to new terminal.
Type MPX, plug,
blow. Hello. Okay, no,
no, no, no, no terminal. Just, I, I don't have a lot of time.
Just close this, go, go to new terminal. And,
and MPX, clod- Oh gosh. Let's flow.
Add alpha. Uhh, space-help.
Help. Uhh,
replace. Hit up. Do memory. Uhh,
I'm pressing,
uhh. you Yeah, you replace
help with memory. And let-lose the dashes.
Uh, uhh.
. . . Yeah.
Alright, copy and paste the error that you saw in control and when you-
do the control-o into a new DSP and just tell to fix it.
Okay.
Can I still
control-o?
you
You
know, copy and paste that.
Alright. . Yeah. Oh no,
not all, it's just the air. Good, a little lower.
Yeah, right there. At the top. Yeah, right there. Reasoning bank.
All the way to the top. Keep going. Keep. Keep going.
Right there. Copy that. Yeah.
Yep, copy that. Peace. . Paste it in there and tell it to,
uh, move that thing out of the way.
And, uh, and then tell it to fix that.
Alright. Okay,
it looks like an SQLite error. error. Okay.
Where
did this? What?
How would you get rid of
this thing? Uhm, yeah, I'm
not sure where that- I came from. Uhm,
just click, uh, shh, just click ok or something.
I gotta go guys. Uhm.
. ? But once you've got that error, the bindings weren't right.
I'll double check that it wasn't something I did, but umm,
once you've got that, it'll, uhh, uhh, uhh, uhh, you should be able to
use the reasoning bank correctly. That, and that's why you keep an eye on
the, the controller. Alright,
I gotta jump. Okay.
Thank
you. Okay. Take care.
Okay. No problem. Come.