somebody preempted me
there okay here we go
it's uh what do we got
here november 20th so
the podcast um well
it's it's i'm i'm to
say i'm busy might be
an understatement of of
the year um this has
been you know the fall
it's usually busy for
for consultants but
this fall has been
absolutely insane and i
wish i could talk more
about the projects that
i'm doing but apparently
everybody has these
ironclad ndas so i'm
i'm careful in what i
need to say all i gotta
say is some of these
projects are just in
insanely large in terms
of the complexity that
we're seeing companies
and folks doing and
it's exciting to be
in the space and
watch you know as this
technology becomes
going from kind
of experimentation
to something more
than that and i'd
say you know one of my
projects would directly
touch close to 40
million people which and
that's just you know
a random thursday
afternoon right so
we're we're we're seeing
massive uptake rob what
how's it going great
great and yeah absolutely
you can hear it from
every direction that
uptake and the level
of conversations that
are happening um you
know outside of the ********
uh agentic engineering
community you can
hear the the quality
and uh the curiosity
um uh just step up day
by day so incredible
um uh tons of stuff
going on rube i think
just the one thing we
may want to mention
before we dive into uh to
the coding session today
um is the the global
uh hack fund that's
coming together and
sort of put the word
out to the community to
be thinking about uh
putting some teams
together yeah so we're
we've been discussing this
idea of hackathons
uh quite a bit lately
and you know and more
to the point like what's
the point of you know
the agentics foundation
what what are we good
at what do we want
to do you know how do
we want to structure
these because it's
been you know been fair
to me loosey-goosey
sort of approach that
we've taken and that's
kind of purposeful i
guess just you know
whatever um but what's
interesting is we have a
core crew that are really
good at sort of
improvisation of building
things, vibing, but not
just vibing garbage.
We're getting really
good at vibing high
quality stuff, stuff
that, you know, proves
a point really quickly
and shows the art of
the possible and how we
can apply this in new
and novel ways. So
what that really means
is we're good at sort
of hackathons, right?
And some of the folks
that have been doing
hackathons, like our
friends from cornell and
a few others that i've
been mentoring you
know they're coming
in first place they're
coming in second place in
in these top hackathons
so we've seen to be
putting together a
really good crew for
for doing that right and
our friends at uh 42
are helping sponsor a
hackathon in partnership
with tv tv sync in
in france and this is
and they're they're a
pretty big deal they
get what half a billion
uh viewers or something
like that that's
right that's right 400
subscribers worldwide
Yeah. So they own
essentially the French,
the francophone, you
know, world in essence.
Right. That's it's
smaller than the
English one, but it's
decent, I guess. Half
a billion people isn't
nothing. So they're
looking at us and
saying, you know, why
don't we do a sort of
hackathon for good?
Right. Is that
am I getting the
story right?
Yeah, absolutely.
You know, the core
challenge is that
globally, on average,
human beings spend 45
minutes a day searching
for what to watch.
So billions of hours
of human hours a
day trying to find
something suitable
for entertainment.
And they have tabled
with the Paris chapter
and the Eugenics
Foundation the
challenge of providing
a solution that can
reduce that time.
Yeah. Pretty interesting.
This is something Jed and
I were just discussing.
So we have a little
pre-show where I get
everything set up. And
Jed was mentioning,
you know, what are
you going to do
with 5,000 or 5 million
agents running in
a kind of parallel
concurrent fashion?
Jed, what were your
thoughts there?
Most of it was trying
to figure out how
all of that was
running within the
same environment while
also talking to the
APIs of the different
LLM providers.
So, I think what you're
saying, yeah, it's
like, okay, I've got,
like, what does the
architecture actually
look like and how do you
apply it? let's say we
want to deploy 5,000
or even 500 million agents
that each represents
a single subscriber
within that pool of
their supposed half a
billion users. So how
would we do that
functionally, right? So
what we're looking to
do is take these self
-learning loops, right?
And hyper-target those
for certain segments
or personas, or in this
case, actual potential
viewers of that
network and then sort of
optimize based on what
we think they want to
see in a sort of self
-fulfilling learning
loop right reinforcement
a couple points up
negative a couple points
down and then at a
certain point you get
this coherence now
what what these agents
can do now is allow us
to spawn up literally
499 million different
agents that exist exist
just to study and
pre-train based on a
particular user and all
the information we have
available to that user
now we can do that
in parallel so we spawn
i don't think we're
going to do a half a
billion depends on the
infrastructure but we
hypothetically could
essentially spawn half
a billion now in a half
a billion scenario
we'd have a lot of
information to parse so
you're creating these
little agentic networks
that are optimized just
for each particular
user understanding that
user saving that to
a user profile or
database or somewhere
and being done in that
entire process can be
done in like 20 minutes
half a billion times
right there's so many
different dimensions
of this problem that
a genix form orchestration
can take a look
at in order to break
it down and then
reconstitute it in a
in a hypercurrent uh
contemporary uh method
with a genix so that's
the hackathon roof.
It'll be, you know,
under your technical
guidance, we'll break
the problem apart. We're
inviting teams from
chapters and members,
individuals, members
from around the
world if you want to
participate. This is not
an internal competitive
hackathon. It's a
collaboration. So
everybody who is involved
and is participating
and brainstorming
in different aspects
will collectively
participate in the results
and or rewards or
outcomes of the actual
challenge and the
potential solution that
we put together
collectively. So there is
a landing page now.
I think we got that
registration form set
up. Is that right, Ruf?
Yeah, we did get a
page up on the site.
Agentix, we did it
yesterday. Let me
share my screen quick
here for you guys.
uh genetics.org
slash hackathon
i think it was
so yeah all
right here we go
hack hackathon
and here let me share
it it's basically
we're gonna would
probably oops i didn't
i i i spelled it wrong
once and now i and
now it remembers the
wrong spelling all right
i need the h here we
go hackathon with an
h i maybe hackathon in
french doesn't have an
age seems superfluous
all right so we've
got i've registered so
i can't show you the
registered uh form
but you've seen one
registration form you've
seen them all whatever
put your name in you're
either an individual
or a a team we're
thinking uh all-star teams
now remember this is
a collective so that
means if you participate
and you put in you
know some some
something back you know
something that works
basically that creates a
pool relating to the
overall sort of thing that
wins so maybe some
other group actually
wins and their system
gets used that forms a
license that they
that's being put into a
um essentially a dow i
think is again it's i
don't want to it's
coming together right but
it's basically a way to
bring people together
so we all share in
the profitability, if
the algorithm or thing
that we invent gets
used broadly, then
TVSank or whoever ends
up using the algorithm
will pay a license fee
to use that algorithm
that we devise as part
of their core sort
of optimization for
their users or whatever
it is that it ends up
doing. So it's a
collective. So yes, we'll
have a winner of some
sort, but the real value
is in the fact that
we're all kind of
doing it together. And
I think that that's the
part that seems right
to me. I don't know.
Yeah, that's right.
It's a collaborative
effort meant to
bring togetherogenic
engineers and members
from around the world
to all lean in on a
very big problem and
all participate in
the rewards and the
outcome if there
just happens to be a
market value to the
solution that emerges.
And interesting
to note that in
this structure, We
already have the next
hackathon challenge
tabled, which happens
to also be from
the Paris chapter.
Tourism France is
looking to address
discoverability in the
new era of GEO with
LOMs and how to
support their historic
tourism industry
across France. So we've
already got the next
one lined up and looking
like there's a
third coming after
that. So this is a
really exciting format.
Collaborative, global,
worldwide, right
in our space,
eugenics warm
orchestration,
problem discovery,
everything.
It's going to
be a lot of fun.
Yeah, for sure. So it's
going to be different.
And if this works,
what I'd like to
start us doing maybe
is more hackathons, you
know, for good, for
profit, whatever it is.
and we will you know
focus on different
problems get maybe
let's try to do like at
least one of these a
month i i love building
something now i got
a reason to build
something right so building
for purpose spectacular
yeah and just to
know the actual event
will be december 5th
6th and 7th friday
saturday sunday but
there's going to be a lot
of preamble leading
up to it and uh i just
want to tip of the
hat to Vincent Sider,
Arsene Jean-Marie out
of the Paris chapter
for quarterbacking and
bringing this
all together and
Roof, your work
with them to help
have it make structural
and technical sense,
getting ready for it.
Spectacular. I'm really
excited to see what
it is. And we can't
forget the crew also,
our marketing crew, we
got Matt actually did
most of the work on
this landing page, by
the way. Yeah, that's
right. Yeah, thanks
Matt for putting that
together. and leandro and
team are working on the
assets yeah so and
dory who's our who made
this site look amazing
she's done she's
spectacular so yeah she's
the one that did the
redesign she took all
the crazy that i want
because i like the
sort of retro console
aesthetic and and she
worked with me um i and as
a as a reformer graphic
designer i think my
wife tells me i'm like
the worst person to
work with because i'm
very nitpicky on like
fonts and locations
so thank you for that
she's done a great job
there um yeah so that's
what we're gonna do uh
you know so if you're
interested this is
gonna be uh the i guess
the opens on the third
and i'm gonna do a
team not sure how i'd
like to see us like
maybe get some team
heads if you guys are
interested in like we We
get Ocean, Jed, and Nick,
and a few others that
sort of lead teams.
You know, that'll
probably work
well for us.
That's a fun problem.
Yep.
Yeah.
That's it. So just
everybody who's
interested, fill out
that registration
form, and we'll
get that big
list, and we'll
start to parse it.
Yeah.
And who else
we got here? We
got Nick. How's
it going, Nick?
I'm just looking
through. Yeah,
I'm just working
away here,
working on a
LLM analytics
system right now.
Okay.
Yeah.
Yeah, you're still
creating the Rust
-based stuff, you
know, the sort
of going from Rust
to an NPM and a
sort of distributed
sort of package.
Yeah.
Have you looked at the
NAPI stuff recently
at all? I haven't got
there yet. So when you
tell me something,
Reuben, it takes me a
couple of weeks to sort
of work it into reality.
So it's in the back
of my mind. It's on
my list here. And I'll
definitely be exploring
that here in the
next couple of weeks.
All right. Okay.
Well, please feel
free to share
whatever you're
building. You're always
building some
really interesting
stuff. I love
seeing that stuff.
So today,
what are we going to
work? Anybody have
any review of
Google's anti-gravity?
I'm thinking I'm going
to go through the
installation process.
I've been swamped, so I
haven't had a chance
to play with it so i
thought maybe i'll start
there and see where
that leads a little
bit i get a new laptop
which means i probably
need to set some things
up anyway um i've been
playing what yeah what
do you what are your
thoughts so i mean so
far it says it's supposed
to be better than
i'm experiencing i i
expected something a
little better i i have
an interesting challenge
that i run through
most of these where I
say, just go on to my
daily New York Times
and print out my
crossword puzzles, a super
simple thing. But New
York Times is massively
scoped out to prevent
any kind of bot. So
it turns out to be a
fairly challenging topic.
And I'm literally
working through it right
now. And two minutes
ago was the first time
I'd actually printed out
the puzzle correctly.
But what was surprising
is I had to walk
it through a lot of
the process. I had
thought it would be savvy
enough to figure that
out diagnose get around
use chrome etc and
it didn't do that so
i just literally the
first thing i've had a
chance to do with it i
got a lot more intentions
to do more with it
i i had a problem i
couldn't seem to find
out how to put my api
key in and it kept saying
you know you're maxed
out on the 30 prime
or the 30 pro product
anybody else see that
well
so far it's not so good
for me the install is
seems to have crashed
you can't put
your own keys into
anti-gravity at
this stage that's
explicitly stated
on their page
oh it says you
cannot yeah they
say it explicitly
at this stage
yeah
alright so yeah so no
so far no no good for
me i it actually maybe
because i have good
zoom going zoom's never
friendly for for doing
installs but the
install uh i i think has
uh actually crashed on
me which isn't a good
scene so i'm gonna have
to uh yes kill that
i guess i mean i used
uh google anti-gravity
yesterday and for
me the results were
actually pretty good so
i i just i pointed it
to a website in about
two hours it replicated
the website and we
made it a note and next
and then JavaScript
everything was working
looked really good I
now there there is a
problem where you usually
hit model overload or
either hit quota
limits just say the for
the LM to try it again
and then it just continues
where it left off uh
i also had it make
me a prototype of a
game written in rust and
it actually worked
pretty fine so uh the
only thing is that it
can have errors or a
model overload because
a lot of people are
using it but if you tell
it just to try again
then usually it gets
around those errors all
right thank you i don't
i i don't think i'm
going to be able to
install it while using
zoom unfortunately but
uh or maybe it's just
locked up i don't know
but it doesn't doesn't
i don't think it
likes zoom installing
because it it basically
doesn't doesn't do it
um but what i what
i want to do there's
there's no shortage of
stuff so i want to do
and i show you some of
my experiments and some
of the things i'm
working on i i was
unfortunate this week
that I was doing some
large scale testings of
swarms and I maxed out
my, um, my clod code
or whatever within the
first 24 hours, but
I've got more than one
account, but that's,
that was a little
unfortunate. So I gotta
be a little more careful
on that, but
essentially I'm going to
show you some things
and like everything, and
by the way, I just
muted everybody. If you
want to talk, just
unmute yourself. This,
this one doesn't auto
mute for some reason.
All right. So here
we go. I'm going
to share my screen
here. Just one sec.
Actually, I'm going
to switch it up.
I've got this laptop
that's got multiple
screens. It's
actually great for
this because it puts
it in a nice spot.
All right. I want
to show you also my
Neurotrader stuff.
I've been looking at
ways to make that work
as essentially within
a cloud code web
or even the anti
-gravity where you
could basically just
pointed at my
particular, what I really
wanted to show you
was basically using an
anti-gravity, but
unfortunately I wasn't
able to get any anti
-gravity installed.
But what, so that
part of the, that
part of my story,
well, I'm going to
have to improvise
here a little bit,
but what I want to
describe is sort of
the idea. So I'm
going to make, I'm
going to make
Neurotrader open source.
It's, you know,
selling it as a direct
sale would be a whole
business, you know,
And I don't think I
want to make my
business the business of
Neurotrader. I like
doing the Neurotrader
work, but I think that
making it open source
allows me to mix and
match it and allows
others to run with
it. And it's a really
cool, powerful system.
So the concept of
Neurotrader is actually,
you know, it's made
up of a whole bunch
of different packages.
So there's this modular
structure to it. So
all the parts of the
system are a kind of
collection of NPM
that you can include,
right? So you include
these, see these at
Neurotrader. So there's
core and there's the
protocol and there's a
whole variety of these
different components
you can add and mix
and match to create a
kind of modular Lego
style sort of approach.
So you've got neural
packages you can add
that add the ability
to do different types
of prediction. You can
then apply that in
a whole variety of
different patterns and
ways. You've got risk and
all kinds of things.
This thing even has
an accounting system
that's been built in
here, sports betting.
you've got so you can
pick parts that you
want and what's also
interesting about this
platform is even though
it's focused on this
idea of trading trading
in essence is like
the is like the form
of most business to
some degree right just
because you're trading
in stock in a future
date that's more
mathematical but you can
apply this as part of
like the way that you
handle the finances of
your business because
the system essentially
has an accounting
system built right
into it. So let me find
the accounting system
here. Quick thing,
Reuven, you're sharing
your anti-gravity
installer and your task
manager screen. Oh,
here. Sorry, guys. One
second. Let me try it.
Let me share again.
Today's not going
so good for me. Thanks
for the heads up.
And how's it
going, David?
Yeah, it's going pretty
good. I've been out
of the fold a little
bit because I joined
the Agent Force AI team
at Salesforce here in
San Francisco. So
I've been little bit
swamped with some
really crazy high volume
enterprise ai stuff going
on but i try to make
you know i'm trying to
figure out how to get
back into spending more
time with the agentic
foundation because
it's so close to my
heart but um you know
and i'm looking for
opportunities on on
how i can you know get
maybe you know agent
force sales force ai stuff
connected with with
what we're doing at the
agentics foundation
always looking for
opportunities so trying
as much as i can to fly
the flag we should uh
you should we should
do a hackathon like
i know i was thinking
about that man i'm
thinking about having a
sales force team and
agent force team yeah i
guys i'm not i'm
agnostic towards the
platforms i really don't
care what we use i i
think that what we need
to do is a uh you know
let's do an agent off
or better yet let's
do a mind meld where
we merge the stuff that
that that that you're
seeing me do with the
stuff that you're
doing and see what kind
of crazy love child
appears from it well i'm
gonna throw something
out here i gotta be
careful what i say
but but you know agent
you know salesforce has
like almost a billion
users of its products
super successful
enterprise business
product but they're very
conservative in how
we're architecting and
building and deploying
ai you know agentic tools
and when i compare
what we're doing here
in the Agenix Foundation
to what a large
business enterprise is
doing with AI. We're
like, really, honestly,
guys, I keep saying
this, the Agenix Foundation
is at the cutting
edge of the industry
compared to what a
humongous, successful
SaaS company is doing in
the business space.
We're light years ahead
of them, like really
light years ahead. You
should be proud of
what we're doing here.
yeah it's it's sometimes
it's hard to tell
right i'm wrapped up in
my own self-fulfilling
manifestation of the
things i build right
what does the world
look like in 10 years
build that and then
some of that's the thing
that i'm known for
building or whatever it's
it's so it's it's hard
to step out of your
own bubble well yeah
and that's why i joined
uh salesforce like
right now i'm actually
architecting uh you know
agentic conversation
and memory for sports
for sales force for agent
force so which we
were doing a long time
ago and now you know
you've got agent db and
the memories memory
bank and all that like
a long time ago so
that's how ahead of the
curve we are here nice
well i really really
appreciate your support
and we should totally
do that uh hackathon
of some sort let's just
build things and see
what we can do our
biggest our biggest
constraint just generally
speaking is lack of
like infrastructure to
support these you know
When I'm doing a 5,000
-agent swarm and maxing
out my account in the
first 24 hours, that's
essentially coming
out of my pocket, right?
So I think our biggest
limitation is the
ability to support the
underlying things that
we're doing. If we had
more technical resources
or, I don't know,
just the ability to
test our stuff more
broadly, we'd be able
to push the boundaries
even further. So we're
limited by being poor.
Like everything
you see me build
is essentially
for the GPU poor.
I don't know, that makes
any sense whatsoever.
But so with that
in mind, hopefully
I share the right
screen this time.
So this made up of
modules, it's made up
of a variety of things
you can plug and play.
So much like an
ecosystem you'd see in
a larger company, SaaS
driven, you've got
different parts and
different products that
you can plug together
in different ways.
I built it in that
sort of fashion. So
for example, the agentic
accounting system,
which would literally
work for any sort
of corporate treasury
that involves
looking at compliance,
looking at, in this
case, it's optimized
for like investment
related activities,
but it's trivial to
sort of modify to look
at the requirements
of your particular
business in terms of
the actual assets and
accounting itself.
So to include that,
all you're doing
is basically using
this. So this would
be like an MPX command
or MPM, if you're
using, depending
on how you're using
it. And you'd
basically say, build me
an accounting system,
make it the world's
smartest accounting
system and go.
And I built all these
things using a high
-performance internal
Rust compilation.
Now you hear me talking
about Rust all the time.
What's interesting
about Rust is its
speed, its performance,
and the ability
for AI to build
things in Rust that
somehow magically
work the first try.
And where Python
and TypeScript take
you down these weird
rabbit holes and
lie to you and say,
yes, I built it.
It's the world's
best. It never is.
But with Rust, it
is. And it works.
It takes several
hours of sort of
combinations and
testing and optimizing.
But generally speaking,
what gets put out
from Rust works no
matter the complexity.
So if you're looking
to build something
crazy, now the problem
with that is you now
have this limitation
of having to compile
the thing, which is
a pain in the ***.
So what the NAPI
-RS algorithm,
well, that's
not algorithm,
it's like
integration for Rust,
allows you to do native
compilations for that
particular environment.
So think Mac,
Linux, Windows, those,
you know, various flavors
of Unix, that sort
of thing. And then it
basically allows you to
deliver that directly
as an NPM, which are
super easy to install
pretty much everywhere.
And then rather than
using the V8 library,
which is essentially
the core kernel of
like Chrome to operate
the node system, it
actually switches that
with the Rust system,
which is many, many times
faster and more capable
in terms of loops
and optimizations so
when you're looking at
these systems what
you're actually seeing
are the rust crates
that make up this system
so if you go let's go
to my crates though
for a second i'll show
you that so so it's
it's two parts so we're
gonna go over to my
most recent recent
downloads uh we'll get
recent updates and you'll
see here i've got my
gentix robotics that's
a whole other thing
i'm gonna have to show
you guys the robotics
That's part two of
what we're doing today.
But before we get
to robotics, we've
got these NT
bindings. So NT stands
for Neurotrader,
Neural Networks.
So these are the
libraries that make up the
core Neurotrader
system. So you can run
these directly in
terms of the highest
performance you can
possibly get. We're talking
nanosecond sort of
loops and capabilities.
You run that directly
using Rust. Now,
there's a bit of overhead
when you're bringing
it into the MPM, but
we're talking minor,
like less than 1% for
most of these things.
So it's so low, it
doesn't even matter.
The benefit of this
is you can sort
of use this as a
kind of derivative.
You can say, take
one of my libraries
and repurpose it
for something else.
So you've got,
you know, all
these different
libraries. So the
core here, let's
go to the core.
You know,
this is the sort of
core library itself
that kind of connects
everything together.
Now, where you really
want to go isn't
here. You're going
to want to go to NPM.
Let's go to
Neural Crater.
So this is all those
components packaged
together. And I haven't
even announced this
yet. So thanks for
everyone who's downloaded.
That's not bad for
something I haven't
put out publicly,
really, other than this.
All right. So continuing.
So these are the key
capabilities. This is
what you're getting.
Now, OK, so I'm showing
you all these crazy
features. It's self
-learning. it's got
tools it's it's crazy
fast but the key part
and this is what you
need to understand is
all you need to do to
start trading with
the system is you're
going to grab where
i'm going to find the
part here is basically
this so we're going to
go to cloud code all
right and hopefully
i don't show any keys
because i love to
expose my keys all right
so we're we're going
to go here and we're,
we're going to, um,
we're going to tell
it, we're going to
go to, we're going to
go to my, my generic
one. I don't want
it to get, I don't
want to get it
commingled with the code.
So I'm going to go
and use my vibe cast.
And you guys can see
this when you, if you
go to the vibe cast,
you'll see a branch
appear based on what
I'm about to do.
You can use it and
play with it, whatever.
All right. So what
I'm going to do right
now is I'm going to
basically tell it to
install
MPX.
Remember, there's
two ways to work with
this library. One
is an MPM, and this
essentially allows you
to assemble the parts
with code. The other
is from the CLI, and
the CLI or MCP allow
you to interact with
the system like a
service, like a secondary
third-party application,
so it's more
app-orientated versus
code-orientated.
The app orientations
generally
works faster and
easier. In this case,
with that i might
go with mpx install
and then i don't
need the install
so i'm going to
lose that and that's
it that's going
to give you the ci
and then i'm going
to also tell it to
review the read readme
and use the one sec
guys i'm going to give
it the api key i'm not
going to give you the
actual api key because
i have it in this
neural trader env here
but i'm going to And this
is the part, actually,
that's the most, I
don't know, tricky?
Maybe that's the wrong
word. The part it
struggles with in Cloud
Code Web is finding
the ENV. Even though
it's in the secret,
it always thinks to
look for a .env file
that doesn't exist.
And I'll say something
like, use API key from
the system secrets.
What is this API key
that you are providing?
So Alpaca API,
what does it
do this particular
API key?
Oh, okay. So I'm going
to get this going
here in a sec, but
I'll show you that.
Okay. So this is a
trading system, right? So
the trading system,
essentially, it needs
real-time data to
know and understand
what's happening in the
market. There's lots
of them out there,
but this one's free.
And the drawback to
the free is it doesn't
do historical unless
you pay for it. But
what it does do is
gives you, assuming the
market's open, which
would be crypto most
of the time or stocks
right now, and then
you can get it to
study the structure of
those stocks. Now, I
can spawn dozens of
different agents using
Cloud Code Web in my
system, the neurotrading
system here that
I'm showing you, to
do lots of different
types of analysis in
potential trades. So
this system also operates
in a paper trading
capacity, which is
the API I just gave
it. So that essentially
allows it to simulate
the trades using real
market information
that's streaming from
the market provider.
It's not particularly
fast, but it's good
enough for sort of
training the system.
And then you can get
a feel for what it
is and how it's going
to operate over an
extended period of
time. So you might let
it run on paper
trades for a week or
longer while it kind
of figures out the
optimal strategies
for how to do certain
types of investment
based on your risk level
or how much money
you have or how much
money you're willing
to lose sometimes.
And it's figuring
that out all the
time. So we can
correlate that with
things like a polymarket.
So the polymarket
would be like
a prediction of
what's going to
happen in the future.
And this polymarket
system is actually
surprisingly accurate at
predicting a lot of things
that you wouldn't
think are possibly
predicted based purely
on sentiment. Like people
are like willing to
put real money against
it, which makes you
think more analytically
about the problem. And
then that very thing
makes the prediction
more likely to happen.
You can correlate that
back to the psycho
structures that make
people sort of want or do
these sorts of things
and analyze that and
then apply it to your
trading patterns. So it
creates a kind of not
only a market signal,
but it creates a kind
of human psychology
that can be analyzed
as part of the process,
which is crazy.
And then you've
got all these
other various
things. Just a quick
thing, Ruben,
for one to beat.
Alpaca, sorry, I got
some background noise.
Alpaca is a trading
platform that has
market data feeds
and it's built, very
modern. And it's built
for – with lots of
APIs, so you can write
code to do programmatic
trading. And
there's lots of the
Polygon and lots of
other – so there's lots
– and some of them
are free. Some of
them you pay for.
Some of them you get
different levels of
API control and stuff.
Alpaca has been
around for a while.
I've been an Alpaca
user for like
five-plus years.
It's really good.
If you're – so
you start with
Alpaca. It's cheap,
easy, and free.
Yeah, sorry. Go ahead.
Oh, no. I was just –
two questions. So, first
of all, I was wondering,
why did you use
Alpaca and not another
free API such as Yahoo
Finance? Yahoo Finance.
I use all of them.
Yeah, yeah.
I have all of them.
What you end up doing
is you find that these
trading platforms,
they try to lock you
and they want you to
pay. So, they give you
a certain amount of
free access. They
either API, rate limit,
amount of data, type of
data, type of trades.
And so, you generally
– like I have built a
trading system and I
have like 29 different
platforms that I use.
in order to get the
data feeds and the
market feeds and the api
access that so you
know you just there's
lots of them and and
you have to figure out
which ones are giving
you what you want
basically for free or
if you want to pay you
you pay there's just
so many of them that's
alpaca is pretty rich
and it's what it can
do what's great what's
great about alpaca
is specifically it's
paper trading capability
so what you what
you and you can fake
paper trading without
the paper trading system.
But what this gives
you is the ability
to understand the real
information from the
market and executing
different types of
purchase strategies in
a way that responds in
a realistic sort of
response. And then once
you're comfortable with
that, it's a really
easy transition to
like their real trading
system, right? So
some of them, not all
of them, will have
paper trading options.
Now, ultimately what
you're really trying to
do is get faster than
those systems, but
it really depends on
your trading strategy.
Sorry, Ruth, I
have a question.
Yeah, sure.
In case that you
have access to
historical data, so
we don't have to wait
for one, two, or
three weeks, and
actually we run for
the last 10 years,
is it ready the system
to do that? There's
something that it will
run the simulations or
back-tested the
simulations so we can train
the system faster?
It's already available?
Well, Alpacit doesn't
really provide a
back-testing historical
trading analyzer.
No, it's easy to
do, though. I do.
There's lots of
platforms that
you can leverage
to do that.
That's literally what I
built. So essentially,
if you go into my
system, you've got all
these different sort
of packages. So these
are the crates and
these explore different
things you've got
available. So in this
case, this would be the
multi-market system.
So a multi-market system
allows you to create
your own backtesting,
right? So you don't
need to sign up for
any of these services.
The only service you
really need is the
service that allows
you to trade, right? So
that would be like
Interactive Brokers in the
US or Alpha, Vantage
or whatever. wherever
you reside, there's
usually different sort
of API-centric brokers
that are the main
provider in that
region. You find the one
that you want. What this
does is does everything
that sits around the
trade. So if you want
to do backtesting for
the last 10 years,
but if you have the
data, that's where this
works best. So if you
don't have the data, the
system will attempt
to go find that data
through either paid or
free sources. You can
start with free and
it'll go and basically
use the web search
capabilities built into
cloud code or whatever.
It's okay. You're getting
the same **** everybody
else is getting.
The ones that are
actually truly successful
in using the system,
they've got their own
source of proprietary
data that they've
collected over an extended
period of time that
they can then correlate
to these different
market segments, right
and so they're in this
here's the market data
aggregator for example
so the market data
aggregator creates and
unifies interfaces
that fetches data among
multiple providers
including alpaca polygon
yahoo alpha advantage
and crypto exchange i
support every single
one that's ever been
created it can create new
ones and if it doesn't
exist you just point
the system at it and
you say go build me that
particular interface
and it uses this library
to basically create
a new provider that
wasn't there before.
And depending on
the provider, you've
got real-time and
historical. So you can
see that right now I
support pretty much
everything you want,
at least in that
department. And here's
the SDK, whatnot.
And then you've
got these different
forms of predictors.
So you've got something
called, I can't
even pronounce it,
conformal prediction.
So the system also
encapsulates this idea
of creating and
predicting based on
different types of
structures, both long,
you know, multi-day,
multi-month years
potentially, but also
really, really small
segments. So it turns
out the system is
best suited for making
it truly accurate
predictions, but they
have to be under 100
milliseconds. The most
accurate prediction
it can make is actually
under 10 milliseconds
that's interesting
because the time it
takes you to get from
the information from new
york to london takes
about 16 milliseconds
so it's pretty freaking
fast now what this
thing does is capable
of making very very
narrow mathematical
generally types of of
reasoning predictions
using causal loops what
will what has happened
what is happening
and what will happen
but that all happens in
sub millisecond
microseconds generally and
and you when you apply
it to certain problems
you can you have a
narrow window where
the thing is actually
moving faster because
of this idea of prediction
than the speed of
light between new york
and london so at that
point you have the
ability to essentially
i don't know what
the right word is but
front load the intelligence.
So it's able to
understand slightly
faster than the others
for certain problems.
And these problems are
generally mathematical
in nature, but some
form of sort of linear
equation of some sort,
most likely. And that's
what a lot of this
is doing. So it's
able to do that in two
millisecond latency,
and then it vectorizes
that to create a
learning sort of hyper
multidimensional learning
structure to that
basically moves in both
temporal, you know,
I said loops, what's
happening, what's, what's
happened and what will
happen in a really
short succession, and
then creating multiple
connected versions of
that in the vector.
That is happening
all the time.
And the system is
learning essentially
what works and
what doesn't,
and then applying it
as quickly as it can.
In between the two,
there are these agents
that spawn up so the
agents and you can see
what else we got here
the the lots there's
so much stuff in here
it's we can just just
do tell them tell me
about is that stacked
against the communication
to receive the
data and then respond
or is that meant to
happen on a super
luminous basis it's meant
it's meant to it's
meant to it's meant to
understand reason respond
i'm it's an oda loop
So you're stuck with
the speed of light
issue when you're
communicating or
sending a signal from
you, wherever the
decisions you need
to be exchanged?
Yeah, so basically
what I'm stuck with is
the limitations of
everybody else around
me. So the problem
is, one, most of the
providers, all the
providers, don't work in
sub-millisecond
increments. They're limited
to about 100, maybe
50 milliseconds into
100 milliseconds. And
I'm working between
50 to a thousand times
faster than that. So
nobody is able to get
my information and
I'm not able to execute
on it because there's
a fundamental traffic
jam in the trading
universe that I
can't overcome. So to
overcome that problem,
what I'm doing is using
that time to make more
informed decisions
and knowing that I'm
not able to overcome
the limitations of
speed. So I can't
front load it really
at that point. But what
I can do is overanalyze
it or be smarter
than everybody else
in making the request.
And the system
is figuring
all that out by itself.
all right so basically
all you to run this
thing all you need to
do is do it exactly
what i just typed so
you're gonna you're gonna
go into whatever you
can do this in if
you're in this case
you're not gonna use this
you're gonna do this
you're gonna say tell
me about the mpx uh
neural neural trader
uh that's it we're gonna
that's all you need
to type and that will
set open a sort of
Pandora's box where it
can follow the sort of
yellow brick road here
wherever it leads.
So the system
essentially, when you
run that, let's just
run that quick and
I'll show you what
that looks like.
MPX Neural Trader,
that's essentially
going to kick off a
series of installs.
And it's not the
lightest app in the
world for all the
things I've just shown
you. You know, you get
to download several
distributions and
it's an enterprise
application. So the
architecture is how
you build for large
scale systems, right?
This would be used in
a bank or something.
All right. So now
we've run that. It's
installed it. You've got
this terminal, right?
So you've got the high
performance neural
training system with GPU
acceleration. And yes,
I included GPU
acceleration because why
not? if for a lot of the
problems you're going
to want to solve
here will need gpu
acceleration that i i'm
as i point out frequently
i'm gpu poor so i'm
using just my local gpu
for most of it but the
the reality is this
gpu stuff is absolutely
crazy so for some
of the problems you're
going to solve you can
literally you can
create these loops using
the same concepts
that i'm using for of
those sublinear loops
that i was describing but
you can do it a trillion
times or something
something beyond that
some giant number
and it's it so depending
what you're doing
you're you're you probably
want to explore that
and to jed's favorite
place um rack space
or one of those sort
of environments would
be perfect for this
because this entire
environment is ephemeral
it the there's a
federation option built
in here that allows all
those processes, whether
local or on Rackspace
or whatever, to run in
a federated fashion,
which allows them to
sort of communicate
with each other sort
of in a distributed
network. Now, I'm using
that quick QUIC protocol,
which basically allows
each of those to
communicate with each
other with no handshake.
So it's instantaneous
sort of communication
between you're
limited by the network
and the speed of
light so but I've been
deploying this on fly
which has global and it's
great works works
perfectly it's cheap it
doesn't cost much so
you're it's you're
basically just letting it
follow follow this kind
of path here a little
bit now for the other
things I was showing
you you're going to
want to do similar
things so we go back to
this for a sec and
you'll if you scroll down
on my npm page here
i'm gonna just move on
your trader are you
auto switching uh to a
different api when you
hit rate limits and
if so how yes uh really
i you if you're free
you're gonna need to
sign up and you can
literally get the agent
to sign up for uh you
know read the terms of
use don't be don't be
jerks about it if
you're making money pay
for the service but
while you're learning
you know you do what
you need to do to learn
but the you can sign
up and use multiple
accounts now you're going
to put that in an env
file and you're going
to tell it basically
to create a kind of
rate limiting or round
robin or some sort of
multi multi-api use
pop you're just going
to tell it to do that
and it'll figure it out
you it's got all the
things it needs to do
anything it needs you
to do the intention
is you just ask it.
It's powerful, but it's
made for vibe coders.
Don't ask me how it
works. Don't ask me
how I built it. It was
hard, but it works.
That's essentially
who I made it for.
That said,
don't be stupid.
This system can
be used for all
kinds of interesting
use cases,
which are
perfectly legal.
And you can also
be used for stupid
things like embedding
and things that
were probably put
you in a place that
you don't want to be.
And if you're using
it for someone
other than yourself,
that is a securities
vulnerability to
you. So you're, what
you're not going to do
is go start a personal
financial business
without getting
the right legal and
regulatory other
things in place. Cause
you'll end up being,
you know, when, when
stuff goes sideways
you'll be left holding
the bag so don't do
that anywho um we
so okay you scroll
down the page you've
got features you've
got market data you've
got brokers each of
these can be used
all right so now if
i want to use the the
mp this one i'm going
to go back to my um
here and i'm going
to go back to claude
for a sec and so it's
it's doing whatever
it's doing it's coming
up with ideas it's
it's telling me
everything it needs to do
now i'm gonna say can
you uh also explore
then the uh i'm
gonna put the mpx i'm
gonna put i'm gonna
do this as an mpm
um i don't know we'll
do mpm and again
mpm is an sdk and
the mpm allows you to
build with it so much
as operate it, you're
operating it still,
but you're operating
it through like new
code that you build
to operate it. So
it's different. So if
you're vibing, you
can try both different
approaches. It's
kind of interesting
to see where that
takes you a little bit.
All right. So now
it's exploring
that. Oh, and you
know what? That anti
-gravity thing actually
is installing.
It just takes
forever to install.
So maybe we'll get to
anti-gravity here in
a moment. All right.
While this does this
thing i want to show
you some other stuff so
that what do we got
here uh all right we're
gonna go to where the
heck did i put that uh
i gotta go to my get
i built too much stuff
i can't remember all
the things i build it's
but i built something
cool and i want but
i'm not sure but i think
it's cool and i want
to show you guys
because it's cool uh all
right so we're gonna
go to my repos here i
gotta remember what the
heck i called it it's
uh rue vector yes i
named them something,
another thing after
myself, because I've got
like weird, some kind
of neuroses, I guess.
Rue vector.
So I've been
thinking a lot about
vectors. I've
been on a vector
kick, as you guys
probably know.
And there are some
really great vector
databases out there,
you know, and I'm not,
and I'm doing this not
because it necessarily
needs to be done, more
that I just wanted
to know how to build
a vector, original
high-performance vector
database from the
ground up with no
lineage to anything that
currently exists,
really. So that's what
I was trying to do.
And of course, because
it kind of works with
Reuven, I put vector
after it and I got
Reuven vector. All
right. So basically
what I was trying to do
is using a few different
approaches here,
you know, to create
the fastest possible
enterprise scale
vector system you could
possibly build. That's
what I'm trying to do.
And so submillsec
and queries using
HN, small world,
whatever they call that,
that's the sort
of hyper-optimized
indexing. I also
want to use SIMD for
optimizing against
your CPU and GPU.
You might want to
make it easy. I want
to be able to deploy
this to different
environments,
probably embedded into
Neurotrader, into
Claude-flow, into
Argenticflow, and other
systems that I've built
that all need
something more than a
single SQLite database
running locally.
And I want this to be
fast, like Supabase
is really slow. I
want something that's
as fast as it could
possibly be for
all the things I just
showed you earlier.
So, and this is what
I built. You guys can
try this. It's a
little rough around the
edges, but you can
probably vibe it in shape.
Latency of 0.05, so
half a millisecond.
I've got throughput of 50
,000 queries per second.
and this is
just running on
low ****** code
spaces very low
memory and really
high recall
and so I can quantify
I can quantify it and
do all kinds of things
to it and I did the
same approach so I
built this using a
series of includes
like I built with the
Neurotrader so similarly
you can mix and match
these pieces to create
new sort of novel you
know integrations of
it. I also built this
to operate in the
actual browser itself.
You can operate
this completely high
-performance vector
built in Rust that are
compiled to a WebAssembly
WASM that can then
sit in a browser
and use the index DB
capabilities of the
HTML5 specification,
which allows you to
save local information
to the sort of person
viewing the page
and use that as a
high-speed vector that
learns directly from
your browser. And
that's 800k. It's
smaller than an image.
So yeah, built
all that. So
let's explore
this a little bit.
That's what we got here.
Let's go to crates.
It's always the most
exciting place to
look. So we've got
different crates. We've
got profiling. We
got the integration.
Oops.
Oh,
Google's trying to
do this. This better
not require a restart.
If Google makes
me restart my computer,
I'm going to freak
out. All right. No,
it looks like I'm
in any gravity as well.
All right. So here
we go. Getting a
bit of a delay here.
Google decided
to do something.
Let's look at
the readme here.
So this is, I'm going
to clean this up
a little bit, but this
is essentially the
WASM that allows
you to integrate the
possibly the most
performant VectorDB
in the market directly
in your browser.
And so you can run
this NPM install.
And yeah,
you've got, have
I published an NPM yet?
I might not have
published this to NPM yet.
I that's that is
something I need to check
quickly let's let's
do that npm I get I'll
do that here this
afternoon and if I
haven't roof vector
no I don't think I've
published that all right
I'll publish it but
for now you're you can
just go and get the
repo which is the roof
vector repo and just
point at that and
that'll that'll get you
up and going pretty
quick um I'm gonna pop
that into the text area
as well it's basically
one last thought
it's basically agent
db vector but hyper
optimized for enterprise
use yeah i'm just
curious so if we had a
a directory to say 50
files mixed files pdfs
word excel powerpoint
etc could we point
this at that and say
pull it all in absorb so
does it have the ability
to read the different
file types etc and
digest and throw it in
the in the vector db
well you'd you'd vibe
the the document ingestion
so you're going to
get a document parser
now i didn't bother
with that because they're
trivial to build but
the basically what
that's going to do is
it's going to parse
whatever source of data
you want it to vectorize
so in that scenario
like what am i pointed
at i had a project this
week for just as an
example they it's in
the legal space and
they had a a repository
of documents around 3
,000 documents. So it's
a mid-sized, smaller
sized legal tech startup.
And they had access to
all their case done.
And I basically pointed
my swarm at it and
said, learn everything
there is to know about
this business, how
it operates, how
successful it is,
what the psychological
characteristics
of opposing counsel
looks like. And
then use this vector
structure to give me all
the things that I
don't know. Find novel
new connections between
all that information.
And I let it go. And
then an hour or so
later, it's looked at
many, many thousands
and probably hundreds
or millions of
different variations.
And it's discovered all
these different ways
to optimize their
business, how when
they give suggestions,
when they meet a certain
lawyer that they've
interacted with
before, all that's
transcribed as part of
the court proceedings.
so the system is able
to then realize okay
based on that you should
probably negotiate
in this this a
particular standpoint and
actually if you if you
provide an offer before
you ever get the trial
you'll increase your
out your profitability
and the amount of
time it takes you to
get to the to a final
conclusion by x percent
that's what these
systems are doing they're
learning about the
nuance of your business
they're applying it
new and novel ways and
giving you a kind of
guide to how to
operate with it.
That's what these
databases are doing. So
they're learning,
right? So in this case,
I've got, here's, let's
go to the profile.
The profiler, you
know, this, this is
creating, this is
optimizing it. We've got,
you know, all the various
parts, but essentially
this entire thing can
work in your browser.
So, so if I'm going to
go and I could literally
just tell it to create
rather than having
to go to Supabase to
do the structure, I
can literally have it
load in my browser. And
then periodically I
might do a sync with a
Supabase, you know,
as it learns, but the
more the user uses my,
my, my web app or my
mobile app or whatever
it is, it's learning
on their particular habits
and then periodically
sending it back to
me. Now, I don't
necessarily even have to
send it, send it back.
Now, if I want the system
to be purely secure,
I can actually have
the system not, you
know, to sort of run
a kind of autonomously
from me itself. So, so
a lot of these services
are using LLM call
-ins, right? You have
your chat bots and you
have your other things.
So I can create a
loop that exists where
it doesn't actually
communicate to me as the,
the, the provider of
the service, but it
communicates sort of
in, you know, separately
from me in a combination
of the front end
and the, I don't on what
you want to call it,
the sort of LLM requests,
the chats and the
AI integration you see
on all these sites.
And that's what this
library is intending
to do. Do I have a
read me? There we go.
So essentially,
this, you include
the root, I haven't
published it yet, I
will this afternoon,
but maybe I have,
let me just check,
maybe I just didn't
publish the root,
let me check that
just for you guys.
You did, you did.
Okay.
yeah i got i think i
think i think i just
need to i just need
to double check this
stuff i don't think
it's fully published
but some of it's
published the crates
are definitely published
and essentially
all this crazy stuff
i'm telling you is
facilitated by having
a system capable of
learning and applying
those learnings in a
hyper uh a hyper graph
structure i'm gonna
pause for a moment.
There's a lot of
freaking information
I just dropped there.
Am I delusional today
or just blabbing?
I have one
clarification to
make here, or a question.
I remember you have
done, like, there
was a package
called fact that
was supposed to
replace rag factory.
sorry and then there
is a agent dv and
now we have this one so
what is the evolution
here or how what
is replacing what
or no none of my
things replace anything
um they're they're
augments to a core
right so i'm using
fact actually and and
you're you're probably
using it without
even knowing it if
you're using any of my
tools. So what this
does is allows me to
understand the
prompt caching within
the request to an
LLM. And essentially
what happens when you
make similar requests
to an LLM, rather
than it charging
you for making the
same request twice,
it essentially allows
you to make the same
request again. And that
creates a significant
improvement in terms
of time and cost of
making requests to
LLMs. Now, the problem
with that is they don't
exist for more than
usually a few minutes,
but with the right
techniques of sort of
poking it every now
and again, you can
actually keep it alive.
Now, by keeping these
caches alive, you
can greatly reduce the
cost because most of
the things people
are asking for are
generally the same. So
let's hypothetically
say you've got a
welcome message on your
homepage and you've got
10 different variants
of that and you want
some bit of change
so you get the LLM
to generate that text
on your homepage. Now,
if you don't invoke
the cash, you're
paying for that every
time someone visits
your homepage and it
gets really expensive.
If you do it using
this fact approach,
it'll just keep it
alive and every
subsequent request is free
and it happens in
almost instantaneously.
Now using that you can
create and structures
that are applied
to the prompt cache
similar to what I'm
showing you in a vector
that exists in this
area between the LLM and
the requests that are
being made to it that
kind of creates a
kind of caching of all
that information that
you can then request
more quickly and more
effectively. So you're
essentially running
a kind of pre-request
having all that
information available to
you and using that and
keeping that alive.
And then that provides
the ability to
structure it in ways
that are already known
to the system. For
example, if you have
two different
possibilities, one that's
correct and one that's
not, and you have a
way to measure what
is correct, you can
then have the cache in
place that basically
always gives you the
correct answer to
that problem that's
commonly asked. And
that sidesteps the
need to do any kind of
fine-tuning. It auto
-fine-tunes for you.
Taking that a step
further, I've got, and
this is something I
published the other day
called dspy.ts. This is
based on dspy Python,
but I re-implemented
it using AgentDB,
which does the self
-learning and the structures
of fact and all the
other things I've
been showing you today
to combine all these
into a system that
learns how to learn.
So in this case, it's
faster because I've
rebuilt the entire D
-SPY platform in Rust,
which you can get on
my crates. So it's like
orders of magnitude
faster than Python,
which is slow and
cumbersome. Then I package
that up again as a
WASM, which means you
can run it in your
browser or as a crate or
in the MPAI, blah,
blah, blah, which allows
you to run it in Node
really easily. So
lots of different ways
to consume it. So, in
this case, you've got,
you know, all these
modules for prediction,
chain of thought,
but this takes that
previous concept I was
describing and essentially
allows it to run,
allows it to sort of
self-run. It allows
it to learn by itself
and it's optimizing
the prompt. And for
that, all you need
to do is install it
this way, npm install
dspyts and just say,
do something crazy,
learn.
That's it.
And it'll learn and
I've included Onyx so
you can use local models
so it can learn and
optimize ****** local
CPU bound models and
it won't cost you a cent.
So you can literally
deploy infinite amount
of these agents with
no external model other
than some Onyx LLM
that doesn't really
cost anything and have
it learn over time
and just do its thing.
and your only cost would
be to your sandbox,
which are next
to nothing. Like
I did a 5,000
agent run the other
day and that
cost me 12 bucks.
So it's- How is
that learning
actually then, I guess,
transposed into
something meaningful?
Because we see the
agents are running
on your lab, on the
local infrastructure
and learning it.
But is the learning
captured somewhere
that can be
leveraged for other
projects as well? Like,
how does that
transition work? Yeah.
So there's a
federation component.
So the federation,
I built that into,
where we got,
oops, where we
at here? I gotta
find my right
screen. Sorry,
guys, one sec.
So in the agentic flow
system, and I think
I don't know what
happened in the screen
here, but in the
agentic flow system, Oh,
good. One sec, guys.
I'm going to fix this.
In agentic flow, there's
a federation system.
So the federation
system, I'm basically
just using Supabase
for this right now. I
might do a hosted
version of that crazy
Rue vector thing once
I do a little more
digging on that. But
what that basically
does is allows all the
different agents to
essentially collectively
work with each
other with a shared
sort of persistent
state of learning and
database using super
base i think i'm using
the pg vector but
you could literally
just use straight up
regular super base um
all right so this is
figure this is telling
me more about the
trading system just
explore it you know
the trade back the
trading ask your
questions and and just
again don't be dumb i
don't want you guys
to get in any trouble
so don't you know
if you don't if you
don't know what you're
doing you probably
shouldn't be starting
a finance company.
So don't go, don't,
don't, don't do
that if you don't,
don't have to. All
right. Now we're
going to go here.
We're going to go
and we're going to do
DSPs, dangerously
skip permissions.
And what we're going
to do now is we're
going to ask it, you
know, tell me about the
MPX agentic flow
federation capabilities.
I love the word federation.
Every time I see
it, I think I'm like,
you know, part of
Star Trek or something,
but uh yeah so that's
what that's what you're
doing and you can
do that just as easily
you know i i like
this interface but we
can go back to here
and we can and we can
do it in cloud web just
as easily so here we
go so this this this
is doing this is
running yeah it's still
struggling with the
api i don't know what's
going on with cloud
code web but you you're
you're probably
gonna you're probably
gonna have some problems
with the keys i don't
know it doesn't seem
to pick up keys well
i've got the keys in
there sometimes it
does and it works
really really well but
other other times it
just doesn't so um you
know anyway you so go
in here go to podcast
sometimes you need
to add a suffix to
the key and then
tell it to reference
the suffix key instead
oh that's a good
idea suffix key so
suffix key would be
like doing doing
something like this
I actually don't name
of the file to look
into. So it was the
same problem I had. But
then I said, look in that
environment file plot
code. I'm not using
environmental. I won't
use environmental
variable files for this.
Like I wouldn't. If
I were you guys, I
wouldn't either. I
don't know where this
is being stored, where
this is being run.
But, you know, the
likelihood of this
being exploited, let's
be honest, is high.
But in your
secrets, the drop
-down that you
have on the right
-hand side,
neuraltrader.inv,
you can... Oh, yeah.
I'm not saying that
that isn't... I'm
saying that's insecure,
too. I'm just saying,
like, one thing I can
do potentially to
make it slightly less
insecure would be not
to use a .env file.
But I hear you.
The code says it's
alpaca key and not API
key. Maybe that's...
Yeah, I didn't
look that closely.
But in this case,
so I'm not going
to do the echo
here, but I'm just
showing you what
to put in here.
So tell me about the
MPX capabilities.
That's it. I'm in
my Vivecast. I'm
just going to switch
to my Rue VNV.
And there we go.
So that's all
you have to do.
Now, I did a
robot one. What
do I have here?
I've got install
Neurotrader Vue API.
Yeah, so here we go. This
one basically
installed it.
yeah it's why don't you
put it on the in the
environment itself
every time you create
an environment you
can add a key yeah it
doesn't work half the
time that's what i'm
telling you it it it
sometimes works takes a
little finagling it
it definitely works if
you're using uh cloud
code straight up so
depending what you're
doing i if you're
comfortable this is this
is probably the way you
you want it you want
to go with doing it uh
for me like it it
it installed it that
created it but then you
had a command that you
i think didn't run
where you said can you
also explore npm and
neural trader brokers
why were you trying
to do that oh so it it
doesn't have everything
i'm only giving you
the core when when
you're going there you
need to uh you need to
give it you know all
all the pieces of of
the puzzle right so in
this case what i did
here because i'm in the
actual repo and you
can clone my repo i
haven't made it public
when i do you can clone
the repo and um or
you can just point it
at that readme file
that i was showing you
earlier which basically
does the same thing
um where did i put
that so yeah if you go
to npm i gotta go back
to wherever the heck
I was there uh mpm
neurotrader yeah and it
basically pointed at
this readme and on on
this readme you'll
see that it's and this
is included in the
package just tell it to
look at the uh the the
package or whatever
you've got all these
extra extra elements now
probably the most
interesting one is some
of the accounting
packages because it's most
it's it's actually
applicable pretty broadly
outside of this area.
I don't know why
it's not linked. I
guess I got to fix that.
But so this is the
accounting package.
So, and you can apply
this to pretty much
any corporate sort of
accounting, you know,
double check the
numbers, guys. I'm
vibing this stuff.
This, the accounting one
in particular, I vibed
it. So, you know,
double check everything.
Everything you do,
you should be double
checking. You guys
see how I'm building
this stuff. So So,
you know, when you're
using it, just double,
triple, quadruple,
check it. And I
would even suggest,
depending on if there's
a lot of money at
stake, get someone
who knows what they're
doing to review it,
needless to say.
But that said, I'm
using it, and there's
lots of people using
it. So, you know.
So, in your main package,
basically, which
is neural-trader,
I'm presuming it's got
everything. So that,
okay, so brokers
is part of Neural
Trader. So when you
say, okay, I understand.
Yeah, so this one's
really cool too.
This Neural Trader
E2B strategies,
this could probably
be its own thing.
This is
essentially a E2B,
a really complex E2B
deployment based on my
agentic flow and a few
other tools. But what
this does is allows
you to do really high
speed sort of swarms in
E2B and it's encrypted
end to end. So if
you're paranoid about
the data and potential
data loss, what this
does is uses these quantum
resistant algorithms
to basically store
the information while
it's in transit, in
stream, when it's saved
in the environment and
then accessed locally.
So it never leaves
any sort of quantum
resistant state of
encryption at any point,
which is, you know, to
all the reasons I was
mentioning on, you know,
for cloud code web.
super low latency one
you know we're talking
just crazy low latency
and when you're
deploying when you're
deploying the sort
of agents that need
to basically manage
your your actual
trading activities or
whatever this is creating
an ephemeral network
of agents and swarms
that are that are
constantly monitoring
data spawning new
new scenarios doing
trades doing analysis
understanding adapting
and it's kind of
continually running as
these kind of i call
it i like the word
ephemeral it just they
come and they go um
this can be applied to
anything it doesn't
need to necessarily only
be applied to the um
the trading it could
be applied to like
anything that involves
real-time information
right so lots of lots
of applications
there um this is also
using the my a Gentic
Jiu-Jitsu integration
that provides the
mechanism to have the
coordination for non
-blocking, like code-based
activities, inversion
control activities.
That's all in there.
Everything you see
in Neurotrader is
everything that I've
built up until last
week, I think is the
way to describe it.
So until your last
package is all included.
other than the root
vector which i created
yesterday and which
is which is okay a
direct result of all
this other **** yeah good
yeah so you're trying
to now you're trying
to replace super vector
now no well maybe
maybe but i bet i
get i give the whole
**** i'm trying to
replace like pg vector
and all the all the
sort of you know state
-of-the-art vector
databases that were state
-of-the-art last
week and i was like
basically what does the
you should see my original
prompt my prompt
was basically what
does a vector database
look like in 20 years
and how do i build
that today and how do
and how do i make that
the best performing
vector style database
for the things that
i need it for which
is outlined on rube.io
slash slash or slash
projects build me that
that's what i told it
to do and did you put
that into agentic flow
or claude flow what
would you put it into
uh well i started
with here i'll let's
let's go let's let's
let's go down memory
lane for a moment yeah
all right you guys go
take a look at my chat
history hopefully
nothing too embarrassing
in here all right we've
got yeah embarrassing
is if like if
you're the world's
biggest nerd um all right
high performance was
this it let's see no
this doesn't look like
it's it uh review the
agentic package high
speed okay this is
it okay so review mpm
agentic db package
and create detail plan
to i'm very redundant
in my to create uh
world's best high speed
low latency rust based
vector system optimized
for mpx agent db
i really wanted to know
about AgentDB. This
will be implemented
as both a crate using
the existing libraries
where possible and
NAP, NAPI, I'm going
to go with NAPI, RS,
along with browser-based
applications,
WASM and IndexDB.
Do deep research
using cutting-edge
vector design and
hypergraph structures.
Okay,
sorry guys, I was
only 10 years ahead
of what's possible
today. I was being
realistic, Like who
wants to go 20 years?
Detailed Spark
implementation design. I
love the fact that
the LLMs now know what
Spark is. I think of
all the things that got
indexed by, you know,
Claude and ChatGPT,
my Spark is the best.
This should be, it
should also include
native TypeScript, WASM,
fallback, folder,
less powerful systems.
Be complete,
benchmarks, optimize,
blah, blah, blah.
All right,
then it worked.
Look, an hour
and 21 minutes.
And it did all
kinds of research.
648 sources.
Yeah.
Lots and lots of
stuff. All right.
Then I came up with this.
Accrotexture,
three-layer design,
core vector optimization.
Oh, I built all
this, by the way.
Like everything
I showed you.
Not all of it. 95
% of it, anyway.
in um cloud code web
i think i might hit it
but where i built so
much stuff in here i
can't even keep track
of it all uh but yeah
i i essentially built
this in uh in cloud
code web and when it's
still free by the way
it's free until 23rd
now your number is
still 972 after one week
yeah yeah it's still
going i don't know
it's we're good but i
built yeah i built it
all and And then the
part where I needed
to, like, finish it off
and put it into crates,
I brought locally,
and then I finished it
off and tested it and
validated it. It's
alpha, I need to say.
But, like, classically,
it does work for me.
But, yeah, going back,
this is what. And then
I posted that just
so you want to go and
give it a spin or try
building it yourself.
If you go to
just root that.
And we'll see here.
Oh, these are...
I'm already on
to other things.
Here we go. Roof vector.
This is the...
This is... This is
what... This was
the original PRD.
Yeah.
We should use this
in the hackathon.
It'd be a great
use case for
it. We could
totally do... Okay.
Can I do... Let's do
that. I've got... an
idea let's go okay so
now we're gonna go we
have oh let's is this
gonna be cheating i'm
gonna cheat i don't care
uh we're we're gonna
we're gonna cheat a
little bit sorry sorry
rob i can't help myself
um we're gonna go
to agentics agentics
it's not cheating really
it's just it's pre
it's it's a pre uh pre
-show oh look no h
hackathon all right so i'm
gonna grab that and
i'm gonna go here and
i'm going to say how oh
can i get a roof vector
oh it's it's got spelt
right roof vector
all right we need
to optimize the roof
vector room vector
system to support
500 million concurrent
learning streams
using a Globally
Dispersed Logentic Flow.
Yeah, Logentic,
gotta spell disperse,
right? It's
easier to build
this stuff than
it is to type it.
Logentic Flow
Implementation using,
I don't think E2B
is up for that
challenge. Let's go
with Google Cloud Run.
Google Cloud Run.
We know we can
do it there.
You know,
create detailed
implementation
and benchmarking.
Oh,
we need to include
burst capabilities
when the French
make it to the World
Cup, but probably
lose to Argentina.
there we go uh roof i
have another question
actually so i was making
an all pocket account
and they don't actually
allow canada to
register and now in
order to get an api key
you have to register
through an account set
up two free factor and
then also prove that
you live in the united
states so how does
a canada person get an
api key then you use
a canadian uh go to
my there's a i've got
a canadian provider
uh let's see okay so
that's that's starting
oh okay you're asking
about which can i think
your question is which
is which can provider
do i have all right
i do have canadian
providers canadian trading
here we go did i nope
didn't implement it
okay so i do have a
i i've got that in uh
v1 so we're gonna go
to so my view i built
this six months ago
was python it was crazy
now i'm like i've
learned a lot b1 is more
battle tested because
i've got you know 70
customers using it um
all right so we go to
where the heck did i
put that under it's src
canadian trading uh
did i put a do a readme
in here information
implementation quest
trade looks like i'm
using quest trade in
canada are you gonna put
it on github i'm sorry
to us i am i gotta
do some final cleanup
but you you tell it
to use quest trade in
canada it'll i'm telling
you it'll figure itself
out just vibe it
you're good the trading
stuff's all built
it's just they're just
connectors all right
so this is so now what
i'm doing is i'm not
and i'm optimizing this
to creating a plan.
I didn't even give it
much guidance. It's
already got a structure,
so it'll likely just
follow that structure.
We'll let that
do its thing.
This is how we support
500 million users.
Now, without having to
spend a fortune on it.
And hopefully
that's not cheating.
I'll let everyone
use it. How's that?
All right. What
else we got here?
Got a few minutes
here. Let me check my
calendars. I just want
to make sure I don't
have anything at the
bottom of the hour.
How's everyone? Is
everyone keeping up
here? Is this another
crazy vibe casting
session or just
talking into the void?
This is great.
I unfortunately have a
call in seven minutes.
But so, you
know, someone got
it. I still have
to make a buck.
All right. Well, that
was all. covered a
lot of stuff here did any
any comments questions
suggestions whatever
rants okay for me
sorry no yeah no if
you can wrap it up the
yeah it's a quick
question i had uh i added
uh uh your goal um
to add to a skill in
claude and the goat
session and so what i'm
trying to figure out
is should i use what's
the difference
between the goat skill
added as a skill in
clod and research as a
trigger as a trigger
in in in clod should i
combine both or should
i just do one or the
other oh oh yeah here
let me show you that
quick um i'm sorry
wrong screen too many
screens it's got
five screens here but
basically i also have if
you use clock flow anyway
you you get you get
that skill so in uh
skills you've got oh
no i did as an agent
yeah so you made
a skill out of my
yes that's smart yeah
that that's that's
a really good way
to do it i should
totally include
that maybe i'll you
you should commit
it commit it to um
commit it to the clock
flow um project and
i'll include it and
you'll get a commit
on the project look
good look good in the
resume there we go all
right i'll do it yeah
so uh yes that so
what what to matt's
mentioning is basically
you can take the
agents and then create
skills that kind of
allow the system to
discover um the agents
which is a really good
way to do it um sorry
i i don't know if uh
jose you had a sorry
question i don't
think i got that no i
mean you have five
minutes so i I guess we
can wrap it up, how
the people can access
to the trading system
and that's it. MPX,
just MPX, Neural Trader.
And then you have
to connect, then
you have to connect
all of them.
Just ask it.
Okay. Ask it. It's
meant to be asked.
You're going to ask
the coding system, how
do I do a trade? How
do I deploy it? How
do I learn? how do i
how do i avoid making
you know making bad
decisions don't ask
it how to avoid losing
money it's going
to tell you dumb ****
just use your brain
reuse your brain it's
building right now
the strategy for crypto
paper trading using
alpaca configuration
so yeah include web
in europe you should
probably use alpha
advantage yeah it's a
better it's a better
tool yeah um yeah
it's but yeah you're
you're uh you're heading
down the right path
um i'm gonna do a
post here some at some
point introducing
it but i was kind of
wanted to get some
people to kind of hit
the tires on it a
little bit before i do a
big blast on it and
see what what i've
already got 6 000
downloads of it but i just
want to make sure
i'm not putting out
something that's got
a bunch of bugs so
that's why i'm slow
rolling it a little bit
um but you guys you
guys got a good little
overview so i think
you should get a
pretty good feel for
what it can do um yeah
it's it's pretty crazy
thank you man oh i
only built it yeah so
the the uh to robert's
point i think i only
built it for linux
distros so if you're
on mac or windows
don't bother i'll get
to it at some point
you you run it in you
got to run it in a
linux environment so
ubuntu or code spaces
or whatever but that
has to be linux for
now i'll i'll do the
uh i'll do the mac
bindings um at some
point so if you're
seeing if you're seeing
stubs that means you're
probably i would
guess mac or windows
I won't let it on a Mac,
just to be clear.
No. It won't
work on Mac, no.
Windows subsystems.
Oh, the NTMP bindings.
Robert, send me
a note and I'll
look into it.
It's exactly the
sort of stuff
I'm looking for.
Some of them
might be stubs.
There's some cleanup
work. There's a lot
of stuff in there.
So maybe create an
issue and I'll have
to get my repo live.
It's probably better
to enforce Linux
only so that people
are more inclined to
use remote servers
because I can already
see someone losing
a bunch of money
running it local level
in Windows or Mac.
Psychological, but
it might be the right
psychology. It's almost
like if you're smart
enough to use Linux,
you're probably
smart enough to use
this application. And I
don't mean to sound
like a ****, but yes.
that that that's
maybe uh some kind of
psychological prerequisite
and by the way i is
amazing how many people
voted that they they
should ban the use
of uh you know arabic
numerals in in school
on my linkedin post
that like anyway that
that was me uh you
know doing some classic
trolling but i can't
people actually voted
no to that anyway um
until next time um i
i really enjoy doing
these calls you guys
get a little sneak peek
in this what what's
coming and uh yeah um
tomorrow we're doing
the the second half
of this where you guys
get to show off what
you're doing um and
that'll be at 12 o'clock
et i probably need
to post it somewhere
but join the whatsapp
channel and you'll
you'll get the uh the
sneak peek of of what
what everyone else is
doing all right sounds
great uh stewart and
thank good to see you
too by the way stewart
um and uh everyone
else let me know what
you do and if you run
into problems which
you will it's freaking
beta just let me know
thank you all right
bye guys bye bye
bye thank you