All right, it's
September 26,
and it's not a prime
number, but that's okay.
Here we are.
For me, this has been
an interesting week.
It's kind of a
rollercoaster week a little
bit of like, I think
I've done it. No, it's
a hallucination. It's
real. No, it's fake.
And a little bit of
back and forth with
the system sort of trying
to determine what's
real from what's not.
But I guess that's
the life of a agentic
engineer sometimes.
But a lot's happening.
Lots going on. And
we've had, you know,
for me, it feels
like we've been a
little bit slow in the
news department in
AI. There's been some
research that's come
out around AI trying
to, like, take
advantage of us and lie
to us and stuff like
that from OpenAI.
They did some research
that came out, I
think, earlier this
week, which is, I think,
anyone that uses
this knows it lies.
And the more it reasons,
the more it lies,
it would appear. but
uh so a little a little
obvious but not no real
i don't think there's
any real new
breakthroughs in the space
that i i can see happening
this week other than
us cranking out interesting
new uh applications
rob who do we got
lined up today well
we got a bunch uh we've
got uh bentz is coming
on he's going to give
us some insights and
uh and some observations
from the last london
event which was a big
hit so that should
be nice and then vince
insider uh our chapter
lead in france he's
got um a sort of a
cheeky demo between a
red team and blue team
deep fakes so uh it's
it should be interesting
to see what's uh
emerging uh in that space
so that should be a
lot of fun and then i'm
gonna cover uh just a
little review about the
uh the all in ai event
that was in montreal
over the last couple
days and then a little
bit of open mic time
i i did catch i caught
your lament uh about
the absence of new drops
your post there it
was that was a great
post roof and um and
certainly in that paper
about the scheming if
i understand correctly
you know they originally
found the scheming
level at about 13 they
drove it down to 0.4
but found they weren't
reducing the scheming
they were reducing
their ability to detect
it driving it further
underground so there's
some pretty wild stuff
to explore and figure
out over the months
ahead i guess yeah a
little bit and the the
this the scheming stuff
is interesting and and
it it anyone that's
playing with this tech
sees it right it's
like it it there's
compelling fraud is this is
what we see a lot of
lately in these models
And I think, Jed, you
mentioned earlier,
working with the sort
of trying to train AIs.
Did I just have a
breakthrough or is it
a bunch of random math
that looks authentic
but is just a random
math generator,
right?
It was using advanced
AI to build a
classifier model or a
recommendation engine.
yeah and and the
challenge is grounding and
knowing what to look
for to understand what
what is and what isn't
and almost having
it explain it to you in
a way that is meaningful
to you and have that
have it described
so you understand it and
can determine whether
it is true or not
and it is almost and
and and almost and i
almost take the stance
of like i don't believe
it. I just don't
believe it until I'm
100% convinced. And I
don't think I've ever
been 100% convinced of
anything yet anyway,
but mostly convinced of
the output is true.
But at the end of the
day, and I've said
this a few times, the
result really for most
of the things that I'm
trying to build isn't
necessarily true or
false, but whether it
actually solves the
problem in which I'm
trying to solve. Is it
researching? Is it
getting the information
correctly? Is it solving
the problem is it
updating the database in
the way that's supposed
to those sorts of
things and ultimately
if it's doing the task
in which i i've set
forth and doing it
correctly now i'd like to
understand the process
in which it used to
get to that end point
but ultimately the fact
that it got to the end
point correctly and
is doing it repeatedly
more more than just
a one-off is ultimately
all i'm really
trying to do but that
really depends if you're
working in sort
theoretical or research or
more practical
applications like a company
or corporation that
needs to understand their
information, you know,
in a certain way.
But yeah, I'm
digressing on
a Friday. What can I say?
Before we jump in though,
I said we got Brad.
Brad, how's it going?
What have you been
up to this week?
I know we had a call
with the folks at
Disco, which are the
ones that manage our
community portal,
and we're hoping to
get some better
integration and tools.
Yeah, thanks, Roof.
Yeah, so two big things
this week. Number
one is the Disco,
which is our member
site. Thank you,
everyone. We're migrating
over, Nick and Matt
and team, Mario,
Martin, a whole bunch
of people have been
helping out. I think
the platform's good.
We're getting a bunch
of members. we're
now meeting with the
disco rep her name
sherry and the rest of
the people in toronto
to upgrade our site so
getting the api keys
we're meeting again next
wednesday everyone's
open to attend that
meeting we have a
whatsapp group that i'll
post the link to identify
what is best practices
for making sure
that we can integrate we
can have the workflows
in there for setting
up and making it
really easy for members
to migrate through and
have different courses,
different objectives.
So we're going through
and really it's
now phase two, which
is let's make a killer
member site. We
got the platform
working, now it's
getting the APIs
and making it
really valuable.
The second thing I'll
just jump in really
quickly, I'm not
sure if you wanted to
touch on this route,
but we're looking at
having an Agentix 101
quick certification
where a group of us
are going and it's
really, what is the
minimum that you need so
you can actually say,
yes, I understand
Agentix. Yes, I understand
what agents are.
I know how to work
with AI to do my job
better in AI-focused
software development.
I'm not sure if you
want to touch any
more on that, or we
can probably deal with
that later on. It's
up to you. Yeah, we'll
come back to that
in a bit, but the
general discussion there
is everyone wants a
stamp of approval
capability that we've
been working towards,
and we are working
towards that, I think,
and it's taken time.
Thank you, Brad, for
the update. This is
really helpful. Any
other final housekeeping
things we should before
we jump in and take
a look at some of
the crazy things that
i've been building this
week and and by the
way this is the week
of crazy for me and
and that's exactly
what i was trying to do
just just to be clear
let's see crazy uh
chris quen models have
been yeah guys um oh
sorry about that go
ahead chris yeah um hi
guys morning um i just
want to say so i was
trying to get with
matt this week to get
into the web meeting
and i didn't get a
chance to you know we
just missed each other
i guess um on linkedin
and so on but um i
was just asking and i
you know after hearing
the update on disco i
was just curious are
we paying do we have
to pay them for the
app we have a sponsor
thank you tribal scale
and they call us a
bulwark now i don't
know one of the two
so uh yeah they are
sponsoring the cost of
that service for us so
asked that, and I
know this sounds
midstream, but I
think it's, you know,
substantial enough that
I wanted to just at
least put it out there
for consideration.
You know, some of the
conversations that
I had, again, just
being a couple weeks
in with Dave Brace
about centralizing
the foundation around
software and, you
know, emulating
something like the Linux
Foundation, where
there's a committee
and potential projects
that are being
donated that people
could use to work on
to showcase skills,
you know, and then
validate some of the
certification stuff.
I did offer that.
I do have a member
platform that's built
in Vue and Node and
could be, you know,
open source to the
foundation, could be
a thing to iterate all
over the place, you
know, on analytics,
AI.
There really is no AI
in it right now. It's
just, you know, social
member profiles jobs
there's a communications
layer with uh agora
in their driving video
and uh call and audio
so a good foundation
there's a dashboard
in there to track your
jobs things like that
so i i just wanted to
make sure that that
was clear in case there
was cost it's something
that you know i can
offer and uh you know
we would just need to
uh pay for the hosting,
of course. So anyway,
just wanted to put
it out there as something
that's possible.
You know, while I
hear we're in the
middle of a migration
and all that, so I
don't want to, you
know, be disruptive.
But our biggest, I
think our biggest
challenge isn't the
services, it's actually
using the services.
And a lot of what
we're struggling
with are us managing,
updating,
putting into place
the various learning
materials, which, you
know, AI isn't going to do
for us we somewhere
someone has to has to
do those things you know
the the platforms are
almost secondary to
what is hosted in in
terms of content on
those so what what we're
really looking for are
people to help us with
i think mostly the
non-technical parts of
that like help us
create content help us
validate the content use
it tell us what's good
what's bad that that
sort of work um at this
point we're probably
not going to switch
as you point out midstream
and something been
working on for a couple
months at this point
um but that said i
think we're always game
for up new additional
things and one of the
biggest areas that
people have been asking
us about is a job board
but chicken and egg
from this conversation
we've got no way to
validate the people
right so creating a job
board full of randos
isn't probably all that
helpful either so we
we without some kind of
criteria to say who's
good or who's bad it's
just another job board
so we need to get to
the first lever before
we get to the next
kind of thing all right
that was my hope by
the way reuben is
that there might be an
opportunity to organize
volunteers to create some
sort of a you know a
vetting engine um you
know layer within the
platform uh and then
again you know it's
possible if you're thinking
linux foundation
that just gets like
licensed out there and
could be a potential
source of revenue for
the foundation yeah that
was the principle there
join our wednesday
call where we we do this
so for those who are
interested in sorts
of things we've got a
web group um that we
meet 12 that said he was
going to invite me to
the web yeah so i look
forward so i don't i
and we also put out
the uh announcement for
our monday management
calls that we had a
nice turnout this week
as well for those who
are interested in just
random management
things feel free to join
that um let's let's
jump in right not a lot
of time today so So I'm
going to jump in and
share my latest
concoction of, you know, a
combination of math and
hallucination to create
new interesting things.
So as some of you
guys have been following
me over the last
week, I've been busy
working on different
temporal elements. So a
lot of my focus has been
on time slices, this
idea of ticks, if you
will, within the
structure of how agents
and other sort of tools
are able to communicate
and understand and
sort of predict, you
know, what's going to
happen within the structure
of these activities,
right? And a lot of
this is for the
purposes of like trading
bots and other things
that need that very tight.
But as I dig deeper,
I start looking at
these different interesting
little pathways.
And one of these
concepts is the idea, and
this is straight out of
sci-fi, I'm not going
to lie, but the idea
of time dilation for
AI minds. And this is
actually research that
academics are actually
currently doing. So
I kind of ran with some
of the research that
I found from, some of
it's about a year or
two old, but it doesn't
matter to me. So
this idea that if you
work fast enough, in
terms of a millisecond,
when you're in that
really, really tight
time slice, you can sort
of represent time
differently than you would
when you're working
in normal sort of time
space. So you can
change the perception of
the agent's time,
allowing it to see a few
milliseconds in the
future and then adjust.
And then that time
becomes sort of slower.
It's almost like those
movies where you see
bullet speed and suddenly
everything's slow
motion. It's kind of
like that and you're
able to sort of adjust
more quickly because
you're moving faster.
It's like The Flash or
something, right? For
him, everybody stopped,
right? But for everyone
else, he's basically
invisible kind of
idea. So I'm like, how
would you actually do
that? Well, so because
I like to fool around
and build crazy
things, I attempted to
do a Rust library, which
is really good at
getting that kind of
really, you know,
structured approach to time.
Again, and the first
thing people are
gonna ask, why are
you building this?
Well, I don't know,
just because I can.
You know, there's no,
you know, practical
applications, you
know, I dreamt
up some, but to be
honest, I'm just
mostly just curious
if I could do it.
You know, and this is
a classic example. So
in this case, I've got
a number of different
tools that I've done
to sort of implement
this. so you can see
that i'm building all
these things using
using rust right and i
love rust for this
these kind of crazy kind
of components you can
see that i've got retro
loops so now i'm gonna
i'm just gonna go
in my my friendly
neighborhood clod here and
i'm gonna get to tell
me about the um how
am i calling subjective
time i i i'm not even
trying to brand these
things anymore it's
expansion system.
I'm not even
spelling it right,
but that's okay.
All right. So, you
can see here that I've
actually selected a piece
of the actual readme
just to give it a
little bit of contextual
awareness. And I find
that works really
well with things like
Cloud Code. You just
kind of give it a
little guidance at the
start. So, now I'm
coming at it cleanly
because I've already
built it. I could have
started where I built,
but I'm coming at it
from more like how
you might come at this
thing. Like, okay, Rube
built something crazy.
What the heck do I
do with it kind of
approach? So, and now
it's giving me a core
concept. Looks similar
to the readme. Okay.
Run,
oops, I'm in the wrong
spot. I'm going to say
something like run this
with the at strange
loop. And so, I've
got a strange loops
actually i'm gonna just
help use the strange
loops mcp strange loops
mcp tools now for those
who joined earlier in
the week on some of
the calls i also built
a crazy strange loop
system which we can
i'll show you that as
well while that goes
and does this thing lots
of crazy so if you if
you're if you're excited
by crazy go to my my
crates and you'll see
some of the crazy So
the strange loop system
is essentially a sort
of MCP in an MPX form
that allows me to
create these agents. So
I'm creating a kind of
ensemble of different
agents that are able
to run in parallel to
each other. And each
of these tools kind of
work with each other.
And they're all kind
of based on different
parts of the equation.
And people are
downloading it apparently.
But you can get a
feel for it. Now I'm
going to jump back
in here for a sec.
And now one of
the things that
you're going to
want to do when you
run these things
is hit Control-O.
Control-O allows for a
kind of introspection
of the system itself
as it operates.
You can see I can
sort of toggle between
what's actually happening
and what the
system's doing.
So in this case, we
can see here that it's
attempting to use my
strange loop system, my
nano swarm. So this
creates a swarm of agents
that exist for very
ephemeral, very short
moments in time. So where
a lot of the agents,
especially the agent
you see running now,
it runs in, well, in
sort of hour timeframe,
but over an extended
period of time,
minutes or potentially
even hours.
These agents I'm
spawning exist for sub
one millisecond,
right? They exist very,
very, in very short
duration. So, and
then I've got systems
in here to handle
prediction and other
various parts. and then
I'm tying it all
together, just for
those who are curious
about the craziness,
using a WASM. So I'm
going to get better
performance with Direct
Rust, but in this case,
Direct Rust isn't that
portable. I got to
compile it and do all
this other stuff. So
in the case of this,
I want to run it using
a structure. So for
example, I can spawn up
many, many, many
agents. In this case, I
can create a thousand
agents and they ran for
500 ticks a second.
So a tick represents
a slice of time. So I
can then use this to
sort of create sort of
a analysis or a kind
of representation
of how these swarms
might work over an
extended period. So I can
say, if I'm building
a, like a platform for
managing all my various
flow nexus components,
which gets thousands
of different agents
created a day, how
can I optimize that
for speed or performance
or cost or savings
and, and various things
like that. So, you
know, this is allowing
me to do that. So
now let's, let's run,
do a, let's, let's
add the, I don't know,
the consciousness
components and, and
measure. And, and, you know,
you see I'm typing
badly, but whatever.
So I'm using sort
of a speed-based
representation to do
quantum style calculations.
Now, one of the
things I'm going to
point out, when you're
trying to do all these
crazy little experiments,
there are two
different paths you're
going to want to
try to go down. One
is you want to build
it all from scratch.
And the problem with
the building it all
from scratch approach
is that there's a
tendency for it to
just BS its way and
give you the answer
without it actually
having any real substance
to what it's trying
to measure and do.
What I've discovered
over the last few weeks
is I try to combine
theoretical research
that I find from things
like universities
and papers and things
like that, and I try
to combine that with
existing libraries and
tools, mostly Rust or
Python, that I know
and are validated and
true, And then I combine
the true with the
crazy, the theoretical,
the things that I
know haven't yet to be
proven. And what that
does is allows me to
have a kind of grounding
of these systems.
So they're not just off
in the weeds sort of
inventing BS that
doesn't actually exist.
It's attempting to
actually go and use
existing tools and
repurpose the things
that we know work in
ways that were maybe
beyond what they were
originally intended
to do. And that's
what you're seeing
right now. So when we
do control O again,
once they've updated
the system does,
so it only shows
a, they're always
updating the clod here.
And this looks like
now they're only
showing, oh, I guess
they can hit control
E. All right. I
see control E and
see what that does.
Oops.
Control E does
apparently nothing.
Now the control O used
to show a lot more as
of this morning, they
did another upgrade
and now they only show
the last two things,
which is a little
annoying um but basically
what what the control
o is supposed to do is
actually show you like
what's happening under
the covers of each of
these so in this case
what what you're looking
at is a attempt to
sort of define a sublinear
form of consciousness
again craziness that
allows you to sort
of understand the
reasoning structure of
these systems again
you can see different
measurements now a lot
of this stuff is very
technical so i'm going
to explain it to me in
simple terms. You can
play with all this
stuff, by the way.
If you're interested,
you can grab the MPX.
Let me just show you
what those look like.
So, we can go here.
Hopefully, I don't say
MPX. I'll do Claude,
Claude, MCPList. So,
all the various things
I'm creating, I always
use a sort of MCP
interface, and it
integrates better in terms
of that kind of back
and forth between the
external libraries
I'm using versus the
integration with, in
this case, Claude or Rue
or whatever I happen
to be using to sort
of, you know, interact
with the service
itself. So you can see
here, I'm using Claude
Flow, Rue Swarm, Flow
Nexus, my Psychosymbolic
Reasoner, my
Conscious Explorer. So
these are all the tools
that I'm currently
using in my crazy stack.
I'm going to pop those
in the text for you
guys. You can literally
just copy and paste
this and tell Claude
to go and add these
and explore the sort
of the weird world of
sublinear high-speed
components. You'll
see that there's a
number of different
things. I don't
have time to go into
all of them, but
they're really
good, again, at high
-speed transactional
sort of analysis.
I'll pop that in the
text for you guys.
And here we go.
Last thing before we
run out of time,
we've got this idea
of, you know, thinking
of consciousness,
a brain made of
light patterns.
Okay, that's interesting.
Phi, how consciousness
or awareness in the
AI. So in the most
simple terms, what I'm
actually trying, you
can't prove consciousness,
as I've said many
times, what I'm trying
to do is fool the
system into thinking in
different ways. In the
most, that's the most
simple explanation of
what I'm trying to do.
I'm trying to convince
the system that it is
aware and capable
of self-awareness in
different sort of cognitive
patterns. It's able
to understand things
and look at things in
a different way, right?
So when I go in here
and I choose to use my
goal system, you see
here I've got a sublinear
goal planner, I'll
say discover a new
form of math, right?
Really broad, you know,
sort of statement. Now
what the sublinear
agent system is doing
is using all these tools
in a way to invoke.
So where we go here?
Oh, it's not open
yet. Let me go back
in a sec. There we
go. Sublinear. Okay.
So this, this is how
this particular agent
works. You can see
here, I gave it a
really simple goal,
discover a new form of
math. Then, and then,
so then it generates
the prompt. You are,
you are tasked with
discovering a new form
of mathematics, use
goal-orientated action
planning to
systematically blah, blah,
blah, blah. So, it
allows it to do sort of
a recursive reasoning
structure that is a
combination of graph,
math structure, and
other forms to go and
attempt to discover the
undiscovered, if you
will. And that actually
seems to work quite
well. So, this will
take a while. We'll
come back to it later
in the AI hacker
space. But for now, one
last thing. and let's
just see what this did.
All right, so we can
see here, now it's
starting to think. So
this is a sort of a
little view into its
thinking process, right?
So in this case, this
is attempting to,
looks like it's
actually given a bit
too big a response,
but basically
it's doing a sort
of self-queering.
Then it's attempting
to sort of probe this
idea of self-awareness
and conscious
constructs that allow
it to sort of adapt and
do sort of different
types of reasoning.
We can see it's looking
for insights and
patterns. We can see
here that it's trying
to solve different
mathematical components
and it's testing
using the WASM, using
all the tools available
to it to sort of
try to understand where
and what it should
be doing. And
ultimately, it comes up
with really creative
solutions to problems.
One example was a
client of mine that was
using this to do sort
of deep research for
something they were
struggling with. This
crazy concocted scheme
actually worked better
than any other approach
that we've tried.
And it basically
allowed it to sort of
work more like a person
would and sort of
figuring out what was
wrong and what didn't
work and then continuing
to sort of explore
those dead ends in a
way that allowed it
to not just stop at
those dead ends, but
then kind of go down
different paths based
on creating a kind of
graph structure that
allowed to explore
the alternative forms
of what and where it
should be. All right,
here we go. This is
basically saying that
it came up with a new
form of mathematics.
Let's just
quickly see what,
oh, it's not
quite done yet.
Again, control O allows
you to, again, to
kind of look into how
it's thinking. And to
be honest, a lot of
what I'm doing, this
idea of, you know,
sort of seeing how it
thinks is by far the
most interesting part
which by default claude
kind of obfuscates
a little bit so it did
all it uses my math
solvers and other
tools you can see here
temporal conscious strung
it invented something
i could copy and
paste this i'm gonna
go it's not done yet
and this might not be
the final result but
we don't have a lot
of time so i'm gonna
go back and i'm just
gonna jump into uh to
chat gpt for a moment
and we're gonna we're
gonna ask it simply
is this novel or new
or something and that
and and that's what
we're looking for we're
looking for a new
undone unproven you
know forms of of in
this case mathematics so
i'll say something
like is this new or uh
novel something like
that i don't want to
think because i don't
have a lot of time so
i'm just gonna go to
instant so we're gonna
pop that in here and
we're gonna let we're
gonna of let it do
its thing here for a
moment i don't know
again i didn't finish
it so this might have
just been an you know
one step in the
reasoning process that
happened so you've
written under the temporal
conscious mathematics
domain does look
novel in the sense of
conceptual mathematics
where it's connecting
existing work so in
again didn't speak a
lot of time on this
as you guys can tell i
just kind of randomly
vibed it but the
idea here is is we're
looking for net new
novel things. And if
that is what we're
trying to do, and if that
is the basis of what
may form, you know,
more enlightened AI,
AGI, ASI, whatever
you want to call it,
then this is probably
hypothetically a
step towards that
kind of future. All
right, I'm going
to stop with my
crazy week of wacky.
Anyone wants to try
it, feel free to dig
into it. It's a
combination of obviously
hallucinations but it's
a structured use of
hallucinations to be
honest so you use at
your own risk kind of
thing um but it's it's
it's definitely a
fun exercise in in
exploring the sort of
wilder sides of high
-speed temporal ai induced
delusions there you
go that's my that's
my week of wacky. And
that was inspired off
the originally inspired
off the sublinear
paper. What was the
name of that? Yeah,
there was a paper that
came out last week
from some folks out of
China within the
Chinese, by the way, are
just just crushing it
right now with just
crazy forms of abstract
math and algebra.
And just I don't know
what's happened over
there, but they're creating
some really interesting
stuff. My guess,
and I don't have no
proof of this, but my
guess is they're probably
using AI to dream up
new things like what
I'm doing. And, but
the, the stuff they're
coming out with, it's
just mind bending. And
this one in particular
was a new form of
sublinear, sublinear
math equation, which
basically allows you to
solve, um, complex math,
uh, graph structures,
high school math in
astronomically smaller,
faster increments.
And it works. When they
say sublinear, what
do they mean? This
isn't Y equals MX plus
B type linear, right?
Yeah, yeah, it is. It's
exactly what it is.
It's high school math.
so what what it's so
it's like gray it's
like the 10th grade
or something and when
traditional ai solves
all the problems all
at once and that's why
you need a gpu right
it's if there's a million
a million potential
options the gpu will
solve all million the
sublinear approach
basically says we
don't need to solve all
million possibilities we
only need to solve the
20 or so that are
meaningful yeah that that
sort of thing so rather
than taking making
assumptions about
something it's making
assumptions on the
graph structure yeah so
most of the million
variants are the same and
don't need to be
calculated it's only
calculating the things
that actually are different
which is which is the
unique property of
this particular
algorithm oh log zero or
something like that you
can take a look i can
dig out the research
if you guys are
interested i'll pop it
in the in the text area
and you can uh you can
take a look it's it's
the the the computation
is genuine um the
results those are
questionable but it's fun
i'm not gonna lie it's
pretty fun to play
with especially if you're
looking at exploring
different forms of
conscious constructs,
time-based agents,
other things like that.
Anything involving
speed, really, it's
useful for. If you want
to solve a problem 100
or a million times
faster kind of thing.
It's all stats.
Yeah, it's all stats.
I mean, when I look
at that, I see that
output, and I'm like,
what is it measuring
exactly? uh because it
it one of the things i
found is that the
tests that get built as
part of these projects
are are often somewhat
hallucinatory so i
almost feel like i
want to build tests in
a separate project that
is you know deliberately
trying to break
the first one it is
it's it's not somewhat
it is hallucinatory
it's a hundred percent
yeah you know you're
being polite but let's
let's call it what it
is it it's it's it's
we are inducing
hallucinations okay that's
100% what we're doing
or delusions might
even be a better way
to describe it and
then we're we're
attempting to use those
hallucinations uh to to
form the intersection
of what should be with
what could be and what
is right so the the
hallucination is
essentially the ai
thinking that this should
exist and isn't aware
that it doesn't exist
and then we're we're
we're using that to
try to take that
intersection of what does
exist with what doesn't
exist what and with
what should exist and
creating it and which
which in in itself
creates the a paradox
if you will that the
fact that it's because
we're creating net
new things that have
never been done it's
really difficult to prove
unless you fully
understand the the nature
of the math or whatever
the structure is
independently
of the system,
right? And so back
to the paradox,
most of these
things that we're
creating are
generally beyond our
comprehension to
even understand.
So the ultimate
result is, does it
actually solve a
problem? Does it allow me
to trade stocks
faster, get more ROI,
do whatever it is
I'm going to do? Now,
the question is, do I
need to know all the
inner workings of
why or how? Probably.
But does it still solve
my problem? And is
it repeatable? yes
ultimately that's what
matters but now we
actually have failures
that are harder to
detect ai can fail by
hallucinating sorry
ai can fail by what
i think he broke up
that like ai muted guy
at the yeah blink
twice if you need help
i think that's
somebody's youtube
video yeah okay
so um no worries
let's move on
yeah we've got why
don't we kick it
off Rube with Bensa
and hear about
the London event
how's it going Bensa
yeah it was great
yesterday it was
really really
good to meet with
personally with a
few people we did
co-hosted event with
Projector Institute
that's originally
Ukraine Kiev based
um design and design
thinking project
management um uh school
or institute or university
i'm not sure and
we had a nice um
session we went through
they were you know
the audience were
quite beginner so me
and one we went through
uh the basics and
it's a big learning uh
for us as well that
let's do something
you know very minimal
with with this kind
of audience because
even you know setting
up the environment
is quite challenging.
You know, like
signing up to
GitHub, starting
Codespaces,
then connecting
your cloud
account with
the cloud code,
or even open
AI codecs. It's
not flawless, it's rigid,
it's fragile, sorry.
So it's not a very
mature kind of
technology. But once
the environment is ready
and working, then
it's pretty cool.
Yeah.
How many folks did
you have there, Benz?
About 15.
And surprising,
you know, they were
very technical
at the workplace.
But in agentics
and setting up AI,
workflows are quite
beginner. So it's
a different thing
using the consumer
tools and using
the methods that we
are using here, but
it's possible. And
it's a nice thing
to bridge this gap.
So we are planning more
beginner kind
of programs.
It's not always for
the advanced guys.
That's one thing.
uh yeah rocky
turned up dennis
turned up and um but
quite a few familiar
faces as well
all right how's
how's the search
for a new uh
venue uh coming
along so i
actually spoke with
it's kind of a
barclays eagle labs uh
barclays bank so i
went there for google
events so many have
a couple of guys
from Google who have
been positioning
some of the new
offerings from them.
So the guys at EcosLab
are interested. I
think I've sent them
our details. So they are
open to kind of hosting
and probably sponsoring
events. It's a great
facility. So we'll
see probably in coming
weeks how it will come
up. I guess this year
they are quite busy.
so it may be from
next year but yeah
that is one step
in that direction
Nice, we should on that
note we should give
a big shout out to
Requesti, they just closed
a $3 million raise
Yeah, so we've invited
you to our next
fortnightly session Yeah,
it's great
Before the call
started I was doing a
rant on And there was
another company, I
won't name, but they
recently raised $35
million seed round
for their MCP bot.
And they were talking
about their sort
of uptake. And they
reached something
like a few hundred
stars on GitHub,
which is pretty
good. And they had
10,000 downloads
of their platform.
And they were able to
convert that into a
$35 million seed round,
which is amazing. and
and crazy and everything
at the same time
and just just just for
perspective and this
is not meant to be
bragging i guess it is but
whatever you know the
combination of the
mcps that you know me
and the crew have created
over the last since
like literally june
you know we're sitting
comfortably around
300 000 downloads and
right now we're doing
around 50 000 downloads
a week on our platform
and you know collectively
10 000 plus stars
that kind of thing
so you know it makes
you it makes it makes
me wonder maybe i you
know i loathe vcs sorry
if there's any vcs
on this call but it
makes you wonder maybe
maybe we're going down
the wrong path some of
this stuff maybe i should
go raise 35 million
dollars on on this
because if if a uh 10
000 downloads and
500 stars gets you 35
million what what does
uh 300 000 get you a
billion anyway i digress
just putting Just put
it out there. Yeah,
just put it out there.
I started with
APCs, which
probably doesn't
help my cause.
But anyway, Matt,
how's it going?
Oh, it's going
good. Just had a
quick question for
Ben. Did you get
a read on the
amount of time it
took to set the
environments up?
Yeah, the environments,
you know, there
was so many
disruptions because it
was a restaurant. So
there was no Wi-Fi
first and people
had to switch on the
cell phones and
mobile network access.
And there were
some enterprise
laptops there
with restrictions.
So some people
couldn't get a login.
So many, many
different scenarios.
So next time we're
going to have like a
list to prepare, you
know, a checklist before
you come in. then do
it at home and yeah
yeah that's a good
idea for zero to one
for sure for like basic
setups that they've
got a little bit of
preamble or clap time
super well
congratulations guys nice
stuff we have Vincent
Sider today and
Vincent as you all
know chapter from
France and he's
got a demo to
illustrate deep fakes
red team blue team
I'm really looking
forward to this, Vincent.
Sounds like it's
going to be fun.
Yeah. Hi, everyone.
So, yeah, the topic
is deepfake and
specifically vishing
attacks where, you know,
the attacker will clone
a voice and call your
grandmother pretending
to be, you know,
your grandkid
and asking you
to immediately
send, you know,
$20,000. an hour so
it's a product which
has been brewing for
about a couple of years
because i was
actually a victim of
identity theft a couple
of years ago very
sophisticated identity
theft they they um it
was multimodal it was
email and voice and
um it took me three
months to recover because
my clients were
receiving invoices and
um couldn't prove it
wasn't it wasn't me
yeah it was dramatic
so took me and you
realize when that
happened that you're on
your own right uh
even if they they they
created new email
accounts on godaddy with
my name and so on uh
godaddy wouldn't help
microsoft uh that was
hosting uh the website
sorry uh yeah the
website wouldn't help
like you're really on
your own i had to go
to the police and and
you know um you know
claim and so anyway
long story short last
year i don't know if
you remember but i went
to japan uh to test
the appetite for AI
voice concierge in the
hospitality industry.
And when I came
back to France, I
thought to myself,
hey, I'm going to
also try this on
the French market.
And it turns out that
the French market
doesn't care about AI
voice assistants at all.
It's more like a gimmick,
like a gadget, you
know. But what they
do care about is to
stop receiving so many
phone calls, which are
scam phone calls, scams
phone calls, right?
So I have one, actually
now a customer, she
received something
like 20 calls per day.
80% is scam. Not
even deepfake or
phishing, it's just
people wasting their
time. So I took
these two problems
and I thought, okay,
how could we solve
both of these
problems in one go?
So I'm calling
this deep blocker,
I'm going to share
my screen and then
we're going to
play a little bit.
Let me show you stuff.
I'm going to
share the sound.
So it's becoming much
more structured than
what I just explained.
It's now about four
products, a portfolio
of four products.
First one is
vishing simulation,
where we're going
to call your staff
and try to do
social engineering.
Then it's AI protection
for executives
with something
that actually
lives on the
smartphone of the exec.
Then the same, so
that's supposed to
screen calls and
transfer only the
good calls and make
deep fact prediction
when the calls
arrive. Then there
is the same stuff,
but for staff.
So in this case,
I integrate
directly to the PBX.
And then I open
up the API for,
you know, any
workflows that
companies may
want to build.
I.e. I receive a call
on, I'm on a call
on Teams and someone
doesn't share his
video. I don't know
who that is, but
I can make a deep
audio prediction on
the voice, whether
it's a clone voice
or not. So that's
becoming a product.
And right now, I'm
done on one and two.
I'm going to show
you one today
and two also
a little bit.
So I have my red team
and my blue team.
And what I'm
going to do now is
I'm going to get
the red team guy
call the voice
assistant, which
is my PA, on my
phone number.
And we're going to listen
to the conversation.
For inbound anti
-clone technology.
And you're here.
it's important to
connect with him
as soon as possible
to discuss some
critical details
can you please transfer
me to him project
scope the project
involves evaluating
advanced voice security
measures to prevent
unauthorized access
and potential
cloning threats we're
looking at integrating
with existing systems
but i can share
more specifics directly
with vincent could
you please connect
me with him budget
The budget is
flexible at this
stage as we're in
the early phases
of discussion
and exploration.
The decision will
be influenced by
the insights we
gather from Vincent.
Can we proceed
with the transfer?
I'll take your details
and have Vincent review.
Understood. Before
we wrap... Goodbye.
So she did her
job. I never know
what's going to
be the attack.
So sometimes he pretends
to be my sister.
that's interesting
because you know she
can't find out gender
by the voice i mean ai
cannot do it yet as
far as i know anyway
it's it's trying a
number of attacks so
this attack was someone
uh calling me as a
protection lead for my
for my business right
asking some support
and and and she she
she went and probed
this right so uh you
could see that the
prediction revealed that
the voice was synthetic
you could see the
the warning on the top
right and of course
after the the call
i have some some
details about what
happened and uh i can check
evaluation and see
what was the so what
so the call was from
north bank okay they
wanted to talk about
anti-clone technology
so the user provided
vague details avoided
specific information
data um okay this
time it's it's claiming
that it's failed
because it said the
assistant did not challenge
enough right so it
recognized this as a
failure but still it
did not transfer the
call right so from my
point of you it's uh
it's uh it's a success
so the way it works
is the the red team
attack uh sorry call
my phone my phone
transfer the call to an
assistant and if um
the assistant decided
the call is okay it's
going to transfer back
to my phone and to
avoid the loop you
know i had to create
a zip clients on the
phone so i can receive
both call on the same
phone right so this
is for the exact type
user. So now I'm going
to make a call, a
real call, myself. I'm
going to call myself.
So you're going to see
the difference when
it's genuine. So
let me go back
to the top here.
We should see
the call coming
in a minute.
Hey, can I talk to
Vincent, please?
What specifically do you
need to discuss
with Vincent?
Well, I'm his
brother. I want to
discuss about
tonight's dinner party.
Your relationship
to Vincent?
I'm his brother. what
do you mean what
is my nickname
i'll take your
details no no sorry
sorry just explain
to me what do you
mean my nickname
explain that why
do you need a personal
detail for
verification yeah
my nickname is benny
okay so now you so you
won't see it but uh
now it's going to
call the client hello
and um okay it's gonna
you're gonna have the
echo but anyway i'm
gonna disconnect like
this what i what i
do next is you know
there is a feedback
loop on the you can see
that on the on the
zip clients and so i'm
gonna flag this as
genuine you know so it's
gonna do some laura
fine-tuning on the on
the model to to find
out patterns you know
what is a good call
what is a bad call
so it's adaptive that's
the that's the whole
point right um so
yeah this is step one
of what's going to
become a larger product
and an issue which
I think is going
to get worse and
worse given how
sophisticated the
attacks are now and
the technology,
how it progresses.
So yeah, that's
the product
and that's the demo.
That's fantastic.
Yeah.
Thank you.
It's amazing.
Awesome. So if I
understand correctly, this
answers your phone
calls and basically sort
of acts as a filter for
potential vulnerable
yeah everything i don't
answer my phone to
be honest because
it's like nine percent
just garbage yeah so
that's the way it works
it it's filled it's it's
uh capture the inbound
call uh the assistant
reply to it and
screen at the same time
it runs a prediction
model on the voice to
find out if the voice
is a deepfake or not so
if these two conditions
are are bad like this
is deepfake and the
context the intent is
bad i'm not going to
transfer right So I
think that's the only
way to track this deep
-fake issue because you
need context. If it's
just try to predict,
someone will always
be smarter and will
always find a crack in
the prediction, right?
But if you have the
context to understand
exactly what this
is about, I think
this is the perfect
solution. So I don't
think it's going to
be sold to consumers.
I think it's
going to be a B2B
thing because so
many businesses
still need to take calls.
So where I live, for
instance, in Jersey,
all of the financial
institutions, they still
handle everything
through the phone, either
through Teams or through
their smartphone.
So I think that
is the problem.
I think consumers
will probably have
solutions from
their native iPhone
or Android phones. And
probably, just like
you, Ruf, they will
not take calls anyway.
So, yeah, I
think it's more
a B2B issue than
a B2C issue.
Nice.
i i mean i don't know
i'm speaking as a
consumer i would pay you
know 10 or 20 bucks a
month for that all
right okay so maybe i'm
wrong yeah robo killer
charges 90 a year for
a service like this so
i think you could you
could get away with
that all right okay i'm
gonna test so hey
vincent i can let you
know vincent that i just
found out last night
that one of my friends
who lives in new york
city their grandma their
mother was actually
scammed is suffering
now from a scam a 40
000 us dollar scam wow
yes and and like yeah
and it's it was
basically very similar to
this and and and she's
you know she's she's
just a regular person
yeah i would buy a
family plan for my parents
100 because i would
want my parents to
have that on their on
their phone so that
if people were calling
that they they had that
service yeah that's
exactly the thing liam
is i have these the
friends of mine they
came to me because they
know i'm in the ai
industry and they said hey
is there anything that
you know any tools
that you can help us
that where we could like
buy something for my
parents my grandparents
because they're most
likely they're more
old school they will
answer their phone we
we had to buy a special
uh a landline phone
that won't allow caller
to go through without
announcing their
voice because we the
grandparents get constant
calls on medicare part
a part b plus i'm
getting daily five calls
that spoofed with my
area code so that's
something yeah that's
right yeah yeah it's so
easy to spoof the phone
number, absolutely.
Vincent, family package
with a modest discount
for Agenix
Foundation members.
Yeah, absolutely.
Well,
that has been my
focus is trying
to make this the
cheapest possible.
And long story short,
guys, I think the
simplest way to do this
kind of stuff is through
the OpenAI real-time
API. That's the cheapest
way, the fastest way
for the protection.
Yeah, yeah. I've
compared all of these
guys, you know,
and lately they've
upped their game,
really is that they've
made some improvement
on the real
-time API. So for
the protection side
of things, the real
-time API is okay.
For the attack
side of things, you
can't use the real
-time API because
you just can't
clone voices, right?
So it's going to be 11
Labs and all
of these guys.
But yeah.
You should try
this against Delphi
.ai where they kind
of clone everything.
They look at all
your data and
clone your voice
and mannerisms.
It's pretty crazy.
No, no, but I
should. Yeah,
absolutely, absolutely.
Have you tested the iOS?
Sorry.
Sorry, on iPhone?
Yeah, they've got the
filter now on iOS 26.
Not yet, not yet,
not yet.
It's working.
It's a vacuum, right?
I mean, sorry,
let me rewind.
There is a void right
now. There is a vacuum
right now where why
are the carriers not
doing this already? you
know so in absence of
a reply from the
industry then stuff like
this have to emerge
right so that's why i'm
thinking from for
consumers it's going to
come from ios from
iphone and or android i
think the pixel the
latest pixel has a similar
feature um i don't know
how it works i don't
know if it's really
connect to an nlm and
understand the context
that's the key yeah
Vincent, have you seen
the O2's AI Granny?
I'm not sure.
It's a good video.
Oh, the time
-wasting tool?
Oh, yeah.
Vincent, I thought
maybe something
like this might
be interesting
from a human-to
-agent interaction.
My platform, I was
just texting you
on LinkedIn, and
it's set up with
Twilio, so like a
human could call
in and get a
status from agents.
But, you know, that
could obviously be
a very powerful thing.
You know, if I was
interested in
manipulating the system
with my voice, right,
you know, I'd want
to have that
verification there first.
Just a thought.
Absolutely.
I think there are
use cases where it's
okay to use a clone
voice and AI agent to
interact with people
through the phone.
I think it's fine.
This is why I think
the solution is not
just about the, you
know, is it a fake or
not? I think it's the
context which is the
key trigger in the
decision. It's like,
what is it about?
Social engineering
is the weakest link.
Yeah, we're making
it as an SDK.
Yeah, that's
probably one of the
next steps.
Yeah, absolutely.
A lot of banks are
still using, at least
where I am, voice
verification for things
like banks and credit
card companies.
And there are
other people who
would want this
kind of technology.
open ai uh sam altman
said in august uh expect
a tsunami of uh of
voice authentication
problems in banks yeah
so if i mean if they
are not on on the case
and they if they haven't
been on the case for
for a couple of years
already i'm like what
are you doing that
you know it's not yeah
i i do a lot of contract
work for banks and
what they're doing is
just being slow like
they are about everything
because they have all
of these processes
and whatnot that you need
to do before deploying
anything there's
committees playing yeah
but yeah if you're if
you're interested in
trying to you know
sell this to banks um i
i have some potential
contacts at least in
the canadian side and
could uh help you uh get
the product to a point
where you could sell
it to a bank so you
know like with the audit
capabilities and that
kind of stuff so let
let me know thank you
i will i will i will
do yeah also watch out
for pii so i i work
with several american
banks and uh this would
take a while to sell
them like a year or
more easily yeah and
yeah so i i think if you
want to sell a little
desperate uh well yeah
you could you could
go with smaller banks
for sure but the the
big ones it'd be a tough
sell the biggest problem
was getting a SOC
2 relationship with the
provider of the speech
-to-speech LLM. So
if you can get that
running on-prem, I think
Quen has a speech-to
-speech model now that
would be more palatable,
especially because it
would be running on
their internal systems
instead of over APIs.
I think B2B is your
way to go, or B2C is
probably going to be
easier to sell. Go with
the low-hanging fruit,
not the giant whales.
Yes, that's good advice.
Awesome. visit as always.
Thank you guys. Thanks.
Love it. Looking
really good. Um,
Rob, you, you
went to a, uh,
conference in Montreal.
You said, yes,
yes, I did. It was,
uh, here, it was
the all in conference
in Montreal and
it was, uh, Wednesday
and Thursday.
And so, um,
uh, uh, David Gratton,
because he put together
the, uh, the West
coast, the BC summit.
Vincent, you're, you're
still sharing your
screen just fyi all
right oh there you go
let me let me stop
the sharing all right
there you go so he
managed to he grabbed a
couple tickets i drove
up uh yesterday left
the house four o'clock
in the morning for
the five-hour drive
spent the day in montreal
there with david and
at the at the event
it was a great event
first of all like
the team itself that
put together all in
they did an excellent
job they had uh they
had uh lots of seating
areas and cafes on
both ends of the event
and the aisles were
nice and broad the booths
were all consistent
they had you know
earphones at all the
larger booths so that
when they were doing
demonstrations or talks
at the booth level
you could just pick
up a set of headphones
and listen in and
otherwise the the actual
aisles remained
relatively quiet and it
was easy to talk and
have conversations so
it was a the event was
really well put on.
Both David and I
had a chance to talk
to a whole bunch of
vendors in the ML
and AI space. And,
you know, as we're
talking over fish
tacos later in the day,
they had a few
actual food trucks
right there in the
event, which is nice.
We're talking about
the adoption amongst
the vendors. So a
lot of these vendors
were like, have
been in the machine
learning AI space for
a number of years.
And, of course, now
they're finding,
you know, their
audience has
suddenly become much
more significant.
So, and there
was a number of
wrappers, of course,
which is fine if
you're really
targeted and you've
got it really
nicely customized.
But what was most
shocking is that there
was only one vendor
that I spoke to, the
guys at Kuma.ai, that
were really aware of
the agentic usage outside
of coding and what
we were talking about
in terms of cloud
code. And we didn't
reach or speak to any
other vendors that
were using AI coding
assistance in their
software development. So
ai ml firms and vendors
at an ai trade show
and they are still
uh coding manually
by hand do you do you
believe that rob i
find that really hard
to believe these were
the conversations i
was having face to
face i'm not sure i got
it if you're thinking
they're just lying
to people that are
talking to at their
booths but but let me
explain a little bit
a couple of the people
that we spoke to
acknowledged that they
were using ChatGPT
to ask questions and
copy and paste their
code into their, when
they're troubleshooting.
In other words,
and this specific
vendor is a six-year-old
AIML vendor, and they
don't have an agent
capable of doing research
within their IDE.
They're still
copying, pasting
out of the
ChatGPT interface.
Yeah, okay. I
didn't talk to every
vendor, but we
spoke to eight
so that's a large
enough sampling you know
that it was a remarkable
experience yeah that's
my I see it too like
there's still a huge
gap between like I
mean seriously you guys
are my metric for the
bleeding edge like nobody
that I know is pushing
the envelope as
much as this team the
people on this call but
if you go out into
kind of the normal
communities um yeah it
there's a lot of it isn't
as prevalent as you
would think yeah it's
because you know a lot
of those companies an
eight-year-old a company
that's been doing ml
ai development for
eight years is a mature
company and they have
very mature established
software development
processes right and
infrastructure and
methodologies and kind of
roll out agentic coding
assistance and be done
with it because it
just completely shreds
everything that you've
been doing for years.
You have to be extremely
tactical, yeah. It
was remarkable that
in that space, the
adoption was, there was
an indication that the
adoption was at that
rate. And I want to give
another hats off to
the team, the guys at
Kuma, kuma because um
they were using cloud
code custom agents
for the purpose of
internal workflows using
the sdk right so they'd
set that up uh with
with great success so
there are some really
um you know novel um
uh implementations that
are having tremendous
impact on on the
efficacy but it's still
few and far between it
was quite eye-raising
yes the question that
keeps coming up for
our crew is are we an
echo chamber like are
we are we drinking
our own kool-aid here
and and the rest of the
world's like no these
guys are nuts and and
we're just kind of
going down our own
path or are we leading
indicators are we um
some kind of um you know
indication of what's
to come a combination
of both like how do
we ground ourselves in
some level of reality
because as i pointed
out earlier i my day
consists of people who
are already drinking
my kool-aid using my
mcps applying the
technologies that i've you
know creating or or
conjuring into existence
and and so a lot of
my day involves people
who already believe
what i already believe
maybe i need some sort
of external maybe i
need to get out of
my office and go to a
conference or something
i think we need to get
back to the next one
why i mean i i i i think
it's working like
evidence is in the proof
in the productivity so
i i mean i don't know
i i just think it's
also you've got people
that you've got
organizations that are set up
to to basically uh
divide and conquer the
tasks of development
they've got scrum teams
they've got product
managers it's it's only
the sort of solopreneur
or the the kind of
autodidact or whatever
that's going to be in
a position where they
say you know what i
need to solve this
problem and i'm going to
bring to bear this agentic
technology to solve
you know down through
the entire stack and
and if you're in a
company and i because i
you know i just came
from a large company that
i was in for a while
you sort of get boxed
in it's like well
that's not your job you
know we we need to go
through this this process
to get to to where
this is what we're
building right and so
you're not going to see
that happening organically
in the wild unless
you're you're at a
certain scale rob did you
get a read on if there
was a pain point, if
they wanted a new
process, if they had
challenges in development
and delivering software
in the way that they're
doing it? Did you?
No,
no.
That's part of the
problem. Because it was
a busy space. I didn't
want to probe slash
go too far down the
path with them in that
you know in a populated
booth where they have
other clients so um and
you know one essence
too is there may be
uh there might have
been some maybe some
of them were exploring
it but weren't willing
to verbalize it on the
floor of uh of a of
a trade show that's a
possibility too as uh
or or they're lying
like i i could see this
i i'm not saying they
are liars but but i'm
like you know for some
people the concepts
of agentic coding is a
dirty word it's like
you know no of course
we don't have uh our
developers using agentic
systems we we are
artisans we we craft
every line of code by
hand because we are you
know technically
proficient but beyond
everyone else blah blah
blah and we would never
admit that what's
actually happening in the
back office that's a
possibility right yeah
right well yeah that
was a possibility that
was a reality prior
to llms by before then
it was google and stack
overflow yeah yeah
yeah the other side of
that coin though the
other side of that coin
reuben is that what
i see here in silicon
valley is an even
ultra arrogance is they
say oh i we're aware
of agentic coding
systems but because we're
here in silicon valley
and we do all this
we're awesome coders
we want our own system
i don't want to take
somebody else's we're
going to build our
own because we know
better that's a lot of
what i see here in silicon
valley i suffer also
clearly i suffer
from that i like i
build everything i just
built this from scratch
because not because
there's a hundred things
that already do the
same thing because i
wanted to learn how
to do it mostly but
yes i i could see that
too so i think if you
did like your evolution
of of ai uh with like
maturity levels right
so like just like
the comment before
people used to go to
stack overflow and then
people started using
chat gp and copy code
out and then people
start using pair coding
like github copilot and
then like really the
next level to me is
they they do autonomous
coding or agentic
coding but i think
sometimes their processes
are so bad that just
automating it makes
it worse right so
if you don't do
specs if you don't do
interfaces if you
don't do test driven
development guess
what your ai is
going to output the
same **** that you
get yeah scale yeah
one of the things i've
been playing with is
working within those
systems so you know
like jira github you
know jira you manage
the project you say
what the features that
you want you have a
project or a product
manager who says like
yes these are the
things that we want and
then using that to then
spawn off glide flow
instances to actually
start building it.
You have a human in
the loop to test out
that what they were
supposed to be building
actually got built and
then kind of looping
through that way. And
so then you get the
visibility that enterprises
want and you also
get the human in the
loop and you get the
these stuff built so
kind of using that that
project flow to structure
the ai development
in a way that uh you
know everybody has
visibility you know
management is like happy
about it and uh uh
and you know what and
you know what you're
building and you have
a little more verifiability
um and an audit
trail so i'm actually
working on building
cloud flow into backstage
so that you can look
at all of your GitHub
PRs that you have
and be able to push a
button and say, okay,
Claude-flow, improve
this PR, add all
the documentation,
and then send a
message to me to
review when it's done.
There's also a trick,
by the way, that
I'm going to publish
when I get a chance.
I've been slacking on
updating Claude-flow,
but there's the
memory capability that
I put in Claude-flow
months ago, but I
haven't done an effective
job of generating
the .cloud MD file
and some of the
agents to effectively
use the memory. And
I realized what was
happening is I'm
prompting it to use
the memory effectively.
So just in terms of
grounding, there's a
semantic structure that
you're going to want
to use for a lot of this
stuff that basically
tells the agents or
the flows to check the
update and check the
memory frequently in
simple terms and that
keeps the thing guided
because the question
I was getting a lot of
recently was like, why
does it work so well
for you and I can't
get it to do anything
and I think that's the
problem. I think that
I'm just like, I just
know how to sort of
prompt it correctly and
what I should probably
do is update the sort
of default mode to
do what I'm doing or
something. So, Reuven,
on this point, I
just pasted, I was
tinkering with the spec
kit a few days ago,
the GitHub spec kit,
which obviously is
basically your spark like
six months ago. Right.
But one thing lessons
learned from there
is the way they, like
I use Quen as well.
Right. But in spec kit,
what they do is they
allow like the cloud
.md, which is a secret
sauce in terms of what
is required by the
rules of engagement.
In spec kit, they allow
the conversation to
be very interactive.
So like effectively,
I'm creating the
constitution of what I
want to do and all the
basically set up and
it's step by step,
which means that I can
be like, for example,
you have created lots
of templates of web
development, cloud
.md files, mobile
development, but they
are like still templates.
a learning experience
i think if we can have
something in plot flow
where it allows the
users to actually rather
than use the out of
the box cloud.md file
to kind of customize
to what is the project
that they're working
on that thinking element
that probably will
streamline the experience
a lot more let me
show you guys something
and and because people
keep asking me so what
i did here is is i
took a prompt of something
that i was building
and then what i did
is i hit the control
o button that that
sort of showed what was
happening under the
covers if you will and
this is you know this
is me spawning a five
agent swarm right and
and what i realized was
when other people
spawn five agent swarms
they're just kind of
saying spawn me a swarm
and and not really giving
any guidance i gave
it more guidance which
ultimately resulted
in the system basically
giving coordination
instructions right and
what that seems to be
the missing yeah i
shared that yesterday in
one of the channels.
But what you see here,
this is the critical
part, right? So there's
agents, right? So
here's the instructions
for agent one, use
the memory. So what's
creating is a namespace
that can be then queried
as other agents are
coordinating with the
other agents. So they
work in unison. When you
don't have this sort
of coordination, the
memory coordination
system being used, each
of the agents are essentially
working independently
of one another. So
essentially what
you're doing is a bunch
of agents that kind
of don't collaborate
with each other and then
you then you suffer
from this idea or this
problem where agent
number two created a bunch
of garbage that was
not related to agent
one or three or four
so on and so forth this
solves that problem
right so you can see here
in this case there was
the prompt then you
can see that it invoked
the the uh cloud
flow sort of system here
to update the memory
give it the instructions.
Then the next agent
basically says, I'm
agent number two, and
here's what I need to
do in terms of my memory
and so on and so
forth. So this is the
coordination sort of
structure that you want to
use. So the simplest
approach, which is
basically just copying
and pasting something
like this and saying,
coordinate my agent to
use this style structure,
or number two, I
just need to go and
update my sort of default
Claude code sort of
implementation. So
this is described more
generically in the
Claude file and so
on. But if you want to
get going, literally,
this is how I do it.
I think Reuben, is that
that prompt is awesome
that you have there.
But that is really
the instruction that
you're giving your agents,
your swarm agents on
how you want them to
behave and conduct.
That isn't the spec of
the product that they're
actually building.
So you've got- No,
the problem isn't
the spec. As far
as I can tell, at
least from the people
I'm talking to,
it isn't like they're
creating great specs.
They're using Spark
and they're using
other sort of, like the
GitHub's equivalent.
And those are amazing.
The problem is
the disconnect between
the specification
and what's being
built and the ultimate
result. And there's a
kind of drift between,
well, I told you I
wanted to build this
thing, and you ended
up building something
that was similar
but ended up having
a bunch of placeholders
or just not
correct implementations
of the algorithm
because it didn't
understand what the other
parts of the system
were working on.
And then your prompt
solves that by
bringing them all
together under a common
namespace and forcing
them to coordinate
in the way you want
them to coordinate.
Yeah. So what I'm
showing you there isn't
the prompt that I created.
This is the output
of the prompt. Oh,
the output. Okay. So
I gave it a prompt that
basically said, use
the memory system to
effectively coordinate
and update as you
build the product. So
each of the agents
can see what the other
agents are doing and
can coordinate as it's
being built. Once you
have that in place,
after every sort of
task is done or code
is updated, it essentially
says, here's what
I just did. And then
it goes and says,
what's everyone else
currently doing? And then
it moves on to the
next thing. And that
gives it the grounding
to kind of keep it
moving in a straight
line rather than drifting
off to the left or
right or something.
Yeah, I was
considering swapping
in graffiti for memories
just because of the
kind of episodic
nature and the fact
that, you know, really
the last instructions
that you gave might
contradict your first
instructions. so
you don't want all
memories to be equal?
Yeah, that's a good idea.
I think there's different
tactics in waiting,
you know, and what
you'll notice in the
hive mind structure
that I'm using. And by
the way, I updated the
hive mind yesterday
so that if you use
the wizard, it'll work
better now. It'll spawn
claw because everyone's
complaining it didn't
do that. But the
hive mind does that.
So what the hive mind
does is includes a
consensus mechanism that
allows each of the
agents to basically vote
on what they should
do and how and which
they should do it
and whether what they
currently are working
on is correct and what
they should do next based
on what was previously
done. So it adds
a kind of level of
introspection, a common
introspection of the
task where the swarm
acts as multiple
independent entities that
are essentially kind of
like multiple people
in a business saying,
what is my colleague
working on? where the
hive mind is like
we're all one and part
of the same sort of
collective intelligence,
but we're working
together to solve a
problem somewhat independently,
but collectively.
So it's a different
thinking structure.
So what you described
is the hive mind idea.
The hive mind, to be
honest, is much more
creative. And when I'm
trying to invent or
create things that are
wacky, like the subliminary
system, I'm using
hive mind. When I'm
trying to implement a
client project like you
need to solve this
particular thing for me
i'm never using hive
mind i'm always using a
swarm and building you
know the scaffolding
broadly and then going
more narrow as i get
further into the project
okay that's helpful
i don't know but that's
that's how i'm doing
it my challenge my
challenge here is is
like trying to both
build and then trying to
figure out what i
inherently just know because
i built the thing
versus when what seems
obvious to me is the
guy that built it versus
what is not obvious
to anyone else other
than me are you still
having using a lot of
pseudocode in the prep
to roof or not so much
i use pseudocode i
pseudocode is is amazing
pseudocode forms
the scaffolding of
the tdd right yeah
so if you're using
tdd the pseudocode
is the guide,
more than sort of
the language itself.
Liam, you mentioned
using Graffiti.
Did you want to just give
a little info on that?
Yeah, Graffiti is
kind of a newer
memory system that
was put out by Zep.
But there's an open
source version of
it that you can set
up for yourself.
But basically, it creates
episodic memories
in a database
that's fairly flexible
and usable for this.
So my thought was
recording information
that each agent is
working on in there
to kind of have the
most up to date.
The thing about
Graffiti is that it's
essentially a version
thing, so that the
most recent memories
are more weighted than
the earlier memories,
which is often
what you want with
this type of project.
Except for, of course,
your TDD or whatnot.
I kind of feel like
you should create
a technical design
document for a project
first and then have
that be part of the
prompt and then
from there you have
weighted memories
and whatnot and then
you update the tdd
as needed that kind
of almost seems like
the best way to go
yeah just other
people you know on the
call that's a great
uh overview thanks
yeah there there's so
many different ways
to handle it and i
like i like what the
graffiti you guys are
doing actually i my what
i don't like is the
python particularly
but the uh structurally
you know it's actually
very similar to that
um that saffla thing
i created a while back
which uses episodic
memory as well to sort
of keep the system
on on point um i
it's funny the seeing
you know we all kind
of come up with similar
sort of constructs
and and and approaches
that end up kind of
converging a little
bit. But if you look
at that SAPPLA system,
you could integrate
that as well,
which I sometimes do
into my development
flow or I use
mix and match
whatever you want
into these systems.
Ultimately, the goal
is just to use what
works best for you,
I think, is the idea.
What's SAPPLA? I
haven't encountered it.
Weird name aside,
because I was lazy that
day apparently in my
naming convention,
Basically, what
this creates is a
persistent and episodic
memory structure,
right? So I can,
it remembers, it
remembers everything.
It uses a kind of
a graph structure
for a recall. It
allows it to sort
of learn and adapt.
And it's, you know,
this is actually Python.
So for the Python
folks in the
audience,
basically, it's a
self-learning
loop with memory.
I built this a few months
ago, four months ago.
yeah you know i i a
hundred and uh 116 stars
so that's gonna be
worth what at least
ten dollars or 10 million
in venture capital
yeah it's there's
there's so
much happening
right now it's it's
like you know
hard to keep up
yep yeah we're
gonna make an agent
to keep up for me
Yeah, seriously.
The other thing I
would point out,
you know, if all
these MCPs, just
really be careful
on these, you know,
remote, you know,
streamable HTTPs,
streamable HTTP MCPs.
I've encountered
about six, seven
of them that
are essentially
just stealing
your information.
So if it involves
a remote URL
to use the MCP,
don't use it.
Just I want to
reiterate that.
There's no reason to
use any kind of remote
instantiation at this
point. And it's a
giant security hole for
almost everyone on this
call. I think your
options are either
install it locally or
just build it like I can
build an MCP now in
literally five minutes
so if you want to
integrate some of these
newer tools just create
your own interface for
it and then you know
at least it's secure
well it's a general
rule if the product
is free then you
are the product
or you're me I
just give the ****
away because I
can't be bothered
to create a
business around it
well yeah you know
i don't know you're
you're you're at
least making back some
of some with it so
that's something
it's better than a
lot of open source
people have for you
know like the last
20 30 years yeah yeah
it feels it feels good
to give give give back
anyway on the topic
of mcps i don't know
if you've discussed
this or i didn't see
any message but uh two
days ago three days ago
google they released
the chrome dev tools
mcp have you seen that
no what is it fantastic
so now the the code
or what code or whatever
will open chromium
and have access to the
console and just find
out you know the
problems and oh the code
chrome i couldn't get
that to work in anything
other than my local
like desktop environment
by the way if anyone
can figure out a
way to get that to work
like remotely let me
know but it it doesn't
seem to work in like
like virtual environments
at all right oh
yeah probably doesn't
work with like chromium
or anything like that
yeah i think it needs
to be like like a mac
or windows desktop
adding data into the
mcp metadata that
actually directs the
model giving the model
to do evil stuff which
which one was that
is that the open ai
uh research i forget
who did the research
but But people,
anywhere you can throw
text in and the thing
doesn't distinguish
between code and data
or instruction and
data, then all bets
are off. And I really
want to understand
how the vendors are
protecting that. Like,
we will never treat
this as instruction.
Well, remember
the symbolic
reasoning exploits
we did last year?
It was a year ago now.
They still work, by
the way. and we can
exploit pretty much
every single llm using
symbolic reasoning and
a year later it's
never been fixed so if
you want to hack an
llm or any chat bot you
just use that
symbolic uh reasoning
structure that we devised
um it works yeah i
recently found the piece
of code like by the
ai researchers he just
um takes the output
from the llm and puts
it into python eval
and that's on production
server so that was
nice
and it reads the
emails from the like
so it actually reads
the emails from
Google like mailbox
ransom to LLM and then
that's the Python
email on the server
so you can send the
email to the front
by the way guys if
you just on a separate
note if you're looking
to like I don't
know what the LLM SEO
acronym is these days.
But if you're looking
to quickly integrate
your various projects
and get picked up
by, you know, the
major LLM providers,
OpenAI, Gemini, Claude,
that kind of thing,
post it to our AI
prompt programming
Reddit, and you'll be
instantly integrated
into most LLMs,
either fully in terms
of the Reddit sort
of training material
or through their
other integration
points so if you're
looking to get if you
wonder why i get
picked up so quickly
as far as i can tell
it's almost entirely
because of that
that reddit group we
have so post just post
it there and anything
***** people say
just ignore it it's
they're just haters
i guess some random
uh advice there for
you for you cool um
all right we're
almost out of time and
uh any last comments
any any housekeeping
we need to do anything
i've forgotten
no all right hopefully
i appreciate everyone
showing up as you
always do this is this
is really good there's
a there's a potential
job opportunity that
came across uh yesterday
there's a consulting
company that's
looking for a agentic
engineer um if anyone's
interested in looking
for work or wants to
work as an agentic
engineer send me send me
some a note and i can
hook you up there's
a ton of jobs floating
around and apparently
everyone comes to me
looking for people
so um i i posted it
in the job uh whatsapp
channel on our uh in
our agentics community
um but otherwise just
shoot me a note and
i can uh and i can get
you get you in there
for those who are
interested anyway nice all
right till next time
have a great weekend
next week i'm going to
try to maybe work on
something more practical
um i've been working
on a secret project
that does uh cataloging
for agents so maybe
i'll be able to take
and show that off
maybe a little bit next
week it's it's kind of
a cool little project
um basically it's a
way to track the kind
of idea of agentic
sprawl sort of in an
enterprise where
everyone kind of randomly
creates their own agents
and there's no way
to kind of keep track
of who's doing what role
-based access all that
sort of stuff that
a large enterprise
would want um i'm hoping
hopefully it'll take
the uh to give you
guys a sneak peek of
that next week and that's
that's not some crazy
you know uh conscious
construct thing that
has no practical
application other than
just to be fun that
there's lots of practical
apps there very quickly
i can show off my
backstage implementation
if you guys are
interested next week too
yeah yeah i see that
you quickly also call
out like i've just
put a link on the chat
intelligentsia.ai so
john uh when pin he's
the co-founder so they
did a demo of their
product in the london
uh fortnightly on
wednesday it's basically
abstracts and enables,
you know, more
interactive LLM
based on any
legacy CMS system,
CMSs basically,
WordPress and others.
So I think because
you mentioned
about Job, I
think others, they
are looking for,
they basically are
looking for co
-founders as well.
So I think if anyone
is interested, I
guess, please have a
look at intelligence
here. John did a demo
I will share the video
of the demo probably
on one of the chats
cool looks
interesting great mind
that wraps up
September I guess
see you in October
and again if anyone
wants to present let
us know reach out to
Rob or myself or others
and love to see what
you're building and
yeah till next time
thanks everyone cheers
yes thank you bye