The 25th tomorrow. Yeah,
and then we got some open mic time to explore all the new,
uh, uh, elements coming out.
Anybody, um, checked out, I think it's called Apex.
The, uh, productivity mark?
I was gonna say not the video game. No,
not the video game. It's the productivity benchmark that's literally measured.
During how well, uh, LLMs are doing at,
uh, absorbing or taking on knowledge work roles.
Ready for boating. Yeah.
It's all the stuff gains, gains momentum,
the, the ripples in the water are growing stronger.
It's talking about caching and stuff. It's just like. Like a telemetry.
Now I'm trying the ability to fully, uh,
duplicate knowledge workers, uh,
roles, uh, like jobs. Okay.
Yeah. There's a, the benchmarks called,
uh, I think it's called. Yeah.
A PEX. A, uh, AI productivity index.
And it gets really curious because all the leading models are on both on
par with each other. Which seems to indicate to me it's a usage pattern.
Versus. Yeah, I mean, I mean, I have the most success by launching agents
and, and having them like be domain experts in certain things.
So curious as to like how that,
how that, I didn't, I didn't know the models were doing that.
Alright guys, we're at, we're at the, we're at the top of the hour.
So, uh, I'm gonna get, I'm gonna get things rolling here.
Let me just get the, the, the stream live.
Umm. Mm.
I'm to your shop.
Beginning of it anyway. Anyway.
Uh, as well because we've only got three out of four. So,
uh, we've got Adam from Plotly who's going to be joining us and giving
us a demo and then Vincent,
our ambassador of the, of the Paris chapter.
It's going to take some time. There's some really interesting stuff that's shaping up,
uh, for the Paris chapter next week,
next Friday. Um, so he's going to give us a rundown.
On that. And then also, uh, like to invite,
uh, Dragan, he's got his, uh,
his, uh, chapters event coming up shortly as well.
So we'll hear from some of those guys.
And it's, uh, it's a fascinating week.
There's all kinds of, um,
uh, folks from the community that are building on some of your tools.
Agency be in such roof. So it'd be really neat.
To see some of those, uh, maybe next Friday,
see some demos of, uh,
where some of these extrapolations and experiments are,
are going. What kinds of tools with tools are being built.
So interesting stuff. Uh,
awesome. And I, I see, I, I see Nick with his baseball,
uh, what, what, he's, he's, he's our day.
Yeah, he's, he's our local sports guy. Everyone's bugging me yesterday because I.
I've brought up the, the, the, the world series here that's happening in Toronto
tonight. And apparently I'm, I'm like the worst baseball,
uh, announcer ever. So Nick,
what, what do we have to look forward to in, in,
on the baseball front here? He's,
he's the expert. He's, he's the way referred to.
Well, we've got, we've got a, uh,
a young rookie trade savage, uh,
starting for the Blue Jays tonight. He started in. Low A ball at the
beginning of the year and traveled to about five different professional leagues,
uh, to, to start game one here.
Uh, you know, the biggest baseball game in,
in the, in the country, uh, for 30 year,
over 30 years. So it's quite a story.
Well, it's exciting. It's been 30 at 30 years since last time and,
and it's, it's almost like a, a nation versus.
A nation battle that we're going to be having here for, for,
for it. So it'll be exciting for, for the,
the baseball fans out there. Um.
Yeah. Go ahead, Rob. Oh yeah. Just his first pitch,
Nick, first pitch is at eight o'clock. Is that right? Yeah.
Fantastic. That's right. There we go. I feel, I feel like I need to
build like some kind of like, uh,
sports analysis. Was it really called the movie that came up?
Years ago, Moneyball. Yeah. Yeah.
That, that would be a great, uh, a great little app that I should,
I might, actually, now they say I might buy that while, while we're chatting
here today. Some, some sort of like stat statistical analysis.
Uh, you know, my baseball thing. I'm a Bob.
I don't know. The gauntlet is down, Rob. Yeah.
Absolutely. Yeah. Unfortunately, I, I, if you're looking for like,
sports guy, I'm not really your guy on that.
But if you're looking for A. Yeah, I, you know, I've probably gotten much
better, uh, details for ya. Um,
and, and, and our, and our European friends are like, baseball,
what, what, what's he, what's he talking about here?
It's kind of like, it's kind of like cricket,
but it doesn't last a week. Okay. I just insulted
the entire world. I'm gonna, I'm gonna quit while I'm behind.
Um. Alright.
All right. What, what else we got going on here? Um, I,
I see, uh, I see driving. You, you,
you bet your big event tomorrow? You know,
you're muted, I think? Yeah, yeah.
Uh, it's next week. Yeah, Tuesday.
Oh, 28? Yeah, yeah, yeah. On Tuesday 28.
If it overlaps with the tribe meeting,
so, you know, I'll probably not be able to join the- tribe maybe at
the, you know, the beginning of it,
but yeah, 60 people already applied.
So, you know, let's see. I expect the,
you know, crew will start growing in the Serbia.
So, let's start spreading the word.
Okay. Well, if you're, if you're in Serbia and you're,
uh, you're watching, make sure you, you go.
It sounds like a great event.
And we, we got one other one. In Abu Dhabi.
Uhm, if I'm not mistaken, is that Tim,
Timmy and Tommy. Yeah,
we got, that's right. That's Abu Dhabi. Abu Dhabi is Rodrigo.
And, uh, that is tomorrow.
That, that's the one that's tomorrow morning. Alright.
Well, we got a new website. And,
uh, so I show you that briefly, but it's up and I didn't know.
Haven't had any complaints that,
which is probably knock on wood. So I, I probably should be saying that.
But, um, yeah, we, we got a, we got a new website.
Uh, and it looks, it's looking pretty good.
It's got the, uh, sort of style and, and you'll see if,
if you want a good one of our events. We got the community page.
So again, if, if you're looking to, uh,
do an event, let us know. We'll, we'll add it here.
We got some of the, I guess the Abu Dhabi ones coming up tomorrow.
We got Serbia. We got Paris meetup coming up.
And I think we, we're, we're going to hear from Vincent here in a
bit in regards to what, what he's been doing in Paris.
So yeah, lots, lots of stuff happening. Um,
yeah, it's good. So I'm, I'm glad we got it up.
Thanks for everyone who contributed. We had a substantial amount of,
uh, contributors to that. So I'm going to, I'm going to give you guys
a quick update on some of the stuff that I've been working on this
week. I've, I've, have a minor obsession with vector-based
systems as you probably are following over the last few weeks.
And I created, uh, I've been working on two parts,
separating the, the vector and memory system from Claude Flow to stand alone.
Cause a lot of people are like, I love the idea of how you're
handling memory and the vectors and the swarms,
but you know what, I don't want to use Claude Code. And,
And so, how do I, and so the question was,
how do I separate that in a way that, that allowed you to use
it in land chain or crew AI or,
or, or master hour, whatever your preferred agent system was.
So that's what I, that's what I'm attempting to do with,
with Agent DB. And I got completely sidetracked and carried away and added
a whole bunch of other capabilities as well. So for,
for just as a quick recap for those who are, who are,
or not familiar, the biggest addition that I've done recently,
and this was really popular in the Claude Flow system was the Reasoning Bank.
The Reasoning Bank system essentially allows the,
the, uh, to learn from experiences to improve over time.
So when you look at what's happening within Claude Flow,
every time you do an action, you edit a file,
you request a website, you ask a question,
and there's this idea of pre and post hooks.
So what the Reasoning Bank is essentially doing is learning what works and what
doesn't, in the most simple terms, or feeding information that relates to what
it needs to do as it's doing it.
So you, there's two approaches you can take when using these types of systems.
You can kind of have it, you know, instinctively learn as it goes,
and that, that's great for certain applications. That are kind of more human orientated,
you're back and forth, you're chatbots, that, that sort of thing.
Or you can kind of pre-train it. And I've done several models that are
kind of pre-trained on different, uh, different types of applications or data sets.
So in this case, you might want to say, I'm interested in using a
particular, uh, framework and,
and, and need the system to sort of understand how the framework works.
And you, you often see this when you- using cloud code or chat GPT
even, that it's not trained on the information because it's,
it's, it's too new or, or whatever,
like a perfect example is when, when chat GPT or OpenAI comes up with
a new API, it wasn't trained on it.
And it sometimes hallucinates the endpoints and the functionality of it.
So to get around that, what you can do with these systems is you
can kind of pre-train it on. The latest information relating to that thing.
It could be a document, it could be an API,
it could be whatever information you want to do.
And this creates a kind of graph structure that defines the overall kind of
how all the information connects and is inter,
sort of related to one another. And that's using a vector-based approach.
And, and then there's different learning plugins that exist to help facilitate exactly how
that works. . . So the biggest update, I've added and jumped to the
bottom, is I've actually,
where is it here? Here it is.
I've added some new memory features and-like,
uh, since Monday. Um-so I've added some-and what's interesting abot
lot of these features that I've been adding, these are all kinda related to
dee- deep mine. Google.
Google's been on a roll for really cool, sort of,
reasoning based algorithms. So most of the stuff,
the reasoning bank and the reflection memory and a few others are all basically
deep mine research papers. What Google doesn't do a particularly good job
of, is actually creating code for their various,
um, experiments. So they're putting out these white papers that explain that we've
just cracked the biggest thing in the world, but we're not gonna actually share
the code with you. We're just gonna- brag about how good it is.
So what I did is I- I take those- those papers that are essentially,
you know, bragging about how great they are, and then I take it and
actually implement it. So in the case of the reasoning bank,
I had that implemented within, I think, 12 hours of them releasing the paper.
For whatever reason, they didn't really put out much code relating- they put out
some code in parents, but not a lot. I- I did a- a much
more full implementation. So in this case,
we've got the- I do have a skill library. So inspired by the skills
within Claude Code, where you can kind of instinctively learn and
adapt based on the task in which it needs to do.
I created a kind of vector style implementation of that.
So within this, you can learn how to do skills.
So what does that mean practically? So I'm gonna jump.
I'm gonna show you that. And I did this this morning. So I've got
a whole bunch of examples in here. Um, these are,
and these examples are all examples that run within a browser.
So there's no cloud infrastructure.
There's actually, from most part other than the request to Gemini,
I'm using, like, the agent marketing and some of the other ones.
There's no actual, um,
LLM. It's, it's learning without any need for a,
a neural net or a language model. And let me show.
I'll show you what that actually looks like. So I'm gonna go, I,
I create this this morning. This is, this is actually for,
for guy, because guy, you know, as a background in the military,
uh, you know, industrial complex,
if you will. Um, alright, so let me,
let me do what I call battle, battleship.
Alright, so this is, so what this is doing,
this is using game theory, which is kind of code for war simulation.
To actually use a series of different algorithms to train
the system. Now, I know it's very bright and colorful here,
but if I click start, I'm gonna actually show,
I don't know if I have this in the console,
we'll find it in a second. But I always, always include the console.
So we see here that I'm in, I'm instantiating the library,
which is a JavaScript, and,
and I'm gonna hit the, it's looking, I'm actually using. In the older one,
for some reason, but that's okay. Um, and now what's happening here is the
system is battling against each other. So,
if we go here and take a look, it's,
it's essentially playing a game of battleship with other versions of agents
that are now using different pattern matching and algorithmic components.
So if we click on help, I'm gonna do that while it's happening.
It's, it's using. Essentially, this idea of different admirals,
red, blue, and green. So you can think of,
like, you know, blue team, red team,
green team, that kind of thing. It's using game theory.
The game theory uses different types of complex algorithms,
Nash equilibrium, Bayesian inference targeting,
prisoner, dilemma, and min-max,
and a few other, uh, strategies. And then they're battling to figure out which
of those strategies- is most effective in sort of winning the battle.
Now, this- this is a perfect example of how you'd use a kind
of pre-training to learn- to help the system learn how to operate.
Now, in this case, it- it's- it's an adversarial sort of,
uh, learning process. So, adversarial is one of those areas that-
that is both great and terrifying at the same time.
So, it- it essentially is battling,
right? So, this is, like, all the worst parts of Skynet.
But on the other side, it's also looking at this idea of sort of
proactively protecting against bad actors.
So, why would you want to use this? Well,
think of if you're creating a security system that is trying to find an
unknown threat. People are trying to attack your- your imprec- Thank much.
They're using AI, they're using agents,
they're using similar, uh, approaches that what I'm doing here to sort of battle
each other. But you don't know what that- that sort of approach might be.
So, you're- you're sort of defending against an unknown adversary.
This type of training allows the system to sort of model,
adapt, and understand what the potential vectors are.
And then because it's- Thank you. Using a vector-based approach,
it's actually able to use a similarity or semantic understanding that
may or may not be related, right?
Where my previous was explicit,
if someone is attacking you in this particular way,
I would understand it. But if someone used to use a kind of,
what they call a polymorphic approach, meaning I'm gonna attack you in this way-
Hey, but I'm gonna, I'm gonna make it look like it's something else.
The system would fail because it only was trained to see the attack in
that particular way. Now, this approach says,
I can understand this attack even if you're trying to masquerade this attack
in a different way. So, if you're,
for example, exploits for finance,
crypto, trading, whatever, it can now understand the- same attack,
but in different positions. So,
in this case, the Admiral Gamma 1, and what's interesting about the Admiral Gamma
is, and this is using a particular approach,
this one always seems to win. So,
it appears that in the game theory,
that particular game theory, actually,
in this particular application, works the best.
Let's take a look at which model that- I actually use this.
So, the Admiral- the Admiral Alpha Red is,
uh, I think I'll say Alpha. Sorry,
I forgot which one one. I think it was that one. Yeah, it was
Admiral Gamma, which is this one,
I guess. Let's go back here. It was the one at the bottom of
Captive Learner. Captive Learner.
Yeah, so, Captive- Yeah. Captive Learner is the one that seems to work,
to work most, to learn and work most.
It doesn't always win, but it seems, and I've only built it this morning
in parents. But in, in the, uh,
in what I've discovered, it seems to win the most. What's interesting about that,
you know, I'm going to jump back for a moment, jump around.
Hopefully my brain isn't going to win too quickly. Um,
there's a model that I've been using that's particularly- Tip early.
A well-s, oop, agent. A-a-a,
got a bit of a delay here for some reason.
Agent, the- a- you'll see that I'm using a diffusion,
uh, or a decision transformer.
And the decision transformer, which is essentially what that is,
is- and where did I put that? I think it's in- there's so much
stuff, like, I can't even keep track. Uh,
here, where is it? Here we go. Yeah.
Yeah. Decision.
Anyway, I- I- I- I can't- I- I don't remember exactly where I put
it, but the decision transformer is essentially one of the models that- that
allows it to understand the decision tree in- in real time,
and then adapt itself to it in- as- as it as it does in
different testing. So, uh,
anyway, as far as- as these go- you're- you're looking at probably,
you know, lots of different options. You- the other thing I did earlier this
week, which was really popular, was this idea of the agentic marketing intelligence system.
So similarly, this is- using the idea of a
kind of real-time view of ads for Google- and Google-
actually, it's meta. And you can go here and- and you can see our-
We're take a using them a more up-to-date, uh, agent, uh,
model here. This is one point v- uh, 3-9.
But when you do this, this is doing a similar approach,
but this is actually training on advertising campaigns to try to optimize for
the return on advertising spending.
And you can see that there's different config options that I have for that.
You've got different algorithms you can choose from,
cosign, you know, these are basically the- the interconnected relationship of the vectors.
The cosign similarity generally is the one I lean towards.
It seems to work best for most things. Now, these- these others,
depending on what you're- what you're doing, you can play around with and see
what- which- which works better for you. You've got budget,
you've got thresholds for how much you want to spend.
So, if you're- if you're building like a, uh,
I don't know, a Shopify site or something, and you want to buy ads,
this- this will, uh, basically help you figure out where and how you should
allocate your budget. And if- if you want to connect it to,
like, real-time ad system, don't use it in terms of the cycles that
I'm doing here. I'm using three second inter- or one second intervals or something.
Make it run over extended period, like days,
not- not seconds. But to train it,
you might want to do seconds. Here's some AI configuration.
I'm using Google Gemini to simulate the data.
Because I'm not actually using real data I wanted to basically train the system.
So I'm basically doing a feedback loop from Google to train the system and
how it needs to look. So essentially Google Pro is- is- is simulating the
flow of data from a hypothetical, um,
ad campaign. Um, one other thing you want to look at here,
if you're running this in the browser, which is what I'm doing.
This is a hundred percent browser base. Use a smaller- embedding.
The more embeddings you're basically getting exponentially more compute required.
And that's kind of why my computer's a bit- a little slow even right
now. So the- the 1536 is the embeddings that you get from OpenAI
and I think also Cloud uses the same embedding system.
Um, but for most things you don't need that- that- that many edges.
So you're good with, uh, this smaller 384.
So it's- when you- yeah. I mean, are you training a model here?
I mean, if so, where is the model actually hosted?
It's in- it's in your memory. So I'm- what I've done is- I- this
is a 100% browser base. So if you can see on the- on the
side here that it's storing patterns, right? Each 114,
118. I'm actually storing all the vectors in this particular scenario.
Let me do an AB test as well. Uh,
AB test. I'm storing- story. All this information,
including the reasoning bank patterns, everything in the client user memory.
So basically, I'm using the WASM as a mechanism to access the memory.
Then I'm creating a vector using a SQLite style,
or actually SQLite specifically, .js.
And then I'm- I'm using that in the form of a- of vector database.
So this is 100% based on memory. 7 8 8 9 Now,
the drawback to that, in this particular scenario,
is there's no persistence. Because as soon as you refresh the page,
the memory would be lost. So you could use- you could easily connect this
to some of- some other persistent store, or even JSON,
or- or other databases. Um, this is meant to show what's possible on
the edge. Like, if I can do a complete learning system with no neural
network and no- well- this one's gut,
Gemini, but generally speaking, no external AI,
then anything's possible. And really what I'm trying to show is- You got a
ton on token calls, done, right? No- well,
yeah, no- well, and in the case of that game I was showing you,
there's no token costs at all. That was a hundred zero.
And taking a step further, if you use some of the other tools that
we- we have available now, like the Onyx system that I've integrated- into the,
uh, agent flow system, you can host your own agent,
or sorry, own LLM directly in the browser itself.
So, there's zero cost. So,
um, one last thing, I'm jumping around a little bit. Uh,
just- Just to be clear though, is that- that's why your system is going
slow. And I should be interested to see what your memory usage,
uh, and CPU usage is ruined. Good.
It's probably high, and I've got a decent system here,
but it's, you know, I'm showing the art of the possible.
Now, if I was- if I was gonna do this for real on the
edge, what I'd probably do is probably get it- it's find an ASIC chip
of some sort that's hyper optimized specifically for this type of work flow,
and then I'm not gonna have that- that problem. Um,
but this one, yeah,
so the- so- I'm getting FPGAs at that point.
Yeah, did you see the, uhm,
Google open source, the Corel TPUs,
so you can actually get the Verilog code and run it on an FPGA?
That gives you about, or Tops, that's pretty cool.
It's exactly what I'd do. Yeah, well said. It's a- it's a hundred percent
what I would do. So, I'm basically giving you guys quick,
dirty examples, but- easiest would be to use my Onyx 5.4
implementation, and this actually runs directly in the browser,
so that gives you a- a language model that is a hundred percent contained
within the client. So, you could literally build a website and have
zero uhm, LLM costs.
Now, the drawback is exactly what you're seeing, you know,
on older machines or ones that have a ton of tabs open like- what
I currently have, it's gonna be slow. And I'm running,
I'm sharing my screen and zoom, and doing a bunch of things.
I've got my VS codes running, so I'm really pushing this thing,
you know, beyond where it- where it should be. But,
it does show that- I think- and I'm gonna go into a rant for
a moment. I think all these data- uh,
these data centers that they're- they're creating for massive build outs of GPU farms,
are s- s- some- some kind of like, umm,
I don't know, red herring. Some s- they're building them for- for obviously a
reason. But, we're not- it's like we're throwing more brute force comp-
compute put capacity when we should be looking at optimization of these systems,
rather than building city-sized data centers. Now,
my- and this is my conspiracy hat on for a moment.
The- the logical ri- Alright. The rationale behind that is mostly probably about- if
we believe that this AI is going towards the future of actual human replacement,
those data centers are not about making chat GPT faster.
They're probably about some mechanism to build at scale systems to
essentially wholesale replace- employ- employees would be my guess.
I got no proof of this. But when you think logically,
we'd like- there's more capacity being built in these data centers in the backwoods
of Louisiana than- than it would ever be needed to for all
the chat GPTs in the world, times several orders of magnitude.
Now, when you take a step back for a moment from that,
what does that actually probably mean? It means continually operating systems- agents,
if you will- that are doing certain tasks.
They're- they're- they're operating in the context of the- roles and responsibilities
of people that generally sit in front of computers and do those tasks today
would be my guess. I have no proof. I'm not trying to- I'm not
trying to-- they have an identity.
Yeah, and that's- that's-- that's- that's- and- and I
think- exactly. I think the- I think the issue we face is this.
If we're- if we're moving towards a future- where there's a handful of really
powerful, sort of, companies that- that control all the AI.
Of course, they're gonna wanna have these systems in place that are GPU-centric because
they're cost-prohibitive for most people. And to compete against,
you know, the- the giant AI companies,
you're gonna have to one-crank these giant AI infrastructures to support it,
and you're gonna need nuclear power, you're gonna need massive- GPU build-outs,
and all this stuff that the average start-ups never gonna be able to do.
So when you look at the stuff that we're doing with,
sort of, the opposite end of the spectrum, what I'm saying is you don't
need any of that. All I think- I think people are
gonna- I think people are gonna have AI babies. Yeah,
I'm just- I'm just borrowing the- the- the GPU and CPU that exists in
your browser on- on your computer, and then- .
. I'm federating that across all the users of my platform.
So in- yeah, so when you look- when you look at,
like, what cloud flow, even with,
you know, I'm- I've got users. I- who knows how many I have.
Tens of thousands, let's say. And if- if I can borrow a bit of
compute from them, I've got more than enough to compete against some of the
largest players even today. But- and that's- in my opinion,
that's the democratization of a- I'm not monolithic,
giant data centers that are locked away from the average individual,
but I'll never be able to touch. And that's my rant.
I'm done. Um, I'm on your team,
I believe you. Yeah. You know,
the- the problem of- not the problem, but the- the duty secret in the
industry around, uh, the killer use case,
being firewall your employees, that's been a- around for many years.
And in fact, the- the early days when agentic apps were just starting to
get going and, you know, robotic process automation became agentic frameworks,
the executives that were all drooling
because they saw that they could fire half their employees,
right? And just have a bunch of agents. That- that would- turned out to
be a lot harder than- and more difficult.
Cool. Then what Silicon Valley thought they could get to and crew AI and
all the other foundational, you know, or other frameworks. But that is still the
duty little secret. The other issue though is Ruben is in.
And I love your idea of being GPU poor. I think that's a really
fundamental thing that I think the foundation here,
um, really centers around. I love that because I think that if everybody's gonna
be different from- from AI, then,
um, you know, you- you can't have billions of people owning GPUs,
which is not- the world isn't going to be able to do that,
right? So I think that the industry is hitting,
should be heading towards, uh,
doing everything on CPUs. CPUs are being really just more available,
right? And- and they're more- they're more average- average computers.
You borrow the brains. You just borrow the brains and keep the context.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yes. Yeah. So I think GPUs are not the way of
the future, to be honest. And I think that, uh,
everybody is GPU poor, except a very small cohort of very wealthy
large companies. Yeah. Yeah,
but David, uh, one thing is, like,
what you mean by GPU? There are some GPUs that are like,
uh, NVIDIA Jetson, they are cheaper than the,
uhm, The reason for training. We need to follow through the training.
Yeah, but you can find, uh,
yeah, cheap, like, small-chip GPUs that are cheaper than the CPUs.
I think it's not really, right?
The, the, the problem with that plan is that, uh,
GPUs are highly optimized for a very specific type of math.
You can't run an operating system on a GPU. That doesn't have enough.
It's a lot of, It's just a lot of waste,
doesn't, Yeah, I mean, they, I mean, there is a real weird kind of
blend between the, like,
Intel was playing with, with, like,
a vector. So the oldest vector extension since CPUs,
they essentially, I mean, in GPUs,
they just use it, I think, Intel was, uh,
128, uh, values, like,
inside of CPU, if you get one of the higher-end Intel's,
like, from, uh, the, uh, series ago. you So that's,
I think, GPU, and another thing, so that whole thing with replacing people with
robots, that actually happened. So when Donald Trump pressurized Fox-Cons to
open the factory somewhere in Minnesota,
and said it's gonna bring, like, billions of dollars,
and lots of jobs, uh, the number of jobs they created,
I think it's about 150. It is billion-dollar production,
but it's basically- Thank you. It's a bunch of guys driving the truck with
the supplies, and a few people that go fix the problem.
Let's- Let's be honest, guys, it's- it's actually really- if you know how,
it's not hard to replace large portions of,
sort of, uh, data-centric jobs,
right? The- The- The- Anything that involves me sitting in front of a computer
interacting with it somehow or other,
for the most part, can be pretty easily automated now by- and the tools
that you see us using on a daily basis. And now,
I- I don't- I don't think the rest of the world's caught up to
us yet, so we're in this kind of weird phase where there's a group
of us that sort of know how to do it, but generally everyone else
thinks it's BS, or it's coming in- in- in the future at some point
when the singularity is met. But the reality is,
for us, we've met that singularity.
We can totally do it. It's- and I would say- please easily 20% of
all sort of middle, you know,
white-collar jobs can be automated to- to some degree,
probably mostly automated at this point. And we're only in the first minutes of
this kind of trans- you know, transformation.
What does it look like in five years or ten years? You think it's
chargegbt is AI? Yeah,
they think chatgbt is AI. It's nobody to chat.
Chatgbt is- is- is- is a fancy, you know,
mere here. Of what you're asking it, for the most part,
but it- it beyond asking it to do something that- that exists,
you know, in a- in a perpetual state,
it doesn't do that, right? You also don't need GPU for it
to work. It's more for training. You mean the- the models are just gonna
train- it's sort of improving off other models,
right? It's pattern learning, so you can learn the patterns.
Training is a huge amount of math,
and it's all linear algebra, right?
And vectors and matrices, and that just happens to be the transistor divisity
in a general purpose CPU that they don't have a lot of that.
Whereas GPUs are literally hundreds of billion millions
of- of- of vector matrices in linear algebra math transistors.
That's- that's what- that's what you're doing.
Yeah. That's kind of like a rabbit hole that the whole industry dug in
themselves. So the reason lots of training uses like linear algebra
is because, uhm, the GPUs are way above and very do it- very
good at linear algebra. Yeah. The actual GPUs,
because we got a couple of jobs ago,
I was working at this by a pharma startup,
if we're simulating cells. I was, and truck things. Our equations could not run
on GPUs because we've been dealing with, uh,
like, you've caused problems, right? It's like one over sine over X,
when it goes to zero, it just goes crazy, right?
So GPUs cannot do anything. There are methods.
The non-linear methods exist. First of all,
you need to like PhD from a MIT to even understand them.
And the GPUs don't- and GPUs don't even have the-
complexity. I mean, they don't have enough complexity for you.
You've seen the other rock, not AI rock,
but the other rock. The- uh, what?
You guys know what I'm talking about? Not- not- not Elon Musk rock.
Oh, yeah. The other rock. They've mastered not- not for training purposes,
but for actually running it- For inference. Yeah.
They're optimized for inference. They're writing a- read.
I mean- Yes. They're building se- they're brooding processes that
are highly optimized, not for model training,
linear algebra. Correct. Correct. For compute inference time,
inference. Yeah. I think it's gonna be more generators, and then- and then it's
gonna spin up- it's gonna spin up, you know, sub-units,
sub-agents that have context, and- you know,
context and pacts is what I call them, and it just- it just has
them run them and shuts them down. Kind of like- managers, kind of like
a company. Yeah. Yeah. There's- and there's no question that,
uhm, that that is exactly where we're heading.
I mean, the term that's, uh, I think has most, uh,
you know, poignancy is a post-labor economy.
The ability to- it's most complex when you try to integrate new native
AI systems with existing human workflows and environments.
When you reimagine the entire business model- on.
AI native, it's less complex.
So, what are these things you're using with that?
No, I have a couple hundred employees and I'm agreeing with you.
It's harder to integrate than it is to- to build for AI.
You need to build for AI not to integrate with the human condition,
I guess. There's- there's what I've run into.
There's a new benchmark out, uh, Apex,
uh, productivity- Thank you very much. And that's exactly what it's measuring.
The ability for models to be able to, uh,
duplicate, uh, knowledge work. And,
uh, and I don't think- I don't think anybody's,
uh, being discreet about it in leadership,
in technical leadership. I think they're being very, very overt.
That this is exactly what's coming down the pipe. And,
uh, and yes, the question, uh,
remains is how do we- we organize society in a place where we have
these systems that are capable of doing the work that humans have been doing.
Check-no, I-I've got a-I've got a thing I push.
And everyone thinks I'm crazy, but I'll say it anyway. I-I call it,
uh, techno-socialism. And I'm not talking communism or any kind of crazy stars and
stuff. I'm talking about technology that is empowering the-the-our
society to be more effective, and more efficient,
and-and hopefully more- for-for all of us.
You know, maybe I'm an idealist, maybe I'm an-an-an altruist,
or just an ideologue, or whatever the term you want to stamp on my
forehead is. But I-I think that this-this technology should-should make us not
just more productive, but happier and more efficient and effective in living our lives,
right? I-I just don't like the idea that I-I-I live my entire life to
sort of- even power some billionaire somewhere off in the-in the distant,
you know, tower somewhere. That's not-that's not-that doesn't do any more.-you're not-you're not the
idea and making a reality is really fast time frame.
I mean, it's-knowledge is freed out. Creativity is really the goal.
Now, labor is becoming free.
One experiment I tried that kind of scared me yesterday,
so I had this very- not complex,
very, like, weird IT task I was just trying to put whatever
I developed locally onto server database, so I-programmed the agent to actually
not be assistant, but be the, like,
labor card. That basically has access to the local thing,
and it was typing me what to do, basically,
right? And, uh, it turned in a mode. We actually did the whole thing
in 15 minutes. But it was- it was kind of harsh saying,
like, type this command, because it could- I didn't move it.
We actually could not get access to the server, but we need to create
a bunch of counts, create a schema, like, very dumb database work.
And when it's in that labor card mode,
like, not in assistant mode, but you are the assistant.
It's actually- we did it very efficiently in 10 minutes.
But that might be like one version of the future,
as the AI is just gonna- them. Drives people do things that it
cannot do, I can- totally already- we are already there.
We're already there. The one thing we know for sure is AI has a
tendency to lie. And that's really problem.
Yeah, every time we- I ask it,
you know, are you sure? Oh, actually, I was wrong. You're 100% right.
Wha- what which is it? Are you 100% done?
I'll test pass? Or am I- am I absolutely- Absolutely.
Right, that it doesn't work. Like, and so there's this dichotomy we face with
these systems where they have a tendency to lie and attempt to manipulate us
to believe that what it's saying is true.
And so, imagine if you're,
you know, someone who isn't as capable of us collectively and just blindly assumes
that what it's telling it is correct, right? And- It doesn't have to be
code. It could be just about anything. And- and two,
we're, like, very easily manipulated by this technology.
Just look at the prevalence of the word delve.
Apparently that's gone up some crazy in order to amount of time in general
discussions. I was out the other day talking with someone and- and they were
telling me that they're gonna delve into it. And I'm like,
you- you're a chat TPT user. He's like,
yeah. Yeah. No one used delve, like,
two years ago. I don't think. Like, I never heard anyone really saying it.
Right? That's a funny article written about those words,
right? It's a funny article that's like these five words that- and delve is
one of the best hilarious. Yes. Yeah. I listen to music while I use
A.I. So I'm a vibeshower. Yeah.
I- I- I need- I need music too because my- I get too much
going on my brain and it- Yeah. is something you can use that helps
me- when we- some weird way helps me focus.
Am I- and I'm also, like, a big fan of a- electronica,
which I apparently- no one else in my house is. But,
uhm, and- No else does a techno no model.
Yeah, there's a- that- that- that- that repetitive beat actually helps me focus.
Yeah. It does. So that- So we should- So- so move on to our,
uh, our- our demos or lightning talks.
Yes. Yes. I'll just come So it would come back.
No- no ramsteen for you, roovut? No ramsteen?
Duhas! Yeah, Duhas! That's kinda harsh,
but I just covered the- yeah. Yeah.
There's a guy on YouTube, like, he has actually, I think,
it's like, I generated- he do- he does this crusader chance and he has
a A- generator- generated videos,
so for the hundreds of thousands crusaders going,
and- sing in these songs, they're all gonna write, and so do you do
it on the stand, like, and kind of repetitive, but it's good to,
like, if you're coding, it's, like- Yeah, it's good for- Cause I can't listen
to, like, words that have meanings, and I try to do,
like, listen in other languages,
and after listening for, like, six months, and songs in one language,
you- you end up, like, understanding it, and then you have to go and
switch one. Yeah. If- if- if Mozart was a la- I have in 2025,
he'd probably, like, be, like, a, uh,
a dark house DJ or something. Alright,
we're- we're we're gonna leave that alone and- and move on.
Uh, we're- we've got a- yeah, let's kick off.
Uh, so we have, uh, with us, uh,
a couple folks, uh, out of, um, out of France that I want to
introduce to everybody, obviously you all know Vincent Sider.
Um, but we're also joined- mind. Uh, with the rest of the leadership team
out of France today, uh, Jean-Marie and Arsene,
um, who, uh, along with Vincent have a wonderful,
uh, background in history and experience in AI.
And have brought a number of innovative, uh,
tools, uh, to the world and to the communities.
So, uh, really excited to- first of all,
to have them, uh, leading up and heading up.
Uh, uh, the chapter in Paris and their first event coming,
uh, late next week. And excited to introduce,
um, the three of you to everybody and everybody to,
uh, to the, uh, to the Paris chapter.
Hey, Vincent. Hello Jean-Marie, Arsene,
welcome. How are you all muted?
Hello. Hi, everybody. Hello.
Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you guys. I'm Arsene and excited to
be co-founding the French chapter with Vincent and Jean-Marie.
Thank you for having us guys. Yeah,
it's so, it's amazing. I, uh, I want to thank especially Vincent for
making this. It's happening and having working with him,
uh, with the English chapter,
the amazing job and all you guys and all the world.
And we still want to reading this, uh,
this community. It's been for us, uh,
like, finding big brothers because we've been fascinating,
like, the same subjects of multi-agent or where you call
them for two years now. And,
It's, uh, we are very,
uh, looking forward to, to embrace this movement with you and helping,
uh, in, uh, whatever extent we can do.
Uh, and, uh, taking the framework that you're bringing that is so great and
making, uh, uh, alive in France very soon.
Nice to know. Well, well, nice to see you and thank you for all
your, all your work and you're helping organize the upcoming,
uh, event as well. Tell, tell us what's going That's right.
Yeah, so on, on the 31st, uh, we've been partnering,
uh, with, uh, a major, um, uh,
software in A.I. School, that's called Ecole Calder in Paris.
So I know, uh, Ruben,
you, you'll be there. You'll be one of the stars that day,
along with Patrick Scortabonde, uh,
the CEO of TV. Thank you. Thank you. Five. And yeah,
we'll be, um, we'll be launching the, um,
the event there. And, uh,
of course, so fully, you know, uh,
uh, best represent the mission of, um,
agentics and, and, you know, uh,
make a mark, uh, for these,
uh, events, launch events. I'd equal 42.
It's a big school. They have 3,000, um, students,
but it's also open to other people that are not- part of the school.
Uh, we have a great venue, uh,
with a great rooftop and a view on Paris,
which is something, uh, that Vincent appreciates the first agentic events that was run
by, uh, Jean-Manoni and Vincent's in,
uh, in June, uh, was also on a rooftop in another part of Paris.
So exciting event ahead. And yeah,
and then we hope to, you know, to connect with all of you guys.
His, uh, value those who already, uh, launched new chapters and learned from you
exchange and, yeah, all grown together. Mm-hmm.
Appreciate it. And the, what we're doing,
and Rob, we've got some other activities with our friends at 42 as well,
right? Rob's,
Rob did the, the very mute that he was,
uh, concerned about. The same thing. Thank you. Yeah,
and that came, uh, by way of an introduction, uh,
through Vince and Sider as well. Um, that we ended up connecting with the
42 originally in Tokyo. And 42 is a free campus.
Uh, it's got a beautiful mandate. So,
uh, it's usually established through philanthropy and,
uh, they provide the learning structure and the hardware for students to be able
to come in and engage with the technology and learn the skills.
Let's go.
So it brings access to people that otherwise would
not have an opportunity to pick up the skills.
So it's such a wonderful mandate. And they've got,
um, I believe it's over 50 campuses around the world.
So, uh, the, uh,
uh, notion that we have been able to,
uh, team up. And now we have, um,
chapters and events that are happening, uh, yes,
in Tokyo is planned for December 3rd. Uh,
Abu Dhabi as well. And then, uh, being led,
uh, by the Paris chapter with the head office of 42 and Colin Paris.
It's, it's a wonderful alignment. And there's,
that means there's an opportunity there to,
uh, open chapters and share.
The technology, uh, with, uh,
aspiring engineers, um,
around the world. So it's really exciting. And,
and they've got tens of thousands, if not more,
students going through their programs every year? Uh,
yeah, and many, many, uh, left thousands of students in many cities.
Some are small, 250 to 750 students,
uh, various campuses. There's three campuses,
for example. In, uh, in Malaysia alone.
Um, in Tokyo, Madagascar, you know,
in the Ivory Coast, uh, throughout Africa.
So they're in, uh, uh, locations you wouldn't necessarily,
um, uh, uh, that are sort of off the beaten path up a little
bit in some cases. But it's, uh, yeah,
it's a great, great program and we're, uh,
we're, it's really great to be along with that.
So. Yeah, and, and I, I, I, I, I, I, I,
I think everyone, uh, sees the opportunity to empower those with the least,
the most. And, and, and if you want to think about the thing that
drives me and the excitement of agentic technologies,
again, I've got no problem with the giant corporations.
Obviously, I work with many of them and, and I appreciate the work that
they give me. But I, I, I feel like our duty,
uh, in terms of, you know,
creating this technology and. Making it available is to help those that,
that need the most. And I don't want,
I don't want to, I don't mind helping those who have.
Obviously, I live in a world where the world, you know,
needs, needs to operate the way it does. But it feels good to do
good within those communities. And I'm really excited by the fact we've been able
to hook up with the, with the crew at 42 and maybe help
us get. To that vision, if we can. I know,
I'm sounding like a crazy altruist again. I'm in a weird mood today,
what to say. Yeah, exactly. So Vincent,
uh, we're excited for you for next Friday. Um,
and, uh, yeah, what are your thoughts?
So my, so I want to put the spotlight on you guys.
Therefore, the way it's gonna run, the game plan is.
. . . Um, we will connect to the,
uh, the live stream, this one, right? And,
uh, yeah, next Friday. Yeah, next next Friday.
And, uh, when, when, when, after we've done the introduction about what this is
about the data, then we're gonna share the live stream,
right? So everybody has a chance to say hello and,
you know, to, to show the power of the community and to get rules
to introduce the the agentics formerly the data so let's let's do it both
ways it's not just you know are we we are live.
It's like the community is there, right? It's together,
right? And that's the idea for the, for the first first.
So that's the, the, part one of the game, part two,
which is kind of connected to the chat we just had about,
you know, what's the end game for all of these. Uh, I want to
focus the, the radar on,
uh, generative engine optimization. Long story short,
although the last couple of weeks has been a deluge of data,
right? But, uh, what the subject? Yes.
By 20, by 2028, 50% of searches would be made within AI,
code, and HTTPS, and all that, right? Guys,
this is $750 billion of value.
750 billion, right? So you can imagine that it's going to be a race
to be visible. So let's,
let's hope that not, not just a big ones are visible.
Let's hope the small ones are visible. And so that's what we want to.
Put the focus on, uh, at the event is, is how,
in a world of agentic, we had everyone be visible in AI searches,
right? And, and, and power everyone to have a voice,
at least, to be able to try, you know? So we're going to get,
uh, the CEO of TV5 loans,
USA, which is the largest, uh, international TV network in France,
400 million subscribers, to come and talk about this from a media point of
view. And then we will, uh, show how agentics,
can, uh, help by helping people create concerns,
and, uh, an outreach for, so, so that AI can,
can, can spot them, but it'd be. So that's the game plan for the
31st. It's going to be about two hours, and, yeah, on the rooftop in
Paris, uh, as you can imagine, always a nice,
nice time, except it's going to be raining, for sure, because it's October,
it's, uh, winter time, and, ha, ha, ha, but we don't care, right?
So that's the idea, that's the game plan. And so, Jean-Marie Arsen,
uh, So, You, you know them. Also, EMAD on the,
on the, on the chat right now, I think you want to chat EMAD,
uh, it was there the first one, and I, I, I, uh,
you would be there on the next one as well. So, yeah, it's a
small community growing. Wonderful.
That's spectacular. What an important schism, as far as democratization is ensuring
that small, medium businesses and such still have a,
a shot at visibility, uh, in that kind of a setup.
Incredible. Thank you, Vincent.
Jean-Marie, our scene. Nice to meet you guys.
Wonderful. Looking forward to next week. Um,
so we have, uh, Nick, uh,
we have Adam from Plotly.
Is that right? Yes. Hi,
Adam. Great. Hi. Thank you.
Robert. Um, thank you for- For inviting me,
Nick. I'm glad we had a chance to talk,
Nick and I also working on potentially a Montreal chapter,
um, and a space there, so that's gonna be kinda cool.
Um, but, uh, I really wanted to- I'm honored to be here,
actually. This is some pretty great minds here,
and I- I'm the community manager of Plotly,
and what I wanted to do is just present a little bit about Plotly
and give just a very short demo of the latest. A.I.
product that we built, which- which has a, uh,
a free tier as well. But I wanna make sure I know there's,
uh, others people probably in line. This is my first time here.
Uh, Nick, how much will Robert, how much time, um,
can I have? Is it five minutes or Great demo? Yeah, we typically do
four- four out of five minutes. Uh, crisp,
but then there's time for Q and A afterwards. perfect okay so let me
try to keep it to under five minutes so is it okay if I
share screen? Okay,
so I'll share my whole desktop. Um,
so for those- the data plotly is the data visualization,
right? Uh, it's a data visualization company.
Um, and we do work with- we have over a hundred graphs.
It's plotly hat- the company name is plotly and it has over- um,
100 graphs that you can build with it,
all in Python. Um,
and this is the main page, plotby.com slash Python.
I'll put everything in the messages later,
the links. And then we have,
uh, dash, uh,
which is to build, uh, data apps, like,
you know, other words, building controls, right?
Components, like checklists and- and dropdowns and slide in the sun.
So on, so you got- actually build fully fledged analytics dashboards or- or data
apps. And we've been doing this since, like, 2013.
One of the biggest libraries in the- Python,
like, I mean, data visualization libraries with over 35 million downloads per month
for plotly open source. And also in the- 5 million,
I think, in the millions for dash. And what we recently built,
being excited about the LLMs, uh,
we built our- product, a new product called plotly studio,
on top of, uhm,
on top of plotly and dash. In other words,
we realized, and it's right here, that a lot of people don't necessarily know
the code, or want to get faster to- to our- to our data app
with access to the code. And so we wanted to use the- the strengths
and the power of AI and AI agents to actually allow them to do
that. And this is what plotly studio pretty much is,
right? And which is just- and you can read more about it on plotly.com,
I'll share it later. But a quick demo since I have about three minutes
left, two and a half minutes, is this is plotly studio.
Probably everybody can see the screen. If you're new to plotly studio and I'll
share the- the download link, is an application that you download to your- to
your Mac or to your Windows. And then,
uh, this is what you'll see. You'll see- this and you'll drag and drop
a file. We'll just drag the food waste. This is part of the- the
data set of the month for- for- of the week for the community that
I, uh, posted. We just discussed in the open source community.
So you just drop the data set instead of CSV sheet.
And you can give me some context and goals. I want to learn more-
this is actually the food waste data set, right?
Call of countries. Umm, I think I took it from information that's beautiful.
Umm, website. I have household estimate,
uh, retails that are just food waste and- and kilograms and tons.
Because I don't necessarily have any goals here. I'll just skip for the interest
of time. It's going to build an outline. And it's going to generate an
outline of- according to Plotly and the agent,
what is the best data app to create?
What are the best, uh, graphs to create,
umm, with, uh, with on top of this data?
data. Right? This usually takes about 30 to 35 seconds.
If it takes longer, I'll just exit and go directly into- into the app
itself. Uh, that I already built for the interest of time.
But it's actually- coming together single, it's- it's analyzing the data,
it's looking at- and- and all this data right here. It's filtering some of
it. It's removing bad, uh,
data, or data that's not- not useful.
Um, and- and then here is the recommendation. One,
two, three, four, five different charts that it said it's going to build.
You can change it. We're gonna remove one. We can tweak one.
We can say, I don't want it to be a box, but I want
it to be a violin chart. And then we can just generate the application.
And this will typically take about a minute. And what's happening here,
which is pretty much what I have left for this demo.
What's happening here, it's actually writing 2000 lines of code.
Under the hood, um, in a matter of hopefully one to two minutes.
And, uh, using, uh, using AI under the hood.
And it's building, um, these separate graphs that,
that we, that we agreed, uh,
that is the best graphs to build for this data set.
Right? So it's building a dashboard, uh,
and analytics dashboard, building a data app. And as things get built out,
you can actually take a look at it, right? So you finish. It's building
the data table of, of the, of the data.
It's finished pretty much right now, building all the five graphs.
And so it should pretty much render soon. What is it still working?
Nope, that's it. I'm going to close this. We can see it on the
browser if we want. Later, if we want,
we can also publish it to the cloud with a click of a button,
which is also free for the first one or two apps.
Um, and again, this is all free still.
Umm, and here is a graph, right? So we have summer.
We have our controls on top. We have,
I see, I have about 20 seconds here. Controller,
we have our summary cards. And then we have all the graphs that are
built to the bar, chart, a nice,
um, uhh, I mean,
map, uh, corpus map, um,
some box plots, which we can go into, with some,
with some, with dropdowns where we can change. Different information in the data.
Another box, chart, and all of this. And we always have a table at
the bottom. And the cool last thing I want to say here is that
this is just plotly this idea of what,
what it thinks is best based on, like, a gigantic prompt that we create
on the back end, and, and our 10 years of,
15 years of experience. But we can edit things so we can say,
you know what, I don't like this chart, or I want- I want it
to look differently. I don't- I want a violin plot in the chart instead
of a box up. And we just edit it here, because this is a
prompt that it used. Alright, a violin chart.
And- and then once we do that with a drop down and we click
play, it would actually recreate the thing.
So we don't need to code it. It will give us the code here.
We can take a look at it later. But it will actually create everything
in other hood, and it will change it. And then you have your violin
chart. So that's it. Quick question.
Can, um, can you support other formats other than CSV?
Great question. So, uh, for now,
we have CSV and parquet files, which is- is powerful because you can have
a 100 megabytes CSV chart and shrink it to,
like, uh, two megabyte parquet files. Uh, and we are in the process,
because this is a fairly new product that came out two months ago.
We're in the process of supporting additional data formats.
Yes. Yeah, they- Thank you. For- the first thing that pops in mind,
because I'm a little bit obsessed with my own, uh, agent DB system,
is whether or not you can support, sort of, my vector format.
And and could that be a really way- interesting way to see the interconnective
relationships of the data itself.
Uh, CSV has a tendency to be,
you know, linear in- in its structure. Yeah.
So we are- you're getting very great- we are putting things in place actually.
Support that. We're actually going to put things in place- support also connectivity to,
um, to external databases, to a mobile DB and stuff like that.
So you can just- instead of- just putting your CSV sheet there,
uh, you connect your data and you'll just build it for you.
Yeah. So that was my question, yeah, if you can connect to LiveDB,
but once you have the connection to LiveDB,
can you make it like a live dashboard, so that the periodically query and
update the graphs, like, so. Well,
we're in the process of- of- of doing that, yeah,
to make it more- more live. Um,
and then once you, uh, just one last thing, this question might come up.
Once you publish it, it will actually go to the cloud, um,
which allows you to- especially the free tier,
I- I think one or two asks, where you can just show the community-
show anybody- show the link, and anybody can- can use it.
We just, Just a,
The last comment, I- I noticed that you had a bit of latency in
the time it took you to generate that code, which said about 2,000 lines
of code. We've got some techniques that would greatly improve that,
by the way. We- we can do 2,000 lines of code in roughly a
hundred milliseconds. So, there's,
uh, if you're looking to hyper-optimize your system,
you're talking to the right crew. Cool.
I'll definitely. You're not one of the engineers,
so a lot of what you- the possible solutions will go over my head,
but I am going to bring this back to our engineers and the person
who created this, Chris. Uh, one of the people who created this,
Chris Palmer. And, uh, so we can get in touch with you and see
what ideas we can have. Or maybe come back next time.
I'd love to join again. My- my guess is he's probably making requests to
either chat, you know, the open AI, or maybe Gemini or something,
and then waiting for the response. And that- that takes a while to churn,
right? It's- it's probably an LLM request and,
you know, there's ways to greatly improve that.
Yeah, awesome. Thank you. Other- I guess one more question.
Um, maybe not super fair. Have you- I mean,
this looks pretty cool, but have you done any studies where somebody using this
system and somebody using like a cloth desktop ecosystem codes now?
and open. Just ask it to create an app and it can actually use
the portly widgets to- Yeah,
you're gonna skill. It's- it's- you- you should create a- a cloth skill.
I think we're- we're glad saying. I'm gonna go,
yeah. Maybe you're given if you don't use your studio,
just use the cloth desktop directly. Yeah,
I guess if you create a skill, but you're like- would the cloth out
the box be like, would the skill improve it or the cloth?
You better. Okay. Benchmark- so we- we use benchmarking for sure.
Glad I'm gonna be- don't be able to answer the whole question, but we
use benchmarking for sure. And we don't necessarily only use- sometimes we'll use cloth,
sometimes we're different. Whatever element is best. And we'll feed it,
like, 100 different data sets. How long does it take to build them?
How many- how many are, like, 90% accurate? How many comes up with errors?
We're limited to errors, like, almost zero percent. Like,
not zero, but very, very low percentage. Thank you for your time.
And, uhm, and what we do- yes, we realize that some people- a lot
of people still code and ask for- or auto- charge a PD to build
dashboards. The advantage- slide advantage here is that,
uhm, with one click of a button, you can publish it and then share
it with others. Uh, you can share it later. We're gonna have teams where
you can actually have other teams join you and- and- and build the app
together or modify it and you can give them certain access and you can
connect to- will be able to connect to external databases.
And- and we found, uh, by compared to Cloud that we have better dashboards
because we're using, like, 10- to 15 years of experience.
Uhm, usually. Yeah. It's awesome.
Really nice work. And you guys- are you guys Canadian? Is that Canadian company?
Or is it- yeah, it's a- it's a Montreal company, a Canadian Montreal.
A lot of our employees are- are co-founders was- were,
uh- uhh- U.S. Uh,
but it's based in Montreal and the headquarters in Montreal. I'm in New York,
but I- I want to move to Montreal. Uh,
you're in New York. Okay. Yeah, we- we will hold that against you.
Excellent. I should, uh, I should note too,
uh, Rube, just on the note. Thank you, Adam. Wonderful.
Thank you. Sounds like, uh, an excuse to spend more time in Montreal if
we get that chapter going. With Nick, too. Rube,
uh, uh, ai- Bye bye. Native DevCon is coming up in November,
and Patrick Dubois, um, I know he's been on some of our calls as
well. He's offered, uh, members of the Jenna Foundation a discount for that event.
So, I don't know, maybe Nick, I'll work with you to get that up
into the community website. Or Brad to get that up into the community website
so folks that are, uh, uh,
are registered, even just the free account, whatever.
Um. I'm, Can get access to that discount for DevCon.
It's in Jersey, New York, November.
New Jersey, or the aisle? Uh,
New Jersey. Are you sure? Because I just got invited to it.
It was in Brooklyn. I mean, okay,
I say correct. Not sure. I don't know.
Maybe I got there. But if you get it,
because I was thinking about it. Sorry about it. Because if you get it,
I don't be wrong, you might, End up very close to where we are,
actually. Uh, yeah, right. Yeah.
Go on. Go on. Yeah,
it is a random taxi even in, you know,
or it works. It is. It works for me.
I came across Washington and, uh, in somewhere that's going to north of England.
I came across Washington, I came across Boston, small small villages.
Uh, nice. Yeah. Every,
Sorry. Yeah, go ahead. No,
just like the New York Red Bulls that play in New Jersey.
Yeah, exactly. Right. Yeah,
there's, uh, everything in New England is based on some other location somewhere
else, you know, in terms of naming, anyway.
Except the roots of a robot. I'm playing that the,
um, it doesn't look like much geographically.
Things should be in this, Now it's like in the England,
actually in the northern New England, right? So that's all mixed up,
right? Yeah, well,
if you're ever in Paris, Ontario, you know,
it looks very nothing like actual Paris.
But, um, yeah,
so, okay, we're in the after-hour portion of our show
here. So this is the open mic. If anyone has,
Has something they want to demo, they want to discuss,
they want to rant, whatever. This is your chance.
You'll see that there's a option to raise your hand.
If you can do that, feel free to, uh,
click there. You know, we had a bit of a rant earlier,
so we love the rant. Um, so,
yeah, this is the part where we can go anywhere you like.
Um, well, have we skipped? Have we missed anybody?
I think we, we, uh, Dragon, um,
uh, covered his, uh, event that's coming up next Tuesday.
Uh, I think we've got everybody, so yeah, no.
Genuinely open mic. I noticed in the AI code chat in the WhatsApp somebody
posted a link lovable is asking people to share sites that
were built with. I thought that was pretty neat.
And, um, uh, and I know I think Shopify.
is here. They have some folks that are here and they've recently integrated with
lovable. So, uh, I'm, I'm curious about that because I don't know about you
guys, but I feel like lovable is capable of producing an e-commerce site
on its own, integrate with Stripe,
and it's good to go. Well, Rube.io,
which I built in lovable and, and Clubflow.
Uh, I just surpassed, uh, well, mmm.
More, more than 150k. So, as one guy,
so that, that, that says something about the ability to monetize lovable really quickly.
I, I like it. I love the integration part with,
um, the Stripe. And there's a,
actually just as an FYI, Stripe has a MCP,
which is really, really nice. And basically,
what I've been doing with that is I just set up my,
my Superbase MCP, my Stripe MCP, and then I connect my lovable- site
back to a GitHub instance, pop it open in VS code,
and kind of make the pretty interface work, and then jump back and forth
between the two. It's a great gentics.org site.
We're doing the exact same thing. So, you know,
Matt and Nick and others are basically just jumping into the lovable interface,
making minor tweaks. And when we get to more complicated things,
like this job board we want to create, we'll pull it back into VS
code, and we'll do all the sort of more complex logic there.
So, anyway, we're workflow. And we're a little biased,
you know, one of the first people we had on the AI hacker space,
uh, what was it? It was an Anton back, uh,
about a year and a half ago. So, yeah,
we- we- we discovered GPT engineers.
So, we- we have a bit of a fondness for that- crew and- and
seeing them grow from, you know, their parents' basement and Stockholm to what they
are today has been just crazy to watch.
Patrick. So, I- I would tell you guys that,
um, the issue is Shopify, and I can understand what- what they would do
lovable is that they're- they're liquid themes.
Like, the vast majority of their businesses are small business owners who just have
to hire agencies to,
to fix their website. Like, that's- I'm literally working on,
like, my second Shopify application to submit,
um, all of the apps under Commerce Studio into their platform.
Mm-hmm. That's part number one.
Part number two, like, I would say that that's why they're integrated with lovable
full-stop. Because the themes are too complicated,
it's too hard to do stuff. You have to use third-party applications to build,
like, Black Friday's coming up, right?
Yeah. And everybody's gonna be making spots pages for Black Friday,
right? And it's prohibitively expensive,
so I could- I could see exactly why they're doing that on the front
end. Being, like, a light integration. Mm-hmm.
But I don't see going beyond that. Like, the stuff that- the groove you're
talking about in terms of the NCP servers and stripes,
like, no, no, no. Like, the opticians are almost the- Retreat.
Like, obviously Shopify's moving up the market to try and get,
like, the really big brands who have their own IT teams who do do
development. Mm-hmm. But, like, you know,
when they celebrate the small entrepreneur who's doing a million orders over five years
and whatever, they're not- they're not gonna leave the platform that
does most of the work for them. I want to upload my products and
I want to make pretty pages and I want to know that I can
build some- So, Somebody, and refund somebody, and retarget somebody.
Yes. Yeah. The- the one thing I would suggest if-
if anyone from Loveable's Listing, or just,
uh, shoving it to avoid, they need to add MCP support directly in the-
the Loveable UI. Like, they've got- they've done a good job of sort of
multi-step agent sort of structure recently.
But where it lacks is- is the ability to create additional capability- ability.
Is within it itself. So anything that- you'll- if you've ever used Loveable,
you see that it falls down really quickly when you try to go anything
beyond sort of the superficial UI and data layer that they've made available.
When you want to give something real, true,
unique capabilities, middleware, you know,
uh, advanced AI, it's actually quite difficult to do within the Loveable system.
And- and MCP would be just trivial for them- five to add,
you know, like, they're at an MCP endpoint. Good to go.
And probably some form of extension or plug-in.
Like, that would- you- if they do that,
they'll have everything and most people will never have to even leave their platform.
Maybe this is a- it- it's a good time to show what I'm building,
right? Yeah! Oh, Matt, hey! How's it going?
Um, I need to introduce you to Krista,
too, when we get a chance for- from, uh, from- from our,
uh, friend- from our friends in Austin. I keep forgetting to do that.
But, uh, yeah. Yeah, good to see you,
Matt. Let's- let's see what you're up to. So- so,
uh, as we talk about lovable, let's see if it's- okay,
can you see my screen? Yep. Okay.
All right. So, I've tried many a times trying to organize my brain.
I've tried a bunch of different- uh, software,
uh, with project management platforms. So the other day,
I was- I was- so I'm a analog guy
in the digital world, so I'm always writing notes.
So I always have tasks, and I always don't complete
the tasks. So I finally figured out a visual way,
because I'm always just writing- a list, like this.
It's always this. I finally figured out a visual way that I think that
I can organize my brain.
Well, free my brain is the intent and the purpose.
So if you see Sunday, Monday, Tuesday,
Thursday, here, up at the top, these are meetings that I have.
These are meetings that are, uh,
based on the calendar that I have.
And these here are tasks that are due on these days.
So I owe someone something or I have to complete something.
That's why they're in the box. This is an ongoing thing that'll remind me,
oh, what you gotta do. You have to pay the gas bill.
This was, you have to pay the water bill by today,
Sunday. So these are some random thoughts.
So what I did. Is I took that idea and I dropped it into,
so rather than starting on the back part with cloud flow,
I started on the front visually because I wrote the notes visually.
So I started with lovable here on the front end.
And so the idea is the same concept is I'll have meetings that will
be pulled. If you see here from.
The calendar. I have more than one calendar,
too. So I want to connect multiple calendars. I have meetings that are pulled
from the calendar. Uh,
I had test data on it. Oh, there it is.
Alright, so I have meetings that are pulled from the calendar.
But then I'll also have tasks to be done by that particular date.
So the idea is this is just like my c***.
Pick my co-pilot. And so here,
what I want to do, for example, I'm always having conversations with app providers
or app, uh, uh,
uh, software vendors and, and Adam,
if you're still there, please put your email in the chat.
We'd like to socialize your app through the community.
Uh, but I'm always having a conversation about workshops.
So the idea is that if I create a.
Say terraform and I do. W or workshop.
Logic in the back end will create all the prompts and all the
30 minutes or one hour that I normally do with cloud or chat GPT
to. Get the workshop agenda to get the crunch phrase profile
to get all the details of.
The company with their current, uhm,
funding rounds, all the things that I like to know about what's happening.
So I'm putting logic in the back end of this and,
uhm, and then the other,
other part is I'm always meeting with people around the world.
And I don't, it takes me 20 minutes to even set up a meeting.
So how do I. I figure out, I just want to put in where
they are, where I am, where the three people are and figure out
the optimized time and just kind of propose that time.
So this is, the purpose of this is a c****** to
manage my brain. It's a boring app,
but the idea is to free my mind so I can get to more
of the complex things. And what brought up,
uh, a question move, as you mentioned,
some of the idea about challenges with,
uh, the middleware and the logic. I want to have this chat
GPT wrapper here and use your agent pay
system here to pay my gas bill or something else.
I don't know. That's it. That's kind of the general idea is to be
able to automatically pay people or something and then initially
initiate a call. I'm still playing around with that.
But the idea is this is my executive assistant co-pilot dashboard and
that's what I got. So your command center perfectly customized to how you
like it laid out and arranged. Okay,
so as I was doing this, I thought,
okay, well, I can do this and click up or I can do this
in XYZ. And I've been through that before.
I've done it four times multiple applications,
trying to, and I've put in all the tasks that I needed to do.
And the next week I didn't use it.
And I listened to, I was listening to an AI,
um. PM podcast with Eleanor Verner from the Head of Growth at
Lovable, by the way. And she had mentioned the biggest threat to users
are the, to companies are their own users.
And so as I was building this, I realized,
um, some satisfying about laying my own bricks.
So, um, I, I, I like it.
It's customized to what, you know, she.
Sure, I can go some, sure,
this solution exists in some form,
but I don't know it or I hadn't experienced it.
And so now what I'd like to do is add the intelligence behind
here, the agents behind here, on top of the,
the boring UI that you see.
There's, if it was me building it, it looks.
It's amazing, Matt. You're such, you're such a creative guy. I,
I love the stuff you're always doing. Umm,
it, it, if, if it was me, what I would do is in the
top right corner, I'd click the, the connected get up option.
And I would implement my, again,
I'm biased, I'm building my own stuff and I, I,
I like to lay my own bricks as well, by the way. But the,
I, I would integrate my agentic flow system, and that's going to do a
couple things for you. It, uhh, you, you can leverage the ability for you
to, um, create agents that run perpetually that,
that are always looking for, for opportunities in your life,
in your calendar and understanding you.
Right? Secondly, I, I just, I'm literally watching it publish as we speak.
That's why it's top of mind. I, I've, I've updated the,
the, the agentic flow reasoning system to include all my agent DB capabilities
for self learning. morning. So what, what's happening is as those agents run and
as those, those agents are seeing the things that are important in terms of
your, your life and your schedule, it's learning what it needs to know about
you and optimizing based on, on those patterns.
Lastly, there's the capability for the,
um, the agentic payment system.
And specifically that, uh,
ED25. you. Bye. Whatever, um,
uh, specification, which creates a cryptographically verified mandate.
The mandate essentially is like, you know,
as an ops, for laws, but specifically for you.
It defines how and where the operational context of the things
that's doing on your behalf, start and end.
And that's really important when it comes to things like money,
paying your bills, and. Potentially even managing your finances,
your accounting, your, your taxes, or whatever it is to do,
because there's no real room for it to sort of make declarative choices that
are outside of the bounds of what it should do. That keeps the system
in check. And also provide, and,
and combine with the, the other components I was saying about earlier,
provides a kind of anti hallucination framework.
So, it long as it's, it's grounded.
In the information that you're saying is factually true,
your calendar, your, your objectives, the things that are important to you as an
individual, the system stays within those boundaries.
Thanks for that. Cause that, you actually reminded me one of the intentions
behind this is somewhat like a Maslow's hierarchy,
where it's just understanding what the needs of the individual is.
And then if you strip this out, and you put marketing in here,
or you put some type of, uh, perpetual motion that needs to be done,
this system in this visual format can,
can do it in that way, whether it's a personal,
uh, c******, uh,
copilot, or a marketing system,
it's something that could potentially go. So,
working, working in progress. But,
yeah, I just have a couple comments,
uhm, about that, because I was working on something very similar this week,
like, so I guess you've read it in my mind. So one way,
like, so this calendar, this is like an old,
uh, previous world, uh, how you look at the information,
because this calendar app is one way to view it,
but sometimes when you're, like, thinking about planning and stuff,
you might- You wanna look as the list, you might wanna look like some
crazy graph, like, so you, uhm, like,
you just don't get hung up on it, because, like, the old school people,
yeah, they had this web app with the calendar, but,
so, and it's sometimes useful, like, if you wanna see the whole week,
right? But sometimes you wanna see, like,
what you have, like, all DevOps, uh,
things in the list for the whole month,
right? And especially- special. Actually, it's, like, there is a blocker,
so you can say, like, if- especially in DevOps,
it's coming, right? So if something is not happening,
there is a whole bunch of tasks you cannot, uh,
do because that's not happening. And actually finding these blockers is important.
Yeah, so if you can just, sort of, step out the box and,
uh, just think, like, that you can have multiple- because with LLMs,
it was very- the reason that this calendar apps exist,
it was very- the into the the part that was very labor-intensive to build
them. LLMs can just present, like,
if they have enough knowledge bank, they can present information in any way you
want, right? They can do it as calendar, they can do it as a
list, they can do it as a picture- my graph,
they can make a video, so it's, uh, it's very easy to jump between
a representation and you'd probably- I don't disagree with you.
Ideally, I- I would, like, I would- but,
like, I know UI, where it's, uh, where it's,
uh, voice-driven, you know, I think that's the future.
So, something that you- but- Uhh,
voice-driven is not always- I mean,
it's actually if you talk to a boy, you just can steal the code
from the- who was presenting,
I think Vincent last couple of weeks ago.
Uh, it's on the GitHub, it's trivial to integrate voice,
like, but sometimes- That's it. Sometimes you don't want voice,
because if you're looking at calendars, uh,
they're very visual, it would take, like, I don't know- Right.
Right. Yeah, right. Right. So, like, sometimes you want voice for,
like, a quick reply, sometimes you want to look at the visual,
because calendar has a spatial information, right?
So, it's, uh, it would take many words to communicate like.
I think the challenge that- that you're facing here a little bit is the
fact that we all think a little- a little bit differently.
Some of us are more inclined towards visuals,
and, and, you know, and others are more text or conceptual or- or other
structures. And I- I- what I- when I see this,
I- what I like is Matt's building something that's specifically tailored the way that
he likes to work. And he started by- by showing,
like, a piece- a piece of paper, right?
And, you know, I- I'm not- up. It's really a paper kind of guy.
You know, I- I- I'm more of an articulator. I like to speak my
thoughts and put those into a textual form and then refer them later.
And- but the- the reality is I think we all have different ways of
working and thinking. And what Matt's showing is the ease of which he's
able to take his conceptual frameworks,
his thought processes, and build something that augments him.
Yeah. Particulate. It's good.
Yeah. But one thing what algorithms can do, they can reframe your information because
it's also depends on the context, right? So,
for example, you want to hold- see you leave a glance,
right? This is the perfect representation of it,
right? But you say you want to see what I call my DevOps tasks
for this next couple of weeks, right?
You want to have a list, like, so it's- it depends a lot on
the context, like, and- Yeah. Absolutely. And even more than tasks,
uh, you know, the idea is I can- I should- I like to put
Terraform in the- the W tag and the system would know
that W means workshop. So that means that I'm planning that I need to
figure out. Yeah. They'll- overall, the- the things that I normally spend one
hour, two hours, five in the quad,
it will automatically- actually do it and put it somewhere here and I can
grab it later. And so I'm just trying to- one thing,
I learned that just- I can go up here. Yeah, can go up here.
There's an entirely different- the Eli Gill wrote,
um, a book of a task- a task management and- and it's funny.
There's something called the EOS planner from the- kind of organizes your date.
Ever news talks about like- level of complexity,
like tackle the hardest things first. Do you- when you kind of write your
stuff down on paper, do you, like, identify, like,
the level of effort? And, like,
would you- cause it's something, like, to get it to use up the background
that you know is, like, relatively easy. Would you ever be,
like, put a layer around,
like, interpreting, hey, these tasks require a lot of work.
You should, like, organize accordingly. accordingly. Cause it's going to take you two to
three hours to do this job. I'd like to,
the job to be done. And I've done all the agile training,
safe, safe certified, all the,
you know, project managed PMI training,
all of those things, just in my brain.
And I've, just the other day,
that's what I was sharing. I've finally found something that my brain- get
grass told of. And, uhm,
and, and, uhm, you're humsin' right,
the job to be done, because if you ignore the brakes on the car,
then you have to buy rotors, right? You can put it out,
put it out, put it out, put your grind on your rotors down,
and then you need new rotors. So, so it's any type of system like
that. I'm still working on it. But that could be baked into this,
so that's good. You know, to,
to Vlad's comment, right? It's a very famous,
uh, phrase going by,
you know, a phrase pronounced, which is a picture with a thousand words,
and the pictures are way more high density,
carry way more high density information than,
than, than words do. I didn't,
did you see it just come out with some? You see our data,
uh, compression, that is image-based data compression?
Yeah. It's spectacular,
and I, I, I'm, I'm looking forward to digging that this weekend.
But yeah, it's, it's basically re, they've reinvented OCR.
It's actually something completely different.
And so one comment to Matt, um, at least what I'm using in my
system, I use instead of text show tags, I use,
There's a lot of emojis, because they are very cheap and like they weren't
talking and then,
Yeah, well, it's the, it's, it's the simple reasoning system we were using last
year, right? Yeah, right. Where we packed all this information into like,
uh, Mandarin and stuff like that.
And, but, for your brain now, so like,
there is a, like, you can do one emoji, you recognize it much,
because they colorful, you can just see your, like all the red things,
all the blue things. And in other things we've been talking at work while
you're speaking at OCR, there is one of Chinese research groups came out recently.
They have a text reasoning models, but that using visual images,
they render their text as the image,
and then they do like whatever them jumps over it,
and they claim to have higher performance. But I'm not sure.
I don't they're using the Chinese characters because those are very visual.
Sometimes. This looks pretty,
pretty cool. I'm not gonna lie, and very,
very useful for anyone who's in a situation where they need to upload an
image and quickly understand all the detail,
or an image like a document or PDF or whatever,
or even an image, and get the sort of contextual relevance of it quickly.
This, this is, this is a pretty major breakthrough in terms of what they're
doing. Uhm, like, I,
I'm obviously on my memory sort of,
uh, path here, but when you think of that,
what, hypothetically, I'm thinking out loud. One of the,
one of the challenges we have with using things like Cloud Code right now
is when you try to upload something other than an MD file,
like, if you put a folder full of PDFs in- you in,
in, um, Cloud Code and say, parse all those PDFs and give me an
update. What generally it does is it goes and creates some kind of convoluted,
uh, Python script that then attempts to parse it,
and that's random. It's like whatever it decided to do at that point,
and that's a whole process. With this,
hypothetically, what we could do,
I'm, I'm, I'm thinking out loud, but what I could do is take- Okay.
Take this, take, create a Rust-based implementation as a crate.
I don't think there are any yet. Compile that as a Wasm,
because that's what I do, and then we can put that in the browser,
and we can have that parse directly on the client side.
Oh boy. Right? And that'd be real time,
zero overhead, and we could fit that into all the other crazy crap we're
building. Roo,
check your message on WhatsApp. I was actually parsing thousands of,
or sorry, hundreds of DWG PDFs,
um, and I literally was playing with your idea of using Rust and Wasm,
um, and PDF reading of the engineering diagrams.
So I actually had, like, a pretty big model that I'm actually training right
now, because I have thousands, I can't say too much about it,
but thousands of tests. Files of both the original file and the actual 3D
output of that object. But I'm training right now.
Nice. That's awesome. And you could do that for,
like, glasses and anything that's visual,
that has visual data that you want to pick up on.
So we don't necessarily just have to limit this to the sort of textual
components. We could probably set this up to infer other,
or measure other elements within- the visual information itself.
So, electrical events. Yeah. I can,
I can give you an example, Ruben. I was actually recently working with a,
with a architect, big engineering architect firm in Israel.
And they were, they, they deal with doors and window frames for your skyscrapers
and stuff. And they have to do what you're talking about,
Alex, like passing all these AutoCAD,
you know, an architectural draw. Orings,
DWG files. And they cannot get a passer,
you know, and they've tried every type of LLM you can imagine.
And they can't get it to pass it and extract all of the tables
and the drawings and information out of the documents with precision,
with deterministic precision. issue. We can talk more later if you want.
It's kind of interesting. You used to publish that,
uh, as an open source project. Sounds right,
right up our alley. Oh, it's master of the understatement. Yeah,
you know, and Alex, you know, as you guys know,
he comes not from a technical background,
you know, as an entrepreneur. So every time I see this,
these, these things he invents, it's just like,
like a proud moment for me. I don't know. It's a seat.
Just. . The evolution over the last a couple years.
It has been perfect first, but it's, it's broken my computer a couple of
times over the weekend, but we'll see. Well,
you're not doing it right if it isn't broken half the time.
Breaking things is, breaking things is,
is my specialty. Although I, I will,
I will note that the amount of breakage I see now versus even a
few months ago is substantially reduced. Uhm,
you know, in, in building, like,
some of these projects, you know, my ability to induce,
you know, regressions and problems,
you know, has actually gone down quite a bit.
Now, I think that is because I'm leveraging sort of shared memories and,
and all the little tips and tricks that I've learned along the way.
But I think it's also the, the LLMs are evolving quite well.
Like, 4.5 was bad, then it was- great.
And it's almost like the first day you,
uh, they release a new LLM, you're like, all this sucks.
And then, you know, 3 days later, you're like, oh man, this is the
best thing I've ever seen. And I'm not sure if it's like,
my system learning how to use it, or they're,
uh, they're fine-tuning it, or maybe there's a combination of both.
But it's, it's kind of a weird space. Oh, I think all the lamps
have like an accent in them and like the more you talk to a
specific LLM, like the worst you performance with the other LLM's and the,
like, with this one, it will improve, like, and yeah.
And another thing, breaking thing is great because somebody say a long time ago
that when something breaks, you really understand how it works.
Like, especially if you're trying to fix it. And if you try to fix
it, and you did fix it, you get very deep understanding how it actually
works, when it comes to it. So,
uh, we're almost out of time. And just as an FYI,
I'm publishing a new update this afternoon,
probably shortly in the next half an hour to Claude Flow,
which completely, um, integrates the AgentDB capabilities into Claude
Flow as well. So now we're amplifying the memory and reasoning systems even
further in, in that for those who are interested.
If, remember, if you, uhh, uhh, some,
for some of the folks who are upgrading Claude Flow, especially if you're already
running an instance, you're gonna see a MPM cache
issue. Uh, if you do run into that MPM cache issue,
pop the error directly into Claude and see fix it.
What's happening is you're essentially running a,
uh, instance of the MPX and then trying to upgrade at the same time,
which causes, uh, kind of, ,conflictive sorts.
So the other option is just kill any processes before trying to upgrade it.
Rov, uh, do we need,
like, an end-to-end test for our agentics site?
Which, which, which, uh, would say?
Adgentics.org, so, you know, do we need some end-to-end tests because,
you know, I'm building, like,
a suit the last, you know, five or, 10 minutes,
you know, preparing something. So if you need,
you know, Yeah, let's do it. You can easily, you know,
edit, yeah. I think you're offering,
and I'm, I'm accepting that offer. Yeah, yeah, I'm offering.
Yeah, definitely. 100% we need that. Yes. I,
I'm using my agents to create it.
So, you know, let's see. I, I, I,
you know, anyone knows, I'm really good at printing bugs.
So, yes, 100% we do.
I thought he found a bug, so. Yeah,
that's what I thought. I'm like, all right,
what, what did I break this? No, no, no, no, no, no. Dust, you
know, giving the safety net, so. Yes,
we, we will take you up on that offer. Yeah,
thank, and, yeah. We, we've got a Wednesday web development
call that we do, Matt, and, and Brad,
and a few others. So if you're interested in joining that,
I call, actually, anybody on the call, you're more than welcome to join our,
our Wednesday calls, and we're building, basically,
the website. The next big thing we're building,
just FYI, uh, we're probably gonna build some form of job,
board, uh, agentic style,
obviously, that will be a place where you can list your,
your, your self, and your projects,
and the things you're building, any certifications you get from the agentics foundation,
and. . And, uh, on the flip side, we'll probably have some mechanism for,
uh, employers looking for agentic engineers to be able to probably pay
for the ability to gain access to that.
Um, we're, we, I think, and I'm mad,
correct me if I'm wrong, I think we decide that we're, we're gonna attempt
to build it ourselves, right? Yes, yes,
and as we're on that, we're looking for a lightweight way to verify members
for those. Those particular reasons.
So, if anybody on the call has,
uh, experienced with identity, identity and verification systems,
um, please join our winded Wednesday meeting.
Uh, right now we're looking at strike and identity or LinkedIn verification.
We don't want to store SSN's or birth certificates,
but we just need something light and easy to- to bear five members in
for most importantly, protect our community as we start rolling out the job placement
said rules talked about and referrals. And can some of this be
an idea for, uh, obviously we are having a proper track or building,
but can it parallel mirror be a hackathon idea?
Like, throughout the idea of creating a job or because lots of people to
the community, maybe for a 72-up. Hope you read us something like that.
I love it. Let's do it. Yeah,
I like it. May the,
may the best agentic job board win.
Um, uh, just, just a couple things.
I'm looking, I, I like, I'd like the, um,
to us to use the ED 2551 specification for cryptographically verifying
the identity. Needs to have MCPs,
for sure. You can't, you can't create an agentic job board with it.
But an MCP interface. And we should probably have some form of agentic something
or other for an agent that can help coordinate,
collaborate, blah, blah, blah, eight, the system.
But yeah, let's, let's totally do that. Excellent.
Two more quick housekeeping things. Um,
uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, roof, if you can pass on the Boston supporter,
uh, uh, uh, corpora- supporter. Right.
Nate and the guys in Boston are getting rolling. Nate Vlad and the guys.
So there's a Boston WhatsApp channel. I've,
uh, added you to it. You can drop any,
uh, info or contact info in there. That would be great.
And then, uh, just wanted to give a big shout out and thank you
again to the guys at Caltura for hosting the video archive,
right? So video. Orca.org is where
folks can always catch, uh,
previous copies and editions of these,
uh, zoom meetings going back.
What is it? A year and a half now, Rive? Yeah.
There's. Yeah. We probably have an issue about sync,
which we need some of us need to resolve. I think it is probably
not syncing and for a while, so we need to fix that.
It's been, it's been a month. Yes. And I.
I've been meaning to reach out to them. I think it involves some kind
of manual syncing that we need to do. I'm on with them at two
o'clock. Yeah, so the problem is me,
just to be a, I intermingled my personal zoom with the,
this zoom and there was data leakage between the stuff that I'm doing,
you know, for my consulting and this. So I think just to solve.
So, all that they basically disabled it or something, so we needed to figure
that out. It's my fault, 100% my fault,
just, just throwing it out there. Um,
but yeah, we'll, we'll address that, I guess. That's what,
Boston, Boston for me. Yeah,
um, and I introduced Vlad to the crew at Introlytics in Boston,
but I, um, I can, I can do a broader introduction there as well.
They have space and they're willing to fund, uh,
the m- Yeah. Pizza, okay, great.
Vlad, you had that contact info? Um,
let me see, I didn't know, did you just send a, I'm sure?
I can, uh, um,
Rob, Rob, can you send a, like, a broad sort of intro to the
Boston team for me and I'll reply and, uh,
introduce the Boston sponsors?
Yeah, that was, that was, I don't see, there is,
don't even have us, they, That WhatsApp group?
Yeah, that's right. Yeah. Okay. I don't see anything that,
through, like, It's okay, well, you know, yeah,
you can, uh, post me on LinkedIn or, you know,
my figure. Got it. Yeah, I, I, I, I've got too many irons in
the fire, whatever the expression is. Um, so,
I'll make it happen. Okay, good. Okay.
Okay. Do you need to remind us, I can ask you, like, on somewhere
else? Like, do you need to remind her to send it in for her?
I'll do it for you. Probably. All right.
I, I, do you know what I'm saying? Oh, do we have 45 seconds?
Oh, yeah, go, go, go, go ahead. I've got a few minutes.
I'm to quickly share. I'm going to leave it myself to 45 seconds.
Just to show you that I was like, trying to create a learning plan
for myself around the idea of,
um, the agent, uh, databases,
right, uh, agenda. We set up. So I basically created.
Hopefully you can see my not sure what I'm sharing.
Actually, could you tell me what you're seeing? Yeah.
I see, I see a quad. Oh,
sorry. I'm sharing. I will share again. And by the way,
just as an FYI, I built, I'm building most of my stuff to work
in those cloud, uh, you know, code,
web-based codes, and boxes. Okay.
So you see cloud and you see my- I get hub repository.
Okay. So I basically use the project here and I had some chats called
AgentDB tinkering, and I started kind of interacting,
connecting the MCP and working.
And, uh, long story short, try to create a learning plan for myself.
And then obviously used it to push it through here.
Uh, because it's 45 seconds, I'll be quick. Effectively,
it did create me a website. Which is this one,
right, through the whole process of, uh,
plot, uhm, uhm, basically we're working for the next stop.
But more importantly, I think what I was thinking about, like, all of these
things that we are creating skills, right? So you're the vector database in
AgentDB, et cetera. I tried to export it and obviously tried to create a
plot skill from it. Because as I went through it and I asked it,
what did you actually learn from it? It had told me that these are
the things that it learned, et cetera. So the point I was trying to
make here is that are we looking at a future where probably we're looking
at these, uhm, you know,
these plot skills that we're all creating? Does it kind of,
what, what could be a vision, I guess? That's the thing.
Is it going to be something more of a community,
uh, ecosystem arising around plot skills and some sort of fun?
Yes. That's exactly,
so back to the Asian DVD, the skills capability.
I think what I want to do is some kind of hosted repo where
you can share all the things you've trained and we can borrow each other's
skills. And you ever watch the Matrix where the guy suddenly downloads a
skill and is like, no, is that a like, kick your shit out of
people? Yeah, exactly. That's what I want to do.
I like you. Yeah, Mondry perfectly stated it.
I want to plug into Mondry skills and suddenly have the power of Mondry.
Yeah, exactly.
We need to do that. So that's it. That can be a project on
the website that links back to the foundation repo.
We got to figure out how to do it. You know, like what the
form of those skills are. Sorry. And it could just be those skills,
skill that MDs or something, or the other option we can do if,
if, you know, if we want more complex skills.
If you look at my, I think it was Agent DB, I create,
I pre-trained a bunch of different DB files.
So if you want to borrow one of my train systems based on how
I program or how I like to build stuff, all you need to do
is download my memory.db file. Replace the memory.db file in
your cloud flow or cloud code folder,
you know, dot swarm slash memory DB. And you instantly get my skills.
So that's a DB form, which gives you a lot more,
uh, it's a lot more transferable because it's just instantly,
instantaneously works. Yeah.
So I love it. Maybe we create a little, Well,
is that another, uh, gentic, uh,
page? Skills, uh,
skills database or skills repo or something?
Actually, something. Yeah. I just added 18 new skills,
like, QA related to my repo this day,
today, and published new version 1.3.0.
So now you have, like, I think,
50 something QA,
QA specific, Big skills if you want to use,
you just go to my repo and, you know. Awesome.
I love this stuff you're building. And, uh, and let me know,
join our Wednesday call. We'll take you up on your,
on your website. Yeah, I'll be able this Wednesday,
because it doesn't overlap with any meetups this week.
So, you know, my meetup is Tuesday this week.
So, see you on Wednesday. Okay.
Any final thoughts? Here, I know I'm out of time and I gotta take
a quick breather. Umm, is there any other things anyone wants to cover or
we're good? I think, uh, thank you to our friends in,
in Paris, Montreal, in the plot,
in the plotly team, Rob, Matt,
everyone help with this blog to this website. Shout out to Dory,
who was our designer on this. She did an amazing job and had to
deal with me, uh, a former graphic. The designer,
which probably makes the worst possible client in the world.
Um, but she did an amazing job. So, really appreciate it.
All the hard work everyone's put in. Um,
that's it. Um, for those who are on
my job. Um, sorry, what was the question?
Was it a win? One day for the five sessions?
It's on Wednesday, right? The 28th? Uh,
I, I, my wife friend is managing that.
I get, I get, I, I don't know.
It's one of the days I apologize. Um,
I'll shoot a message on the WhatsApp channel just to confirm the date.
Awesome. Thank you. Thank you. Let's go blue days.
Go blue days. Let's days. Let's go. I'm sorry.