All right.
It's September
19th, 2025.
We're all at more
than nine months
into the year here,
which seems like
a blink of an eye.
I don't have any
math for today's
date of any sort. So
we're going to just
jump right into it.
Thanks for one. I
think we did an office
hours last week.
I was away at a
little road trip
to Akron, Ohio and
Cleveland, Ohio to
the Rock and Roll Hall
of Fame with my
daughter, she's 12,
to see her favorite
artist, musician,
a guy named Conan
Gray, kind of a
poppy sort of
thing. And I was in
a sea of about
10,000, you know,
young ladies that are
excited to see him.
But it was fun to go
to my daughter's first
concert and be part
of that whole thing.
So thanks for everyone
who sort of stepped
in last week, Rob
and Jed and others.
I appreciate you, you
know, filling in the
void there. Well,
but I'm back. So here
we are. What's what's
what's shaking, Rob?
I don't know
much. Great week.
Yeah. Welcome
home. Welcome back.
We've got today for
speakers. We got some
open mic time. We have
Joe Anandaraja and
he's got a recommendation
engine that's
combining some organic
aspects and some
traditional MLAI. So
looking forward to that.
No doubt. Some member
updates. We're just
in the final day of
IPA, the big Asia
-Pacific AI summit that
Robert Yee organized
in Kuala Lumpur.
Tommy, our ambassador
from Dubai, was on
one of the panels.
The prime minister of
Malaysia was there at
the event. So a really
big four-day event
and went off just
incredibly well. So we
probably won't get an
update until next week
on that one, but lots
of stuff going on.
Dragan, I got your request
for your first event
in Serbia for opening
up a new chapter, so
you'll have that looming
shortly. And then
tons of stuff going
on all over the place.
Paris, London, New York
City just had theirs.
And, yeah, it's been
a busy couple weeks.
Yeah, it certainly
has been.
There's no shortage
of activity in
the space. new and
exciting things.
This week, I've been
playing around with
the new Codex
updates that OpenAI
rolled out. If you
haven't looked at it,
I'd say the best
and easiest way to
use Codex, if you
are interested,
is they have a VS
Code extension.
It's much nicer
than their CLI,
which is a
little bit wonky,
if that's a
technical term,
to say the least.
I'll show you some of
that here in a few
minutes. But before we
do, what other updates
do we have? We have
anyone from London or
any other chapters.
We have Tommy. I think
he's sitting on a
chair somewhere in
the sun I saw earlier.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's right.
And Timo's got a
whole bunch of stuff
going on there in
Helsinki in Finland.
Timo, are you there
for a quick update?
We're putting him on
the spot for sure.
Anyway, if you – yeah,
no worries. you know
what this this week
again has been you know
a bit of a catch-up
week for me i there is
one thing that i i've
been working on and i
had been working with
one of my clients that
works in the permit
space and it's an
interesting space it
doesn't it doesn't sound
particularly challenging
but it actually is really
challenging more so
than some of the sub
-overnal management
systems and whatnot which
are just algorithms
the the issue that i
was facing in one
particular focus was these,
these permits, this
company basically does
permits and they're
looking. So let's say
you're a large organization
looking to, um, move
into a new city or
open up a restaurant or
retail location or
what have you, you need
permits to do that.
Right. And those permits
are constantly changing
based on jurisdiction,
based on the goalposts
of a given city.
Like if for, for
example, in LA, if you're
in a Van Nuys versus
Los Angeles versus, uh,
you know, different
areas, then you might
actually not be, even
though you're part of
Los Angeles, you might
actually be separate.
And the AI has a really
hard time distinguishing
that you're in LA
County, but you're
actually have a
different permitting
organization that's
dedicated to it. And then on
top of all that, the
information frequently
changes because the
permits are changing
almost like a yearly
or sometimes multiple
times a year. And the AI
is trained on information
from X point of view.
And then to make
it even more difficult,
if you're using
fire crawl or the,
actually, I'm a big fan of
it, the grounding
system from Google, that
information is not
even up to date either.
So there's all these
moving parts and it's
almost impossible to
figure out what is
actually factually correct
or what was correct
a year ago, but now
is not correct. So to
help sort of resolve
that problem, I needed
to come up with a
agent structure that
essentially allows us to
sort of operate within
this idea of a goal
-orientated action plan,
which the AI called
GOPE, which I would have
just called goal, but
you know, whatever.
You can tell when I
don't bother to actually
name these things.
But I want to show
you this because it's
actually kind of a
cool process. And it
actually was the process
that ended up solving
it. And I've been
using it on several
other applications and
concepts. So let me
show you that quick.
I'm going to show you
a few things here.
And so first of all,
right now I'm, this is
actually building an
NAM, which I'm doing
concurrently, which
I'll show you in a
moment, but it's not
the most complicated
component in the world.
Like you can use this
in like ChatGPT or
Claude directly and so
on. And if you want
this to actually work,
if you want to add this
to your Claude code
or Claude flow, all
you need to do is run
this command. And by
the way, I'm thinking
about moving, you
know, this giant folder
of agents and commands
that I have, which
is getting a little bit
too much and filling
up the context window.
I'm thinking of
actually moving all
those into sub in it. So
you notice here how
I have goal or I have
neural net, for example.
So if, so what I'm
thinking is you can,
you can instantiate
Oops, I brought space.
You will be able to
instantiate these by
doing specifically just
the title, right? So
in this case, you can
see that I went down
this path for goal.
So you've got
different options for
instantiating that.
So I'm going to not
give you everything
out of the box just
to kind of keep it
a little cleaner.
And the other one
I added just as
an FYI while I got
you here before
I go into goal is
I added neural.
and i've been doing
a lot of these micro
neural nets so i've been
focused on sort of how
to use cloud flow to
more efficiently do
that so inversely if
you want to just do the
neural you can just do
the cloud flow in it
with the neural
component and then what i
might do is actually
create like a repo of
different agents and if
anyone has cool agents
or whatever they want
to contribute looking
at you ocean we could
do like a lion agent
and other things
and the system will
automatically grab it,
install it. And hopefully,
if it works, maybe I
can get you guys a few
extra downloads of
your libraries. We're
doing about 50,000
downloads a week of these
various things that
I've concocted. So if I
can spread the love a
little bit, why not?
All right. Can I just
ask real quick, what's
the MCP JSON look
like when you first
load up from init force
is that yeah that's
i got all the mcps yeah
that's another good
point so right now
and by the way when
you're when you do what
the first thing i do
after i instantiate i
do mcp quad list right
and that shows me
but you bring up a
really good point and
this is part of the
problem i'm looking to
solve i'm i'm adding
oh well again of course
i'm gonna show oh i
didn't going to do here
is is probably make
these components
optional right so and
and before someone tells
me i guess i'm gonna
have to change my i
guess i'm gonna have
to change my key
later sorry about that
there's always there's
always something but
anyway um so yeah
each one of those mcps
essentially gives you
the um unfortunately
all the context and as
you can tell my mcps
are very tool heavy,
which fills up your
context window. So I'm
going to have to figure
out a way to more
effectively do that.
All right. So, yeah.
So for the goal
orientated planning
system, this is, you
see here that I
instantiate it. Now
there's a folder in
agents called goal,
and this is this
file goal planner. So
basically it's breaking
down the parts, you know,
so it's a dynamic
planning. It uses something
called an A star
search algorithm. I
discovered this earlier
this week, so I thought
I'd give it a spin.
I'm not going to get
into the details of
it. Basically, it's a
shortest path algorithm,
similar to the BMSSP
algorithm that I
worked with a few weeks
ago. But basically, it
tries to find the path
of least resistance
to get to an answer,
which at first I
thought was going to
cause me the whole,
oh, I'm going to
get lazy and give you
the easiest solution
rather than the
best. But no, it
doesn't seem to do that
at all. It actually
seems to give me
the best solution.
Um, it looks at
effects prediction,
uh,
adaptive pre-planning
and replanning.
So this is particularly
important step.
So what happens is
it realizes that the,
that it's doing
something that is not,
uh,
that's outside of
the bounds of what
it was supposed to
do, which as you
guys know, happens
quite frequently
and then replans
itself on the fly
doing a kind of
gold decomposition.
So all these steps ended
up working surprisingly
well. And the way
that I actually tested
it was on this permit
approach that I was
talking about earlier.
So it was the first
of like, I don't know
how many dozens of
different approaches
we've tried to solve that
problem that actually
worked out of the box.
So it was pretty
cool to see.
So you can see
here, you're doing
state assessment,
action analysis,
plan generation,
execution monitoring.
And then at the
very end, what
I'm doing is I'm
integrating the flow
MCP as part of the
process itself. And
I'm just telling it
how it can sort of
initialize swarms
and do a few other
cool components.
Now, the other
part here that I'm
doing is let's go
here to Claude.
And I've got this
running as well.
So it looks like
it's still working.
So create adaptive
goal oriented
workflow for the
drawback to goal
is, is it's really
fairly slow.
It takes a while to
sort of come to whatever
it needs to do. So
one of the things that
I've been working on
is a more persistent
way to sort of interact
with these workflows.
So a lot of the workflows
that you'll notice
when you're using
these things like
Claude-flow or others,
they work at the time, but
they're not repeatable,
and they're not
particularly well-defined
beyond whatever the
AI happened to create
when it needed to
create it. So, what
I've done here is I've
created some, you know,
I've created an interface,
so you can see here
I'm hosting this
particular instance on
fly.dev, which is nice
and cheap and easy,
and so I basically just
deployed N8N against
that, and you can see
that now it's deployed
there, I can use things
like Claude-flow
and others to create
these different types
of workflows that can,
in this case, this would
basically be a swarm
orchestration that
can now not only use
the local environment
for the swarm, but also
execute that across
remote instantiations
using some of the
other tools I've made
available. Now, right
now I asked it to do the
goal, which has taken a
little while to build.
I'm not sure why it's
taken so long, but
you get the idea. So
you can see here, so
here's like a FlowNexus
server-side event
monitor. So this is pretty
simple. This is just
telling me whether or
not my server version
of FlowNexus is running
or not. And if it
isn't, I can send an
activation to my Discord
channel. I've got
basically a private
Discord that I use kind
of like my own Slack
kind of thing. And it
basically just sends
me a note and then it
just pops up my phone.
That said, having
my own private
Discord channel and
I'm literally me and
my bots are the
only members of it,
it's cheaper and
easier than Slack
because you don't
have to pay for
it, which is cool.
It's got the web
hooks and like as
you can see here.
And what's also cool
about using the Discord
approach which is
if, and when I have
problems, like let's
say something goes down,
like I haven't, it
actually hasn't gone
down yet, but
hypothetically, if it had
gone down, I could
actually reply to the
agent that sent me
a note saying that
currently your FlowNexus
SSE is down. And
then that could kick
off another workflow
that basically spins
up a cloud code,
looks at the
problem, and then
determines whether
or not it can fix it.
Generally it does.
And then I could then
say, okay, go fix it.
And then it does all
this sort of magic
in the background.
And a lot of what
you're seeing is done
through these workflows,
right? So each of
these workflows are in,
it's kind of inbound
or responsing to
whatever I'm saying.
And I'm just sort of
pinging my Discord
channel and saying, do
this, do that, which
is a particularly
nice and easy way to
sort of handle the
kind of responsiveness.
Let's jump back
here and see. Has
it created my,
yeah, since here,
I've got DevOps
related ones.
So this is basically
doing a GitHub push
And in this case, I
included Slack because I
was curious because a
lot of my clients use
Slack, so I need to
see how that worked.
What else we got here?
We've got my Flow
Nexus MCP integration.
So this one is basically
just integrating
the actual NCP endpoint
itself as a post.
You can see here at
the bottom here, I got
my posts and I can go
here and I can just
execute that one step
now i'm creating all
these um all these sort
of steps not in the
ui itself i'm actually
just going back into
cloud code and there's
mcp that that's also
pretty good but i'm
just getting it to do
here so you can see here
you know it's telling
me uh go go create
this go do that and
it's it's building it
now here's here's you
can see my my goat
workflow is actually
taking a really long time
it's been running for
about 12 minutes
looks like it's almost
done let's see if I
can see, I'm just, I'm
almost done. I promise.
I'm just curious if
it actually created it.
Cause what I'm trying
to do is create that
goal or gop or whatever
they call it, whatever
it's calling itself
as an, as a MP or NAM
workflow here. No,
it looks like it still
hasn't created it.
But yeah, this is
it. This is all,
this is, it works
right in the box.
What the configuration
was super easy.
What I might end up
doing is a tutorial
maybe later today
after I get done my
calls and some copy
and paste for you guys
to just point Claude
at so you can start
creating your own
workflows. But yeah,
it's, it's great.
I'm a, I'm a big fan.
It works, works,
uh, it works really
good. It's super
cheap. This, this
instance, uh, you see
running here is the
most cheap instance
I could buy. It costs
like literally
three bucks a month.
So yeah, it's, it doesn't
take any, any
resources, um,
worth worthwhile for
those who are wanting
to create something
persistent, like
trading bots or marketing
bots, you know, if
you want to manage
like business processes
of a business, you
could create, you know,
you could create like
a series of agents,
this, the, the,
the controller, the
CFO, the whatever, and
they can all take on
these personas. And
then they're, they can
be executed through
these eight, eight,
these N8N meets my
flow. Nexus meets my
cloud flow and then
orchestrating in the
cloud using sandboxes
and with the endpoint
being like Slack or
Discord or something.
So for me, that looks
like what does the
future of like an
autonomous business look
like? It looks a
little bit like that.
All right. That
was a lot really
quick. Hopefully
that all made sense.
Any questions, comments,
you know? Am I crazy?
Ooh.
Did you say you're
using the MCP from
Claude to N8N to do
a lot of that stuff?
No, I'm actually,
in this case,
everything you
saw was done using
JavaScript wrappers
for the N8M API.
So what I did, I
will create it. I
will 100% use the
MCP at some point.
A lot of things are
just easier to learn
when you can see
the code. And so the
benefit to the JavaScript
was it essentially
allowed me to, you
know, see how the pieces
were put together.
When I jump straight
into an MCP-based UI,
which is super easy
for a lot of things,
it obfuscates what's
actually happening.
It works, but then
I don't know what
the heck's happening
and I can't explain
it. I don't like that.
So did you wrap each
MCP and Claude-flow
into an entity that's
visible in N8N?
Yes.
So in Claude-flow,
we've got workflow
capabilities. We've
got the neural network
capability, swarm,
hive mind, and
other capabilities
that are both exposed
to MPX commands,
which is the MPX
is essentially a
fallback. And the
primary interface is
the MCP interface.
Now, so those MCPs
can then be tied
directly into sort
of invocation that
happens locally,
studio, and
remotely when he's
executing and
maintained persistence.
The persistence traditionally
in my environment
has happened either
in a SQLite database,
like you'll see for
like the hive mind
and the swarm components,
it's like what's
happening or session
JSONs that you see in
the sort of session,
whatever.session.json.
And that's great, but
what I wanted to do
is basically say, I
need this to run over
an extended period,
like ping Discord if my
site goes down kind
of extended session.
That I push off to an 8n
and let it run forever.
And so periodically
I'm like, tell
me what's
happening kind of
thing and then
it'll go query that.
All right.
There's lots of
different ways to
handle these types
of workflows.
There's Redis databases,
there's message
queues. This was cheap
and easy. So I liked
both those things.
Have you considered
looking at using
different templates like
best practices? If you're
looking at a persona
and here's the way
that a CFO bot would
look at something or
if you're here's gold
standard code blocks
or stuff like that?
Yeah, there's the
last. It's interesting
you bring that up. The
lat when you if you
look at that goal
approach I was telling you
guys about earlier,
the last step uses
something called an ODA
loop. I'm not sure if
you're familiar with
the ODA loop, but the
ODA loop works really
well in that scenario.
So the ODA loop
is for execution
monitoring. And basically
it stands for observe
Monitor current state
and execution process.
Orientation or orient.
Analyze the changes
and deviation from the
expected state. What
was I supposed to do
and how was I supposed
to do it? Well, if
you're a CFO, you want
to make sure that the
company is profitable.
No one's exploiting
something.
You're losing money
kind of thing.
Then the D is
decide or determine.
Determine if replanning
is needed. And that's
actually the real
important step. because
a lot of times it, that
re sort of re positioning
is what makes the
thing either go down
a rabbit hole. It
shouldn't build a bunch of
**** or reassess itself
and say, Oh, actually,
I'm going down a rabbit
hole and building
a bunch of ****.
Let's not do that. And
then, and then the last
step, and I think in
ODA or O O A D A is act
execute the next action
or trigger for replanning
creates a loop,
keeps looping, looping
upon itself with a
kind of self-reinforcement
and understanding.
So if there's
anything that I
think that's important
for any agent
is that kind of
loop structure.
All right.
Any other
questions before we
move on to our
first presentation?
Take that.
All right. Then
let's make it happen.
Hello, Joe. Welcome.
Good to see you again.
Thanks, Robert.
We'll have to set up to
enable you to
share a page.
It looks like I can,
so I'll... Super.
Okay.
Okay, you guys
can see it, right?
Looks good.
Okay, yeah. So
basically, in this demo,
I'm going to
showcase a marketing
example where I
combine Google Search
Console data and
Google Analytics for
data and use it to
convert that to signals
and give you
actionable insights.
So if you look at Google
Search Console data,
what you
essentially see is
basically a
bunch of numbers.
It gives you top queries,
clicks, impressions,
CTR, position.
You know, you can
port this information
and sort it and try
to make some sense of
it. you can kind of
say, okay, the brand
name's up top front. You
know, the other stuff
doesn't necessarily
make obvious sense.
So what I am doing
here is essentially
as a first step,
I've already selected
the company and
I want to, let's
say, do a keywords
analysis and just
ask it to start
doing the analysis.
and and what it'll do
is it'll kind of do
the query analysis
identify the top keywords
and then uh you
know the ones
that are converting
better converting
uh not converting
very well
and do that for
both query and
keywords so it
tells you you
know what are
the most engaged
uh uh queries you
know it gives you you
know dunwoody harley
davidson etc and
with the highest
engagement rate sometimes
quite often the ones
with the highest
engagement rates
have small samples so
they're marked as
insufficient if i want
to i can just mark
it as moderate and um
and get that information
uh if i uh if i look
at what's converting
the least this
information saying that
the Harley Davidson dealer
motorcycle these things
are not converting
very well and then you
have similar information
uh saying you know
what are the what are
the words that are
converting the most um
and then what are the
words that are not
converting uh I mean would
have a higher engagement
rate and then it
also says what's not
converting quite often
what's not converting
is the most interesting
so motorcycle and
motorcycles did not
convert very well cvo i
don't know what that is
but dina didn't convert
very well touring
didn't convert very well
bike women didn't
convert very well so the
other thing is i also
do clustering there's
different algorithms
but you know you can
view what's converting
very well and what's
not converting very
well or what has higher
views, I can then go
in and basically, oops,
done. Okay, let me
try to go to the
next one and try
to do the same.
And try to select
all of this,
like where what
you see is in
these areas, when
you select them,
they all have common
components. So
like right here,
everything here is
related to women and the
words that are not
converting very well.
If somebody is searching
for women's motorcycle
or female motorcycle
or women riders,
they are not converting
very well. So
that gives you some
insights. And what
we then do is we
take this information
and we feed it into
a reasoning engine.
In this case, it
was O3 that did the
reasoning, and it goes
through multi-step
process, comes up with
an executive summary
and tells you the
brand names are doing
very well, but
dealers, service, used
motorcycle, specific
models are not doing
very well. It gives
you the strong
performance, it gives
you the weak performance,
and it gives you why
it's interpreting
that way, what is
the recommendation.
and it identifies
specific
opportunities and
the actions you need
to take from a
marketing perspective
and the rationale,
et cetera.
And then the user sees
this, the marketing
person sees this,
the other stuff that
I showed you before
can be automatically
executed like on a
weekly or monthly
basis. And then if
you want to drill
down and take more
actions, then you can.
But the other thing
is, so that's at an
individual section level.
So there's a different
report for affinity.
There's age analysis,
gender analysis. So
we do demographic,
psychographic, all this
information. And then,
you know, we can
make a recommendation
and then use another
reasoning engine to
consolidate all of them
and then give them the
best few recommendations
and the predicted
lift out of it. um
um yeah and and and
then another step to
do is like based on
this data and specific
analytical input you
can generate content
that's very much
targeted so it'll tell
you for this group that
is like women motorcycle
or something like
that uh it will um um
you know it creates
this ad and these are
the points that it
wanted to mention and
here's a copy and you
can edit it and so
on. So we combine it.
Yeah.
So you've got,
you're doing some
sort of like
analytics. And is that
analytics being
analyzed by an
LLM or using like
a machine model?
So the analytics
itself is done using
stats and ML algorithms.
And then the reasoning
on top of that is
done by OpenAI O3.
And what kind of ML
model are you using?
Well, we are using
scikit-learn, various
clustering algorithms
like HDB scan,
you know, various
ways to take the word
vectors, word
embeddings or phrase
embeddings, and map
it into a 2D space.
All that's the
analytics. And if it's
predictive analytics,
then we go into more
advanced stuff, usually
just classical machine
learning as opposed
to deep learning.
But because the
deep learning
stuff is harder to
automate, right?
But what we found
out is when we asked
LLMs, like even O3,
to kind of do some of
this analysis, the
results we got is very
different and not the
best. So we fed them.
Yeah, so that is the
question. And how
do you determine that
the reasoning models
are particularly
susceptible to
reinterpretation of
the information you get
it? So you might say
that there's a 2% to
4% CPA reduction or
whatever. But how
do you know that that
number that is being
spit back to you
in the executive
summary hasn't been
altered when there's
like a 20% chance that
it's been altered?
uh so so basically
what we're trying to do
is we're trying to
minimize the number of
steps that the llm takes
we are pre uh like we
are gathering a certain
amount of information
and putting it to
that and then we are
validating it so we
have like creating and a
validation uh engine
and then it spits it out
so unless it passes
through the validation
check it doesn't So
it's like a grounding
system of some sort
that indicates that the
input is the same as
the output or something?
The input maps
to the output,
yes. Okay, cool.
Independent.
So what's interesting
about what you're
describing, I did a post
last week on this idea
of agentic marketing,
which plays perfectly
into what you're
describing. using your type
of approach you could
tie this into let's
say like a meta ads
campaign have it understand
the demographics that
work and then the
and then more explicitly
the ads that you
need to sell a female
motorcycle enthusiast
versus a male motorcycle
enthusiast and then
sort of a b test the ****
out of it automatically
until you find the
right combination of
factors now what i
would do just throwing
it out there i would
probably train a secondary
model to optimize
based on that. And then
I can kind of repurpose
those models when
similar demographics
come up in the future.
That's cool.
Okay, yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah.
We did the first
step. We haven't
done a secondary
model yet.
Well, you should totally.
And try that neural
command I was showing
you guys earlier.
That's why I built
it, for exactly
that step. So if
you want to take all
that data, connect
it to the Symantec
Insights Planner
and then create
secondary neural nets
optimized for whatever
purpose, buying
ads or something.
And then you could
take it a step further,
that N8N system I was
showing, you could
actually handle the
execution of the procurement
of the ads, making sure
there's a profitable
flow from someone
buying, and then maybe
taking the first x
amount of revenue and
reinvesting it into
more ads kind of thing
cool thanks yeah that
makes total 100 really
useful really cool
stuff and there's an api
or mcp or some sort of
interface for it you
have no i mean this
is package is an
application right now
it's a sas application at
this point you should
okay one moment i'm
gonna rant i can't
help myself um the one
thing i've discovered
over the last few months
of building a million
of these dashboards
nobody wants a dashboard
in any company and
just just to be clear
everybody wants to be
able to take whatever
crazy thing you built
and use it inside
whatever crazy thing
they've already built
and so so the reality i
think if i'm forming
a thesis here is the
that if you the benefit
to mcps is you can take
this what you exactly
built right now slap
it directly into
chap gpt and all of a
sudden they have the
ability to get all that
data just by asking
chat gpt they're happy
everyone's happy and
there's no you you have
a dashboard used like
cell pocs but no one's
ever going to touch it
beyond the the first
pitch you give the
company yeah i mean
they're just using it
to like validate and
maybe refine the idea
but the most the the
interest that they have
is mostly uh configuring
uh the ads uh and also
generating content
right they're not
they're not that's where
the value comes in
it's not it's not the
dashboard itself ping
me later and and let's
see if we can tie in
that agentic marketing
system i concocted last
week with what you're
doing and see what
we can put out there
because i've already
built something that
probably ties into your
system really easily
to be able to MCP have
my agent tie into that
and come out the other
side with a bunch
of content suggestions
yeah and definitely
in A10 we're targeting
digital marketing,
funnel management and
product managers so
definitely at a corporate
level the A10 workflow
definitely makes sense
longer term for us
Yeah, actually, I'd
be interested to
hear Alex's, Alex
DeBold, because
he does tons of
this sort of thing.
That's basically
your, his entire bit.
Oh, yeah, his hands
up. How do I know?
Sorry, I was just saying,
Alex. yeah no it's
um so yeah Reuven I
want to figure out how
to integrate your piece
so the practice studio
that I demoed a
couple I don't know it
feels like months ago
now um if everything is
so one I've started
to use this analogy of
Apple and CarPlay where
most companies that
are monolithic do are
like the stereo system
in your car and they
will never move away
from it so if you can
use the analogy that
Reuven just said in terms
of like hey you bring
your iPhone into your
car and you can use
car play and it just
enriches the user
experience without
destroying the
legacy infrastructure
that is like a
really easy analogy
that i've been using
over the last couple of
weeks and the second
thing is um if you tie
any of your metrics
back to the actual kpis
for the business so if
you have cac like cost
of customer acquisition
or ltv as like the
most basic metrics that
everybody knows right
and then the second
component of it is um
using the google cloud
cli and again okay
you can if they give
you permissions you can
pull in their historical
ad campaign data and
riven i can talk about
this separately to
basically give like
to create a sandbox to
say in order to establish
a baseline the the
scariest thing about
what Reuven created with
the marketing campaign
if people don't know
how to manage multi
-million dollar campaigns
and I've done this
through SEM and SEO is
that the thing goes
off the rails and you
burn through your client's
entire year budget
because it's not been
controlled properly.
Yeah. So how do you
know your analytics
aren't hallucinating?
You need a baseline data.
If you're doing this
kind of work, where
is another system where
you can pull stuff
into a sandbox to
establish the baseline,
run your algorithms
against the
historical
campaign marketing
data, and then
move stuff forward?
100 yeah really really
well said i i i think
that for me the sort
of marketing and ad
sort of analytic space
i i as you know i love
data i love real-time
data and lots of it and
other than like trading
algorithms which
after a while gets you
know a little monotonous
the marketing related
where you know data
is is probably the most
abundant that we can
get in a kind of real
-time stream so it's
fun to play with and
without compromising uh
like pii data right so
it's you know that's
that's that's that's
important because a lot
of the internal stuff
when we use these
algorithms to do like
churn prediction you know
once you have to get
into the internal data
of the corporation it
just gets much harder
a lot of lot of hurdles
to go through but if
you're connecting to
Google Search Console,
Google Analytics,
or Google Ads, or
like other CDP stuff.
It's the PIA, as
long as you keep,
it's relatively
easy to keep the PIA
out and keep things
secure. So easier,
easy to enter.
One thing I want to
also point out for
anyone that's playing
around with sort of
agentic marketing
-related activities, when
there's a bunch of
like services that are
charging for like
MCPs, and their hosted
services generally
using streamable HTTP,
several of them
were just overtly
fraud. So be careful
in the space.
And they're looking
to basically
steal your keys,
if you will. And as
far as I can tell,
your best bet, if
you are going to
go down this road,
use locally hosted
studio MCPs,
especially if you're
just learning or trying
something out for
the first time. I
would say, I don't know
the exact percentages,
because i make up
like 60 of my stats
but i would say like a
large portion of them
are essentially just
fraudulent trying
to steal your data so
if it's remote unless
you really trust them
like super base or
a company you you
definitely know like
google's of the world
i would basically steer
clear of any hosted
mcps for now thanks
good advice yeah all
right uh can i uh before
we go to the next,
I'm going to show
you something quick.
Can I get the screen
share back? Yeah,
there we go. So while I
was showing you guys,
or we were talking
earlier that the goal
MCP kept running here,
and you can see here
that it created a new
workflow, specifically
using that GOAP.
I'm going to change
that to goal because I
think GOAP sounds
terrible. But anyway,
you can see your parse
goals, assesses current
state, it authenticates
against my Flow
Nexus system. It
discovers available
actions from the
Flownexus system. And then
it creates a plan. It
validates the plan.
It executes the plan
and so on and so forth.
This is pretty much
the workflow for
anything analytical that
needs to continually
run and make decisions,
ads, trading,
whatever. This is pretty
much the flow you're
always going to use.
And then this just
runs in a circle forever
and ever and ever.
So hopefully
that was helpful.
Who's up next?
We got some
open mic time.
If somebody has
something that they
want to show, has
been working on.
All right.
We got a little
bit of a...
There's never a dull
moment, as you know.
I've got plenty to
show. Hey, Jed, I know
you've been working
on some cool stuff.
What do you got?
I don't know that I
can share it, Roof.
That's part of the
problem. This is cool
stuff on behalf of
others. Solving a problem
in a place where I
am paid to solve it.
That's too bad.
I have a comment or
observation
for the group.
I just,
right up to now, up to
literally yesterday,
I've been steadfastly
sticking with Python
because I know that
you don't like Python
because of its indentation
and all that, but
I just had this fear
that, you know, I got
to be able to modify
the code and I know
Python so I can customize
it well yes I was
trying to program
a microcontroller
and uh it's the
thing with C++
so you know I
thought all right
I'm just gonna
do it and um
sure enough it was
fine I don't know why
I was so fearful of
switching the you
know having my agent
coding partner generate
a different language
i mean i was
easily able to customize
what i needed to
and uh the whole
point of your ai
coding partner
is that it does
the onerous
boilerplate that you
despise of language x
y or z i'm looking at
you jvm but um yeah
so that's just an
observation probably
obvious to everyone but no
i okay sorry go ahead
uh so i have a similar
i think i made it
here like i made it to
multiple people not
sure like where and to
whom uh i had a very
similar experience i
always wanted to learn
go and recently i was
working on a gizmo that
has to go on all kinds
of machines like
very ancient like bsd
servers like ancient
linuxes and stuff and
apparently go is the only
sort of platform that
you can just drop the
binary it has everything
it's just single
file and it runs like
and i was had very
good experience and
actually i would just
write the code in python
and tell the cloud code
basically implement
this in go and it was
pretty good and even
when it was like kind
of messing up like go
is very like it's a
standard language kind
of like so it's if you
know javascript python
and stuff you can look
at go code and see
like exactly where it
messed up but that's
my comment in there so
i like go i i i want
to like it more and
every time i think i'm
gonna go with go i've
done a few things in
go recently i ended up
going back to rust and
i had the parallel
thing with go and rust
so rust you cannot deploy
like as many places
as with go like no i
had the exact opposite
problem so rust i can
compile to wasm and
deploy everywhere
without any worry of like
any kind of um
dependencies whatsoever go
had had more dependencies
now for the go i
i quickly realized
that i could compile my
go as a wasm also and
as soon as i realized
like i could compile
my go as a wasm to have
all the same benefits
i then realized that
rust just worked better
as a wasm and i'm
like back to rust again
i had actually around
the parallel thing i
was running one cloud
doing go and another
cloud doing rust like
the bot came up with
the thing that works
but when i went around
deployment i had the
problem with rust if
you see library if
you're running some
ancient operating system
and the c library is
ancient there rust has
dependency on it and
it will um and also i
had to talk to all
these cloud providers at
the same time all the
google cloud and amazon's
like so that's like
i had like go just
works out of the box
basically that's for me
yeah no i and 90 of
it is is just does
it work bottom bottom
line is basically
it's kind of like
there is less fear now
of doing stuff in
unfamiliar language
big if it's language
like kind of looking
standard go doesn't
look many different
than python and c It
has four loops and has
like methods, function,
classes. So you can
understand what the
code is like. You can
actually look and see
what it does like.
My biggest issue
with Python, and if
anyone that's done
any kind of, you know,
agentic coding in
Python is the, again,
indentation. How
much time does it
spend fixing inappropriate
indentations?
And it's such a
stupid sort of problem
that it runs into.
Oh, I didn't tab
it enough. And that
never happens in
Rust or JavaScript
TypeScript ever,
right? Yeah, because
they have curly braces.
Yeah, so if you
want to save
easily 20% to 30%
in terms of token
cost and time,
avoid Python.
Although, to be fair,
my recent C++
microcontroller code
had some curly
braces mismatch that
was eerily reminiscent
of this issue.
I'm not saying it
goes away, and anyone
that's played with
TypeScript sees the same
exact thing, or even
worse, I've put the same
function in three
times for some unknown
reason, you know, that
stuff doesn't go away.
But it spends less
time on it, and this is
just my sort of view.
I don't find it as
big, because I do see,
but I put a lot of
unit tests and rough
and everything, so it
kind of, like,
automatically, where I just
let it run and it just
doesn't stink alike.
Yeah, yeah, for sure.
Forgive me for
being a developer,
but I had a really
quick question.
When it takes away
the indents, and
because I'm not a
developer, I don't know,
the code will
still run, true?
No. Python, no.
Well,
sort of.
It depends how badly
the indentation is. So
if, you know, if the
function is related
to another and the
indentation is, you know,
one or less or more
different than the
other, and the relational
sort of sub functions
will break. So maybe
if it's the first
thing, it'll run, but
everything else won't.
The worst problem
is actually if the
indentation messed
up and the code
still runs because
it does not what
it's intended to
do. Like it's still.
Yeah, I can see
that. I can see that.
so it's trying to fix
the code but sometimes
the automatic over
fixes what doesn't
need yeah that's why
unit tests have help
a lot because there
is the second party to
actually because you
wrote the code you
think it does what it
does and it actually
ran you don't get no
errors but then it
doesn't do what's what
was the intent like
it's just the code that
runs like which Yeah,
that's why I go
back to that. When I
teach, I try to teach
human in the loop because
people are fascinated
by these tools.
But what I teach
everybody is that for AI,
the place we have the
input is on the output.
it yeah but i usually
have a three agents
like a team of three
agents one does the
testing another one
does sort of quality
control and another one
writes the code like
so they all kind it's
like all agents in
the loop but they um
counterbalance each
other that's like where
this whole generative
ai came from like
because and again since
i'm in the presence
of so many geniuses uh
i had been advised i
put it in a chat uh i'm
starting to play with
ai agents now uh i
have been advised to
start with the uh ai
agent from chat gpt
it's called gpt agent
mode for you know
those of us that are
relatively new to coding
and that was a good place
to start are there
any thoughts on that
I'm of the opinion
you should ask
the LLM to explain
a thing to you.
Don't bother trying
to use a human-curated
course. Have the LLM
investigate the code
that you're
working with or the
documentation associated
with the feature and to
explain it in terms
that are related to
the question you're
asking. One, you'll
learn how to develop
a framework for asking
specific questions
about specific topics.
So it increases your
speed of learning.
And two, the biggest
thing I try to
educate others on
is human in the loop
effectively means you're
micromanaging the AI.
I'm a much bigger
advocate for
autonomous AI loops,
something that
Roof pioneered
however long it's been
now, eight months,
what longer?
So I try to, because
of the risk of
AI doing things that
are not expected
or creating
unhappy accidents,
I always make sure that
the AI or LLM-powered
tools that I'm running
run inside sandboxes
that are wide enough to
allow the development
of these happy and
unhappy accidents
while simultaneously
retaining tall enough
walls to prevent the LLM
from escaping and also
prevent malicious
actors from getting in.
One note.
So in regards to the
question of using chat
GPT's agent uh and
versus um some of their
other capabilities
their that agent system
that they devised
isn't necessarily truly
agentic it it's geared
towards like web-based
access to things it's
i think what they
rebranded their operator
system to um so if
you're looking at creating
you know autonomous
recurring operating
systems you know that
don't that don't stop
after your chat's
over, that ain't it.
So OpenAI does have a
really nice hosted agent
API. Actually, in my
opinion, it's actually
one of the best.
They've got native MCP
integration. They've
had it forever at this
point. It runs really
well. It's cheap. It's
direct integration
with all the various
OpenAI tools. Now, the
drawback is it's hosted
on OpenAI, but if
you're already in the
Microsoft OpenAI ecosystem,
whatever. It's just
another point of
lock-in for you. And
it's easy to get going.
So if you want to
start playing, that's
probably the easiest
place to play.
No hosted environments,
no nothing.
Just point at that.
It's like magic.
All right.
Any other comments here?
I had a couple things
to make folks aware
of. There were a
couple of cool articles
that came out one
was talking about how
people are using wasm
to compile the cloud
backends and make them
30 to 40 percent more
efficient so kind of
on your whole wasm
run that was a really
interesting article
where did you see that
oh yeah that's that's
that's right up my
alley the and and it
was like dumb discovery
it's like i can
take some random python
project and improve
the performance It's
a thousand X by just
basically re-transcribing
it into Rust.
And that's literally
how Roof Swarm and, you
know, the neurodivergent
libraries came
to be. I just took
the Python and said,
rebuild this exact
Python library, Rust, and
then do a comparative
analysis to tell me
that it works and how
much faster is it.
Yeah, and there's another
interesting article
from Mary Muriati.
She sounds like an
evil villain, but she
was a founder, CTO of
OpenAI and started
thinkingmachines.lab.
And they found
how to get AIs to
give the same
answer when they
dial down
temperature to zero.
And the thing that was
causing variant answers
was the order of the
calculations done
in the neural net. So
if they force an order
of calculation, they
can get the same answer
every time, which
was really kind of
interesting and you know
how do you lock down
an ai to give a predictable
response and then
the third decision
100 the same floating
point precision uh
they didn't say that in
the article they just
control the uh order
that all the math was
done on the neural net
it is yeah it's actually
i was reading that
and there was something
else because one
surprise i mean it's
not surprising it's
actually been known
and it's like how this
browser trackers
works the gpus are non
-deterministic like so you
can get different results
from the same calculation
like on different
gpus like and i think
what she was pointing
at if you're on a
big shared host that
shares models with
others like even if yours
is isolated you get
the kind of noise
influence like from the
other so it's a noisy
neighbor kind of problem
the other the other
interesting one was
open ai's paper on the
cause of hallucination
so they looked at
why the the way they
train now models give
very confident incorrect
answers and it's
because it's much like
multiple choice tests
and you know college you
you don't get in some
of them you don't get
penalized for putting
the wrong answer in
so it's better to
guess than leave it
blank and so they found
that if they change
the reward function so
that you know if you
get it wrong you get
penalized if you get it
right you get plus plus
one point and if you
say i don't know you
don't lose anything
you get zero you get a
neutral point and they
think if they add that
to the ais there'll
be you know less
hallucinations happening
so really interesting
discoveries about how
those models work and
it's almost all our
problems right now are
interrelated to either
this idea that it answers
the question regardless
of whether that
answer is is true it
almost wants to solve
problems without actually
solving the problems
and make you happy
or something you're
absolutely correct never
say that again please
right it's like i didn't
i don't want to be
absolutely correct i
just want you fix it
now it's interesting stuff
guy really appreciate
the update there's uh
there's no shortage
of interesting
opportunities i'm not sure
if that's a uh 10
billion dollar startup
idea that she had seems
like a random tuesday
to me but um good good
for her yeah i guess
yeah it's like that's
it's like i i'm
totally missing the
value proposition
how she raised $2
billion, but I guess
I'm impressed that
you could do that.
The space is a
little overly
frothy. Let's just
leave it at that.
Yeah, I'll just make
a quick note here.
It's either traction
or track record in
the Valley when it
comes to VCs and there's
so much money trying
to get invested.
It's like her resume
is what they invested
in regardless of
what she was really
trying to do. Well,
let's think of it this
way for a moment. So
let's hypothetically
say we agree that the
companies were $10
billion, which we've
been told, no product,
no revenue, a random
thesis paper that
probably could be done
with deep research.
Now, the investors
are looking for a
minimum buyback on that,
like minimum, let's
say even conservatively,
they're looking
for 10x, they're
late, late, late
investors. That makes
that means she would have
to sell her business
for $100 billion
for any of their
investors to make their
quota or whatever,
their carry.
And even
conservatively, say it's
like 3x, that's
still $30 billion.
To get the $30 billion,
she either needs to
have a **** of a lot
of users in the many,
many millions of
users of her service,
which again, it's
a GitHub repo, or
she's going to have to
generate substantially
more revenue in
the order of probably
multiple billions
to support that as
well, there is no way
any of their investors
are ever going
to make their money
back unless she sells
as like an acqui
-hire for $30 billion.
Maybe, I guess,
OpenAI will
hire her back,
but it's the very
definition of
a Ponzi scheme.
Hey, guys, I can tell
you that there's a
couple posts that just
went on Twitter that
i saw that basically
said you know if if you
go if you're growing
at 30 percent year
over year it's not enough
it's basically like
you're either a rocket
ship but there's
no defensibility in
terms of like people are
raising more money so
fast that the people
throwing money at
the companies haven't
seen customers churn
yet so there's no
defensibility so contracts
haven't renewed yet
in terms of what
they're doing um so like
in my in my case of
the unsexy industry of
global eyewear it's
like these people are
monoliths it's a
valuable business we're
applying ai but there's
this basically uh the
old playbook used to
be triple triple double
double just show growth
but now it's either
you're either profitable
and a small one
-person team with a
very good product or
you have this obscene
ridiculous um hockey
stick of stuff but um
if you guys want i can
you something that
I'm trying to release
on Monday. I'm having
some annoying related
Claude issues
because it keeps
on applying mocks
when I tell it
to only do
testing in Docker.
It's up to you guys
if you want to see it.
Yeah, I'm game.
We all suffer through
simulations and
mocks, by the way.
And that's the drawback
to a test-driven
development
approach is the line
between the test
and the real thing.
Yeah.
So can you guys
see my screen?
yeah we see we see a
loud yeah super admin
dashboard yes so
basically one of the one
of the aspects of of
what i've been trying
to do for varia is a
vertically integrated
platform and what i
actually believe is that
how we bring products
to market like this
cup is ultimately
going to change because
everybody designs
products in in a browser
sorry people tend to
design stuff and whatever
in in autocad or
whatever process they
get quotes from china
and it comes back so
one of the aspects of
um our platform was
hey how do we accelerate
the process between
manufacturers and
product designers so
that you can collapse
that whole process um
you guys have seen
platforms like sketchfab
um that allows
people like upload 3d
models and you know,
all this kind of stuff,
it's kind of like,
okay, this is kind
of fun, but it's kind
of useless because
it doesn't have a
business function. Like
you can see and you
can see the models.
This system, which
I'm currently in the
midst of testing, I
was able to create
like dozens of tests,
is that any design
team can come in and
actually start loading
their models. So I
have a team in India
that actually makes
3D models on behalf
of brands, right?
So we get continuous
briefs for making 3d
models right so if
you go here so we literally
get on we literally
get these two
-dimensional drawings from
the brands from around
the world and we
turn them into we
send them into autocad
then we create glbs
and then you have these
wonderful 3d models
that look like this
this process is still
really slow it's
cumbersome but it
takes a lot of work to
generate this there's a
whole bunch of technical
problems around
making photorealistic
issues i believe there's
an opportunity to
compress all of this
but in order to do this
i needed to build a
collaboration platform
so now i'm basically
i think i've written
or i've used claude
flow to write over
112 different personas
between the project
the team approvals a
commenting system and
a whole bunch of scoped
roles and permissions
because we're talking
about intellectual
property here so
we're doing work for
brands like Bugatti and
Aconi who are giving
us designs before
they go to the market.
So not only do you have
to have the individual
roles and assets and
role-based access
control, but all the
assets have to be segmented
and separated between
different pieces.
So as you go through
this process,
and now it's going to
break the second
I do this,
you can create the
teams, you can invite the
teams, it can be across
the entire process.
and right now in the
back end it's complaining
because i'm doing
development on my mac
and it's a different
ios than claude i'm
sorry than um the deployment
but i've literally
written a zillion
different tests for the
seeding process to
establish each of the
individual personas in
the platform so you know
here are all of the
different roles here's
all the different kinds
of permissions between
the admin the super
admin the cat designer
the designer the
manufacturer and actually
threading all of the
stuff together which
is a massive step change
in terms of the ability
to produce stuff because
otherwise I would
be sitting there
waiting for my teams to
do stuff one at a time
so there's thousands
of lines in terms of
project management built
and the dependency
between everything else
but Claude Flow has
been a game changer in
being able to write
all of these individual
unit tests and continuously
and this is one
thing that has me crazy
i've been updating
the clod flow to make
sure that like do not
do anything without
mocks only do testing
through docker because
i want a consistent
testing environment so
i've got all the rules
and the personas and
the tests written but i
want this process between
the env for dev env
for staging env for
prod to be consistent
and that's just been
one of my struggles kind
of finalizing this
project because i know
the components are right
i know the logic is
right but that last
little piece of getting
out the door is driving
me super badass the
last five percent takes
95 of the time and
i've said been saying
this for a while the
you can crank out this
crazy dashboard in like
10 minutes and it
doesn't do anything but
it looks amazing and
then and then you spend
you know weeks trying
to debug the data the
off and the and the
admin versus the end
user and all that sort
of stuff and the ai
doesn't necessarily help
so much there it actually
in some ways the the
more stuff you're
cranking out the more
stuff you have to validate
later and and it's
still somewhere someone
has to check it yeah
that is a beautiful
real world use case
of swarm orchestration
yeah you know one last
thing you should do
um uh in terms of like
trying to keep it on
rails try the goal um
uh component i've been
pushing so much today
that that's the that's
the intention is because
i've been suffering
through all the same
things you guys probably
have like it's lying
to me again and
that's my attempt to try
to solve that problem
i'll have to go back
and look at the first
part of the video the
last little wiggle
that i had in this
platform that i built was
the ability to get
quotes so i actually
believe that the trillion
dollars of products
that are shipped as
we all talk about
tariffs or else we hear
about tariffs in the
news. I actually believe
that this process
potentially has the
ability to basically
shorten the lifecycle
of product development
because there's real
-time commenting built
into the whole process.
There are a couple
of really cool, so
there's two things.
I actually have a grant
from the NRC right
now from IRAP around
the 3D modeling
process and texturing.
And there's also a bunch
of cool open source
library around CAD.
My dream scenario
would be like, I
train an AI model
on what eyewear is,
right? Eyewear has
certain components in
the 3D space, and I have
over 10,000 examples
of these CADs and
GLBs in my directory.
If that is the basis
of understanding a
3D space and an
object and how it gets
textured and has a
logo and a screwdriver,
like the frames
that Rue's wearing,
theoretically if
you could have a
texture library
and you had a base
library of objects you
could theoretically
train an ai agent
right to help
you co-develop a
pair of eyeglasses
in in the 3d space
because there are there
are now people
working on cad like an
ai versions of cad
yeah and then then you
can apply to any
vertical is alex what
would you say the
resolution is for real
world 3D scanning. So
for example, if I were
to scan your face,
could I then customize
a pair of glasses
according to whatever
design parameters
that perfectly fits?
I believe
that's done now.
Yes. I know it's
possible with a Kinect,
but Kinect resolution
is quite low on
the order of one
point per, I think,
two square millimeters.
So it doesn't have
to be that accurate.
So right now media
pipe tracks 468
points in your face.
I can actually show
you demos or send
links later around
how we're actually,
we've built a tool.
So number one, media
pipe already tracks
468 points in
your face. So if you
turn on your camera
and you use that
library from Google,
you've got that.
You can translate
that data into
millimeters based
on the pixels
on your screen.
Right? And like, I
can get your PD, the
distance between
your eyes within one
millimeter using an existing
camera on any device
i actually had a
pair of glasses that
i ordered online i
went totally online and
the glasses were
delivered to me and as
you said it did all
the measurements on i
was amazed well i had
to use my phone yeah
well and your phone
uses lidar so what i
built actually doesn't
require lidar so
i'm going to show you
guys this this is a
tool we just built.
What phone has LiDAR?
Yeah,
at least I know
I have an iPhone,
so for me, things
be pretty good.
Yeah, iPhone front-facing
camera is LiDAR-based.
So they have it, but
they're no longer
using that, right?
They're starting to
switch over to the
other algorithms with
image recognition.
Yeah, the resolution
on LiDAR is lower
than camera, correct?
Yeah, I'm going to
show you guys this.
So this is a fitting
height tool. So here
I actually have in my
database the glasses
and I have all the
dimensions, the physical
dimensions of the
glasses in my database.
If I skip all of this, I
actually activate
the camera.
And I actually
grab the frames.
I don't know if
it's going to work
because I'm
sharing my screen.
Oh, it does.
So here I'm
directly into the
camera, I'm
tracking my eyes.
it's going to measure
is this your app yep
and actually built it
using agentix i i'm
i'm so impressed by
alex i've known alex
for for 20 something
years and seeing your
evolution is just
astounding to me you you're
you always amaze me
really really good i
just need to commercialize
this now so this
tool might be used
by a retail two one
in europe and one here
so you guys remember
the commerce studio.
No, I showed you
the practice studio.
I have another
application that I'm
launching, but this is
one of the apps.
This replaces a $20
,000 piece of equipment
in the optician.
So I've just
given you your
left eye, your right eye.
I've actually,
because I know
the measurements
of your face,
I can do all of this.
So this is on my
standard MacBook
camera, not using LiDAR,
accessing the MediaPap
library with a
whole bunch of code
in the back end.
That's amazing. have
you actually looked
into doing things
where it's actually i
mean i'm imagining based
on that if they turn
to the left and the
right being able to
get the distance from
the front of their
face to the back of
the ears for comfort
fit of all that stuff
like have that all
completely integrated
in so that it becomes
more like a lidar scan
where you're getting
that full 3d based
on just that or so
there are other there
are other companies
that um i would love
to do all of But yes,
the four platforms that
I've developed have
been like hundreds
of thousands of lines
of code that are
that are now finished
over the last kind of
six or seven months.
That would be nice to
do, but not a need to do.
Because ultimately
you have things
like the reason why
you have that bubble
and you have my
eyes is that the
second you rotate
your head left or
right, now you're
changing the depth.
So you have to choose
that. It's just it's
not about the technology.
It's about the
users. Like we just
finished something for
parents to be able to
do glasses for kids.
And guess what? Kids who
are five don't sit still,
right? Well, one of the
things I'm wondering
right now is because
looking at that and
one of the things I'm
playing around with
right now with stable
diffusion and depth
perception stuff is
being able to take those
images, but actually
then generate the depth
map of it from that
image, even if it's just
like assessed right
now. but if you're
looking at it and you're
doing the media pipe
thing media pipe is
just doing heuristics on
finding where the face
is but we can actually
now use agents to go
cool let's get the
depth of that image
and then use that depth
to create the actual
3d model so like you
know right now i have
looking out on my computer
image coming in
running through huyan
getting out with the
3d model of it when i
take that off my face
the model i get of my
face is pretty **** good
even off of my cheap
resolution camera
but if you take media
pipe where you're
getting all those points
those points give you
really really good
triangulation that you
can then build off of yeah
let's let's talk
offline for sure that's
that's absolutely brilliant
yeah research like
thing like almost 10
years ago they were
using the motion to get
much better 3d models
but the trick is you
need to know either
how you're moving like
the camera is moving
or how the object
moving precisely because
if you if you know
that you know exactly
where the points are
going to be and the new
ones come up and you
get much better because
you get the depth basically
just from movement
but you need to know
what the movement
is and I also I've been
struggling with this
whole mocking issue
and I was able to
overcome it just by careful
prompting and I have
a little guidance for
the LLM since do not
mock under any
circumstances right but now
it's actually came
up with the different
sneaky trick it puts in
the test, it actually
puts the test in the
exceptions, and if it
fails, it would actually
have in the catch
things, like checks
if there was an error,
and says the test
passed. So it just
writes the test
that pass all the
time without the pass.
But those are easy to
spot because somehow
Claude always tries to
make the test pass by
subverting the
whole testing system
instead of It does,
and that's the thing
that drives me crazy
with this platform
alone there are 112
individual tests
and it'll say it
passed all the tests,
and then I'm like
okay, but did you
so the one question
for everybody
here is there
are things like
Jest and Puppeteer
and Playwright
you have to make sure
it's running in Docker
I wish there was when
it spins up a swarm,
I wish there was a way
to lock down the persona
to say you are the
tester these are the
tools based on the
application that i've
created and it still
subverts it it'll be like
the problem with that
approach alex is that
if you start the tester
at the beginning of
the project the tester
has nothing to do so
it thinks it successfully
passed all tests
and then turns itself off
while the other agents
are still going you
need something that's
able to spawn the
test instance at the
completion of whatever
code segment so what i've
been doing is i've been
spawning the tester
as a background task
to then review as to
-do items get checked
off the list and somehow
the background task
is able to access that
it will then up it'll
then review based on
whatever testing
infrastructure i have in
place update the
to-do list or flag
the orchestrator
to update the to
-do list which then
prompts the coder to
continue uh building toward
that test there's
another approach there's
There's another approach
that I devised a
few months ago. I called
it stream chaining.
It's very similar to
what Jed just described
as a sort of background
process. So what
stream chaining does,
and specifically in
Claude-flow, allows you
to use inactive Cloudcode
sessions that are
invoked through hooks.
So what happens is
you create a task, and
the task is building a
functional component.
And it might even be
doing some testing.
But once it's done,
you can invoke that
secondary Cloud instance
that doesn't actually
run in the primary
UI. It's basically a
background process that's
using Cloud code and
agents explicitly
geared to solve or look
at different problems.
And in my scenario,
what I'm doing is I'm
getting them to basically
validate against the
original objectives,
specs and strategy
and data, and then
review the tests and
output of the original.
And then if something
isn't correct from
that original sort of
task, you know, you
see five different
agents running, it'll
then continue and
improve and fix those
problems. So by the
time you get to the end,
it takes longer, but
generally it avoided
all those problems
because I'm basically
hooking the streams.
And in those hooks,
I also say, if it's
all good, just stop
and move on to the
next thing. but that
gives it a secondary
look and you can use
it in the hooks so if
you're using Claude-flow
ask it to use the
stream chaining
capabilities of
Claude-flow and update your
config.json in the
.cloud folder and then
you can have that
automatically executed
so I'm going to
re-watch what
you just said
later in the video
I can show you guys
there's so much ****
in there it's crazy
Sorry, go ahead,
Jen. The possibility,
Alex, is to have
two TMOX instances.
One builds, the
other validates,
and they leave notes
for each other.
Hey,
Alex, I put another
thing in the chat. There
was somebody, he was
trying to do the make
LLAMs do solid modeling
because there is a
tool called OpenSCAD.
I was actually using
it a lot for my own
things because I could
never, I mean, I do a
little bit 3D printing.
i could never use
regular card because it's
like to get the
measurements right it's
like super like tedious
so so ultimately you
just it's a code right
you just say you want
the whole thing to be
hundred millimeters
millimeters long right
and then you compute
the other dimension so
i write my like solid
models you're right
listen the one come
we're working with the
warby parker of europe
ace and tate and there
are lots of companies
that actually use
3d printers in their
office to see the fit
of the glasses so they
can monkey around with
stuff and then print
it so like i believe
i truly believe that
the the spam into it
what Reuven is talking
about in terms of agentic
marketing like the
compression cycle in
terms of insights from
what the consumers want
and what the market's
willing to pay for
and the ability to
create it from a front
and iterate super fast
like that cycle is
going to be super super
super small unless
you're talking about a
car but consumables
between like the only thing
you can do at home
is print your lenses.
And that's legitimately
even printing lenses
is going to be something
that's going to
be on the table very
soon. Like it's kind of
crazy how amazing 3d
printing is getting.
Speaking of 3d
printing, I just got
there recently. Now
you can get a little
mini CNC machine.
So it's like the,
it's a lot like ratomail
like, so it's like
all the, because that
way you can actually
do like aluminum. You
can do like acrylic.
you can do like i'm
gonna i'm gonna let you
know right now i have
one they're fun but man
they're a pain in the
*** i mean yeah yeah
because i used to work
like two jobs ago we
had this whole 500 000
cnc machine and like
yeah the desk and actually
yeah it was exactly
like shop like we
actually got it before
we got the 3d printer
for biological stuff
and you can do stuff i
mean if you like a medium
organization you can
spend 500 grand on
the machine and then uh
you can just cut like
things out of aluminum
like within oh yeah
i mean so the what the
bantam tools and don't
get bantam because of
the ownership of it
but bantam tools is a
four thousand dollar
cnc desktop machine um
there it's really fun
to go through but i
think alex what what's
amazing that you're
talking about is exactly
where mindset my mindset
has been there's a
book it's published
i think 2010 called
makers by cory doctro and
he discusses that this
economy that is based
on the idea that
people have essentially
a machine in their house
that can manufacture
anything they want um
it's kind of like a
replicator but it is
built in this whole
this mindset of it's not
star trek where it's
materializing it it is
you know it is 3d
printing it and cnc-ing it
out and it's getting
to these these objects
that change the paradigm
of how the business
economy world works
that whole premise of
you know i'm i'm i
don't have my camera on
but i'm a glasses wearer
my entire life like
glasses are something
that is very unique to
each person they want
their specific taste
and touch you go into
a glass manufacturer
right now into like a
lens lens store they've
got thousands of
different styles that are
just sitting on a shelf
never getting used
and getting thrown out
like they just cycle
through that stuff it's
all they have to be
more data-based if you
have something where it
is a pipeline that
says okay here's your
specific style your
your materials you want
your texturing your whatever
and it can literally
manufacture that
stuff and then code it
all in a shop on the
fly then that changes
the entire paradigm of
that entire industry
um and people will end
up with their exact
what they want there's
very little waste because
you're just talking
about raw materials
coming in in some cases
i think the lenses
printing is something
that i remember reading
and seeing a video on
people have been working
on polished 3d lenses
using resin um if
i remember correctly
and then the ability to
do like the um what
the **** is it there's
a new printer coming
out right now that will
literally 3d print
your textures and your
materials onto surfaces
um yeah you're preaching
to the choir i put
the link While we were
talking, it successfully
deployed to GCP.
I actually built
four components.
So, Verizon is
for vertically
integrated
agentic retail.
So, the design platform,
I built the design
platform, I demoed the
practice studio, the
commerce studio I'm hoping
to launch next week
that has a whole series
of plugins like an
app store that have
the fitting height,
the virtual try-on, the
face shape recognition,
all that kind of jazz.
um yeah so basically
the parts and i built
the whole system for
for cleaning up the
data so yes i agree this
is this is 1 billion
frames were produced
last year um 20 or more
are going to be wasted
i think it's a a
cool opportunity but um
like it's one step at
a time right you have
to make it stupid easy
like Reuven said
before like my commerce
studio has a plugin
for shopify magenta
woocommerce all built
agentically with an app
store that can pull in
all of the data and it
i can't say anymore
because i'm going to
record my whole proprietary
business strategy
here in a public session
so let's just say
that you're not very
far off um there's
four platforms i'm
releasing i've now demoed
two two are in the
background that are going
to be launched in the
next kind of 60 days
and alex just for
everyone that isn't
familiar you're not a
developer right you're
like what's what's what's
your background and
like how do you make
this shift towards to
like master agentic
engineer well uh i have
a degree in political
science on my wall
right there in 1996
uh i launched i am an
early adopter i launched
one of the first e
-commerce textbook
companies in canada in 1996
where i learned that
my development team
didn't understand what
load balancing was.
And that's how I started
learning about code.
So I think of me like a
technical founder, but
not an actual coder.
So I've understood
all of the principles
around software and
design and I can
sit there and talk
with the CTO or others.
The last kind of, I
would say, year and
a half has been
starting with the
individual entity
applications and then
starting just following
what rUv posting.
So just going deeper
and deeper and deeper
and deeper and realizing
I have less and
less and less dependency
on my developers.
And I just saw a
post today, by the
way, guys, that
Shopify is interviewing
product managers and
requiring them to
actually build their
MVPs identically,
right, or at
least with some
kind of vibe
coding application.
So I'm a
technical founder
based on my experience.
I wrote a patent
in 2017 that was
granted in 2019 or I'm
having AI and human
in the loop for
ratings and reviews.
So this has just
given me the shortcut
of not having
to waste cycles
waiting for engineers
to do stuff.
It's massive. Have you
done some research?
Your application is
great, by the way. It's
especially for Amazon
sellers who want
to bring a product to
market and want to get
their own gi joe for
example and have a
design that goes from
china all the way bring
it land it in the
states or have it on
the amazon platform
have you done research
on vibe inventing for
example if and what
that looks like and
why i asked here's why
i asked i was uh
traveling home the other
day i had an idea
i've had several ideas
but hadn't had the
right connections to
bring them to market
what i did the day before
yesterday is that i
got a business plan
i got a um 3d printer
diagram to not to
scale of the application
i did market research
i figured out you
know if this product
exists that i have
all vibed with the llm
and And so, but the
concern is they, you
know, I also asked for
engineering diagrams
and what it visually
could look like and
things like that. So
the concern is how much
of it is me and my
thoughts and how much
is the LLM and can I
patent that, right?
Why bother with
the patent?
Like momentum, win the
market. Who cares about
patent? if you can be
first to market and
dominate faster than
anybody else okay like
what are you gonna do
spend your day suing
suing random people you
know that's not really
a business there's no
no suffer suffer is
absolutely a commodity
like somebody could
literally point clod
or something else at
anything that i've built
or anything that you
guys built and reverse
engineer it the difference
is all of the junk
that i've described
that i've put in the back
end around protecting
intellectual property
routes like all of
this other stuff like
i don't know if you
guys remember but in
the first.com there are
these brothers in
europe who would clone
facebook who would clone
anything that came up
in north america that's
right because they
had enough money to do
it so software is not
a point of differentiation
the question is
can you build the data
mode and in building
the data lake can you
create enough value for
the participants in
your ecosystem that they
don't want to leave
because if lovable is
simply a preset group
of preset stack of react
and whatever else like
there's no defensibility
in lovable they
just have scale and
they have brand recognition
no different than
cheerios versus checks
on the supermarket
shelf oh sorry so i i
like ru's point why bother
with patent but it's
not software it's a
hardware it's a a
physical hardware device.
Yep.
Yeah, that's all.
Matt, but what's
the problem with
patenting output of
the LLM? I think you
can just patent it.
You can, you just
have to have the
money to defend it,
right? I have a
patent and I can't do
anything with it. I
mean, it's a nice ego
thing. I can say I
have a patent now.
Yeah.
Sure. Yeah.
I mean, as long as
it's not prioritized,
nobody checks how
it was produced.
There's a lot of
issues on patents
that this conversation
misses now i'm an ex
-lawyer who did my own
patents so i know a
little bit about them
but the conversation
is like me trying to
understand what rube
is saying so i'm not
ready to engage in
that but there are two
things in patents and
this is not legal advice
Because nobody has
any kind of attorney
-client privilege with
me without a assigned
retainer. But the
two scopes, the two
things that are important
to understand, the
distinction that's
critical is between
this specification, that
is the specific thing
that was built, and
the claims. And the
claims are, imagine
Columbus goes to an
island in North America,
he lands in the
islands. That is the
specification. Took a
trip, landed in an island,
went back. But he claims
all of the territory
of North America for
Spain or Portugal,
whichever one it is. I
don't remember exactly.
That's the difference.
And the scope and
the strength of the
claims is what gives the
patent really a very
powerful usage if it's
used correctly for
security for the MCP
servers. There's a company
called CrowdStrike,
and CrowdStrike is
developing a way of
using the client endpoint
as a way of determining
whether there has been
a prompt injection
before it gets to the
LLM and sanitizing
it in the process. Now,
they have, I think,
I haven't really
examined it, but that
then converts CrowdStrike
into a kind of an
operating system for
the users of whoever
is building on top of
them for scaffolding.
They have never been
profitable from what
I understand, but they
have a huge market
cap and they're a very
well-known company.
So if anybody wants
to develop a security
model like that, they
would have to know
the strengths and
the scope of those
claims, not just the
specific specification
on which it was built.
And that's kind of
where patent law sits
so that, you know,
the idea that a
patent is useless, it
depends on not only
whether you can enforce
it, but it depends also
on whether somebody's
claims preempt what
you're doing, even
though they never
built a specification
that looks anything
like yours. And do
they have the wherewithal
to enforce that
patent application,
that patented object?
And that's where the
rubber meets the road.
So, you know, it's a
little bit more complicated
than the level you
guys are talking
about. I couldn't get...
Sorry, guys, we're
almost out of time. But
I think the takeaway
here, guys, is I was
specifically talking about
software. and the
the ability to copy
create in either direct
or polymorphic do this
but don't infringe is
become ridiculously
simple right so this idea
that the the technology
itself is somehow
a like um unique
differentiator is probably
not much you know maybe
in hardware i suppose
but for for anything
soft it's not really
a differentiator at
this point like the
guy i mentioned you can
literally point your you
know one of our swarms
at and say rebuild
this and do it a way
it doesn't infringe but
i will but i will say
one thing so my older
brother who worked
for the united nations
for 15 years wanted to
build a translator app
and to john's point
like i couldn't get i
got my canadian patent
i couldn't get my u
.s patent because the
the patent examiner just
kept on pulling stuff
out of the hat i was
like no matter what i
just wasn't going to
get it and i was like
It just wasn't worth
it. But I did actually
ask, and this is probably
good, to say, look,
your swarm or your
application is going to
pull in a whole bunch
of code from GitHub.
You should probably
instruct it to make
sure that the terms
of the license
associated with the code
you're incorporating
into your product
allow you to do so.
So you can make
sure that the AI...
Or rebuild it.
Rebuild it. Like,
there's nothing stopping
you from taking someone
else's open source
code that's in a terrible
license and reviewing
it and say, build
me that that doesn't
infringe. And it will
just rebuild the entire,
you know, library for
you. Yeah. But I was
specifically looking
at medical translations
for building an app. And
some of the libraries
were not publicly
reusable. So I had to
make sure explicitly in
my prompt to say, this
is a great amount of
research. these are
really great GitHub
repositories, but do not
use anything that is
commercial for my MVP.
That's really
interesting.
There was an old
school solution for
that. I think
companies called
BlackDAQ. So they
had a product, it was
not very cheap, but
it was basically
preventing just human
developers going
to GitHub and copying
something and pasting
into your code. It
would actually have
the whole base of
the open source code,
and it would just
recognize if this is
the code that matches
against the database.
It's funny you
mentioned Black Duck.
A long time ago, in a
previous life, I was
an open source consultant
and did this sort
of thing for open
source, like early 2000s.
One of my first investors
in one of my early
companies was the
founder of Black Duck,
which is under Boston,
and his name is Doug
Levin, great guy. I
think he's a professor
now at Harvard. um
but yeah really cool
interesting company they
the the problem ultimately
was nobody cared about
intellectual property
right and it was important
but not important
enough for anyone to
say if and when it's
a problem just sue me
it was kind of expensive
because i was like
working like as them
like selecting the
products for security
back then and i talked
a lot of it like that
they wanted 15 grand
just for that like yeah
and not 15 grand that's
like a year or something
like and yeah it's
a long time ago just
take the risk right you
know i think they're
around to some degree
i gotta chill around
yeah i mean yeah i
apologize i've got non
-stop meetings today it's
one of those days where
i go from eight until
seven in the evening
so always a pleasure
thanks everyone who
tuned in and and gave
us an input it was a
little more conversational
which i generally
like um pushed out a new
version of claude flow
earlier this morning
so if you want to give
that to spin i fixed
some mocking issues
surprise surprise so when
now when you uh check
the status the status
isn't bs sorry about
that i even i get
caught up my own uh fake
uh outputs that's been
fixed um claude flow
and is is is it join
the discord channel for
anyone we got some
events coming up uh too
many to count but if
you if you're interested
in hosting an event
let us know we we've
got potential space i
think nick was telling
me in austin for matt
so ping nick about the
austin space and oh one
last thing on mondays
we do our agentics
management meetings at
12 noon um for anyone
that's interested in
learning about what
we're doing to organize
ourselves for the agentics
foundation it's more
like how we are
spreading the gospel of
agentics globally but
i think a lot of people
ask how and where they
can get involved i'll
try to send out a note
um on the uh whatsapp
and discord channel but
there is a management
discord channel you
can join and uh and
we'll share the zoom
and anyone that wants to
join and add their
opinion you're more than
welcome and that's it
i gotta go i'm already
late thanks everyone
thanks bye all right