Testing one, two,
three, testing
one. This is Ruben.
Test, test, test.
Hey, Jed, how am
I coming through?
Softer than usual.
Yeah, I'm at
my lake house.
So I'm using my headset.
So it won't be,
maybe I need to
get a better mic
for the cottage or
something, but for
now, I don't do
these very often
at the cottage.
That's no big deal.
Yeah, I hope yesterday's,
yesterday's uh demo
was okay i kind
of spent a lot
of time on it but
anyway i think most
people don't know
where to start so i
anticipate once the
beta group is let
loose on it they'll
just start poking
holes everywhere it's
a cool idea though
that's it's everything
they can it's fun
building on the
things i've already built
creating applications
it's like layer
cake or something
well usually you
should also be pruning
features me never
pruning features
you go crazy well i'm
i'm like vibing my
way into uh you know
crazy crazy land
since vibe coatings
it's is is terrible
and people don't know
what they're doing
but you know whatever
we know different
and i'm happy to caught
around them you can
create all kinds of
amazing things okay
i see fatigue how's
it going oh he's still
connecting maybe um
yeah so maybe next
week or maybe the
weekend when i get second
i'll i'll uh spin up
a uh whatsapp group
and we'll see if we
can solicit some people
to test there's obviously
quite a bizarreity
up there are 12 of
us oh okay i must
have missed i've been
swamped uh the uh i
i have a tendency to
take too much on like
just that's an fyi
i'm like that that is
my specialty is is
over committing myself
so uh today i'm going
to talk about the
uh sort of mcp cli
centric business
models that are
emerging and i'm using
my stuff as an example
of at least where
my thinking is on
that how and why
it's built the way
it is and i just did
a linkedin post on
the similar subject
that desktop app
seems like it's
been an afterthought
i can never
get the link to a
group yeah it's a
bit it's a bit of
an afterthought
drop this in
your zoom chat
so if you want to
announce to anyone
yeah they're announced
to your beta group
it's there yeah still
yes exactly i'm still
thing a beta group
this is the type of app
that needs a decent
beta group to really
figure out the
competition
system right that's
those are the
currently 11 or
12 volunteers
perfect i'm gonna i
have to publish the
um the actual npx
which is gonna be
super simple again
i'm gonna have a fnx
which is three letters
to get the thing
going or you know
flow nexus but fnx
short kind of
like kate's k
k8s for the
kubernetes crew we
need to have a
discussion on like
our like um i don't
know what you want
to call it like a
service desk for uh
uh the genetics
foundation have you
seen any of that
conversation happening
what service desk
no there's a lot of
debate on service
decks i'm not a big i'm
not a huge fan of
of jira so there's a
bit of a debate
around using atlassian
and stuff like that
buy up another one
ticketing systems are
well defined they're
just a database
let's be honest hey
how's it going
it's very good
the Dubai weather is
is what it is but
I assume it's hot
it is
41 or something
like that and very
humid just had a talk
with Rob and Robert
about opening a
chapter here in Dubai,
so we are proceeding
with that one.
Yeah.
Let me know. We've got
quite a few
people in Dubai.
Yeah.
I was talking with
Rob and Robert, so
at least they sent
me some Jake Nguyen
who's also someone.
I posted. And we
might be able to... I
think there's a facility
in Abu Dhabi, 42.
have you been there
yeah yeah so we yeah
we've got a new
relationship uh i'm not
sure if we're allowed
to announce it yet or
whatever but we with
42 i think it's the
same org i'm if i'm
not mistaken and they
might it might they're
a base out of paris
i think um but we
could probably use
their facilities yeah
that'd be nice globally
yeah the abu dhabi
is one and a half
hours two hours away
and Abu Dhabi is like
one-fifth of Dubai
size and usually
people don't
travel that much
between these
cities for events so
I will definitely
be talking with okay
Rob and Robert will
be coordinating that
one so yeah well
you can hop in your
friendly neighborhood
Lamborghini
and get there in
like 20 minutes
it has to be a
Rolls Royce what
do you see Rolls
Royce or Ferrari?
I see more Rolls Royce
where I live because
this is one of
the best places so
there's a garage
downstairs so at least five
and once the
number in the
plate is something
that is meaningful and
there was number one
in front of my building
and that's kind of
super hyper expensive
plate that they're
paying tens of
thousands of euros for
that to get that plate
or even more it
usually means that some
their highnesses as
they call this emirate
okay
uh yeah it's it sounds
like a an interesting
country yeah and
very interesting
oh by the way you're
more than welcome to
join my uh training
sessions on the 9th and
23rd for the trading
trading system don't worry
about it i'll get you
in there okay good
all right so what are
we doing for time 10
minutes been been busy
building this week
i'm i'm worried that my
clog code is going to
run out of capacity in
in a week and a half
and so i've been
cranking out lots of new
stuff i just can't help
myself it's just like
every time i get an
idea i'm like oh i
just gotta go build that
so i'm like a kid in
a candy store that with
no self-control but
the uh the difference
is i'm building crazy
uh web apps for or
libraries for no particular
purpose may i ask
Reuven when you're
doing this uh these
different types of projects
how much you you
keep on adjusting the
the the agents and their
their like contents
how they behave i think
that you mentioned
something about that
you have a wiki about
it or also but for
different type of projects
are you creating new
agents perhaps or are
you using the same
same agents for all i'm
changing them all i'm
totally customizing
the agents the commands
and the cloud md one
and and it's it's a
battle with um anthropic
so they keep changing
their internal guidance
system so i have to
keep modifying the
way that the system
you know invocates the
agents so I had to do
an update yesterday
that was literally
nothing more than changing
my guidance so it
would tell it to use uh
Claude agents and uh
tasks so we invoke it
correctly and that was
a change that they made
a week or so ago so
everything I do is
customized to the
particulars of the thing I'm
doing and building
how do you do that are
you asking Claude to
change the behavior yeah
exactly what I'm doing
so once I so there's
two parts of it once
I built the thing I
have to optimize it.
So when I'm using, I'm
generally creating
either CLIs or MCPs for
the tools that I'm
building. Then I integrate
those into CLAW
directly, both as an MCP
and I get the commands
and agents to understand
that those MCP tools
are available for
it to use in whatever
context. Then I get
it to sort of run deep
sort of variants on
how to use the whatever
tool and optimize and
check for errors and
and problems and things
like that and that
creates a reciprocal
kind of self-improvement
of the system once
it's built so it ensures
that it's not fake
right are you relying
solely on on the cloud
code on this this one
or are you using perhaps
the gemini cli to
to like validate or
improve those i uh i
use rue or klein as a
secondary validation if
if there's breakage in
the mcp or cli that that
could cause uh problems
um i've been looking
at you know using
open code i just haven't
had time to really
fully implement it okay
sst open code project
yeah so so basically
all of the projects
that you have a different
types of behavior of
these agents uh in
order to get the best
results yeah keep in
mind i'm doing easily a
dozen to some weeks, 20
different projects on
the fly. So, you know,
between all the random
calls I have and
things I'm building,
things I previously built,
you know, I'm juggling
dozens of these things,
you know, both on
the fly. Someone
calls me up, you know,
randomly on a Tuesday and
says, I need something
built. And you've got
60 minutes to build
it to longer term
engagements right so i'm
i'm juggling a lot so
the way that i the way
that i keep organized
in this sort of high
high text shifting which
is me i um i make sure
that my agents and my
commands are specific
to what the thing
needs to do so when i
come back in two weeks
and forgot totally what
i built all i need to
do is know that my the
structure i set up for
the customer or client
in the agents folder
and commands and clod
are set up basically
correctly unless
they've changed them
but generally they don't
mess around with that
stuff and then i just
continue on where i left
off and the other thing
i do is i create
issues in github with
details of whatever it
is that i built yeah so
basically if you're
updating cloud flow
something that you have
like a backup of these
agents and you will
just uh then then use
those yeah the other yeah
the other part of the
equation and depending
on the clients larger
companies don't always
want me to include
my fireflies but the
fireflies records every
single conversation
i have and stores it
into a into my google
drive and then because
chat gpt and claude
both have integrations
with google drive all
i need to do before my
call or or let's be
honest during my random
calls it'll i'll go and
say you know chat gpt
or claude tell me
everything i need to know
about what was previously
discussed and what
i need to do going
forward and that gives
me a kind of long-term
memory because it's
really hard to remember
everything when you're
doing 20 or 30 different
random calls a week
yeah sure that makes
sense okay thanks that
helps a lot hi rob
yeah hey tommy good to
see you again i find it
really neat roof that
you've got uh that
it's actually rue still
has a place in the ide
to help manage uh mcp
servers yeah i right
yeah i'm using the i'm
using the uh cloud
code integration mind
you but uh to save a
few bucks but yeah works
pretty good yeah neat
they're making and
they've We've got an
agent system coming soon.
That's a question
related to Claude-flow
and the
integration between
the user interface
and the background,
the front end and
the background.
I have heard someone
else also than me having
problems with the
integration from the
front end to back end
because of the Spark
methodology or something
in the agents that
tend to fill in with
a hack or a mock data
or a quick fix if they
run into something.
That's a thing.
100% it's a thing.
And I've been working
on, if you do the
latest version to help,
you'll see that
there's a truth of
verification and a pair
programming paradigm.
Now, unfortunately, I
have to spend more time
actually showing people
how to use it. But
basically what that does
is when you integrate
that into your
development flow, So let's
say you have a multi
-phase implementation,
you can have a validation
and verification
phase as part of it,
and you create a series
of agents that basically
are explicit for
the project that you
want to build. And as
it progresses through
the project, it chooses
different agents, and
then it has hooks or
explicitly defined in
the agent prompt when
to use the verification
steps to validate
that it's not fake,
simulated, or BS. Yes.
Yeah. Yeah. And I
actually have tried this
trust score 95 or
something, but still there
was the Claude seems
to try to do something.
And you have to be
really careful. I myself
tell to my team and
other acquaintances that
you become a manager
who is like overseeing
what the team has
done. and you have to
sometimes double check
even if you ask from the
court that how did you
do did did you do any
any uh mocks or find
out something at first
no no everything is
working but then you
just don't yeah yeah
it's it's a challenge and
it's getting worse um
i think getting worse
it's getting worse
yeah not better it was
easier a month two
months ago so it's it's
something has that has
to do with the guidance
and brad last week uh
showed an example of
his prompt that he's using
for sort of grounding
so the key is the
grounding it's how do
you you know how you
define what's real and
you explicitly define
the the output and
validation of the output
that is you know using
a database and the
proper algorithms and
whatever it is that
it's supposed to do and
it's not just returning
some data that indicates
that it works the
way it's it thinks it
should and yeah so
that that all has to do
with context engineering
and and if you don't
explicitly define what
it needs to do in terms
of and how to validate
that it did those
things then you're
gonna get you're gonna
likely get a first
iteration that's basically
mocked which is okay
but then then you want
to go from mock to
real and then that that
is a a test driven
development process that
indicates how you tell
it what's real and what's
fake yeah and i i
think that's just a
question related to that
if you're going to put
a hive mind to work on
the project it tends
to get more more of
the mock data and then
later on you will be
able to if you narrow
down the task and give
more exact prompt then
it will produce better
results do you agree
with that yeah i do
yeah exactly so it's and
but to be honest when
i see that i'm like
well that's why we the
world needs agentic
engineers and it all
it like validates our
existence as as
professionals in the space if
you know at a point
where you just randomly
ask a question and it
magically sort of gives
you the answer we
there's the question of
our our valid our value
becomes less but i
don't i don't see that
happening anytime soon
but still it's so much
faster okay it's it's
it's ours thank you
yeah we're at yeah
we're at we're at the
top of the hour so just
as a quick uh a quick
warning to all this is
going to be long oh
we lost you we've got
we got cottage level
cottage level lag roof
yeah okay we go oh
all right so uh you're
back oh yeah i'm i'm
i'm on the uh i'm
i'm on the wi-fi
at the internet
unfortunately so hopefully
this holds through
all right i'm gonna
broadcast and max
out my uh my system
here all right