right going live
hey it's the 24th of
july time flies today
i'm i don't have a
huge i don't have a
solid plan but i do
have a bit of a plan i'm
going to dig around
a little bit in the
open code cli maybe
i'll show you guys a
little of this web
dashboard that i've been
working on for the uh
cloud cloud flow and
separate the system
from the use of Claude
as much as I can.
But to be honest, I
haven't been able to
find any CLIs that really
come close to the
ability to sort of run
things in a kind of
concurrent fashion.
Supposedly, the open
code system does that.
So I was going to try
to investigate that
a little bit. But in
the little that I've
investigated, I've
struggled a little to
get uh it looks like
it defaults to like
the github use uh
github i don't know what
it is basically the
github's llm integration
which makes it a
little tricky to use
so let me let me
start by showing a
little bit what
i'm working on here
but and uh well and
welcome everyone and
thanks for showing
up to another one of
our live vibe coding
sessions all right
so for those who are
new that basically
all i do is show you
what i'm building
and and in real time
so this is this is
one of the things i'm
building right now
this is a uh something
i it's it's super
retro let's just so this
is basically a ui for
the front end of claude
uh claude flow and
i did it as retro as
i possibly could but
basically what what
you're going to see here
uh so what i'm building
this is a let's
just go back out so
it's a see i don't know
what you want to call
it a dashboard i guess
so i'm using a
combination of components
here i'm using web
sockets to connect to the
the back end mcp oops
it looks like a jump
it opened that up it's
super retro interface
and uh in in this case
we we can see here
that i've got a number
of tools here's a
web socket i've got
my sync manager i'm
looking here's the
information i'm getting so
this allows me to sort
of get a feel for how
it's going to run how
it's going to operate
you'll see that all
the services started
that looks good so now
i'm going to go back
and we're going to
take a look so there's
a few different elements
here you see that
there's this sort
of initial dashboard
components i don't know
why i've got two scroll
bars that's a little
weird i got to fix
that but anyway um now
we can go here we can
see the swarm i can
uh i can add i can add
my various swarm
elements so i can choose
and we can spawn a
swarm i can i can choose
different options like
an architect or or
tester coordinator code
or whatever so then i
can spawn it so i'm
going to spawn that we
can zoom out i can
add let's see if i can
add another one a lot
of researcher spawn
that and i can move
those around oh maybe i
don't move it around.
I'm not sure. I'm still
building it just as
an FYI. I guess my
dragging component
doesn't quite work right.
I can add tasks,
test, submit that.
And that will show up
here in the task flow.
And we got my various
memory components.
This is basically
just showing
it how it's storing
the various memories
for what's
interacting with it.
Lots of information here.
This is raw. I
probably got to do
a better job of
cleaning it up, but
I'll start raw.
The other part I
have here is the
MPX integration.
So in this case,
I can do different
initializations. So
if I want to execute
a tool, I go here
and execute that. And
we can see the tool
being integrated.
You can see all the
various options here.
So if I choose like
GitHub integration,
we'll see GitHub
components or system
and utilities. I
got those as well.
This is early. I haven't,
there is a branch
that if you guys are
interested in taking
a look, uh, that I
had, it's, it's still
very, very alpha. I'm
still working, working
on it, but, uh, you
get, you'll get the
general idea. Basically
I'm creating a UI
for all the sort of
system variables and data
points. Uh, here's,
this will be memory.
So in this case, I'm
going to look at the
memory for, you know,
different entries.
So this is just, what
I'm trying to do is
just give it a better
introspection, just
kind of figure out how
it thinks and how it
works. So here would
be the high bind
components. So this
would give me different
options to see the various
components. And then
in this case, we've
got a terminal. So
the terminal here
allows me to just access
the terminal through
a web-based interface.
Seems a little
redundant, but why not?
So you can see here.
So now I can, let's add
a command here. Here,
let's add this one.
oh no that's not what
I wanted uh oh you
know I need I need
ability to clear this
oh I guess I can
select all all right
let's choose the right
one uh here's this
is a command this is
a useful command by
the way for clod code
that allows you to
stream the output so
it skips their user
interface so in this
case i'm going to
say you know test a
con current uh agent
swarm so the dash p
prints out the output
the output format is
defined as the the json
stream and then you need
verbose this is going
to be the basis of
how i'm going to add a
new feature here in a
moment. So, I'm going
to go here and I'm just
going to type that.
So, now we can see it
giving me the output
each step along
the way. So, now
I need to actually
render that in a
way that's useful.
So, that's the next
feature I think I'm
going to try to add
here. I'm going to
add a cloud flow
section to the UI and
then rather than
invoking the interface
using the default
cloud code system which
doesn't work
particularly well in in a
web browser i'm going
to uh attempt to
build an a web-based
interface for it
what this is doing
is just showing
me the sort of
thinking process this
is what happens
essentially under the
covers when you're
using cloud code
so you can see the
the assistant this is
basically you know uh
the request we can scroll
to the right here
we'll see more details
the id now i could
probably store all that
information to a db
as well which i'll do
in a later stage roof
yeah did you did you
define like in those
logs right there like
did you define that
that type assistant or
is that actually what
what's being returned
from clod and that's
being that's being
returned from a clod
you can see the all this
there is the assistant
basically okay yeah
so this is what you
see if you want to call
the system directly
this is how you do it.
So lots, lots
of thinking.
Claude doesn't
permission to bash. You
haven't granted it.
All right. So what I'm
noticing is I don't,
I'm not giving it
permission. So I'm
going to, I'm going
to switch for a moment.
So let me see, I
hit control C. Now
what I'm going to do,
I'm just going to
go back here for a
moment and I'm going
to just test. So what
I'm trying to do
figure out exactly how
this stuff all works
under the covers.
So in this case I'm gonna
paste this in again.
This one.
This time,
oh, actually before
I do that I'm going
to go and do help
and I'm gonna add
the dangerously
skipped permissions.
This is way over here.
And then I'll put
format, rebose,
yeah looks good
actually i'm
going to use the
one i just did
and i'm going to add
the dangerously skip
permissions option
this time what i'm
going to do is i'm
going to you know to
to do research to
a simple world in,
hello.
All right, so I'm
just gonna grab
that quick so I
have that handy.
So once I have that, so
this is the
initial output.
I know not the most
exciting thing to
look at, but this
gives me this direct
integration with
their system so I can
bypass having to use
the cloud code CLI.
All right, and what I'm
going to do once
I have that,
let's see,
is I'm going to
copy and paste this.
So this is how it uses
the parent tool use.
This last thing,
it basically
reverse engineer
their UI.
We can see here that
it's using my MPX tools.
I saw it a
second ago here.
Yeah, I was going
to say to Alexander
that the minus P
switch basically
tells Claude to
reveal everything
that it's doing
under the covers.
Yeah, it's exactly
what it's doing.
All right. So while
I does this thing,
I'm going to jump
back here for a
sec, and I'm going
to use Cloud Code
Standard, and I'm
going to say update.
I got to type it
right. Update the,
where did we
run that again?
I'm going to stop
that for a sec.
I'm going to give it
the exact address.
So here.
I don't need this
one. This looks like
a one update to
include a new clod flow
page on left and a
nav that uses the
following command to
interact, I guess,
interact and display
the resources.
Ruben, you're
just using the
standard cloud
right now, right?
No, I'm using cloud flow.
This is flow, okay.
Yeah, so just as an
FYI, you don't have
to use the Claude-flow
CLI or the CLI. All
you need to do to use
Claude-flow is type
Cloud and then use the
dangerously skipped
permission option here.
And then what you
have here when
you do that is
when you see
slash, you get
all my commands,
right? So you get
all the various
commands. So if I type
GitHub, you get my
GitHub commands.
If I type Spark,
you get my Spark
commands, right? So I
don't need to
invoke it using the
Claude-flow CLI. I
just use it this way.
And if I don't do anything,
it's automatically
getting my clod.md
file, right? So it
already knows how to
use my system because
I've already put it
in the clod.md file.
This is telling it
how it needs to work.
So the Claude-flow
at alpha but is
mostly for cloud
code to know how
to interact with
it using the MPX.
All right. So
let's jump back
here. We're
back. This one.
All right. So it's
just consuming
tokens out of the
system prompt.
Yes, it is.
And I think it's the
first time it runs.
So back to the,
you know, let's
just check this
for a moment.
This is still going.
Every time you open
up a new terminal, are
you having, are you
having to re like initiate
the cloud flow in
that terminal or is it
already no no it's all
i occasionally update
it well this you're
looking at actually the
environment that i have
to do my cloud flow
development but assuming
this was not that
environment i would i
would need to probably
reinstantiate it
if i know there's a
new update but you
automatically get
that because i'm
using the mpx which
will give you the
most recent alpha
version if you use
the at alpha tag
gotcha so go ahead
the npx the uh so the
way i do is claw dangerous
escape permissions
first so they're
Claude um the normal
you know typing window
comes in and then i
generally run the npx
command with force
function to create all
the folder structures
on the terminal so
you are saying that uh
you know that that's
what creates all of
the files right all
the folder structures
exactly so once you do
it you know once you
do it once you probably
don't have to do
it again unless there's
an error but there's
uh sometimes there's
a uh like they
changed for example last
week they changed the
structure for how the
um the settings.json
worked so i had to
basically reinstantiate
that which made
that error go away i
don't know why they
they changed it and you
know two weeks after
launching it but anyway
that's what they did
so i had to go and
fix that and
reinstantiated for all the
things I had previously
run the in it on so
now I'm what I'm
doing is I'm giving an
example so I'm gonna go
here and I go back and
I think it's which
one is it I don't even
know now to go back
let's scroll back up
oh it's still still
building but you can see
here I'm this output
is working in exactly
the same way so i'm
gonna i'm gonna go back
here and i'm gonna
say make sure to parse
parse the uh sorry
guys i'm getting a
bit of uh there we go
so i'm just telling
them to parse the
json correctly in
the web ui and then
i've got to go and
i've got to figure
out which one of my
things I just made
actually does that.
So I'm just going to
create a new file quick.
New file.
All right. Pop
that in here.
Oops.
Was it this one?
Yeah.
This one will give
it a good example.
Get rid of that.
Here's an example.
What?
And now, you
know, you can also
change the mode,
but I think
it's control.
What's the control?
No, I always forget.
There's a control
mode that lets you
go to planning mode.
You guys remember
what the control
for changing between
planning mode is?
Command, tab, tab.
Okay. Yeah, I'm not
going to do it right now
because I don't want
to get stuck in that
mode. But I could do
planning mode here.
not going to bother all
right pasted that in
i'm in the agentic
flow that's good
so now what i'm
gonna so well just to
recap what i'm doing
so while that bakes
what i'm attempting
to do here is create
a new section along
the side here which
will be like a clod
flow which basically
will will make this
more pretty and show it
in the ui similar what
i'm doing in these
with these you you
know user interfaces
i don't think this is
actually running at
the moment no i
think i turned it off
yeah i turned it off
let me run that again
run start so this is
all using web so at the
very least what i'm
doing here which is
useful for you guys is
i'm actually i've created
a mechanism that
allows me to interact
with um cloud code through
web, web, web hooks,
web, web sockets. So
if you want to use
that as part of some
secondary application,
you want to have
additional sort of swarm
capabilities or whatever
it is you want to do.
This is, this
is meant to just
show how to do it.
So I did it in a
crazy sort of a
1980s, you know,
hacker style, but you
can basically use my,
my web hooks to integrate
this to whatever
application you want
and this is just a
nice quick example
of how to do that and
you're saying that
you're saying that this
is swarm as a service
basically but yeah so
that's exactly what
it's warm as a service
you can see that i've
exposed them using
in this case local
local you know urls but
you this could be
whatever.com i don't have
any security on it
currently so you know
secure it so this
this is on this isn't
running publicly this
is on a local host So
if you do want to
run this as a service
somewhere else, then
you're going to want to
add auth to it. I
haven't gotten there yet.
But you can see here's
how it's interacting.
Here's
initialization. I've
got Mastra integration.
Studio.
This isn't a major
error. This means that
it already started
the server, and it's
getting an error so it
doesn't need to start
it again. I might
give it more elegant
server already started
message rather
than an error.
Let's go back here.
All right, so now
I'm going to create
a new Claude-flow
component, update
the navigation
and modify that.
All right, while
we do that, I
am going to try
something else.
Let's go to the end here.
Hold on.
Do I have open code in
this one? Yeah, I do.
So this is something
else I've been
looking at.
OpenCode, is anyone
on the call familiar
with OpenCode?
Well, OpenCode is
basically a sort of open
source version.
You can call it the
version of CloudCode,
similar in structure.
I've been looking
at OpenCode,
Reuven, and it's
pretty unstable
and raw at the
moment, man.
Yeah, that's
my specialty.
yeah i like it
yeah you're a good
you're a good
match for uh for
open code at the
moment for sure
yeah yeah but i i i
100 agree i i tried
it earlier um it's i
i wasn't see how it
defaults to github
copilot 4.1 which is the
free which is cool
because it's free but
i i can't for the
life of me get it to
switch to you know use
my uh my sonic account
all right so now
it's initializing and
And that's actually
weird because that's
one of the fundamental
design principles
of OpenCode is to
have as many back-end
models configurable
as you possibly can.
Well, I can't
figure it out.
But the most useful
part of OpenCode is –
so I'm just initializing
it right now. It's
cool that it's free.
I love the fact that
it's free. So if there
was ever a fallback,
it's a good one. um so
now it's it's looking
at the environment
it's creating the uh
cloud code all right
so update the what do
they call that file and
how do you scroll up
there's no obvious
way to scroll either
i don't i don't know
it's it's broken in many
ways this thing but
it has potential one
sorry for interrupting
um you are using the
the wrong um open code
there are two versions
ah that's true there
are two and and and you
must use the sst open
code um there are also
the owner of opencode
.ai um and this is
really a beautiful tool
all right let's let's
let's use the right
one the other one is
bought from a company um
the developer and there
was some issues i
don't know actually i'm
gonna before i do i'm
just gonna remove yeah
i'm gonna remove that
so i'm gonna flood
dangerously skip i'm
gonna call out and remove
open code you're right
that's exactly what i
did i'm like this looked
different last week
that explains it all
right i think it's this
is t1 right yeah
open code mpm and all
files all right let's
let's go use the right
one open code there's
two like results here
and i think i gotta do
it i think i gotta do
a uh this sst yeah what
what a what a terrible
name like call it
yeah there's some
issues about the the the
trademarks and things
like that but um in the
end a better developer
behind open code is
this one okay that
explains i'm like this i
swear this looked different
last week yeah i i
uh i installed the other
one that if this is
also an npm mind you
just uses a different
looks like they're
they're using
dash ai oh just
just to make
it uh just to
make it confusing
all right let's
go back let's
split two for
cloud code i guess
someone took the
original anthropic
all right so i'm
gonna clean that up
let's take a look
what's going on here
all right so this
is working so or
let's see how bad
i broke it let's
go back i'm doing
i'm doing multiple
things at the same
time here oops
where did i put
that over here
no that's not it
maybe i closed it
that's okay i'll
restart it I've got
it so it auto
I've got too many
windows open open
browser all right now
we've got a cloud
flow section all right
test the concurrent
let's see see how quickly
I was able to do that
well it's probably
gonna break but we'll
see it is once you've
got a template in
place it's pretty it's
pretty fast all right
look that looks good um
climate moment is
it is it gonna work
now i get i get
unknown message
heartbeat it doesn't
look like it's working
for some reason
terminal connected
um not getting i'm not
getting a response okay
one second i'm
now we're gonna go
back here i'm I'm
doing two things at
once here, but
that's the fun part.
All right. Did it
get rid of the open
code? Okay. So now
I'm going to go back.
And this time I'm
going to get it to open
code SST. Is that what
it was? Yeah. This
one is the SST
version. So it actually
confuses everybody
about. Well, the worst
part is I actually was
using the other version
last week. and today
i'm like oh they
must have updated their
ui no it's just the
wrong **** version
yeah and i actually
think there's some
issue with it kind of
being hacked or
something as well and and
dangerous or something
so you kind of got to
be careful there's
something going on
between these two
competing orgs long story
short there are um where
two main developers
um that are reaching
the pro of the first
project um and the
the guy who was
inventing the the repo
at the first time, was
hired from another
company for big money.
And now the two
guys who are made a
lot of code for
the alpha versions,
they have the
domain open code.ai
and also the repo.
And there are the
better developers,
as I have seen.
And so they have a
little bit struggle
about naming and
things and contracts
and things like
that. But in the
end, SST open code,
easy to remind.
Okay.
So I'm going to go
here and I'm going
to tell to install
the right one.
All right. Let's go
ahead and do that.
And now while that
does that, I'm going to
jump back here and see
what this is doing.
I didn't see an output,
which indicates it
just wasn't returning
the output correctly.
But the UI looked good.
So that's good news.
So basically what I'm
doing is I'm attempting
to create a, using
the streaming
output from claude
code i want to output
that into the ui then
i want to sort of
take that output and
clean it up and make
it pretty and show the
various integrations
so i want to bypass
the traditional ui
make my own so it
doesn't do all that
flickering and all
that other crazy stuff
so i want to i
want to be able to
parse the tasks and
the to-dos and and
the responses and
then segment those,
basically recreate
the sort of general
flow and vibe of
Claude code, but
do it in this kind
of retro style UI.
That's my idea.
How come you have
the HTML inspect
window open?
This tells me
what's happening.
Yeah, I know what
it is. I'm just
wondering what you're
doing with it. So
when I start, so a lot
of what, especially
when you're doing a
front-end website,
and I'm using
WebSockets here,
you're going to see
a few things. And so
let me refresh the
page for a moment.
So you see here, I
initialize it. And
then we see here,
there's the initial
socket. That's always
gonna fail because it
takes a second for
the server to start.
I probably need to
do that differently.
Then what I'm doing
is I'm connecting
to my real-time
synchronization, which
you see here as use
real-time sync. And
then I'm using an
auto-connect every
three seconds, I
guess, or 30 seconds.
And then I'm connecting
to the router.
so this is giving me
the general idea of
what's happening right
so as I do things I can
always see exactly how
it works here now the
so the other thing
I'm doing is I'm going
to copy if I'm running
into an error I'm
just going to copy and
paste the stuff that
cloud code can't see
in the in the UI now I
could probably use
something like what's the
tool the playwright to
do this as well if I
wanted to I'm lazy right
now I didn't bother
installing playwright
but playwright would
essentially automate
this a bit for me but
I'd actually when it
comes to UI I don't mind
actually doing it so
right so when I go to
mcb tools you can see
here it's it's always
show I'm getting an
error here what's what's
this one okay this
is this is a good
example so it looks like
I'm getting a web socket
error but this that
might because it's
currently working so I'm
just going to go back
and see what it's
actually doing it looks
like it might have
broke the web socket it.
So I'm going to
go back here.
And I'm going to stop it.
I generally don't have
to restart it. But
sometimes if it
changes the WebSocket
server, I'm going to
have to restart it. So
again, I'm showing a
verbose output here
as well. I'm always
curious what the heck
it's doing and how
and how it's doing it.
And we're going to go
back here. I'm going
to refresh it those
logs automatically get
saved somewhere in your
memory or like no no
they don't um i do
well yes sort of well
yeah you mean the inspect
window logs console
logs alexander the
console i know but no
they don't i've got
logs that i'm storing in
in in here as well i
think it'd be super
interesting to like take
this community's like
logs like do some data
analysis on it parse
it and like kind of
get a sense of like
what the what a successful
projects like cadence
would be in terms
of like how we're
prompting it to get to
like a completed outcome
well ui stuff is always
the trickiest because
it requires kind of
iteration back and
forth see how i'm i'm
pasting the that it broke
the uh the web's
socket so now i gotta
tell it how it broken
it will it if you know
the middleware is
easier because it's more
kind of iterative back
and forth this is you
know it doesn't see
the things it doesn't
see uh what's the file
with that one I mean
a screenshot of a UI
we can upload that and
send it where this
prompt but is it possible
I'm not sure I
understand your question
I mean you know this one
is not exactly seeing
the UI so maybe we
can have a screenshot
and send it through
via prompt but if it is
possible the the issue
isn't isn't visually
the screen look it
looks fine right i it's
loading correctly the
issue here is is uh
you know kind of
hidden from from
view that's why i
have the console
open it's basically
not connect
dev tools back into
a log file that's
accessible from cloud
code so you can at
least yeah i could
totally do that i
could save it to a
sqlite or something and
then just tell it
to review that or i
could send it directly
back to uh right
here right and show
it and show it on
in this area i
could i suppose
you know i'm
just i'm kind of
winging it a
little bit today
but that's what that's
what this is doing
that's your style
man yeah i'm i'm
vibing it what can i
say it's this doesn't
look like a major
issue but it looks
like and now they're
ready a simple test
it so it's going to
write a little test
script to figure out
what the issue is
all right update
the components
let it create a
mock clod script
for testing purposes oh i
don't like mock
but we'll see so
it's simula oh it's doing
two different things here
okay i see the
i see the issue
let's go back
here for a second
um i noticed that every
time i use cloud i
don't know if it's
cloud or if there's the
swarm but it's always
trying to make mock uh
or simulations to try
to fake results i don't
know why i keep first
i keep pushing back
like you are you gotta
mock it before you
create it that's my spark
methodology if if
you're trying to build
before you know what
you're building it's going
to fail and go down
a rabbit hole of just
constant errors so
when you use spark the
first step is to create
a pseudo code outline
and mocks of of the
structure using a test
driven development
approach that means it's
working correctly the
part that that you
need to watch out for
is after all your mocks
are are complete you
need to make sure that
the system has gone
from a mock version of
it to a functional
version but if you're
trying to skip the
testing phase then you're
gonna have a lot of
problems i will say that
it's pretty good the
mocks that it does are
pretty good at faking
you out i get caught
all the time like oh
it's working but then i
realized oh it's just
the box yes yeah but
sometimes sometimes
doesn't catch uh all of
them so it keeps it fix
most of them but then
they have a couple of
things going around
in mark or in the
simulations so it's hard
to get it yeah oh i
agree um come on cli it
is installed on the
on this point about uh
basically test-driven
development right in
when we went in group
code world i used to like
in my prompt specifically
say follow the
ddd method london
school and write tests
before you write a code
in cloud flow generally
and i could see all
the test cases created
first before it built
but in the cloud flow
bed i don't see the
test cases created is
that because do we have
to specifically mention
that in the cloud.md
or or do you do yes
unless you're vibing
you don't care you need
to tell it what it
needs to do it's not
gonna it's not gonna
magically know what you
want to build so in
your you know out of
the box cloud.md basically
it's not there is
what i'm presuming
uh i'm not sure i
understand your question
He's referring to the
Spark methodology,
Reuven, which has the TDD
built into it and the
pseudocode mode phase
of it. He's just
wondering, is that Spark
methodology integrated
into Flow or not?
It is integrated
into Flow.
I'm just not sure
if I understand
exactly what
you're asking.
so so basically in
when we were doing in
drew code i would in
my prom specifically
say that use for
example test driven
development approach
london school write test
before you develop
anything you know follow
that methodology so
you don't have it
would write all the
test cases first feature
by feature and then
build now when i use
for example swarm or
hive mind I generally
have a PRD and I
ask it, here is the
PRD, here are all the
specs, now build it.
So it does build
it, it mocks things
up and it works,
but I don't see
it writing the
test cases per se.
I'm wondering,
that's because
maybe I need to
explicitly ask
even when I am
writing the PRD,
that write test
cases before
you develop and
follow Spark.
Yeah, it depends
on which command
you're using,
but it sounds
like you're on
the right track.
If you don't define
your test, your unit
tests or testing
strategy in your PRD,
there's a high likelihood
it will either skip
it or use a rudimentary
implementation.
Now, I've got that in
the slash spark command.
So there's a, well,
I had to restart
my code space.
I crashed here,
but I'll show you
that in a moment.
So I attempted
to paste too much
and then crash
the terminal.
So we're going to
go back here for a
moment and hopefully
this restarts here.
But you've got in
this folder here,
and you see the commands?
You've got a folder,
you've got all the
commands, you just
got to use them.
You have to invoke
the Spark commands.
So for example,
you've got TDD here.
So this would be
the test-driven
development
command, right? This
tells it how it
needs to use it.
These are your various
commands. These
are your
viewers, your MCP
integrations. So you
can invoke all those.
Now, why isn't my
terminal loading?
so is is hive calling
spark tdd no you
are you're still doing
all this manually
well it could it
could if you update
your cloud.md file
so the first thing
i do is i update
this cloud md file
this one here uh
to be specific to
the project in
which i'm working on
so in your case you
know so this the one
you get by default is
is is generic right
it's it's saying
here's here's how the
swarm needs to work
but it's not really
doing anything uh you
know specific like
if you want spark you
might you probably
need to add that as
as more directions
so you can customize
this a bit now i have
no idea when my terminal
is not working do
you manually edit your
CloudMD or do you just
copy in a template
that you you woo that
you're you I depending
what depending what I'm
doing I'll I'll manage
it I'm not sure why
my terminal stopped
working yeah man your
icons are not refreshing
in the little shell
so idea yeah that you
got some problems there
yeah I'm not sure
what's going on here uh
close remote connection
i might reload the
developer uh window
with the command palette
the command palette
isn't loading oh really
i guess it's time to
just turn it off and
turn it on i i already
did that uh reese
yeah reload window
maybe yes i tried that
usually that that's
enough to code restart
to update code container
compose restart
um which one is it
there's a there's a
a lot or code space
i don't want to
rebuild the container
that seems a little
dramatic connect
to code space
i gotta tell you
i i hate reloading
rebuilding the
container in code spaces
because if it fails
your your code space
boots into like a
recovery mode and then
you gotta fix it yeah
well i've got all
the data it's not it's
not that big a deal
i've been but it's
persistent yeah it's
just it's just uh
i'm gonna try i'm
gonna try one more
close remote connection
it's weird i i don't
i don't know why it i
haven't seen this before
of course it's it's
only going to happen
on a live broadcast.
But here, we're going to
see what we can do here.
So before I go, I'm going
to attempt to restart it.
So you guys get to
watch that for a moment.
So we're going to go
to GitHub Codespaces.
Oops.
Bit of a delay there.
and I'm gonna see if
I can just restart
the machine itself
where's my cloud
flow right here and
stop code space to
which
what was the name
of that one I
might had more
than one running.
Refactored carnival?
Refactored carnival. All
right, let's
give that a go.
Otherwise, I might need a
more drastic approach or
I might need,
you know, what I might
need, actually, you
know what I might
need to do? If it
doesn't work, it's
probably not the code
space. It's probably
via, I probably need to
kill VS code. I probably
over, I'd probably
that some sort of
overflow when i try
to copy and paste all
that uh json we'll
give that one more try
yeah you guys get to
watch me debug i guess
if that's exciting i
was waiting i have a
question that worked
all right so so yeah
go ahead one thing
note when you when
you're when you're
recovering you can
always do dash c looks
like i looks like
the restart worked so
what was sorry what
was your question
um i was curious
about the sequence
of commands that
you explicitly
um basically ask at the
beginning like during
the flow so the previous
question was about
explicitly calling
tdt as spark tdt um so
i'm curious what's your
standard sequence of
comments like spark
researcher and then spark
studio code or then
spark tdd what's the
sequence that you usually
recommend to follow
so it it depends what
i'm doing and i'm not
sure why this is
taking so long to start
but i'll show you here
in a sec uh let's see
here let's see another
plot and you see what's
going on there that's
that's working oops
wants to do that
roof i think this is
a great question
um the way i i'm
still getting used
to the whole swarm
and i've been using
it for a few things
but emmanuel like
the way i do is
prd first then i say
to plot of plot flow
basically um you know
this is the prd what
do you recommend what
what what structure of
agents number of agents
you recommend provide
me full commands how
I proceed so then
it tells me this is
how it is I initializes
the swarm right and
then once it does that
then I say okay go and
build it I think what
I have not been doing
is as roof pointed
out is because I would
prefer to do it through
a TDD approach so I
should actually go
into the cloud that
MD file and say follow
maybe I need to put a
line in there to say
follow tdd approach
spark but i guess your
questions about
researcher and all of this
stuff uh yeah i would
love you know prove your
your inputs will be
welcome like how you
know i think i guess
so you've got you've
got different you've got
different modes right
and those and those
modes can be invoked
either through
programmatic means or often
just you doing it so
in this case when you
do slash and we do spark
you'll see that i've
got different spark
modes i could ask you
know i get integration
i got optimizer
devops reviewer re you
know my here's my super
base admin coders so
this is using sort of
my my preferred approach
right so i've got
so tdd obviously
would be td and i just
did that up here so
in this case i told
i basically said to
add the tdd components
to my claw.md file
so now when i when
i reinstantiate it's
going to have the
tdd components included
automatically so
here we go so now we
see here it's it's
decided you know
i'll go here and i'll
find it tdd so this
is how it's going to
orchestrate the tdd
components and get it
gives it more guidance
how to refactor
how to do you know tdd
swarm roles for that
so i've just given
i i've given it more
guidance on how the
agents need to interact
with when doing tdd based
components so i know
there's a lot and i'm
what i'm trying to
do here is not give
you everything because
if i gave you everything
then it would just
do nothing particularly
well so i'm i'm
invoking certain things
at certain points when
i need them and now
as part of the initial
sort of guidance what
i might do is i might
go with a research mode,
like Swarm Research
or something, and I
might say, include
a TDD-driven approach
using Spark or something,
and it'll know to
include that as well.
So I'm guiding it.
I'm the engineer here.
Today I'm vibing a
little bit, but generally
speaking, as an
engineer, your job is to
provide guidance in
terms of architecture,
in terms of
procedures and
process and data
and whatever.
Without that,
you're just vibing.
I had an observation,
I've been noticing
a lot of creativity,
you know, from yourself
and from others
coming through and in
the sort of these
techniques and workflows
and updates people are
making and customising
their Claude.md
to get sort of the
workflow that you
that you desire. And I
wonder if there's an
opportunity to maybe
kind of optimize the
updates to Claude.md
and maybe some kind
of management layer
for how to better work
with the Claude.md.
You mean like to
have a repo where
everybody can dump
their Claude.md versions
in there somehow?
Well, potentially
this, yeah, like a
kind of a best practice
library for cloud
.md customizations,
but then also an
injection method for
how to actually
update it dynamically.
And prompt cloud code.
Yeah, for sure. sure
but he was just like
yeah but like leveraging
all this best practice
and doing it in a
programmatic way that
and that can be done
you know i want that one
now or now i'm switching
to that one kind
of thing or it could
also be something like
md actually it could
just pull from a github
repo right we could
all just dump our mds
into a github repo and
then and then you It
could just say, find
the best Claude.md for
this problem that I'm
looking for right now,
and it will go out to
that Claude.md repo
and the Agentex repo
and find it, scan it,
find it, and then say,
here, I found it. Do you
want me to push it
right now to your M&D?
Yeah.
yeah or another idea
is like if we point it
to the code modules
folder Claude basically
and say you know i'm
going to solve this
problem and i want to
do this kind of approach
as some kind of user
prompt can you kind
of look at those modules
and update the cloud
on md file suitably
before i initiate this
swarm right yeah exactly
that's that's exactly
what i was thinking
more of a modular
way like i like that
chunk not not to replace
the whole thing but
just just pieces but in
that case we can
create like a gpt so it
would be expert on
creating cloud mds and then
you just describe exactly
what's the project
and they would create
it perfectly yeah
but you but you want
you want the benefit you
want to benefit from
everybody's Claude md
file to find the
best one not not just
scanning your code you're
also constrained by
the context window so
you need to be yeah you
need to optimize
what elements or what
features you want to
curate into your cloud md
could we use the
switches maybe for this
would that be useful
the slash commands
yeah yeah the slash
commands are generally
geared towards human
interaction yeah where
where the clod the
doc clod file is kind
of the default guidance
so the suggestion
to have different
clod mds is actually
a really good one
because that's really
what this is the most
important file this
tells it how everything
else needs to work
yeah i think it only
reads it i think
it reads it when it
boots when it boots
up right i don't
know if you can
refresh the clod md it
can refresh the clod
md but more what
i've been doing is
launching Claude code
from within different
folders so that they
reference different
Claude MD files and then
have them effectively
work on separate
areas of the code. I
think... Opinionated
best practices. Yeah, I
discovered that it
does that by accident.
I think that happens
automatically now,
Jed, if I'm not mistaken.
So when it goes into a
directory to do work,
it's going to
check and see what
the closest
ClaudeMD file is.
So ClaudeMD files
actually stack with
increasing specificity
depending on
how deep into the
code base you are.
Actually, I think
you're right,
Rob. But I think
that... Sorry?
So if I have a ClaudeMD
in a subfolder,
does ClaudeCode
only pay attention
to that ClaudeMD
file? No, it stacks.
It stacks. yeah
it's in the
documentation actually
yeah it stacks so
the idea of like
toggling between
planning mode testing
mode development mode
in in a series of
cloud md files is is an
interesting one i
don't know how you'd
accomplish it but but
yeah they stack and then
that way you can
have a cloud md file
specific to a subfolder
but i don't think
that's a new feature
rob i think that's been
around for a while
because i remember reading
that way back uh like
a couple months ago
yeah yeah see there's
another way to think
about these are all
really good suggestions
by the way the other
option you guys
can think about and
this is something i've
been looking at um is
the settings.json file
so these are really
interesting because
you they are hooks
that execute you know
before after and during
the execution of various
tools right so you
can see that i'm using
it here as part of
the you know i'm using
basically bash it
was and i can use my
mpx and then i'm using
that and then i'm
inserting dynamic
information as part of that
into my my mpx commands
and now i didn't
bother with with with
the mcp because oops
did i just break it
there we go because um
I know this works and
I'm working in this
case I'm working in the
environment that I'm
actually building Claude
Flow in so I can't
recursively work on the
tool that I'm building
because it will break
frequently so to
get around that I'm
using the mpx as a remote
instantiation so I'm
essentially using the
last version that
worked and then and I'm
calling that mpx in
this you know in this
case you know pre-tool
use whenever write edit
multi-edit is called
then you're gonna
you're going to do this
command. Now I can do
that for lots of things.
For example, let's
say every time I do a
certain command like
post tool, I might want
to update my GitHub
and do a stash. And
then what that would
allow me to do is roll
back at any point as
the system executes. So
I'm basically creating
checkpoints at every
point along the way.
I'm not doing that
here because it's
a bit much, but
I could do that.
You can see here I've
got different matchers
for write, edit,
and multi-edit now i
could take this further
and i could i could
add it to like the
to-dos and and tasks
and stuff like that
and then when it ends
it does this last
session basically closes
the session itself
and this is all being
stored to the swarm
environment and and then
i'm enabling my mcp
servers as well the roof
flow and and roof
swarm components but
there's a lot of opportunity
in in this particular
file and i'm giving
you a generic sort
of initial one but you
could you could fool
around with that
let's see what else we
got here what's i'm
still trying to get the
the stream the output
i'm not sure what it's
doing here i hate this
flickering thing i
wish they would fix
this it's so annoying
and it gets worse as
long the further you go
I don't think it's
done. I think it's
still looks like
it's working. I don't
think this has been
implemented yet.
The debug adds.
So when I click
the debug button,
you see here, I've
got different
debug information,
sending ping, so
I'm just iteratively
sort of doing
it step by step.
but it looks
like everything's
other than oh this
one's still giving
me an error i'll
fix that later
let's see if this
actually how bad
how bad that it how
bad i broke that
no not bad it's
a minor error so
this is basically
in this case i just
executed that particular
feature which are
all the other
features i showed you
i'm just giving you
i'm basically giving
you guys a way to
interact with the swarm
through a website
that's really all
that's really all i
was trying to show you
guys how to do here
once you give up
give up on the open
code uh demo or eval
uh well i crashed
when i was and i got
sidetracked uh let's go
let's go back here uh
install i'm going to
tell it to install
the right one this
time if i can find it
this this one there
we go yeah so note
to self two different
open code projects that
basically do exactly
the same thing in
completely different
ways which is a little
annoying all right i've
successfully updated
the You'll be properly
handled with Jason's
streaming events.
All right, let's
go back there
and see what
that looks like.
No, it's doing
the wrong command.
Quick question for you,
Reuben. How's things
coming with Mesh?
Is Mesh done, or are
you still hacking on
it? Well, I've been on
a little bit of vacation,
and my wife told
me I wasn't allowed to
turn on my computer.
I'm not pressuring
you, man.
I just wondered.
I know that one. yeah
she was not keen on
me uh you know sitting
in front of my computer
at the cottage so uh
yeah i i i haven't
been as productive i've
been pretty productive
just not as productive
as i usually am
no pressure man i'm
just i'm just wondering
david you seem like
identification now
what's that nursing
uh the dave gratton i
think you seem like
navigation with your
hawaii t-shirt a hawaii
shirt and everything
briefly came on the
camera yeah i should
i should have wore my
hawaii shirt yeah i'm
at the cottage so um
i am indeed outside
next to the lake so yes
it's oh yeah oh there
we go yeah he said
that's is that is that
hawaiian or canadian
tropics uh this is
dominican republic
but um no i'm i'm just
by i'm just up in the
muskocas so which is
which i like to call
the canadian tropics
oh well it feels pretty
tropical right now
i can tell you that
much yeah i don't know
if that's a thing um
i i might have just
invented that as a thing
at some point there
was certainly tropics
right yes 250 million
years ago there was
a tropical sea in
this general area of
canada but uh that was
a lot where are you
typically martin where
are you um i'm um port
seven that kind of
area if you know i'll
see if i can give you
a um i'm from Panatang
originally, just
around the corner.
Yeah, just around the
corner. Do you imagine
it's a six-mile lake?
There you go.
Nice.
Down there. How
big is the lake?
I'm going to
say six miles.
It's not about the size
of the lake, Reuven.
What's that in Canadian?
That's got to be like
about 10 kilometers.
Have you got your
cycle? Are you going to
go biking again? You're
enjoying your bike
rides? Oh, yeah. I've
just gotten into this
whole cycle cycling
craziness i'm i'm going
on a um big cycle group
with uh the toronto
biking network it's
going to be like four
days of any length of
journey you want so i
did myself nuts the
other day i um i usually
i indoor bike that's
my thing if i would
do about 50 kilometers
in the morning i watch
youtube and all the
rest of it and i post
all my stuff to strava
my my friend he goes
ah you're missing it
you're missing it all
like indoor cycling
that's a three outdoor
cycling that's a 10
you got to do it so he
he made me cycle 110
kilometers once i was
halfway there i was
committed i couldn't
just get off and there
was a big meal at the
end of it so um yeah
and now i'm doing this
this thing over in
peterborough so prove
it's it's an option
you don't just have to
indoor cycle my my
exercise bike broke this
morning so now i i
might have to go outside
right yeah come to
peterborough that might
be much sure um Reuven
i've got a bit of an
update on synaptic mesh
if you want sure yeah
good to see chris um
you'll have to apologize
um for the robe um
it is five o'clock
in the morning here in
new zealand and cool
uh i'm trying to
share the host is not
allowing sharing can
the host please sharing
yeah that that was thanks
to our our our last
uh yep quick on the
buttons yeah how do i
make just one person
be able to share let's
see here allow you
can't just make i okay
i'm gonna i'm gonna
allow share okay you
requested there you
go i was worried that
there might be some like
craziness as of last
week my apologies on
that too by the way
yeah i've been looking
into settings i'll
update you later i
figured i figured out i
turned it off well
that's one way but you
can also stop you don't
have to let everybody
share at the same
time you basically say
that if someone's
sharing no one else can
share and also you can
turn off the um the
scribble thing which
was the first instant.
So here we are. I
don't know if you
if you remember and
some of you might
not have been on the
call but a couple
of weeks back I
shared this mock
-up of a what a swarm
might look like
and none of it's real
and on the call Reuven
said oh well you've
done the front end I've
got the backing for
you and so that's where
he introduced me to
synaptic mesh um i don't
really know what this
does Reuven um do you
but synaptic mesh well
it's my attempt to
share compute capacity
based on several other
projects i've created
but it's it's very
generally the your idea
around uh yeah sharing
cloud exactly so so
then um what i did was
um very crudely um
attempted to brute force
the inclusion
of synaptic mesh
into the search
for the artificial
super intelligence
mock-up
and it proceeded
proceeded to i
let it cook
overnight and i
returned to 120
000 lines of code
um it got very very
busy it did a lot of
stuff um none of it
really worked a lot of it
i don't know um so
basically i then tried
to recover from that
by um giving it a bit
of structure and so
i invented this um
customizations i called
the yolo protocols and
essentially what that's
doing is it's just
giving instructions to
call.md to how to do
the the work chunking
and the GitHub issues.
So, you know, create
the epic, create the
feature, create the
the stories, so to
speak, and make sure
they're all linked.
Make sure that you
only deliver based on
those things and then
close them as you go.
And it was it was very
effective and, you
know, structuring
the work. so you know
essentially did a
review of of of the
code base and then
said right based on um
where we need
to go now let's
plan forward and
and so that's
where all these
issues started up
um and then you
know it's again
been very busy
it's it's we've
got 45 closed
issues in here
uh i'm showing you all
of the the admin um
you should you see
it yeah that's it you
do okay one sec sorry
um cool um so so i'm
showing you all the all
the busy work um did
it do anything well
what it did do is it
created a new component
for roof fan called
neural bridge i don't
know what the ****
it is um i don't know
what it is but i love
it it's a high
performance wasm neural
network library with
samd acceleration and
real-time monitoring um
anyway i've i've i've
linked that to an issue
on the on the roof
fan um github repo
um so you can take a
look and see if that's
worth including and
again not really sure
what it's doing it
thought it needed to
optimize something in the
process what's so can
you run it uh i don't
i don't know if
you can just run it
straight off the bat or
if it needs some other
stuff again um not
not really too sure um
have you talked to
claude code about it
have you like have you
like at least like put
it in the like try to
run it or like kind
of ask like what what
exactly are you doing
i i tried that i
couldn't understand it
it's it's explain to
me like like i'm a like
a 15 year old or
something is what i so
this is reaching that
that edge here where
ai we just are not
going to understand
everything that's going
on this is like kind
of like starting to
emerge so it's it's kind
of the the ADHD brain
just moved me to
other other tasks so
I got going with other
things but anyway did
some pretty cool things
in the meantime I
was trying to get the
authentication working
so sorry I'm jumping
around a little bit
the first feature I
asked it to do was
well actually let's get
the Claude max authentication
working because
on the front page
hopefully this works
on the front page the
idea is that you come
in here and you
connect your Claude Max
account and then if
everyone comes in and
connects their Claude
Max accounts then we can
kind of contribute
to the mega swarm and
then we can all kind of
work on sorry if we're
repeating because we
did this the other
week but you know you'd
have your projects
in here and I could
add my github repo you
could add yours and we
could kind of vote on
which tasks we wanted
to to get done together
and as part of that
that mega swarm
activity and some features
that it added since
the other week was
that it added mcp tools
so it's got the Claude
flow mcp server and
some of those tools
are there and then you
can come in and come
in and push buttons and
do stuff it's probably
just a mock i don't
really know what it's
doing but yeah it was
it was a wild it was
a wild west cowboy
attempt at trying to
do some kind of a merge
and it was a fun learning
exercise um that's
that's how i would
put it nice i like the
ui i'm sure we could
get it get it working
well i think i
think uh you've
you've probably
leapfrogged with
with your with
your fancy new
CRT-inspired UI, Ruth?
No, no, no. To be
honest, the UI is more
about the WebSockets
and how you actually
interact with
it than it is the
graphical components.
Now that I've
got WebSockets,
you can basically
just use my
example and say
make mine work.
By the way, I've
been able to get
the other version
of OpenCode working,
so I'm going to
attempt to log in.
and anthropic I guess
clod max and let's
see what happens
here explains why it
worked last week and
suddenly look totally
different sweet guys
wasn't my brain wasn't
fully functioning
earlier all right so
I'm gonna log in to
my clod and authorize
that and I'm gonna
copy my code go back
many times someone
else says when we
go to this code
thing right it
defaults a local host
callback function
sometimes like I'm
authenticating with
a subscription from
a code space it
goes back to local
host and do a few
times it works it's
just quite strange
yeah that's that
only happens
when it uses the
OAuth component
how do you not use it
sorry I'll
look it up next
Yeah, you can, there's
an option when you
log in that someone says
Claude Max or Claude
Max or something, and
the other says API.
Oh, okay. Thank you.
The current
research agents?
I don't even know.
And this is talking to
Claude Flo as
well right now?
API bad root.
No, open code. Are
we in open code
right now? Is this
open code? Yeah.
So OpenCode's main
feature, Alex, is that
they wanted a coding
system that kind of
is similar to
ClaudeCode, but you have
complete control on
the back end of what
models you want to use
and how many models
you want to use and
how you switch between
those models. It's
a multi-model back
end system, whereas
ClaudeCode is one model,
right? It took a
couple of models, Opus
and Sonnet, but it's
tied to Anthropic.
What's that? it's clod
code meets open router
like in the term in
your cli basically yes
it's it's basically
open router behind clod
code and you're not
tied to anyone's
subscription or a key or
or anything but spawn but
spawn is a is a clod
flow you know kind of
concept at this point
i mean is open code
also spawning up
multiple agents you mean
swarms no i mean you i
mean i guess rube just
used the word spawn I
wasn't sure if that was
a command that you
were using Groove well
Claude code has this um
this concept of batch
mode right you can
batch batch the batch
command allows you
this the hidden command
that they took out of
the documentation that
allows you to just spawn
off as many parallel
instances of Claude
and that's native to to
Claude that's we
didn't know what nobody
coded that into Claude
that's just part of it
but we discovered
that they removed that
from their documentation
because they kind of,
I guess they don't
want people to do that.
But they left it
as a capability.
The batch feature,
you know, Ruben,
earlier on, Ruben
just mentioned
that, you know, or
maybe it was another
meeting, that
the previous systems
like Rue code, for
example, is very
serialized. You can't, you
can't, it does all
its work serialized.
But with the batch
command with Claude, you
can parallelize work
by just spawning off
agents one after the
after the other and
batch them off i'll let
you you you got a much
better explanation on
that uh reuben you've
done a lot of work
on that i don't know
i'm i i'm logging
into logging into uh
anthropic made the whole
thing stop working oh
yeah it's this thing
is a little bit
kludgy it's got a
great concept but
uh i don't know
how well they're
actually making it
work yet see i'm
getting now i'm
getting this api this
i don't know what
this error is i
logged in and it
stopped working
conceptually it's good
yeah but it don't work
i i don't know too
many people that
actually have it working
anyone on the call
to make it work as
soon as i added as soon
as i added anthropic
it stopped working
and now i logged
out and if i remember
correctly open
code uses the open ai
api library not the
anthropic api library
well i have that
right here but it
doesn't seem to want
to use it now let's
see if i can just
go here and see what's
going on nothing
i'm sure someone can
uh demo their working
instance at
tomorrow's uh well it
worked for about two
seconds but then i went
and added anthropic
and it stopped
working now i might
be able to log back in
see maybe it's one
of those login twice
to give it let's
try this one i
think i'm already
logged into that
yeah but it
doesn't have the
oaf token in that session
I
think it's working
on my machine,
so I don't know. Maybe it
doesn't work
with Codespaces.
I can't see why it works
with Codespaces
to GitHub.
Let's just give
it one more.
Let's give it
one more go.
Yeah, I'm still getting
the request of models.
That's a different error.
Yeah.
Maybe I just have
the model, but yes.
I have models.
I think it's
just using the
wrong model.
Yeah, you can do slash
models when it's running.
And we'll choose that.
I guess they added so
much more recently.
how do i choose the
model model i think
if you just do open
code and then when
you're in the interface
you can do slash
models i don't know
if you uh how to
do it yeah you can
do slash models see
it's only seeing like
the copilot models but
not the entropic so
maybe that's the issue
Yeah.
I think it's worth it.
All right. Uh,
run to agents.
I'm currently, I'll
figure it out. I'm,
I'm persistent.
And it's able to do
that because it's
looking at your
cloud.md file, right?
I haven't gotten that
far yet. I'm just
using open code. I'm not
sure what it's looking
at, but it looks
like it's running to
look. so it does do two
that's cool it's not
flickering okay let's
try another let's
go here i'm gonna let
that do its thing so
you you've configured
it to use um but it's
not using your Claude
mac subscription
right it's using the api
direct yeah i'm still
getting the error
here oh i just jinxed
All right. Well, the
concurrent
works from here.
I think I know the
issue. I don't think
it likes, I think it
needs to be GPT-4.1.
Okay. Let's go back here.
And we'll go back
here for a moment
then we'll do slash
models oh uh let's
let's try i i think
maybe the entropic
subscription
didn't go cool or
something no i realized
you only oh okay
uh bottles all right
then this time i'm
gonna do slash m and
i'm gonna choose the
one i know works which
is this one there
we go i'm cooking
all right that's what
i wanted okay so what
i wanted to do was
be able to invoke
open code through the
command line similar
what i was doing with
the stream but i don't
i use other models
so now i'm gonna
see i'm gonna see uh
I'll figure it out.
There we go.
Invalid, oh, I'm
getting the
invalid thing.
Descript you are
first agent of two.
Invalid tool input.
Not sure what that means.
are you sure that gpt
4.1 is good and in
two links and calling
no i'm not that's maybe
the problem let's
try it how does it
know to run npx cord
flow alpha when you
didn't you didn't tell
it to do that i i told
it to run this one
where i did the dash m
command yeah so what
i'm going to try i'm
gonna try i'm gonna
try logging in again
i think i know what
the issue was actually
now i think the auth
did work i just didn't
select the right
model it wasn't the ui
wasn't particularly
obvious so i'm gonna
log in this time i'm
gonna do the anthropic
one again i'm using
i'm gonna use my max
account now that i'm
from now that i know
that you can select
different models i'm
to be more explicit
in the model I select.
So then I'm
going to go here
and I'm going to
copy copy that
go back here
all right paste
that in and then
I'm going to go
list
anthropic I got
two credentials now
just to make it
more that seems like
a bad idea I got
this and this okay
I don't know
how I'm going to
fix that but
anyway open code I
got it working
so now that we get
that I'm going to
stop that
And then I'm going to go
back and try
the run thing.
And this time I'm
going to choose just, I
don't know which one
I'm going to choose.
Cheap one. I'll
choose this.
Yeah.
Something cheap
and reliable.
All right. So then I'll
go here and I'm going
to go back to the
one, but this time I'm
going to not use, I'm
going to use dash M.
System error
about model name.
Okay.
I swear that
looks like the right name
let's try without the
well you chose opus 4
can you try opus 4 then
maybe I'll just try
something well
why would it list
the name and not
make the name work
yeah
I could just do
opus 4 or opus
3 let's see what
happens there
Oops, I forgot
the M, dash M,
nope, that doesn't work,
I don't know, it's
a little beta.
Yeah.
No, I don't want to
interrupt the phone
of trying to connect
to these systems,
but I'm trying
to keep thinking
out of the box and
I think the biggest
bottleneck that we
have is this, relying
on these resources to
be able to program so
I know that you have
implemented something
that I'm still
scratching my head around
is the the CUDA and
the Kimi K2 wasn't
so i was wondering
if it's possible to
run properly somehow
these systems in
cpus in a very powerful
way so we can replace
this cloud or gemini
yeah to run it
locally with those
implications you could
use on onyx i think
it's called onyx uh
Do you know what I
mean, no? Yeah, I do.
You're going
to use these.
But because this will
be us flying far ahead
because this is the
biggest bottleneck we
have now, right now.
The timing that we
have for resources to
be able to continue.
And we're going around
trying to solve this
issue and invent new
stuff to connect it,
but the bottleneck
is still there. so is
it possible that with
this implementation
that you have done we
can run this beast in a
cpu no no it's too
big it's it's too big
it's it's way too big
so uh kimmy k2 is is
a trillion parameter
model yeah it's monstrous
yeah so what i did
if uh where did i put
that uh i think i
put that in yeah they
hosted on grok right
they host kimmy on grok
no he's talking about
a project i did a
couple weeks ago
and what i did on my
implementation i didn't
finish it i'm this is a
proof of concept uh let's
go here to my recent
updates just just type
kimmy i think it's
the only one yeah so
kimmy core fan this
was the one i did so
what i tried to do here
is i what what i wanted
to do is separate
all the pieces of the
Kimi K2 mixture of
experts and rather
than doing one trillion
parameter model I
came up with 365 micro
models that I connect
you know independently
so that's what I was
attempting to do here
so it's you you you
carved out of Kimi all
of its micro models
yes that's exactly what
i did and then and
then i built and then
i packaged each of
those as a kind of cpu
friendly version so
it's when you make a
request a request
it's actually sort of
determining which of the
experts it should do so
rather than trying
to you know load a
trillion parameter model
it's only loading the
particular expert it
needs to say what is
machine learning now i
was i was able to get
the rudimentary version
of this actually
working um it's just i
moved on this is this
is called an moe router
right that's that's
the the router sits
in front of an mo
um yeah moe router sits
in front of the models
and figures out which
model it should be
routing this particular
request to yes the
weights still need to
be loaded and unloaded
there's uh there's
it's not exactly a
fast start no well the
way each each of the
each of the models
is independent so i'm
loading i'm loading a
model for for whatever
you know it needs to
do so i'm separating
it into many many
smaller models and then
and then i'm routing it
to david's point yeah
that's that's what
actually happens in an
mwe architecture is
you have a single front
model and you have
a router and it has
to do really fast
routing well gateway yeah
so but the problem is
the you don't separate
all the parts so
what i've done is i
separate i separate all
the parts to be independent
of one another and
then i do an ultra
fast routing using the
the rust based routing
system which can
do the routing in
milliseconds is there a
is there a benefit to to
kind of uh decomposing
uh so to speak um a
larger model like that
as opposed to using a
smaller model um such
as queen 3 1.7 b um
and and just kind of
having those kind of
single purpose micro
yeah no you're i'm trying
just to push to see
what if i could do it
but your approach
probably is more is more
logical um what what
you could do is use
on and i'm using onyx
as well but onyx um yeah
chris this is called
um domain specific
narrow narrow scoped
use cases and uh small
language models are
the are the future like
the problem with very
large models is that
they're just big and
you don't ever need
100 100 david i'm what
i'm saying is that that
there are these micro
models um that that
you could adopt and
and i think that rave's
just they're right here
with uh just seeing
what's possible yeah
so that's what these
models are essentially
doing um so what i
what i would likely
do is use that neuro
architecture and then
just optimize alongside
of one of these lesser
models and then get
the performance increase
by having particular
neural networks that
are specifically
tailored to each part
of the uh domain experts
that are being called
so then i'll take a
****** model make it
great greater better
all right i gotta jump
i gotta jump to my
next call guys um i'm
not sure about open code
yet i think maybe i
might clone the repo
and see if i can improve
it but uh um i think
the takeaway from
this call is basically
a lot of the a lot of
the challenge you guys
are having seems to
be claude code or
sorry clod.md if you
start messing with the
clod.md file and start
messing with the hooks
there's a lot more
you could probably do
i mean many of us are
already connected on
linkedin we're trying
to make an effort to
like get everyone like
ramped up on this so
if you want to message
me either in discord
or i guess whatsapp or
linkedin i can try to
centralize all this
feedback about where
people have like some
sticky spots and maybe
we can kind of like
create more of a direct
um kind of approach to
this like yeah or our
discord which martin
is graciously managing
for us um i do think
actually if you have
knowledge articles
you're better off putting
them into a wiki but um
if someone's interested
in that then reach
out otherwise i'm
gonna assume that that's
not the approach you
want to take there is
yeah it's a great idea
and alexander but what
you really want is
to be able to point
your claude code flow
instance at that knowledge
base that's that's
what you want and all
of us can contribute
to it and all of us can
leverage it so having
it in discord is not
the best like you know
can we can we use
this because with the
check this out there's
a wiki section here and
the you can use cloud
flow to manage the
wiki i don't want to
be full of ai slop or
anything but we could
go in here and basically
point cloud flow and
say organize the wiki
for us nice and also
we also have the
community.agentix.org
so if anyone wants to
contribute in terms of
knowledge like there are
features where you
can create a course as
well so there there are
mechanics i'll share
a brief video on how to
use that if that helps
so if anyone is coming
up with learnings
we can basically document
that yeah and i'd
have a suggestion to
put out like i don't
know a blog entry like
it's not not hard you
know like you have a
team blog and you just
have people posting
like this is what i'm
looking at a little video
a little demo and it
would create seeds of
conversation that you
can take forward and
communicate with roof
can you open up that
wiki section for us to
contribute to it doesn't
seem to be open i
just i i just opened it
just now uh roof don't
don't forget if you're
going to share your
implementation of the
web hook to be able
to the one that you
show in the beginning oh
uh that is the web hooks
are already integrated
with cloud flow and
if you were if you're
curious about my web
sockets that's in a
that's in a
agentic flow
branch
and I publish it I still
can't edit the wiki
yeah the wiki's there
but we can't edit it
oh do I need a new
page or something yeah
okay one other
branch okay
yeah
I think it's
called agentic flow
Lewis I might have
to I might have to
like I might have
to give like access
in my settings
or something yeah
Yeah.
Thanks, Reuven.
You better
jump to your call, mate.
Yeah, I'm late. I'm late.
All right. Thanks, guys.
Thank you.
Okay.
Thanks, Reuven.
See you tomorrow.
Bye. Bye.