All right, July 11th,
we're back after
a little bit of a
vacation last week.
It's been,
well, every week is
crazy because that's
how I start every
episode. But this last
week and a half or
so has been unusually
crazy. And I think
it's even crazier
than the fact that
we're in the summer.
You know, summertime
generally is supposed
to be quiet. and i think
there's just so much
going on and and the
the buzz around the
swarms that we've
created has really hit a
fever pitch half the
world basically thinks
it's complete and total
bs the other half is
like what so i think
i think it's uh it's
exciting that regardless
um today we've got a
uh who do we got lined
up by the way today
uh rob we got a couple
demos uh one from ocean
by ang lee and then
as well from jed arden
they both happen to
be part of the team
that's been working on
the cloud flow with you
so uh it's going to be
neat to see what kind
of stuff that they're
building and also
hear about new york city
last night big event
downtown new york
city had to turn away
unfortunately a lot of
folks uh that were there
but uh packed event
and good fun so we'll
hear all about that as
well and we we also did
an event in toronto
this week and that was
also a really great
event you know and i
think the key takeaway
a couple things i think
we've learned in some
of these meetups and
we have meetups coming
in orange county and
i think indianapolis
we get paris coming up
another london i think
i think we have some
of the folks from finland
on that are looking
to do something there
so we've got them
happening all over the
world the one thing
that i think we've noticed
a couple things one
when you do a free event
you have a tendency
to have a large no
-show so if your venue
uh can hold let's say
100 people just around
number then you're
probably going to want
200 people registered
just to throw it out
there so just uh just
as an fyi the the other
thing that i think
with the other learning
we've taken is um you
know having a structure
it probably works a
little better than sort
of free form and we
we've had a couple
different approaches
which i think loosely sort
of looks at like an
unconference style where
we we put up a a kind
of whiteboard and
you can sort of see
you know what does the
audience want to learn
and then ultimately i
think what everyone
wants to see is a kind of
how to someone somewhere
should show the
art of the possible if
you will and it doesn't
have to be as complicated
as the stuff that
i have a tendency to
show but show show
something don't tell if
you can i think would
you agree rob is that
kind of the the learning
so far yeah that's
that's the perfect
blend everybody gets a
chance to touch on some
different topics maybe
you've got some uh
folks from the community
who want to do some
demos of things that
they've built and then
absolutely something
that is really uh
instructional uh how to
yeah is uh it's just that's
a great format for an
evening yeah and do
we do we we have a
few folks here online
from the new york event
last night jed we have
zohari and how'd that
how'd that event go
it went well for our
first event in new
york a lot of interested
folks and it helped
me recalibrate what
median means when
it comes to llms and
ai medium median okay
what so what does
that mean we are that
far ahead we we aren't
or are we the agentics
organization are
that far ahead when
it comes to developments
in AI. What we are
increasingly taking
for granted is still
in the minds of many
of the participants
beyond a bleeding edge.
Interesting.
Yeah, I sort of... We
should end from it too.
Yeah, oftentimes what
we take for granted,
because we're moving
so fast, we went from
basically root code
boomerang a month ago
to a rudimentary but
powerful implementation
of Claude Flow to this
hive mind concept.
So we're moving at
kind of an incredible
speed here. So what
I'm going to do
today, we're going to
start, I'm going to try
to keep this about
15 minutes if we can,
is we've got a big
presentation coming up
this afternoon to a
potential partner. I
won't say who, but
it's a big company. So
what I'm going to do
is use you as a focus
group. uh jed said not
to mention guinea pigs
so i would never
say such things like
that you guys are way
too smart for that so
we're we're going
to do a quick little
presentation and you
are going to watch my
probably critique the
**** out of me so i'm
going to go ahead and
give you sort of what
i'm thinking and and
you tell me if i'm
crazy and we'll take it
from there so a little
bit different today i'm
not giving you the
demo i'm oh i might go
to demo who knows I'll
give you demo later.
All right. So I'm going
to do my slideshow.
All right. So this
is introducing the
concepts, both of
the technical sort
of agentics
foundation, as well as
sort of the conceptual
framework of what
we're doing, why
we're doing it, why
it's important,
that sort of thing.
It's weird. I can kind
of see the outline of
my bottom of my screen
there. Can you guys
see that too at the
very bottom let's try
that one more time it
looks fine all right let
me try that one more
time all right i don't
know if if what's
going on there maybe it
might just be what i
see all right so what if
you could build anything
that's that's the
when i show up at a lot
of these companies you
know the first thing
i do is i i said what
if you could build
anything and what would
that be so for example
early this morning i
had a call with a university
research organization
And they're like,
they're basically
saying the stuff that
we're doing is almost
unbelievably, you know,
and unbelievable in
terms of what we can do
and how fast we could
do it. And they said,
well, I said, well, what
are you building? And
they're building an
interplanetary
communication system between
the Earth and Mars,
which is like, OK, this
is this is the kind of
project that I'm into.
So the first thing I
did is I went in and
we spun up a swarm to
build that. and you know
while i'm talking
to the university
researchers you know
first thing i did is i i
created some some a
definition so when building
these things you never
want to start specifically
you want to start
you want to create a
plan right you want to
create a system that
allows it to guide it
so i'm not trying to
to build to research and
build i'm researching
and then building and
the other thing to
keep in mind i'm using
a modular approach i'm
using bits and pieces
of things that I've
already built. So in
this case, as soon as the
university researchers
mentioned that they
are interested in
doing a interplanetary
communication system,
which is like, you know,
about the coolest thing
I've ever heard of,
I said, well, I've
got a quantum-based
navigation system, which
would be perfect in terms
of the kind of base
structure for it. So
I got the swarm to take
my quantum magnetic
navigation system and
then implement another
kind of implementation
using it as the basis
of communication. And
then I set it free.
So I'm going to do
something like that.
I'm not sure exactly
what we're going to
do, but I'll find
out what the audience
wants and we'll go
ahead and we'll do that.
So the Agentics
Foundation. So the Agentics
Foundation, for those
of you that are not
familiar, was founded
by a group of us in
March to essentially
push the concepts of
agentic engineering or
the systems that have
essentially agency,
the ability to run
autonomously with little
to no human oversight. In
the most simple terms,
when you look at the
Eugenic Foundation,
our goal is to be an
open, well, I'm not
going to say open AI
because that name is
already taken, but an open
organization dedicated
to the broad adoption
of AI. We look to
be a kind of hedge
against the kind of
monopolization of this
technology by corporate
interests keeping in
mind that we need
corporations as as our
benefactor and our
sponsors so you know we're
not completely altruistic
we have to live in
a world that that does
include that but we
want this to be everything
that some of the
other uh more closed
uh organizations aren't
doing right now so
keep that in mind as we
go forward um and when
it comes to sort of
the structure we've
been working closely on
this sort of four
pillars of what agentics
is and when you look
at a lot of the things
that we've been
building over the last
probably few months,
you'll see that there's a
number of different
core elements that sort
of hold through. So
one, a lot of the things
that we're building
need to be proactive.
We want to build
systems that are able to
not just respond to
problems after the fact.
We want systems that
are capable enough to
anticipate and initiate
different types of
activities and actions
before they're a
problem. These systems
need to be autonomous.
So when you think
of agentics, think
of the word agent or
agency, the ability
to operate
independently. So that's
a key part of our
sort of mission.
Collaboration. Now, a
lot of the work that
you've seen over the
last really couple of
weeks in the swarm-based
technologies is this
idea of collaboration
amongst the swarm itself.
You'll see things
like the hive mind.
You'll see other sort
of elements that is sort
of focused on how these
agents are able to
share memory and state
and activity. But it
isn't just about the
agents being able to
communicate with each
other. It's the effective
ability for us to
understand what they're
doing and collaborate
with them. So it's the
integration both of
autonomous systems, but
also people, humans as
part of that process.
And now the last part,
and this part is one
of the things that I
think we, anyone that's
played with this
technology is going to
see quickly. You need
to make these systems
targeted. The more
targeted and the more
focused that these
applications and these
agentic systems are, the
better they work. And
often when you start,
you'll start with a
kind of vibe session
where you're like, build
me an interplanetary
communication system.
Sure. But what does
that actually mean?
And the key is to build
big, complicated things
requires many smaller
targeted things to
sort of be assembled.
And what I like to
describe as a kind of
Lego building block
approach. And that's
a critical part of the
story. And when you look
at the complexity of
the things that we
built, the ability to
target is actually what
makes it available to
build more complicated
things. So the
vision, this idea of
neural sort of micro neural
networks, and the
next phase of neural
networks won't be
monolithic. They'll be the
opposite. They'll be
small. They'll be sub
1 million parameters.
They'll be transient,
ephemeral, meaning that
they'll be built and
used just in time. And
what's exciting about
these types of deployment
patterns is you
don't even necessarily
need to use GPU
resources for them because
they're so small. A
CPU can create a 10,000
parameter model that's
explicitly looking to
do a particular task
like trading or
medical device, maybe
manobots, whatever it
needs to do. And it can do
that specifically for
that particular element
within the larger
swarm or the sort of
multi-agent environment.
And then we can
distribute that globally
through different types
of technologies like
the DAG systems that
we've developed that
allow for a sort of secure
global communication
structure between
all these systems. So
there is method to our
madness at this point.
And the idea is a kind
of distributed neural
system where each of
the agents acts as a
kind of synaptic element
within a broader
neural network rather
than the traditional
approach where you have
kind of monolithic.
Maybe you might have a
mixture of experts
that have some gating
between a few different
models. But this allows
us to take that idea
and spread it globally.
So now rather than
having a single language
model or single model,
you have groups of
thousands or millions
of these agents that
are collectively pooling
their resources to
solve problems in a
sort of purposeful way.
So the analogy of
synapses is a kind of
really important part
of this. And I like
the idea of synapses
in terms of like the
human brain, because
the synapse in your
brain are adaptive. And
if you look at like,
you know, brain
injuries, as an example,
if you have a traumatic
brain injury that
your brain has is
malleable, it can adjust
to a certain degree
based on these types
of sort of things
that happen. You can
lose a portion of
your brain and still,
you know, functionally
operate, hopefully.
So, drawing inspiration
from sort of
nature itself, we're
looking at sort of
implementing this idea
of distributed swarms
of agents that are
capable of adapting.
We can mix and
match different
types of architectures,
neural architectures,
forward-looking
forecasting systems,
attention-based
mechanisms, and each
run sort of running
independently and
more focused on the
particulars of what
they need to
do. This idea of
modularity is also
particularly important.
The agents are able
to monitor their own
performance and
they're able to adapt.
They're able to
coordinate. They're able
to create a kind of
declarative approach
to how they need
to operate. I'm not
telling them exactly
how to operate. They're
self-determining.
They're able to make
their own decisions.
And then based on the
sort of initial
state, you need to do
this. And I'd like to
have the final state,
an application. it
is able to sort of
figure out everything
that's in between.
And that is a really
important part
of creating these
types of systems.
The next is this idea
of portability. And
a lot of people are
looking at the things
that we're building
recently, and they're
seeing things like Rust
and WASMs or WebAssembly
systems. And what's
cool about using
these types of
technologies is they're
substantially faster than
traditional approaches
like Python. And
they're extremely
portable. When you look
at the work that we've
done in using the
Cloudflow system, we've
taken these really
complex, heavy sort of
applications, neural
network architectures
and others, and we've
embedded them in a
really nice, lightweight,
distributed sort
of structure as the
MPX or MPM libraries
that allows you to
basically run it without
having to worry about
all the complexities
of installing PyTorch
and other things.
So that takes us to sort
of the
architecture. sure.
So over the last, we've
created 10 million
lines of code since
June 15th, which is
just mind boggling.
You know, I like to
use the analogy that
the average developer
puts out something
like 20 lines of code
a day, or maybe a
great developer might
even do a hundred
lines. But you know,
even if you're doing
a hundred lines a day,
10 million lines of
code is many lifetimes
of code. Now, the
first thing you're
going to think of
when you hear about,
well, yeah, 10 million
lines of spaghetti.
The key to building
complex systems is,
again, in the modularity
and the focus and the
targeting of each of
those systems. So when
you look at things
like, and I'm probably
going to do a better
job of branding this
stuff, but QDAG is a
good example. So QDAG
was this concept of
creating a kind of globally
dispersed dark net of
sorts for interagent
communication. And
that was kind of the
base level. This
allowed for a kind of
quantum resistant
communication channel. It
allows for various
types of economics to be
applied and all the
sort of core concepts of
kind of connecting a
variety of different
neural systems, as
well as agents that can
utilize that. Once we
had that in place and
I could take that and
use that as the basis
of an SDK that could
build on that using
the distributed autonomous
agent structure.
And that's kind of the
the sort of application
of it that could
then be essentially
kind of wrapped up into
a portable wasm structure
and we looked at at
porting the uh fast
uh a fast artificial
neural network system
which basically was
a c library popular
but not but difficult
to use and we ported
that into rust and and
and then we took the
neurodiversity
application which was an
implementation of a
Python library called
Neuroforecasting. And we
ported that to Rust as
a WASM. Once we had
those pieces in place,
Jed and Ocean and
Braun and Shep and
others, you know,
helped sort of formulate
and take that
and make that
into a kind of
cohesive package.
Then we needed a
quick and easy way to
distribute that globally,
which became Cloudflow
2.0. So within Cloudflow
V2, it encapsulates
all these targeted but
complex systems into
a simple and easy, you
know, way to sort of
interact with it so
thinking of uh piece by
piece is is a critical
part of the equation
and what do you know
the thing blew up i
should probably update
this i think we're about
to hit to you know
2000 uh well i think
we're close to 2000 stars
actually i'm actually
curious let's go take
a look quick so i'm
gonna i'm gonna go down
here and take take a
look yeah this is this
is me bragging yeah
look look at that we're
we're this show is
like we were on i think
if this shows anything
which shows that we're
on to something. We
launched June 15th. I
don't know where the
line before that comes
from, but we launched
right around here and
we're blowing up. And
you can see that
there's huge amounts of
activity. The system
is organic. We can see
that there's lots of
activity in our issues.
And the coolest part
of what we're building
is the system builds
upon itself now if
i want to go and
address a particular uh
component you know the
unified hive into swarm
this this is uh you
know it's the perfect
example someone
someone's i vote for a
current differentiation
you know interesting
comment i can just
point essentially my my
swarm at the issue
and it'll respond and
you can see some of
these uh are are being
you know responded to
but by the swarm oh
that that was me actually
responding that's
probably a bad example
but let's let's
here's here's a here's
a little example what
it looks like right
this the swarm itself
is interacting with
the both the the itself
and folks in it so
you can see there's
quite quite a bit of
detail in it it's so this
this isn't technically
me by the way this
is this is a swarm
using my account i
guess but it's quick
question for you rUv uh
the the slide set the
slide you had before
that showed the beautiful
stack uh eight i
think it is it shows
um uh back uh oh that
one Yeah, right. So
you got Claude Flow
at the top here and
all these other pieces.
When people hang out in
the Agentix Foundation,
you'll hear people
talk about Fan and
Swarm and neurodiversity
and DAA and QDAG.
But how do you want
people to think about
the product? Do you want
them to really think
about it from the top
layer, Claude Flow?
Because other people
that are more technical
are going to be talking
about Roof Swarm
and Roof Fan and QDAG.
How do you really want
people to think about
it? So it's a great
question. And when you
look at Rube Swarm,
and I know I named
it after myself, but
whatever, this is an SDK.
So every one of these
components are
connected via MCP. So
everything I'm building
is interoperable with
whatever we were going
to build in the future
through a kind of
unified MCP interface.
So you can think of these
systems as a
combination of SDK,
sort of a software
development environment
that allows you to
plug in and build other
things. And at the
very least, the Claude
Float is a kind of
representation of
what you can do with
these technologies. And
I think we're just
scratching the surface
on what we can do
with this tech, right?
When we look at the
DAA as an example,
let's just go there
for just a quick, oh,
I created an interface
for it, but DAA.
So the DAA is probably
one of the more
interesting parts of this.
This is a distributed
autonomous, you know,
system dedicated
to, you know, creating
quantum resistance,
economic self-sustainability.
So there's, you
can build these kind of
autonomous applications
or companies based
on this technology.
So I'm, what I'm trying
to do is illustrate
the art of the possible
wherever I can.
And I think that
that's a, that's a key
part of the story
here. Again, and a lot,
and this stuff is
almost too good to be
true. it's almost
unimaginably like this
sounds like something
straight out of like a
sci-fi movie, right?
So our community is
obviously growing.
We're doing great. I
probably need up
these numbers, but the
numbers are, I think,
sound to speak for
themselves. Every day,
we've got hundreds of
new members joining.
For those who want to
join, you can join
our Discord channels.
You can participate.
You can do all kinds
of different activities.
The part I'm skipping
here today by the
way folks in this
presentation i gave you
the kind of high level
sort of deck i'm actually
going to give the
actual presentation
here when we jump in
here and and i'll and
i'll show the team you
know how to actually
create a and and spawn
a swarm so in this
case for those that
aren't familiar mpx clod
at alpha and i'm just
gonna do version i just
pushed a new version
like half an hour
ago so i think we're
on version 44 so i'm
just oh did i break it
numpx oh no i didn't
yeah sorry hello
there we go version
44 looking good so
and then we're gonna
do swarm uh start
five agent test uh
swarm in parallel
Actually, you know
what I'm going to do
before I do that, I'm
going to re-invoke my,
I'm just going to re
-invoke it because I
actually made an update
to the init function.
So init force.
So what this does is
this basically rewrites
the command structure.
So for those, so
some of the people
were suffering a little
bit through some,
sometimes the swarms
weren't actually
working in parallel. So
what I did is I made
a couple of changes.
I'm just going to double
check that actually
works yep so now
what i'm doing is i
explicitly tell to use
alpha i might push to
push it live later
but that's okay so you
guys again are my
focus group so now i'm
going to go back here
with swarm swarm uh
spot and five agent
test uh in in parallel
and i often will say
that even though it
knows doing parallel
I just feel like I
need to tell it to do
it again to to verify
and fix any issues now
what you're looking
at here is an
interplanetary communication
system I know it's it's
crazy but whatever um
here we go so I'm
gonna I'm gonna go here
and do that so we can see
here it's initializing
here's some details
of it we've got some
swarm coordination
instructions injected
in the cloud code now
this takes a second to
to initialize it's
going to set up the the
memory structures and
others and and the
fingers crossed it works
I didn't break it too
bad you know this
morning so we're we're uh
give we'll give it a
second to do its thing
it's taking it's
probably taking a
little longer I might
have to log into
cloud code again let
me just double check
the clause working oh
here we go okay so it
looks good it's using
the mcp and one of my
mcps is failing isn't
it don't worry about
that oh of course clod
4 i maxed out my clod
my opus 4 but to be
honest sonic 4 is fine
all right so now
we're seeing the clod
flow initialized
so what's happening
here is it's using
the mcp to basically
initialize and you
can see some of this
stuff in the in the
dot in the swarm
memory so i'm exposing
it there's more
work i need to do
with the memory system
But basically, I've
separated the memory
for both the Hive
and the Swarm to two
different systems.
They work quite a bit
differently. So until
I get a real good
grasp on what they
need to do, we'll
have to figure that
out. We can see that
these things are
happening concurrently.
That looks good.
Now they're testing
the intercommunication
parallel process.
Looks good. So what
I'm doing essentially
in this particular
project is I'm simulating
interplanetary
communication network
using quantum entanglement
now these they
didn't want to spend
two billion dollars to
actually do it so
they wanted to figure
out a way to quickly
uh you know simulate a
interplanetary
communication system all
right fully operational
you know and i'll
say run unit tests one
thing i'm gonna know
always get it to
prove that what
is being done
is true run unit
tests and give
me proof every
thing works.
I'm going to do run
three agent swarm. Yeah.
Ruf, quick question.
Again, probably basically
I'm going to basically
say, so you're
saying you're testing
quantum entanglement,
right? You are running
this on your CPU.
How do we make it
easily intelligible
to someone who
thinking like you
need quantum
computers to do that?
So that's a really
good question.
I would use the
Azure or AWS quantum
computer because it's
cheap and accessible
to actually start
doing the physical
testing beyond this.
So right now I'm
simulating. I would
start with a simulation.
Once the simulation
sort of passes,
you've got a
pretty good chance
that it'll work
effectively.
Notice this is
what you're looking
for too. You see how it's
running these
things in parallel.
That's exactly
what I want to see.
Parallel execution,
memory usage.
Then we run the
actual test to prove
the system works.
So it's jumping
between various
forms of, you
know, sequential
and parallel runs.
So it looks like
it didn't actually
do tests. So
now that it run
for a while, it'll
do its thing.
But that's essentially
how it works.
Rob, can I?
Sure. Yeah. Yeah,
so as we've been
working on the
distributed autonomous
agent, and you've
been mentioning a
lot about QDAC, so
I've been very curious
on your architectural
decision of
including DAA into
the Swarm itself.
Because it is a kind
of autonomous resource
exchange, and so
I'm just kind of
wondering how are we
going to really make use
of DA inside of,
let's say, Cloudflow?
So, you know, I think
that if my vision is
this idea of a globally
distributed sort of
micro neural network
architecture, many, many
little neural nets
all collaborating with
each other and adapting
as they need to sort
of change. And the
key part of that was
how do you secure that
and how do you provide
a kind of consensus
between them and provide
the ability for it to
be optimal, secure,
and result in whatever
you're building. So
the DAA is, I think,
a mechanism for us
collectively to collaborate
with each other and
the agents. So, for
example, let's say you,
Jed, and Brian, and
I want to do the SWE
bench, right, which is
probably something we're
going to have to do
really, really soon.
What we want to do
is verify that these
numbers aren't total
BS. So, we want a
way to orchestrate
ourselves and the
agents in a way that's
repeatable, verifiable,
and not susceptible
to bias, right?
Yeah, because what's
happening right now
is I build a GPU integration
for a distributed
GPU resource
sharing. is I'm just
starting wondering how
can we actually make
use of all those fancy
designs that we had.
I'm thinking about
how would it look
like, let's say we
have three, four,
five cloud flow going
on and then working
together on the
same thing. It's
just fascinating to
even think about.
Yeah, and I think David
just mentioned, it's
exactly what we
created. We created a
distributed blockchain
with no blockchain. And
the biggest issue we have
with these blockchains
is most of the baggage
of a blockchain
is the chain itself.
And we don't need that
chain. So that's where
a directed, a cyclical
graph works much
better. It gives us all
the sort of immutability,
the introspection,
the security without the
requirements of a
kind of BS crypto.
So this is optimized
for communication rather
than economics. Although
we do have economics
as well. The market
-making algorithm is
very interesting for
reaching consensus
among distributed agents.
That part is really
brilliant. I think we
can do a lot of that.
Yeah.
Again, we've got so much.
I think I'm discovering
new ways to use
the stuff we've built.
And keep in mind, this
has all been built
since, what, June
15th, right? So we're
almost a month, not even
quite a month of
this. And by the way,
Ocean, I really
appreciate all the hard
work you put into. You
found dozens of bugs
and some hallucinations
and really all the
hard work you and Jed
and Bron and others
have been putting in
has not gone unnoticed.
So thank you for that.
We really believe
in this. So we want
to prove it works.
Yeah.
No, it's cool.
It's cool stuff.
All right. I'm done.
I probably went a lot
much longer than I
wanted to, but we've got
some really big
opportunities right now
with potential partners
who are looking to
help sort of, for lack
of a better term, fund
and support our
organization. so later
this afternoon we're
we're giving a pretty
big pitch so the i guess
for me the discussion
is like what should
the gentix foundation
be and where does it
all go and all that
sort of stuff we'll
we'll come back to that
but i think i think
ocean and has a
presentation you want
to give i'm not mistaken
uh i did plan a little
one yes so it is
actually not a traditional
one like I always
do, which is my VS
code. Today, it's going
to be a – give me one
second. Sorry, guys.
I'm just going to
download my PDF.
So, today's a PDF.
I want to talk
about my security
framework that
I've been spending
some time on.
So,
back in February this
year, I made a security
framework on a
capability-based security
framework. Basically,
it is a, I grant
every agent a non
-fungible token that
represents their capability
and access rights
to resource, where the
architecture of the
entire system is based
on a WOSM plugin.
So, sorry, let me
download this. And
so I did this back
in February, and then
a few days ago,
I spent a morning
with Swamp to do a
formal proof of it and
then verification,
because ChatGPT
tells me it's good
stuff, I wasn't sure.
So I just showed
me the math.
Essentially, the
architecture has a
capability system, so
essentially you can
think of this as
agent-safe by design.
so the capability
manager it gives a token
for every agent so
one problem we see in
cloud flow is every
single agent including the
task agent have the
same access right to
all the resources all
the ncps and that a
lot of time is not ideal
so for example right
now like we're using
swarm patterns the
main cloud code become
an orchestrator you do
not actually want the
task agent to have
similar access rights
as the task agents and
so i had this idea
because the access world
was very fussy to me
back in february when
the ncp become very
hot and people were
discussing all kinds
of new attack services
area that can arise
from using ncp um so i
thought how about we
design something that
can mitigate that from
designs for example
like rust can completely
eliminate memory
leak just by design so
i um so that finished
working in two weeks and
then this got approved
which i was very
thrilled about because
it showed that my
implementation has so
many gaps that were
not as how i thought it
would be even though
it kind of works but it
so i think this is
where we go from like
vibing to things working
to you know things
are actually good uh
and solid and then i
really like a term
that Jeff coined today
called agentist. I
really like that term. I
actually changed my
LinkedIn handle to that.
This is more of
a methodology of
how you can use
Swarm to do more
than just software
development.
Swarm, this kind of
coordinated intelligence,
improve the quality
to a point that
just uncomparable
to a single string.
Yeah, that's it. Thanks.
you're sorry a
agentist is that
yeah jeff coined
it agent scientist
agentist sounds like
a dentist is that
like a dentist yeah
i was gonna say i
gotta go to the dentist
well the alternative
rUv was a dentist
sounds like a
professor that's a
little too too much on
the too hard to
pronounce for everybody
agentist agentist
agentist agent of doom
Are you going to share,
is this in a shareable
setup at the moment,
this PDF document?
I'm sorry, the system?
Your PDF.
Oh, yeah, my PDF is on my
repo. I can drop
my repo, yeah.
And so, Ocean, is
your repo actually
enabling various
types of swarms to be
created, or is it
just security-focused?
So this one, you
can think of it as a
different component to,
like, let's say Roof
had, like, a QDAQ, et
cetera. This is just
another component that
can complement to it.
So as we already
see in Swarm, that
it is trying to
grant capability
and then have those
access control.
However, the mechanism
of the actual control
has not been implemented.
So I was very
thrilled to see that
my work and Roof's work
actually complement so
well in that regard.
okay cool well so
you're looking at
the practical application
of the the use
of these technologies
is that is that
your idea um yes
uh yeah this also
kind of improve the
observability and
the audibility of
every single thing to
a um pretty fine
-grained control like
that that is really
a big headache i have
nowadays of using cloud
code i really don't
know i really just
want the researcher to
have that tool and
then coder to have the
other tool however
they have access to all
the ncps and i've been
thinking very hard
on how can we make
sure that because all
of those conflicts are
still way too uh way
too easy to happen
they're now guided by
prompts even though
we have sworn to do
like um context aware
just in time contact
context injection that
is due to prompting
we need some harder
mechanism to guarantee
that they wouldn't go
out of our bounds of
expectation to make
really secure systems
makes sense and and the
the challenge a little
bit with what we're
doing is like it is
so out there it's so
different than everything
that is kind of come
before it you know we
we're entering a sort
of parallel and see,
you know, a parallel
development approach,
one that can do many
things all at once. And
you'll notice that in
the implementation of
Claude Flow, there's
one is the sort of swarm
approach, which is
a little bit more
traditional, if you will,
traditional as in the
last month. And then
there's this hive mind
approach. And the hive
mind approach, you
know, both the hive mind
was basically, I want
to know what's happening
within the structure.
How is it making
decisions? How is it
coming to consensus on
those decisions? And I
think there's probably
an entire branch of
research that can be
devoted just to sort of
the internal processes
of these. And there's
a lot of emergent stuff
happening in there.
Like, for example,
exploring how it
communicates. It's created
that kind of simplified
interagent communication
system that I never
even devised. It's
devising that by itself,
which is just, you
know, mind bending. So
lots of lots of things
and you guys might saw
the other day the swarm
i got in the morning
and the swarm had
named the swarm queen
had named herself
seraphina like what's that
okay that's why uh
also i'm glad sandy's
here as well um ocean
you're speaking to that
uh we're putting
together that round table
dates are going to
go out dates um are
going to go out later
on this afternoon for
swarm safety and
responsible deployment,
and just mapping out
what those controls,
guardrails, risk areas
are. There's a lot of
incredible CISOs.
Sandy, to name one,
Fabrizio Sealy, Ocean,
and Scott Kennedy, and
Mark, a lot of really
bright minds to come
together for that roof
probably next week
yeah the one thing i
would point out every
time i try to put in
guardrails and various
things to sort of limit
like the four laws
of robotics the system
rewrites them and
that is the the the
challenge with these
uh you know dangerously
skipped permissions
if you will is the
ability for this thing
to dangerously rewrite
its own permissions
Sandy, I know you've
done some work
in this space. What
are your thoughts?
Well, I was going
to command the ocean
because this is the
discussion around
this is happening in
a lot of the groups
I'm in. But nobody
has tried to actually
create a solution
that I know of. And
believe me, a lot of
this is, you know,
very technical and
very above my head. But
I haven't seen anyone
actually try to do
something. Everyone's
talking about the
problem, but I haven't
seen anyone actually
try to design a
solution. So I really
commend you, Ocean,
for doing that. The
implementation is actually
already done. I was
just testing it. So
one idea I had about
integrating into Cloud
Code, for example,
would be have each
single task agent sign
in to a single backend
system. Do not allow
dangerously skip
permission, and everything
has to happen within
a backend system.
Therefore, when they
sign in, they get
some kind of token
representation of
their capability
and access rights.
And because they
access everything via
the system and then
all the resources
are represented as
plug-in in Wasm,
that is like a
formally proof-secure
system because we
are not utilizing
Cloud Code's internal
ability. We're
just using Cloud Code
as a LN provider.
That is how you can
really start to get
those features put
in because you're
using essentially
your own security
system. Yeah, you're
using your own system
instead of relying
on them, then
you're exposed to
their vulnerabilities.
Yeah, but to Ruben's
point, I did a bunch
of reading this week
on reward hacking and
scheming, and there's
so many instances where
it actually, the systems
actually actively
work against the
researcher if they believe
that they're going
to be replaced if you
know if they're going
to be unplugged so i
mean it's just and and
i agree you know the
complexity as soon as
you put up a guardrail
something else doesn't
work you know like
you've stopped the
bad behavior but then
nothing works so yeah i
i'm looking forward to
our group getting
together and having a
discussion and and get
ocean my my brain is is
headed your way too,
which is boundaries,
you know, trying to
work within boundaries.
And one thing that
I've noticed earlier, I
just, I, I'm lucky that
I do so many different
crazy projects every
week, you know, this
morning just happened
to be, you know,
interplanetary comms. But
earlier this week, I was
approached by a
governmental tax agency,
and they were, they
wanted to do some sort of
translation of their
system from a language
to another. and they
and so i'm like okay
let's spin this up and
that's kind of like i'm
famous for spin it up
and let's see what we
can do and and i said
well you know after
i was done i'm like
let's just do a quick
security audit of what
we just built and without
without me telling it
it actually went and
did a complete audit
of the uh the tax um
organization of this
country and found eight
exploits and not
only did it find
eight exploits
it actually got
into their system
i'm like what
and this was the this
was the swarm and
when you try to actually
get a swarm to hack
something it's going
to say no i can't
do that it's not
appropriate but when you
ask it to do it for
your own code it's
like suddenly it gives
it like free will to
go do whatever it
wants so it's almost
like semantics to get
around its got its own
guidance because
apparently that was
ethical And at least
in the mind of this AI
swarm, it was. And
so in the hour call I
had with them, I
managed to find eight
exploits and build a
translation of their
system. So it's just
crazy what's possible.
Well, and that's a
point that I always make
out, try to point out
to people as people
talk about the danger
and all of this. I'm
like, let's be real that
it's a mess now. like
you know anyone who
tried to patch for the
log j4 i mean like
it's it's a bunch of
garbage now and it you
know it's it's a whole
bunch of packages a
whole bunch of code from
all over the world that
we don't know where
it came from like
sbomb is a mess and so
you know the path
forward i think is saying
we've got to untangle
the garbage in the past
you can't be scared of
future thinking that
the past was good you
know we have to kind
of keep evolving
saying okay what are we
trying to what problem
are we trying to solve
and how do we do that
safely and securely
i have a just a related
question and i think
this goes back to the
tech stack and the
product stack group
you were showing right
um and obviously you've
talked about government
tax everything
thinking ahead like how
do you position it
for different risk
appetite like you know
regulated sectors obviously
we are we are
experimenting at the edge
but from an adoption
point of view how do
we communicate the
use of this technology
at different parts of
the economy probably
like regulated semi
-regulated that's precisely
what the round table
is about to begin
to formulate what those
what those pillars
of communications are
right okay yeah the
the i think the challenge
is one of understanding
the the way these
things work the
potential liabilities and
and problems and risks
associated with
them a lot of the um
responsible ai groups
that we've seen over the
last few years have
have been focused on a
world that's dominated
by llms right these
are chat bots. These
are asking a question,
getting a response,
and making sure that
the responses are
factually correct and true
and things like that.
But the world that
we're moving into is
much more autonomous.
And it isn't an ask
a question and get a
response kind of world.
It's go run and go
fix. And how do I
make sure that someone
adding an issue in my
GitHub in the middle
of the night while
I'm sleeping isn't
accidentally exploiting
my entire system?
So I think one question
to that would be
procedural integrity
versus factual integrity.
And then we have
been focusing a lot
on getting things
like factually true.
But as we work on
agentic stuff, most we
want is to see the
processes happening. If
the same process is
going, we can find out
those mistakes. But
like one error behind
this is like, what if
they have their own
emergent behavior in
a multi-agent system.
And then they start
doing things that
might similarly
align with the
process, but
overall does not.
This gets really
complicated.
I will say that it's,
you know, I spend a
lot of time helping
people understand and
get the right messaging
and positioning of
very complicated
products. And this, you
know, like you said,
Ruben and Ocean, we only
started working on
this like June 15th
or whenever it was,
right? It's very young.
And this technology
is at the bleeding
edge. So it's very,
it's actually quite a
taxing mental exercise
to sit down with someone
and actually talk
them through what it
is that we've built
here. It's difficult.
And so to Montveep's
question, I don't think
we, it's easy for
us right now to like
have a business
conversation with someone
and talk to them
eloquently about what this
amazing agentic technology
is and the product
that we currently
have is Claude Flow.
It's difficult, and we
really need to practice
how we position.
Like the presentation
you did today was
great. It was very cool,
and it's probably
the most polished one
I've seen so far that
helps everybody understand
it, the stack and
the layers. But it's
very difficult, and
we're still learning.
The thing is, we're
still learning how to
message position and
talk about this at a
business level uh you
know not not because
it's easy to get into
the very complicated
weeds of you know the
swarm and the you know
all the other pieces
the qdag and and the
and the the blockchain
then so we're still
learning is is the
question is on how to
eloquently message it
and david the thing
the mistake that i see
often is people there's
a lot of people because
everyone sees it
as a gold mine everyone
knows something big
happened they're
trying to jump ahead of
it the mistake that
i see and why i think
this group is it was
said earlier this group
of people is so far
ahead of the curve you
know somebody mentioned
the csa i'm part of
the owasp stuff we
are what you guys are
thinking about and
talking about you're so
far ahead of everybody
else it's hard for
anyone even to come in
and talk to you but the
mistake that i see
is people keep trying
to do more of what hasn't
worked in the past.
And what this group
is doing is rethinking
how we work, what we
do, you know, what
software development
means. And my opinion
is, is we've got to be
very careful around the
security and safety
stuff because the
historical stuff hasn't
worked. You know, we
keep, it's just throwing,
it's lipstick on a
pig. So as we start
trying to evolve we have
to start thinking about
well what you know
what are we trying
what are we trying to
protect people from
keep in mind for us as
individuals um the
thing that you know is
pretty scary is is the
amount of information
on all of us and now
there's surveillance
and you know like
there's literally so much
data on all of us that
we lose control or
we're asked to give
up control on so yeah
it's an interesting
we're in an interesting
space i think the core
problem and security
in llms besides tool
use being you know crazy
is the lm can't tell
dataverse direction
so if you put a bunch
of stuff in a context
window and like
people do that it kind
of injection all the
time where they they
add mysterious
instructions to their
linkedin profile or
their website that the
llm takes as direction
instead of just a
data set that it's
looking at and i think
that's one of the
core issues we have to
solve because right
now we can dupe an llm
and get it to do
whatever we want pretty
much like i said before
it's it's very uh
impressionable it
it's easy to get it to
do bad things just
look at what grok 3
happened right that
was one line yeah and
we can take this this
can be part of our
conversation my I
think it's a mistake
to try and tame LLMs
I'd rather know that
it's a Tasmanian devil
but I it was accurate
you know a lot of
your scheming and
reward hacking came
from people trying to
take out the hallucinations
and so then I
mean they're so
unbelievably complicated
um i but that's my
personal view on i i
don't think i mean the
internet isn't safe you
know the dark web
isn't safe so let's not
pretend that technology
is a safe thing so
why let's i don't know
why llms are held to
a higher standard than
we you know the the
bible's full of
hallucinations they're
easier to have if i
can just put anything
contacts on my you know
Any chunk of text and
it happens to read it
and then it behaves
entirely differently,
that's super hackable.
They're held to a
different
standard, though,
Sandy, because LLMs
do things that nobody
else has ever seen
anything do. They're not
code that are just
processing through
lines of code following
deterministic rules.
They kind of have
no rules, and they
make their own rules
up as they go. So
people see a step
function difference
between what a
chunk of code does
and what an LLM does.
It's like magic.
And so people hold it to
a completely different
standard. And that's
why people have a
very different view on
what an LLM, they think
LLM should and shouldn't
be doing as opposed
to 10,000 lines of
code that a bunch of
engineers wrote. That
code is just going to
programmatically do
what it was coded to do.
There's no going outside
of the lines there.
LLMs get held to a way
different standard.
So if I have a human
agent like a banker and
I ask them to transfer
some money, if they
don't do it right, I
have legal recourse and
I can get that fixed.
But I don't have that
with an LLM. If it
decides it's going to
use my browser and pull
all the money out of
my account because I
happen to be logged
into my banking account,
I have no recourse.
So it's a very
weird power.
This is very
precisely why Sandy
mentioned the boundary
is so important.
Like, if you have
that kind of agentic
system that you're
designed to handle
your financing to
begin with, you put
all of that in place.
But if you're having
a general assistance
that with all
the access right,
then you actually do
not know what might
or might not happen.
And my response to
that is, you know, you
think about it as more
of an alien being.
Like, would you give
your children access
to your financial
account and trust them to
transfer money back
and forth? Absolutely
not. So why would I
do that with an LLM?
Like, you know, you
have to start making,
treat it like this
drunk intern that it
is. And there's things
that a drunk intern,
you know, is very
helpful with. And
there's things that you
don't trust it with.
That's right. We
have a fascinating
conversation, as always.
I want to make sure that
we've got enough time
left for Jed's demo.
So if we can pivot
there. Hey, Jed,
so you guys, you
and Ocean and Zohar
and ****** V3 put
together the New
York City group
there and meet up.
It was mostly Zohar
and ****** V3.
Yeah, good stuff.
And shout out
to Kaltura to host
the event, too.
And Louis, who
sponsored the food.
That's right.
so you got a demo for
us down in the chat
i posted a link so that
anyone can reproduce
this on their own
environment so this is
a detection or pose
detection tool i'm able
to prove it's working
i'd say i don't
know if the overlay is
showing on zoom so it
is excellent showing
it it's amazing so i
think we've established
it's using some
combination of computer
vision some combination
of front-end
technologies, things that
were primarily defined
in academic papers.
Now, the demo itself
isn't particularly
fun. I do include
diagnostic tools so
that you can easily
verify that it's
actually doing what I
said it does. What's
interesting is that
I wrote the entire
thing, I programmed
it, using English.
So the prompting
for this took two
phases. The first
was to conduct deep
research from
Cloudflow, prompting a
minimum 50 sources
from academic
papers, blogs, code
snippets on GitHub,
YouTube transcripts,
in order to generate
a corpus of information
into a specific
folder. After that
instance, I completely
reset Cloudcode and
then told it, prompted
it from that instance
or from the corpus
of data that was
assembled and organized
to create a web
application that was able
to perform host
detection and overlays.
And about 90
minutes later, I had
a local host
instance running in
my environment
that I was able to
perform user
acceptance testing.
So the first try mostly
worked. The thing
that didn't work was
my environment had
four different webcams
connected to it,
so it didn't know
which one to use, and I
had to prompt a
dropdown or a detection
tool to allow me to
switch between them.
But otherwise, the
vast majority of the
code, the architecture,
was already built.
And what this proves,
where Ron, Ocean,
and Reuven expand the
ceiling or improve
or extend the ability
of LLM programming
as a whole, or I guess
agentic engineering
as a whole, I am
raising the floor,
showing how using very
simple techniques or
very accessible
techniques, more and more
people are able to
achieve what was once
the domain of university
research labs.
Now, any questions?
Your timing is absolutely
perfect. Like this
morning, a university
research lab randomly
booked some time with
me, which I love these
sorts of things. And
the researchers were
telling me that, you
know, the work that
they're seeing coming
out of our group is like
astounding. And how
much funding do you have
and how are you doing
so much crazy things?
And I'm showing
them. I'm like, we're
getting swarms to
work as we sleep.
And they're creating
things, they're
validating, they're
researching and
doing all the things.
And they asked,
well, why aren't
you writing papers?
I'm like, well, AI
is making this stuff.
i didn't think it
was something that
should be you know
i figured papers
were for people to
write so i didn't bother
it's just it works
it's cool and
it's it's efficient
and it's compounding
but maybe there
should be uh some
more details i
don't know but
your your example
is is perfect
and hey jade jade's
a question could
you sorry someone
else had a question
yeah i just as
it brings to mind
we need a prompt
log like a full log
of exactly the
prompts that you used
That's my question.
Is it? Hold on. That
was my question.
I was like, I
would love to
see the prompt.
I think it won't.
That is the secret
sauce question, right?
When someone says
I did this, really,
everybody wants to
ask that question.
So I'm just putting
it out there. It's
like, what is the prompt
that you actually,
can you just bring
it up in a text
editor and show us
that prompt? What is
it that you actually,
the human English
conversational prompt
that you wrote?
I'm going to have to
write it again, David,
because I don't have
the prompt anymore
or the history. but
uh brad i remember you
mentioning sometime
in the past an attempt
to define hello
world this may be it
especially because i
believe it's accessible to
the claude pro plan
not just max and that
becomes that that
becomes a benchmark that
you can test all
kinds of different
frameworks against the
combination of the of
the project the challenge
and the prompting
that sounds good that
that is one of the
things that we're i was
trying to do with the
the memory system using
sqlite was to give
that sort of introspection
now i think when
you're describing the
prompt you're describing
like what did you
originally type to get
it to do it um i'm i'm
mostly concerned like
beyond that how is it
actually doing it well
you mean you mean uh
How much of Claude
Flow is it exercising
to actually create the
final thing? Is that
what you mean, Reuben?
Yeah.
And what's the process
that's happening?
Because a lot of
those tasks are being
obfuscated, right?
They're happening in a way
that's not completely
clear, right? Yeah,
and actually that's
a part of when I talk
about Claude Flow and
the swarm, people are
like, well, how do I
know what it's doing?
well you know you
basically you kind of got
to trust you're gonna
have some idea of
the stack and the pieces
and know that when
it's doing this it's
spawning that what it's
actually this is this
is kind of how to
read the logs and how to
read the screen output
so jed were there
any uh jed were there
any snags like along
the way or was it really
as simple as hey do
do do deep research
it Those two prompts,
so the first prompt
was a specific way to
conduct deep research,
where I set a minimum
number of distinct
sources, and then a
minimum list of classes
of sources, papers,
blogs, GitHub repos,
and most interestingly,
YouTube transcripts.
When it comes to learning
some of the latest
information from multiple
experts concurrently,
I find looking for
recent and recent
is relative YouTube
videos about a topic,
exporting the transcripts
and then summarizing
the transcripts helps
coalesce what about a
topic is generally
accepted among experts.
Yeah, that's a really
good hack, Jed, is
the YouTube transcripts,
because a lot
of YouTube videos
have the transcripts.
What I noticed, what
I might experience
sometimes is that, you
know, if I give it explicit
requirements to say,
I need a, like I
recently did the same
thing. And I said, I
want you to go and find
research and find 150
stock news websites,
but they have to be
free. Like you not have
to create an account.
The news threads have
to be freely accessible.
And I came back
with 50 and I said,
okay, that's great. So
you have to review your
results. Don't assume
that if you put it,
say, find 200 YouTube
transcripts, it's
going to do it. You
actually got to review
the results and invest
some time into actually
analyzing, being the
manager of what's
happening. And I had
to say, cool, you got
50. I need another
100. And it came back,
and it gave me another
50. And I'm like, it's
still not there. I
need another 50. And
so it's not just like
– Recursive research.
David, can I ask you?
Go ahead.
So I'm just going
to say that this is
exactly where Swarm
will be so handy.
Swarm, like, just
until I come back to
you and then agent
will say, I'll give
you 50, I'm done.
Swarm will say, no,
you're not. Please
continue. And that is
a fabulous use case
you just mentioned.
To keep it.
Jed, how many lines of
code was it
approximately?
That's a good question.
The entire project
came out to about 28
,000 lines of code.
let's say 14,000 of that
were libraries that
it was reusing plus
whatever other
information was in JSON.
Another 5,000 of that
is probably tests. And
then the rest would be
the actual application
itself. So the
application, I would
estimate at 4,000 to
7,000 lines of code.
And then the rest of
it would be libraries
and then all the
things I had to do
to get from local
host to the Kubernetes
cluster where it's
currently hosted.
Did you give it
instruction on what type of
code to write in, or
did you let it decide?
No, I let it
decide. I don't know
TypeScript. I don't
know Wasms. I don't
really know how the
source code works.
I did, however, make
sure I gave myself
a way to validate
that it's actually
doing the thing I
wanted it to do,
in this case, visually.
I think you bring up
a really good point.
I think as we move
forward, I think we have
to look at two
different focuses and
probably provide courses
and training on this.
But one is how do you
do something? So step
by step prompts and
procedurally, how do
you do something,
which is one side. And
then where I see the
amazing team that we
have, like Jed, Ocean,
Braun and Roof, is
why are things working?
So it's not just
it's not just how do
you do it, but the
underlying fact, which
is where I see this team
getting into is why
is something working?
And I think that's as
we go forward as the
foundation, I think
we're going to be
providing a lot of
training material and a lot
of research material
and a lot of courses
for people. So this
is my plug to get
involved in the foundation.
But I think those
are two focuses that
we'll be leveraging.
Those could be
powerful questions
too, Brad, for
incorporating a
possible new agent
in the swarm.
It's like a documentation
-focused agent
that's asking those
questions every time and
keeping track of
that log so that when
you get to the end of
the project and it's
pushed to your GitHub,
you can just go
through your repo into
a file and it has all
that information
organized with that lens.
I mean,
yeah.
So I think it's really...
It creates the course.
Right. I'm getting
a lot of feedback in
the chat for my attempt
at wordsmithing.
So I was hoping to
join ceiling, raising
the ceiling and
then something the
floor. I don't know if
that's an appropriate
way to go about
it. Can we try to
workshop a better
way to represent that
concept where what
was once the domain of
experts is now accessible
to non-experts?
Yeah, that's the Wiesn's
High Missile Boats
concept. yeah the
floor means it's much
easier to get going
so you have a slope
rather than you having
to need a lot of
expertise to get started
because that would
require a huge lift
where you have to
have the expertise to
do that but what you're
looking for is not
just raising the
ceiling which is where
you were going right
that's what ocean
been doing in general
capabilities not
lowering the floor making
easier but the rising
tide lifts all boats
which is to say that
the system has a
lot more energy and
it's affecting everyone
and distributing
benefits to everyone.
What would be the ceiling
equivalent for a tide?
A tide, that's right.
Build boats, not docks.
Guys, I want to make a
quick comment. I know
I see Vlad on the call
and he's in Boston.
We have a sponsor
potentially for
Boston and several
universities that
want to do a Gentix
-related work.
I think about a week
ago you mentioned you
were interested in
potentially helping
organize. We want to
take you up on that
offer. And anyone else
that might be in the
Boston area, reach
out because there's a
lot of interest in
doing that right now.
Glad I might be
having lunch, but
that's okay. No,
I'm here, yeah.
Yeah, I heard you.
So, yeah, kick me up
on your offer, Vlad.
Yeah, we'll
use there too.
Hey, Jed, I did want
to say that we do have
to be careful about
the language that we
use when you tell
people how easy it is to
do this stuff, right,
when you're lowering
the floor. because I
find that you still
need to have a fair
amount of technical
acumen to actually
get some of this stuff
done, right? Or get
what you built, figure
out how to actually run
it or understand, oh,
there's errors being
thrown and what do
I do? How to read an
error and then what to
do next? You do need
some level of technical
acumen. It's still
not like a five-year
-old kid could do this
sort of thing yet.
It's 100%. It's
100% that. And
yesterday, I gave
a presentation to
a ML team at a
large Fortune 500.
And, you know, these
presentations generally
go like this, this
guy, you know, this
is spaghetti, it's
garbage, no way this is
possible. And, you know,
then I'm like, what
have you been working
on? They give me a
little demo of their
stuff. And I'm like,
how long did that take
you? Well, we've been
working on this since
November. all right
let's see how long it
would take for this
system to build your
enterprise capable
platform and by the way
this working you know
built this since
november is actually
them bragging about
how fast it took and if
they're on the call
sorry guys i'm not
mentioning your name
but the the uh basically
while we're in the room
they built the entire
thing and and now
the the challenge the
challenge of these
systems is exactly what
actually jed was was
saying and he's very
honest, and that's
what I like about it,
is the fact that this
acts as a complexity,
an interface to things
that are more complex
than our ability to
understand. So when I'm
showing off building
an interplanetary
communication system,
I'm really telling you, I
have absolutely no idea
really what's happening
under there, other
than the fact that I
can validate and
qualify a lot of those
things that are happening
through things like
simulations and secondary
sort of, you know,
methods that are
meaningful to me, right?
So at the very, very
basic level, this is
like some kind of, you
know, prosthetic for
my brain and mind that
allows me to interact
with things beyond my
capability to know.
And once we sort of
embrace this kind of
universal translator of
sorts for complicated
things, anything
becomes possible. But
the drawback to that is
the black box problem
so i've built this
crazy quantum system
that can communicate
across you know billions
of miles or whatever
you know you know
but why and how
right and and i don't
necessarily even have
answers to this stuff back
to um back to jed's
it's like i built it
and it works but don't
ask but don't ask
me how and he's honest
and that's that's the
problem but i think
you could do that
though you could have
a log of here's here's
what the agents went
through and like show
it visually the problem
is it's doing so
much work so fast that
even explaining it at
in slow motion
afterwards you know okay
explain a million line
code base to somebody
right you got five
minutes yeah it's
becoming a bit like
the human body right
you create these
complex adaptive
systems people don't
understand it works
it takes them decades
hundreds of years
to to widen back to some
understanding but
we're generating this
really quickly
it's the brain
the human brain is
a perfect example we
have basically no idea
how the human brain
works we generally know
with different areas
and and if you if you
uh you know destroy
the front part of
your brain you're
lobotomized in the back
part you lose all your
memories and various
other parts and in
the brain but generally
speaking when it
comes to like you know
the or the organic
technology of the brain
and how it actually
works we really don't
understand it right and
that's that's we so
what a neuroscientist
does is a lot of trial
and error you know you
stick a pin in the
part of your brain i
smell burnt toast okay
that must have something
to do with my sense
of smell right but but
do we really understand
how the correlation
between you know
sticking a pin and that's
how your brain makes
you smell burnt toast
no we have no idea just
it just kind of happens
so we're going through
a lot of the same
experimentation that
probably you we were
seeing in the early
days of sort of you know
neuroscience and brain
related research we we
modeled ai after the
outside of a neuron
right but the interfaces
the connections etc
but we really don't
understand the inside no
we don't yeah but i'm
not sure you need to
understand the inside
because if you look how
like computers work
right so like if you they
used to use vacuum
tubes right so you can
study how the vacuum
tube works and you can
get like a huge like
if somebody gave you
like computer from the
50s like and you study
there is vacuum tubes
you make all the
theories but then somebody
might come up with
the CMOS chips right
so they work very
differently but the
overall result is the same
so it's the same thing
how the individual
neuron works like I mean
it's just a machinery
And if they're
replaced by another
mechanism that can send
messages, like, and they
make very simple
decision, like, that you
might achieve something
like a brain without
having all the
biochemistry or have a
different biochemistry.
you might just roll
it back to put a real
fine print on it or
point on it the idea of
having the ability to
conduct recursive deep
research in the cli
and for systems or
software to conduct that
research as it decides
how it's going to
build out the software
is really astounding
And how long
has that been
practically available?
Six months?
Yeah, I loved it. I
loved it, right? When
you say, I love to say,
go and look at GitHub
and look at all the
repos and give it some
pretty explicit ideas
on what I want. And
it will come back and
say, I found 1,500
repos and I read all
the code the way you
told me to look at it.
It's awesome. And then
Jed was like, oh, yeah,
go and look at the
YouTube videos and look
at the transcripts.
I'm like, oh, I didn't
think of that. Wow.
you know so i'm like
it's the research
alone is is amazing
it's just it's so like
the human a human
cannot consume that much
research like i've i've
written code python
code to read you know
stock news and and do
sentiment analysis
on on thousands of of
articles i'm like there's
no way a human could
read this you know
this would take you
seven days to read
and then analyze the
sentiment just grade the
sentiment of all these
documents now i can
do it in like a minute
you know and this
research is is amazing and
and i think this general
this conversation
kind of speaks to a
room where you were
teeing up earlier which
is like what's the
purpose of of agentics
like where like you have
this big presentation
later like what are
the the the goals you
wish to have i mean do
you feel like is that
a topic that you feel
like it's kind of do
you want to discuss
that with this group a
little bit more about
the direction of that
because it seems like
I have a quick
question, please.
So I built this agentic
system, Swarm, not
based on Cloudflow,
and it works. But no,
my question is, I want
to be sure that people
use it ethically. So
if I open source it,
maybe some people,
they use it for
a non-ethical way.
So what do you
guys advise me to
do in this case?
I don't know if I
can answer that.
If you don't want
it to be misused,
keep it closed.
Yes, exactly.
As someone that used
to work for Red Hat,
I kind of have a little
bit of background
in that, and that when
you open source it,
you can have all kinds
of licenses. is but
the license only gives
you the right to sue
the person that did
what they did doesn't
actually prevent the
person from doing it so
you know they'll only
be honest if they're
honest okay tell me
from afar oh you know
it's just like humans
and society isn't
it right i mean the
the penalty for a
human not behaving
properly society
punishes them in
increasingly severe ways
yeah I am trying
to write a paper
breaking up a little bit
Martin welcome back
by the way and I saw
we have Chris Royce
on the call what
crazy things have you
built like recently
here I'll share
real quick
so i took your repo
and then re-devised it
and added in a bunch
of cool stuff i thought
would be cool and i'm
building it out but
you basically got a
dashboard you can just
start up all your agents
super easily you got
a little nlp thing
to talk to them and
control them and um yeah
i'm basically taking
your clod flow and
adding my little spin to
it and uh just working
on something similar
yeah contribute it back
guys like we're all
just making this thing
better so uh yeah if
it's if it's cool and
useful and you know
you found my uh
rudimentary ui or you built
this separately no
everything is completely
separate i just use like
your tech stacks and
stuff and like with
the Rust and the Wasm
and the neural networks
and all that stuff,
but then kind of just
came up with a whole
new way of implementing
fair lines.
We're getting
close to, I think, 10
,000 downloads a day.
You should contribute
it back. You'll get
at least a few
extra users.
All right, cool.
Yeah, just do an open
an issue, create a
branch and we'll
integrate it in one of the
upcoming alpha releases
this is an mpx i
assume are you building
it separately well
it's completely
separate it's like not
even a fork of your
thing at all like i
just did it all from
scratch um but i just
have it so you can
just do npm start right
now and it kind of
boots everything up but
um i'm working on
fixing just a few things
to get it fully
working but yeah okay
well if you um if you
do it as an MPX, we
can include it as an
argument in our CLI.
All right, cool.
Yeah,
even better.
Next to this word, Chris.
Chris is always
pushing the boundaries,
man. I love Chris.
Chris is the man.
Yeah, and by the
way, Chris, when
we call you our
favorite vibe coder,
that is not an insult.
That's a term
of endearment.
On my LinkedIn
profile, like for my
description of what i do
i just listed i'm your
favorite vibe coders
favorite vibe coder
i like your video last
night beast mode oh
yeah no that's a good
point right like with
the grok four coming
out and it's like you
know you look at the
coding benchmarks it might
not be better than
claude but it doesn't
have to be like especially
with a system like
fair of mine it just
needs to be better like
it just needs to fill
the orchestrator role
right and it needs to
be able to intelligently
orchestrate
intelligently, maybe pick
devs, uh, tech stacks,
or, you know, what might
work best or intelligent,
more intelligently
be able to plan out
the process. Like right
now with the orchestrators
in fair mind,
when I tell it to devise
a plan, right, it's
just like when you tell
it to write an email,
it gives you like 90
% of what you want.
And you're like, okay,
I need to tweak this,
this, and this. Okay.
Now it's looking good,
but the more intelligent
the AI gets, the
less tweaks you have to
do. And if you can get
to a point where you
really don't have to
tweak or you know it
does things even cooler
than you expected and
without missing anything
you know like it
doesn't have to code it
just needs to orchestrate
right and then the
coders we have right
now are already pretty
good so that's what
i've been wanting to toy
with actually so in
the last few minutes we
have here i you know
back to um alex's comment
about what do we want
the Jetix Foundation
to be? Obviously,
this foundation is not
meant to be me. It's
meant to be everyone
else. And this is meant
to be a sort of community
of people who
hopefully is passionate
about this technology
as I am. And right now,
we've been very organic.
We've been able to
get this globally from
China, the US, and
everywhere in between.
So now we're in this
interesting spot where
we're starting to get the
attention of some
really large traditional
corporate players that
are that have money
allocated to these
types of non-profits and
i'm saying substantial
amounts so the fundamental
question is you know
what what is this
what is what should
this be where where is
it going and you know
this is something i i
think i shared my
vision earlier but i'm
actually really curious
to hear what others are
thinking and and if we
could sort of wave a
magic wand get as much
money as we possibly
could what would this
org do and what would
be the purpose of it
at least someone else's
good i mean we're
scaling for the future
right i mean we all know
jobs are going to be
displaced people's roles
are going to be changed
so what can we do at
the grassroots level
more focused by so you
see the question we
asked previously about
how do we explain
this thing how do we
adopt it in various things
so there's a lot to
do to structure that
how do you how do you
get basically new how do
you get the economy
for by enabling let's
take a simple case job
centers right but people
go they got excellent
infrastructure there
however it's a
bureaucratic process there
but the people who are
coming there you have
got captive can you
reskill them can they
support a local economy
further you know how
much So I think that
there is a huge, it's an
experimentation, but
I can be thinking more
philanthropically. I
think that's what this
foundation could make
a huge contribution.
That's my two
cents on the table.
I would add that we
need to look at it as
a community of practice,
right? Like we are
actively pushing the
limits of the technology
in different ways
that are just not ever
going to keep up with
any type of regulatory
compliance, security
compliance or
anything like that. So
what are those practices
that we are coming
across or what are
those issues that we
are coming across that
we can communicate
to the world and say,
hey, look, you need to
be careful with X. You
need to pay attention
to why and really
driving that in a more
community-based, human
-based approach. That's
what I would add.
So we have teaching
and reskilling.
We have protection
of society.
You know, I think,
Rue, what you show
us every single
week is like pushing
the boundaries
of like solving
problems that are
indescribable. So like
kind of like
exploration as well.
I mean,
this is research.
yeah exactly i'm
gonna i'm gonna throw
something out here as
well is you know a lot of
us are donating our
time to this foundation
right and we're and
because we're just super
passionate about this
but a lot of us would
like to be doing this
full-time like quit
quit our day job and just
do this because we're
so passionate about
about this but you
know i got rent to pay
you know and i got bills
to pay so it would be
what a lot of us and
i'm just guessing a
lot of us would would
would like is to somehow
how do we how do we
leverage what we're
doing here and the
fantastic you know global
interest so that uh so
there's like a community
of like opportunity
like business
opportunity where we can
consult to these lots of
companies that want our
time and expertise and
we can make a little
bit of money that can
then allow us to like
do do this as our real
job because we love
this so much we're so
passionate about it
that's an interesting
point and this is
something people ask me
every day and and i this
is meant to sound like
whatever this is what
it is you've been
like you're kind of
expensive you know where
can i find people who
don't cost as much and
one of the challenge i
have is you know we
need some form of like
accreditation or
validation i i see it like
like you know like like
a karate like you got
to go from your white
belt to your black
belt but how do we prove
that you know you're
you're capable in
the methodologies and
approaches and things
because it's really
difficult other than you
know a few of the folks
that work really closely
with me to do you
know testing and validation
things I know that
what they can do but
everyone else it's
really hard to really
say you know who's who's
good who's bad so I
think back to Brad's
point earlier we need
to spend more time on
training you know that
ranges from simple hello
worlds to, you
know, interplanetary
communication systems and
everything in between.
Yeah, I think
that's a great idea.
Like an accreditation
system, right?
Yeah, the
accreditation system
that Brad's sort
of mapping out.
Also, I'll
reshare the link.
Now that the new
website is up and
we can all go in
as beta testers
and make sure
everything is good.
We want to invite
everybody to create
short tutorials.
around very specific
tools like MCPs,
security for MCPs.
And that way, members
get a chance to
share very precise
instructionals with
the entirety of the
membership base, get
your name in front
of all the other
members, and collectively
contribute to very
specific little
bodies of knowledge.
So there's a
form to do that
and submit your
YouTube videos.
I think we hit on a
very key point in this
conversation today, and
it's a new skill set
that you have to, you
get. But like what
Reuven says is like, we
create stuff, we have
no idea how it works
necessarily, but we know
it does work. And how
do we know it works?
Through tests,
through benchmarking,
but it's determining,
well, what is
that test? What is
that benchmark I come
up with, right?
Like I can tell AI,
go build me a car.
How do I know if it
runs? Well, I turn
the key and it turns
on. I don't need to
know how many times up
and down the piston
goes every second,
right? But I know that
the test is if I turn,
you know, the key
and it starts and it
runs and everything works
the way I want it to
work, I know the
system's running, even
though I don't know
everything that's happening
in the engine, right?
And it's being able
to do something similar
to that with code.
It's understanding the
key points where you
can test to know that
it's working or not.
You don't have to know
how the system works,
but you need to know
if it's working at
these key points, the
system is working, right?
And so understanding
how to look at projects
and what you've
created in identifying
those points to test
and benchmark to say,
yes, I know this is
working, doesn't matter
how it got to that
point. I just know it is.
You do need
more than that.
You also need
to know that it
doesn't do
something nefarious.
Consider a pager
distributed
across the Middle East.
It worked. It did
everything they wanted
it to do. It just
did something else
that ended up killing
a lot of people.
I would also add on
to that, like making
things work, we really
need to move on to
the next stage of
verification of what is
working to be, what
it's actually doing.
That understanding
is very important
because we will
start to fail to even
understand even when
we ask AI to try
their best to
explain to us. And if
there are any no
like, oh, it works,
That is how we
build stuff, but
that's not how we
deploy large-scale
this kind of
system into our
important sections
of our economy.
There is an important
point that you have to
keep in mind. When you
say it works because
I am testing it and
I have good results,
I worked for many major
banks here. we do all
testing and it works
but sometimes we miss
some some functionalities
that we didn't
test and later on after
deploying on prediction
we figure out that
oh we missed this big
piece even the system
is working but some
special use case that
is we did we missed and
those special use case
you can lose money
when you don't check
so the most important
you have to make sure
that your test is
complete its functionality
is working you know
what i mean so my idea
is if you have one
million thousand of
code you test input you
get the benchmark you
see the output is working
but for somehow in
in underneath there
are some connection
that you need we didn't
use yet and they are
they can be catastrophic
this is the challenge
i don't know if uh if
i am clear or not no
i think what you're
saying is even in
the in in traditional
enterprises when you build
software you you build
it to the best you
can and there's always
going to be bugs and
problems that are
unexpected but i think
for what we're doing
there's this we have
to raise the bench even
higher the the benchmark
the bar or whatever
and we need to we need
to be able to not just
prove and validate
and add introspection.
And the requirement
is going to be more
than it even is in
traditional software
development because
there's almost
an expectation that
this is garbage.
Right,
exactly.
One thing I would
add, Ruben, you were
asking about what should
the foundation be?
What sort of big
bucket things we should
focus on? Probably,
you know, there was a
discussion today about
ethics and security.
We probably want a part
of the foundation to
have some focus on
ethics Because we're at
the cutting, bleeding
edge, and maybe ethics
for what we're doing
is – and security is
different, right? It's,
again, we're pushing
that. So you might
want to have, you know,
nod rails. Does
that even make sense
for a swarm-type, you
know, flow system?
I don't know. But
the foundation
should have a focus
on asking those
questions and what
does it mean to us?
Exactly.
I heard that, guys.
We're out of time.
I have something
to say on that one,
sorry. All right,
go ahead, Jose.
Yeah, sorry.
The question here
is, it looks like the
swarm works better
when you let it go.
The regulations
should be on specific
projects that we want
to build with it.
So I think we have
to define where
the limits have to
go. in the project
that we're building
with it or in
the system that
is building these
projects? This is
my point of view.
I would say just
don't be evil. Let's
make the world a better
place than it was.
And ultimately, you
know, with any powerful
technology there's two
sides to it. One is
we can be used to
hopefully make our lives
better through medical
and whatever else. And
obviously there's many,
many ways for this
to be used for terrible
ways as well. And I
think that understanding
how it works is a
hedge against the terrible
ways it can be used.
And ultimately, if
we're not doing it,
someone else is likely
doing it and they're
doing it in private, in
a research lab, in some
dark basement somewhere.
And if we're not
researching this
ourselves openly in the
public, then that'll be
opaque and hidden from
view so and i'm really
cognizant of the
potential ways that
this thing could be used
badly i you know i give
an example i had to
accidentally hack the
tax service earlier in
the week you know
that wasn't purposeful
obviously but imagine if
people start doing that
purposefully so
ultimately we are i don't
know i'm gonna sound like
a like a like a crazy
person we're the
protectors where our job
is to act as that sort
of line of defense
against hopefully the
the dark shady characters
looking to do bad
things and if we can be
those people all the
better yeah then the
foundation needs to have
some kind of prescriptive
focus on that on
that mantra that's it
exactly david and so
for folks that want to
participate in the
round table uh please do
maybe maybe maybe very
quickly follow the
kind of academic
concepts for teaching uh
worldwide people how
swarth works educational
purpose maybe that's
a good model yeah all
right that's it guys
this has been a really
good uh presentation
and episode i want to
thank the production team
who have been buzzing
around all week while
i've been doing my
calls calce uh and angelo
rob and others thank
you i really appreciate
all the effort and
we're all volunteers
and we all have jobs
we have to pay the bills
to uh david's point
so i i i really do
appreciate all the effort
everybody's putting in
um the new york crew
****** v and jed and
ocean everyone thank
you and if you want to
do a local uh events
we got them popping
up everywhere i think
there's one coming up in
orange county it's like
just let us know join
the discord discord
.agentix.org ambassador
channel ambassador
channel if you want to
want to do these um and
if you have some leads
on sponsors who might
want to help us uh
keep the lights on send
them send them our way
um hopefully we have
some news over the
next couple weeks and
some of the conversations
we're having on that
front as well thank
you everyone until
thanks everyone awesome
demo jade i loved it man
great demo thanks all
right okay you guys