This used to work.
All right. Hey, thanks
everyone. Thanks
for, thanks for
joining this. It's
been an interesting
week. And the, the
amount of interest in
this thing has been
absolutely crazy.
For, for those who
aren't familiar,
the, you know, the
other day I launched
this, this idea
of Claude flow,
which, you know,
I just throw it
there as a, you
know, a random idea.
And the thing seems
to have blown up.
I, I can't keep interest
that, that seems
to be coming in.
So I'm gonna do my
best to sort of
help people through
problems and debugging
if we can. Maybe we'll
fix some errors as
well. I did a push
last night at one o
'clock in the morning
after I finished
all my other work.
So make sure you're
using the version,
the most recent version.
And I'm gonna
actually, one sec, I'm
gonna mute you guys.
I can hear someone's,
there we go. All right.
so make sure you're
using the the
version 72 and you're
wondering why there's
72 one of the i'm using
the the swarm itself
to build the swarm so
sometimes it decides
to go and auto publish
that so before i
even realized it did
like 20 freaking versions
and that so that's
how we're up 72 so so
quickly but so that
is a learning lesson
make sure that you
give it clear and
concise guidance. But the
key here is that
I've added a few new
features. One, I added
the settings option.
The settings option,
let me show you that
quick. So to instantiate
it, you're going to
run something like
mpx quad dash flow at
latest. And then you
can do init and then
spark. Now in this
case, I'm going to do
this in a subfolder
just to show you the
files because I've
already done this before.
So I'm going to go
here. I'm going to MK a
init test, and then
I'm going to go into
that folder, init test,
and then I'm going to
run this in this
folder. And what that'll
do is it'll give me just
an idea of the files
that are getting
created, right? So in
this case, we can see
here that it's created
the cloud flow. It's
created, this is the
wrapper. So to Martin's
point earlier, if you
want to use an alias,
you're going to point
it at this wrapper.
This wrapper essentially
allows me to execute
from a working
folder it's and this
essentially gets around
the problem with the
node modules that you
sometimes might might
experience but in order
to use it what you
have to do is you're
gonna have to use
something like this so dot
quad flow and that
will essentially allow
you to see it that it's
working see all the
different options
available to you and so
on the and the other
thing that sometimes
people run into here
is when they're when
they're trying to you
know use it they might
not have clod instantiated
correctly so what
you want to do before
you even start she
logged in and and you've
installed clod flow
or sorry clod code
so i think it's mpn i
actually don't remember
what the mpn is but
you can you can do a
search for that and find
that pretty easily but
make sure make sure
it's installed you
can just tell it's
installed by doing this
sell the commands the
the most important
command And here, and you
can use it directly
as well. So if I don't
use the Cloudflow, you
can go and do this.
And we're gonna
go here and do
dangerously skip
permissions.
I'm handling
the permission
separately, but what
you can also see
are some of the
different folders
and different
options available to,
you know,
different modes,
swarm commands
like this, some
maintenance.
So I've added lots of
different options,
researcher,
and these are
essentially these modes
here. So you can
see the commands.
So these are some of
the modes that, and
you can add your own
if you want as well.
These are meant to
just be sort of a
guide for what you
might wanna do yourself.
I'm having an issue. I
need to re-instantiate
this. I'll do a
push later this
afternoon where it
fixes the fact it's not
creating all the Spark
files, but it does
work when you actually
instantiate directly,
which I'm gonna do
here in a moment.
So I just confirmed
everything works. so I'm
gonna I'm gonna go
back up one level run
it from that location I
don't I probably don't
need this in a test
so I'll get rid of
that and I'm gonna
delete that all right so
now that now we got that
out of the way you've
used so step one
install cloud code step
to install the cloud
flow system step three
once it once those
two things are both
initialized you can start
running various options
so against dot slash
cloud flow and we can
and I'm gonna use
swarm which is the kind
of the coolest feature
and let me do help on
that now this this
will show us all the
various help commands
now you if you don't add
anything even you just
you need to run it
with this command you
you basically are getting
the auto mode the auto
mode automatically
determines the best
approach i generally
use that if i'm if i'm
doing other i can use
different modes they're
centralized hierarchical
and these are different
structures for
how the the swarms
communicate with each
other in a sort of
logical sort of sort of
way so in this case
let's say i want to do
something of interest
so let's go here and i'm
gonna i'm just gonna
go and grab let's do
the let's do this one
cloud or architecture
just for a heck of
it and i'm gonna stop
before it actually works
but we'll go here and
we'll distribute it
strategy research this
is this This is using
some variables. So you
can see here that
status is researched,
mode is distributed,
and that's gonna change
up the actual guidance
that's passed to it.
So you can see I'm
telling you how to use
the memory and I'm
doing various other
things. And by the
way, if anyone ran into
that memory issue, I
fixed it last night.
I'm one guy and I'm
trying to juggle
probably more than
I should. And that
was a bug that I
induced a couple days
ago and never had
a chance to fix.
I'm just as good at
creating bugs as I am
code. mode, but now
we see here that we're
going to execute a swarm,
and I'm only executing
the swarm just to
see what's happening.
Unfortunately,
Claude, I maxed out my
Opus 4, so thinking
mode is disabled.
If you're lucky enough
to start and you're
going to have a
thinking mode, the
thinking mode really
kicks up a notch.
I've actually optimized
the thinking mode
as well in the... Do
I not have my Claude
folder? Yeah, it
looks like I don't.
Whoops. All right, I'm
gonna fix that while
this works. But we
can see here that it's
initialized a... So
what's happening here
is we now have a swarm
of five working in
unison to each other.
So in this case, this
swarm is basically
just doing research.
So, and this one's
actually, you can
see it's due ahead
in the memory.
So the memory
essentially allows it to
give it a sort of
short-term memory of
what it's doing and
what it's done in the
past. And I'm using
a super simple sort
of approach to memory.
I'm using just a
sort of JSON style.
I've got another
implementation using
SQLite, but I need to
do some more testing,
so I won't get into
that right now. But
basically, it stores
it as a kind of
sequential JSON file.
So you see here,
you can see it
thinking through
its processes.
This particular
mode, research mode,
is essentially a
deep, deep research.
But the benefit to
this mode is I can then
use that to actually
implement whatever
I'm researching so
you can see here some
of the data that's
creating here's the
json files for the
memory nothing nothing at
it yet so let's see
what else we got here
so quick quick
question for you Ruben
is that is your uh your
research is it using
an mcp tool or is
it just native cloud
it's using the native
cloud uh web search
capability as there was
no sense reinventing
the wheel so I just
use the one that's
built in now I noticed
there was a slight
problem so I'm to stop
this for a moment.
And then I'm going
to jump to another
terminal for a
sec. And I noticed
that I actually,
looks like I might
have accidentally
deleted the cloud
folder. So I'm going
to go cloudflow,
init, spark, and
I'll be forced
since I'm overwriting
some files.
Oops, I got to do init,
spell that correctly.
What is force
doing? Right?
Force is
overriding. So I'm
overriding some
of the files.
So in this case,
I wanted to create
this. This is giving
me the commands.
I actually didn't
have those.
If it removes the memory,
like if I had
memory stored.
Yeah, it does, it
overrides. So use, so
what I could have
done if I was worried
about overriding the
memory, I haven't
done anything yet
to really care about
that. But what I
could have done is did
this in a subfolder
and just copied the
bits and pieces
that I wanted from a
subfolder, you know,
which I showed earlier.
So we're going to
go back. I'm going
to close this up
again. This time I'm
going to let's try
a different mode
just to see what happens.
We have different
options here. So
I'm going to do a
mode where I do 10
agents this time.
So, again, the key
here is you probably
need to use the
wrapper. first a dot
slash cloud flow
swarm analyze user
data. That's a pretty
bad one. So I'm
going to say research
the development
of a zero person
startup and place in
dot plans. Now,
this is particularly
well suited for
really deep research
because you can do
it concurrently.
don't implement
this document.
All right. So what
I'm doing right now is
I'm testing 10 agents.
I've done this at
the 50 agents. I'm not
going to do 50 agents
right now because I
know it'll max it out.
And I got work to do
this afternoon beyond
this call. So I
don't want to be rate
limited um by by clod
but 50 agents is just
crazy it it can do all
kinds of things now
the the most of
these swarms beyond
research i find is like
optimization so i i've
been i've been working
on a project where
i'm creating a kind
of you know a quantum
inspired dark net
and a lot of that was
sort of optimization
and benchmarking and
basically i create a
swarm and basically
pointed and said give
me you know the most
optimized version i can
possibly have for for
this system and and
then it worked for
several hours and
eventually it gave me the
sort of final optimized
uh options for it
all right so oh the
thinking is working again
okay so i this one
the thing is working
because i added the
cloud folder so that
specifically is relating
to this file the
settings the settings
file tells you what's
allowed so i'm allowing
all the various things
tells you max timeout
rate so if you run
into the timeout issue
i i've added that so
that resolves that problem
i've set the working
directory option so
you sort of might
work better time you
know and various other
things here's some
automation rules for for
my system backoffs things
like that now let's
take a look at what's
happening down here
all right so now
what what i'm testing
right now is i want to
do it i uh let's let me
begin my researching
zero person startups
let's see check
interesting it it created
the plan but now
it's working and
it's sometimes like
like a like a boat
motor a little bit
so it's doing it's
doing the uh it's
doing this in parallel
So this is why you
have to watch it.
I'll see spawn a 10 agent
swarm using batch tool.
So I noticed it probably
would have eventually
got to the 10
agents, but I want to
spawn it earlier
because right now it's
kind of doing the
initial research. And we
can, now that I've
got the thinking mode,
the thinking mode
is good for certain
things, but also sometimes
makes it kind of go
in more and more
declarative direction
that I don't always
like. But that's okay.
I caught it early.
So now we see
it spawning each
of these agents.
So when you don't run
the system with Claude
Flow, it would have
done what it was going
to originally try to
do. It would have just
done each of these one
at a time sequentially.
But what I actually
want it to do is run
it in parallel. Now
the parallel you're
going to see here is
especially when you're
running 10 is this
weird screen flickering
thing that's a cloud
flow thing and i don't
think they've necessarily
built the system for
concurrency so but
it doesn't mean it's
not working it just means
that you need a bigger
screen and i'm on
a smaller screen to
sort of show you guys
how this looks let's see
maybe i can make it
a little bigger and
zoom out a little bit
yeah zooming out usually
usually solves it let's
see yeah it's still
flickering a little
bit but that's because
I've got so many
different agents running.
Yeah, we're one,
two, three, four.
Yeah, looks
like we're good.
So we can see the
different, I know you
probably can't see
that because I zoomed
out too much, but
basically you can see each
of the agents creates
its own subtasks.
Now I can get really
detailed in that. So
if I wanna take this
a step further, I can
use the workflow
orchestration components
and get really detailed
on what each of
those agents need to
do but in this case
i gave it a pretty
broad description i you
know i said basically
create me a business
plan for um doing a
zero person startup
you know so it's
basically researching
what a zero person
startup would even do and
it's going to put
place those in the
plans folder you see
that it's starting to
build some files for
it let's see so this
is an automation there's
the automated design
for admission minimal
well you probably
can't see that i
think i zoomed out too
So basically, this is the
first one that's done.
Let's see what
it's doing here.
Control-Shift-V to
render markdown, by
the way, if you're
interested. I just
like reading it
when it's rendered.
So this document
outlines a comprehensive
workflow for minimal
human intervention.
Okay. Looks pretty good.
financial that's cool
everyone seems to want
a zero person startup
so want to create
a system for it that's
kind of what i was
thinking and again the
this flickering things
little annoying but
doesn't necessarily
mean anything it is
it is working question
for you will this uh
recording be available
after the call here
yeah it will at some
point be on video dot
uh video.agentix.org
if you guys are this
week i'm going to move
to restream or maybe
find someone to
help me set it up
before the call um two
weeks in a row i haven't
been able to stream
to linkedin for some
random error that i
don't feel like
debugging right now so uh
sorry about that but
we do we are recording
this here's another
file so this is
creating the comprehensive
zero person startup
implementation guide
so this is what
i'll and i get a kick
out of this by the way
one to two months for
this sort of thing
i i one month one
before this is stuff
that'll take literally
like an hour or two
it's i don't know
where it works
i guess if
humans were doing
it it might take
eight months
12 months 18 months
and then this will
basically allow
it to follow the
implementation
alright so it's still
still doing its thing
I picked up 10
quick question for
you Ruben you know the
github issue you were
talking about where
it just created 20
check-ins and pushes.
Are you using the
native Claude GitHub
integration where if you
use that, you're forced
to use their workflow
with, you know, you've
got to create issues,
going to create PRs,
going to add Claude
mention, review the PR.
Or are you using
GitHub MCP where
you can use your
own GitHub workflow?
I'm just telling it
to commit and skipping
all that stuff. And
I'm just saying go and
commit it to my, create
a branch and commit it
kind of thing, you
know. and or i'm using
what they call it the
work workspace or work
tree option i've used
that a few times work
where each of the
different agents has his
own work tree and then
then i've got the final
agent bring all the
brings all the work
trees together there's
depending what you're
doing there's lots of
different ways to sort
of you know to orchestrate
these swarms i'm
still learning to be
honest like i launched
this a few days ago and
i so i'm still trying
to figure out exactly
what the optimal
swarm is for different
types of jobs and
processes generally speaking
what i've discovered
this week is this is
really good for complex
code bases so if you
if someone you know
showed me a code base
yesterday they had this
10 year old php
applications about 30 30
000 lines of code and
it was like a storage
system and i pointed
at it and i created a
rust version of it and
it basically recreated
the entire uh it took
that took about an
hour um it's good at that
and it's good at this
kind of early stage
research where i want
to figure out what
exactly i want to do and
then and then implement
it in in in a more
structured way later
now the fact that 10 10
agents was probably
an overkill for
what i'm trying to do
here i'm really just
trying to show off
that i could do
10 agents you can
see here it's storing
it's it's it's storing
its uh you know,
plans and information
to storage. So
some of this being
stored to memory.
I'm gonna let
this continue.
Now I can go over here
and now I can
concurrently
do another swarm.
And I'll do spawn.
And this time I'm
just going to do
something a little
more simple, you
know, assist the
other agents in
the implementation.
Implementation of the dot
plans, focus on
the development.
I'm vibing this.
I'm not even sure
what the heck it's
going to build.
You know, nothing
really matters. I'm
just showing what's
possible. So in this
case, I've got
another swarm. Oops.
I did spawn, not swarm.
spawn something I
am working on spawn
but that's a different
feature that I will
announce later swarm
spawns basically split
spawn does or will do
when I'm done is a it
uses a more age agent
style approach where
the agent is a little
more intelligent and
and will orchestrate
self-orchestrate
it's kind of more
reminiscent of like brew
and the orchestration
mode than that that
but right now I'm all
about swarm so we're
gonna stick with that
for now you can see the
files keep on getting
created here but to
speed up the process
i'm just going to
go in here and i'm
getting this this particular
one which is using
the auto strategy
centralized and five
agents to go and start
implementing the plans
yeah you see i maxed
out my my cloud 4.
as far as
All right. And in
this case, I don't
necessarily want the
agent. I want the agents to
sort of do a quick
review, which so and
that so the spawning of
the of the specialized
agents should happen
after it looked at
what it needs to do.
And I really like this
new thinking option.
I added yesterday.
It really seems to
give it a nice sort of,
you know, improvement
in terms of capability.
It was pretty capable
before. But you
can see now you can
see what it's thinking,
which I like. so now
i need to spawn five
agents yeah lead or
court yeah that's good
so now now we've got
concurrently we've
got this this one
running here doing the
research and now we have
this this one running
doing the implementation
so i'm currently
running a 15 agent
swarm for no freaking
cost so just just
to give you guys an
idea cost for a moment
which is just absolutely
crazy over the last
year i i've produced
give or take 15
million lines of code,
which is astronomical.
That's many lifetimes
of code in the last
year. In the last
two weeks, I've
created 5 million lines
of code, which is also
absolutely bonkers.
And in the last day,
yesterday, I created
2 million lines
of code, which is,
so give or take 10
% of my overall code
generation over the
last year happened
yesterday. And what's
even more amazing,
I spent give or
take $100,000
on API-related
work for the stuff
I do over the
last 12 months.
In the last four weeks
since I've switched
to the Claude Max, I
spent a grand total,
including Claude Max,
of something like $250.
So if I was to run
this exact same
Swarm setup using
my Spark 1 agent
that I built last
year, it would run
me around $7,500
an hour. And now
I'm doing that at
basically no cost.
And it's all included
in the $200 that I'm
paying. So we're at
this weird inflection
point where it's both
exponentially more
capable, but also not
just exponentially more
capable, but exponentially
cheaper at the
same time, which
is a weird kind of
inflection. You don't
usually see the movement
of both capability and
price drop and go in
either direction.
So I would say when
looking back at 2025
as a formative year for
Agentix, I would say
last week or last couple
of weeks might be the
most transformative
of this year so far,
at least if you're
working in automated
code-based development
systems, just the kind
of transformation.
Just as a matter
of interest, what
kind of platform
have you been
creating 2 million
lines of code in?
Oh, okay. Is that a
Salesforce replica?
No. Well, you're
a good question.
All right. Well, client
projects, but I am
actually working on
something in particular.
Where did I put that?
Is it this one?
Yeah, here it is.
All right.
I'm going to let that
keep baking a little bit.
Yeah, so I'm trying
to build the most
complicated thing I
could possibly imagine.
Like,
I'm not even kidding.
it sounds like i'm full
of **** when i say it
but it's true um so
what what i'm attempting
to build here is a
novel new distributed
ledger system that
doesn't require any bs
crypto or anything like
that to actually work
but it's completely free
and open so this is
a quantum resistant
distributed communication
platform built with
a direct acillic graph
dag architecture and
it's It's hyper-optimized
for speed, where
blockchains are antiquated
20-year-old tech.
If you're going
to build a darknet
today, you're not
going to use blockchain
unless you want a
slow-*** database.
So what I was
attempting to build,
and what I wanted
to build here was
a darknet service,
just because.
So we're using the
dark address. It uses
post-quantum-based
encryption algorithms,
high-performance
DAG, QR Avalanche,
Consensus, Anonymous,
Onion Routing.
I wanted to actually
work with my Cloudflare
account. So, you know,
secure communications,
network infrastructure,
darknet sub
-domain system. This
all freaking works, by
the way, unless I broke
it just before the
call. Let's just keep
our fingers crossed.
Yeah, here we
go. So basically,
so let's do cloud start.
This is gonna
run the node.
This is, I
literally built
like a next generation
distributed ledger
with millions of lines
of code. Well, in
this case, not millions,
but I churned through
millions of lines of
code to get to this
in the last few days.
And this is gonna be
a blog post I might
do later today or
tomorrow, but I've got a
P2P consensus algorithm,
DAG consensus, dark
resolver. So if I
want to go here and
add a domain, let's go
here. I'll show you
what that looks like.
I'll do, and I got to
remember what the command
was. And I, and I
optimized it using self
benchmarking
system. So this, the
benchmarking system is
actually built in Python.
And this allowed me
to get, you know,
millisecond response
times. So now
if I want to add
a domain I'm going
to do that address
I don't remember
what that was so
I'll do help on that
and we'll add
that so we'll add
register I think
it's register
and then I usually
I just point the
AI you get to this
and there's a whole
API with this too
by the way yeah
you know it just
uh what I've seen
here is what's being
unlocked is play
just being able to play
at that create level
of creativity is is
what hasn't been there
yes i've been i built
a novel massive this
this is like roughly
uh you know a thousand
times more complex
than the first version
of ethereum just if
you want to base if
you want a sort of base
level of complexity
and it's obviously
way more efficient
and doesn't require
some ******** crypto to
to use right so
this is everything a
blockchain should be it
isn't a blockchain it's
a dag but you know
conceptually it's
similar um but yeah
it's like hey i'm gonna
build i want to i
literally said to the swarm
i want to build
something that's never
been done and crazy
complicated like basically
that's the guidance
i'm giving it and
it gave me some ideas
and like why don't
you think about doing
a p2p style uh quantum
proof dark net well
sure let's do that.
And I did that, you
know, and this has
been running basically
for the last, uh, 48
hours or so. But if
you go here, you can,
you can check it
out. I'm going to do
a blog post on it when
I get it, when I'm
fully done doing it.
I'm sure everyone
will be like, what
the **** man, but, um,
here it is. You
guys can try
it. And this
has been, by the
way, this is all
built in rust,
which is probably
the most complicated
system you could
probably build these
things in. So we
can go here. We can
see the core. We'll
go to the core.
Can I ask you a question
about this warm?
Sure. Let's go
back to that.
Wouldn't you be
duplicating some tasks
that are similar for
each particular process?
Or how does that work?
You know what I mean?
i ran i ran i ran i
reached my limit when
is 5 p.m utc in in in
a half an hour **** i
went i overdid i overdid
this warm guy sorry
about that sorry say say
your say your question
again so you're
creating obviously the
parallel the actual
processes and they have to
create the tasks correct
with regard to what
they're doing wouldn't
some of those tasks
be repetitive and
you're basically birding
tokens as they're
doing it no i've got
coordinator that
that manages that
so the coordinator
the coordination
system it basically
allows for the system
to avoid overlap so when
you look at each of
these tasks and we can
hit control r to get oh
no i can't do that with
with this but basically
each of these you
see one's doing market
research the other
doing is doing the
technology stack the others
in model agent legal
compliance and so on
and this one it was
doing this this one was
doing the implementation
so this is a lead
coordinator agent then
it's got the customer
acquisition specialist
and so the each each of
which is using different
approaches so what's
interesting here
when you look at the
actual steps is the
time now if i was using
cursor or Roo or Klein
or one of those tools, I
could probably do most
of the same things,
but those are going to
happen sequentially.
So the first thing would
take seven minutes.
The next would take
13, seven, two, seven,
seven, seven. This would
have been what? I'm
not doing the math
quickly, but let's say
probably more like 40
minutes, 45 minutes. But
instead I did it all
in roughly 13 minutes,
right? So I'm taking
a 45 minute, at
least a 45 minute
project and doing it
in 10, 13 in this
case. Have you thought
about the ability
of the parallel
processes talking to
each other somehow,
communicating through
the JSON memory?
Yes.
Yeah, so that's
exactly what's
happening. So there's
an internal memory
that allows it to
also coordinate.
So you'll see here,
and I apologize,
guys. I was on
call since 8 o
'clock this morning,
so I apparently
maxed out for the
next half an hour.
But we can discuss
it regardless, or I
can help you guys see
some of your bugs.
But in this case, you've
got this option
for memory.
And I'm going to build
this out. Again, I
launched this last week
after building it for
like a day. So, you
know, it's... And last
one is, this is my first
time actually physically
looking at you.
You're one of the few
people that actually
looks younger than their
picture. I don't know
if that's a purpose.
For those who care,
I'm 46. six yeah so i
but which which in like
the age of ai means
i'm like a grandfather
i i've been i've come
to learn but well
you're impressive that's
exactly what we all
try to do at least i
try to do the same
thing when i get to a
certain point and i need
to get further the only
verbiage i can come
up with is ludicrous
mode or something to
get to the next level
and think of something
so you're absolutely
this is this is great
stuff man i'm really
looking forward to uh
you know following you
on this and one more
thing i know you
probably don't even
notice it but like i work
with high schools and
stuff and i point the
kids to you so you may
not you may think we're
a bunch of old geeks
looking at you but
there's a whole
generation of people that
really are looking at
what you're accomplishing
so definitely keep it
going man i appreciate
that and again i'm
just i'm loving this
sort of age of creation
the age of abundance
the ability to build
random ideas on
monday launch it on
tuesday and and basically
either it works and
there's 50 000 downloads
on wednesday or i move
on to the next thing
that's it that's my
entire plan and this
so this sort of thing
is i like as an old
school dev i'm like living
the sort of cyberpunk
future i read about
when i was a teenager
right so if you don't
mind me asking that
question around the
turn of the century you
were on 20 right and
you saw the whole dot
-com evolution happen
how does this relate
to what you experienced
25 years ago. And
I don't want to get
too much into this.
I'm kind of
blocking everybody's
time, but I'm just
kind of curious.
Well, what's interesting,
for those who know me,
when I was 12,
this was 1990.
You can do the math.
I am what I am. I was
one of the first beta
testers for AOL pre
-launch of Windows 3.1.
And that was my introduction
to sort of online
technology. At the
time, I was running my
own BBS, plugging up my
parents' phone lines.
So I've always had
an interest in this
technology. And when,
you know, when I was a
teenager, you know,
1994, the internet became
a thing. And of course,
I created the high
school internet club
because, you know, I'm
what a nerd grows up
to look like. and and
that introduction to
sort of you know other
like-minded individuals
i created my gopher
message uh system and
all that sort of stuff
similar to you know the
discord channel today
but using gopher for
those old enough to
remember what that was
and then i discovered
ic irc and was literally
the irc and it was
distributed it was
decentralized and i met
sean fanning on on irc
who was creating these
bots. So a group of
us, this was like 1997.
We were creating these
bots, F-bots, looks
almost exactly like
what this is. Like
this is what essentially
an F-bot was, right?
You had these
different commands, you
could run them. And we
were using it to share
this brand new
technology, which was
blowing our minds at
the time, called an MP3.
And we're like, what
if we could create a
system to share these
MP3s in a more automated
way, like not just
using this kind of
text-based interface so
sean who i met on the
irc says let's let's
design this thing and
so we devised this
thing called napster
and the what what happened
was it blew up kind
of like the claw
the cloud flow like
literally overnight based
on this kind of core
group of ic irc users
and next thing you
know everyone everywhere
was using it and it
became a whole thing
and then metallica
which was my my my idol
i loved metallica in
the 90s i saw them
in Irvine, you know,
Meadows in Los Angeles
and the whole place burned
down. It was like my,
my, my band, they,
they like suit us,
which was like the most
devastating thing you
could ever imagine.
Anyway, long
story short, that,
that, that burned
out pretty quickly,
but that introduced
me to a whole
variety of other
technologies.
So everything that
you're seeing now is kind
of like for me, an
evolution of like the
last 30 years, right?
I dreamed of creating
these autonomous AI systems
that could communicate
and collaborate and
spawn, share information.
You know, when we
launched AWS in 2006,
the driving factor
for the first versions
of AWS was to create
these kind of autonomous
platforms that would
self-heal and self
-scale. But it turned out
what we were missing,
you know, in that
early work was the fact
that we didn't have the
sort of intelligence
to do the self-automation.
So as long as we
stayed within the sort
of guidelines of the
procedures, DevOps
style, it would work. But
as soon as something
went beyond the sort of
scope of those procedures
it all it would all
fall down that now
all goes away anyway
yeah this is great
thanks man yeah good to
virtually meet you so
yeah thanks thanks for
showing up um good
question on your on your
memory system uh rUv are
you using in your current
system you are you
are using the claude
native hash memory
slash memory system or
using your your pre-built
or an mcp memory system
i'm using mine and
it's and currently it's
json um and i'm just
compressing and i'm
thinking about using
my symbolic uh logic
system this you know
symbolic language system
potentially for that going
forward but basically
i'm doing i'm using
two approaches i
haven't rolled out but
hidden in in the code
you'll see that i'm using
SQL lite as well, which
I might use in an
update maybe next week,
or if anyone wants to
help contribute to the
project, you might want
to take a look. But
basically, I thought
the simplest approach
is the best approach.
So rather than going
and using a vector,
which I could do, and for
those who are interested,
I do have a vector
implementation here,
which I called fact,
which I could easily
integrate to do exactly
that. But this seemed
to me to be overkill.
so rather than rather
than using uh you know
this approach i figured
i'd go and use a a
much simpler json based
approach i mean that's
what you're seeing right
here so the benefit
of that is you can
integrate with anything
so this is this is
what it looks like so
i mean the simplest the
simplest system is to
use claude's native
inbuilt hash memory
system but um but that's
fine it doesn't work
well i i know i agree
i agree i've tested it
extensively and i do
not like it it's it's
not it doesn't work well
yeah so i i tried that
at first because i'm
like oh i'll just use
what they have and
then i quickly realized
that it uses this idea
of the clod file here
as the basis and the
problem is it only pays
attention to this file
at the very beginning
right that's what
that's what it does yeah
yeah so what i did is
i took this clod file
and i gave it some
guidance on how to use
my monitoring systems
and my and the various
other things like i i
created a uh a ui as
well which again i'm
looking for contributors
you guys are interested
let me show you what
that looks like i think
it's not working by
the way i'm it's it's
still in development
and uh yeah it's this
is in development
this is not it's it's
definitely not stable
i do have a stupid
question are the tasks
able to use our mcps
to do stuff that we
set up or no uh yes
yeah yeah yeah i use
all i i use the like
you can see here i've
got i don't know if
i have mcps on this
particular install but
um yeah the sub agents
in here at the mcp
configure of the of
the parent yeah yeah
i would love to know
what mcps you use
actually i like i'm using
one of my favorites
is is the Supabase MCP
for really complex
edge functions. I'm
using it for the various
types of triggers
and stored procedures,
it's spectacular.
So I'll point it at a
project and basically
say, create me the
world's most intricate
database structure
and it'll just do it.
What about for like
scraping or anything
like that or even
bringing data in besides
the native cloud stuff?
How would that work?
um yeah yeah you can use
playwright
things like that
so i'm gonna work i and
fire crawl are usually
good for external
browsers uh whoever was
asking earlier yeah
fire crawl is my go-to
no i guess i'm just
thinking about the process
right now you mentioned
that the native
uh claude used the
native cloud tools to be
able to do the research
right we can't replace
them if we wanted to
at that level right
now right yeah yeah you
can yeah so i i don't
have that in this
particular version but
um yeah you can add
and and they rolled out
streamable http the
other day so now you can
use all the streamable
ones as well like
composio and and mcp run
and a few other services
um i'm to those who
mentioned yes this
is a work in progress
um the issue that i i'm
i haven't got to yet
is i'm using i think
web sockets for this
particular implementation
of the ui but i do
have the ui i just need
to connect the web
socket again i just gotta
have time and you hear
the biggest complaint
about anthropic with
regard to their deep
search is not really
working the way it used
to when it first came
out because they're
overloaded with they're
using a similar process
as you are but what
i hear is the results
from deep search are
just **** right now
and people are complaining
i don't know if you
heard that or not or
uh which service like
deep like for deep search
from claude themselves
uh the ones you know
it's in beta you
can go to desk top or
whatever oh yeah yeah
yeah and it's a it's a
multi-threaded process
and um in the beginning
was amazing now it's
**** from what i
understand and people are
beginning to complain
about it due to the
fact that because so
many people are yeah i'm
doing stuff like this
yeah yeah so i look
look what i did i i
was showing off and and
i i got this yeah and
and the only reason i
got this is because i
uh i was i was actually
showing off all
morning on like several
other calls i should have
probably limited myself
this today just to
make time for this call
so my apologies but
um you guys get the
get the idea that this
is pretty spectacular.
Quick question.
I've been trying to
get clone the repo
and rebuild it
locally, and it's been
failing in the previous
recent disrelease.
Just wondering if
I'm doing anything
wrong. I created
an issue for it,
but if anyone else
has not had that
problem or has
had that problem.
Yeah, the way I
fixed it, I did it
from Claude, and
Claude fixed it.
Yeah, you know
what's probably the
problem is I'm
pushing my local dev
environment and
there's probably like
configurations that
I haven't included
potentially. But the
suggestion to use
Cloud Code to fix
it is a good one.
That's probably
what I'll do.
You're probably seeing
TypeScript errors,
I would guess.
Yeah, that's right.
And Dino and...
Yeah, I didn't have
Dino installed the
PK-zip, PK-unzip.
And it kept blasting,
crashing. So when
I did it through
Claw to just install,
told me what to
do, how to install
it, and the whole
thing just worked.
Yeah, I've been
moving away from Dino.
So the biggest issue
I had last week was
everyone was suffering
through Dino issues.
So what I did is I
ended up rebuilding the
entire thing. Well,
I, the bot, whatever,
ended up rebuilding
the entire thing using
Node.js TypeScript.
and now the the there
was some regression in
terms of capabilities
that's why for example
the ui stopped working
because i you know i
moved i had to move
it all from dino so
all the stuff that was
working in dino's now
has to be rebuilt a
little bit so i focused
on the core capabilities
and the swarm
capabilities i'll build
i'll i'll get to the
complete fix for all
that stuff but But
the quick, and you see
that I've got a build
script specifically for
how I deploy to my
NPM, that build script
should work. And it
sort of disregards the,
where, oh, this is not
the one I want to show.
I got too many projects
on the go here.
Yeah, so there's a
build script in here.
Where the heck
did I put that?
I got to clean this up.
It's a little messy.
Have you thought
about doing anything
around agent-to
-agent payments
and how that would
work eventually?
Yeah, I did.
Stuff like that?
Of course I did.
Of course. I
haven't done it
recently. Of course.
Yeah, of course.
I called Quantum...
No, that's not much for
Quantum Applications.
Where did I put that?
Yeah, here it is.
Is there any reason why
you're moving
away from Dina?
It's hard to
use with MPX.
Yeah.
Okay. Yeah.
So I was attempting to do
a quantum cryptocurrency.
I did this a while
back, six months
ago. I should take
this and I should
integrate it with
my quantum proof
system I was
building this week.
Well, that's what
I was thinking,
kind of. Are you talking
about the DAG
stuff or different?
what are you talking
about yeah yeah that's
exactly what i'm
thinking that's exactly
what i was thinking
when you when you
start talking about
blockchain being old i
started thinking yeah
if you're able to
record all this stuff
appropriately that's
huge and i also there's
a little freebie
in here i do a symbolic
trading platform
as well for anyone
that's looking to do you
know crypto style
trading you forgot to
put the word quantum
in it for marketing
Well, this doesn't –
this other one actually
– I know, I know. I'm
just goofing around.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, I'm going
to totally do –
I deployed this.
I deployed this
using Azure
Quantum Services.
Wow, that's impressive.
And this was six
months ago, by the way.
So this was actually
built with my Spark B1,
and I probably spent
several hundred dollars
building this, And it's
way more rudimentary,
but I'm like, I'm,
I'm a good sort of
example of what, what
the space looks like
over time, because I've
been sort of doing this
since 2022, at least
the agentic engineering
components. So looking
at my GitHub is
kind of like looking
at the evolution of the
capabilities of these
systems. Now, you can
see here back six months
ago, I was already
using my Spark architecture
and pseudocode.
And this was kind
of the major sort
of aha moment for a
lot of this stuff.
And it started, you
know, having sort
of iterative test
components in here.
And I was able
to sort of start
iterating on it
and having it
automate for long
periods of time.
But this is probably
embarrassing to even
look at, given it's six
months old. i should
i should point um
once i get the quota
back up i should point
it at this and say
integrate it so what
what i might do i
might actually do that
that's that'll give
that'll give this other
project a currency
i'm just not really
big on cryptocurrencies
maybe that's my
problem i feel like
there's a regulator
ready to jump on on me
and sue me for something
are you Are you
able to share your
default ClawdMD file?
Yeah, it's built
by default.
When you do the
init command,
when you go, yeah,
you get that.
So, and I'm struggling
to whether or not to
give you like the minimal
or the optimal. So
I might add an optimal
option because right
now this is minimal.
What I'm basically
doing is I'm taking the
scaffolding and then
one of the first things
I'm doing is customizing
the scaffolding to
the project in which
i'm working on so if
i'm working on like a
quantum whatever i'm
gonna say update all the
commands and make
those commands optimize
for this particular
project so when you look
at these that's why
they're minimal they're
minimal because i i'm
going and making them
more yeah i do the
same thing when i when
i go to for optimal this
thing explodes on me
i'm like holy ****
what am i looking at so
many different things
going on so but it's
interesting so yeah the
optimal is tricky the
because the once the
the problem with the
optimal approach is it's
optimal for the thing
i tested against but
not anything else so
it's like okay i just
optimized it to do a
quantum system great
but now i want to build
a dashboard for
something else it's like
well it's going to try
to do quantum stuff so
it's just not you know
i'm just i think it's
gonna i think this is
meant to be kind of
a start kind of
scaffolding more than any
i'm not really sure
what i want it to be but
that's what i'm thinking
for me as you know
i'll take both so i
don't care whatever you
want to give don't take
it so it's good stuff
really good stuff i
i'm curious how you
think about kind of
integrating with other team
members like i'd start
using um applaud to
create user stories
and personas put them
into confluence and
jira through mcp to be
able to collaborate
with other people in the
agent tech workflow have
you done any of that
kind of collaboration
or do you have any
recommendations for
that yeah there i have
there's a slack mcp and
i of all the ones i've
tried the slack mcp
is by far the best and
what i can do with the
slack mcp i'll have
to dig that out i just
i just get too much
stuff it's hard to
remember the stuff i was
fooling around with
three days ago. But the
Slack MCP allows for a
sort of bi-directional
communication with the
system. So not only
can I get the Swarm
to sort of update the
Slack, I can then respond
to the messages sent
in Slack that get sent
back to the Swarm.
And I have a secondary
means of communicating
with the Swarm itself,
which is crazy and
amazing at the same
time, where when I go
here and i try to
communicate with the swarm
you'll notice that i i
basically have to wait
until it's done for
any of my commands to
get accepted so it's
going to do all this
stuff and then i'm sitting
back and waiting for
it to to finish by
adding the by adding the
slack mcp i've got
the ability to embed
communications directly
in each one of the
swarms itself and then
subtly sort of manipulate
or see what's happening
in the context of
that swarm so each
of these creates It's
basically a, what do
they call it in Slack? A
direct, like a direct
chat or I don't know,
some sort of direct.
Yeah, private channel.
Yeah, private
channel or something
like that. And so
then I can output
what's happening
within the context
of that to the
private channel and
then I can kind of
interact with it.
There's another
way. Are you using
that as a human in
the loop guardrails?
Yes. Is that part of it?
That's exactly
what it is.
It's the key to the
human in the loop is
because I'm in this
case, I've got 10
different agents running.
I need to be able
to communicate with
either all of them all
at once, everybody move
on or specifically,
oh, automation agent,
you're going down
the wrong path. So
secondly, I need to
be able to understand
what the heck the
automation agent is
actually doing to understand
where it's going
down the wrong path.
Because the way that
they set up this
interface, it sort of
obscures some of the
information a little
bit, which I'm exposing
in my memory system,
but it's still not
easy to quite see
in real time. So how
do you communicate
with them during Slack?
I'm confused a little
bit there. You're
seeing the process,
right? But you're able
to talk back basically
and say something?
Exactly.
So I'm able to
inject the response
directly back into
the system. Now, I
can do that because
I've created a
ton of **** here.
So this is in the
build you gave us,
what you just said?
Yeah, I'm just
having trouble
describing everything.
There's just so
much stuff going
on. But there is an
MCP mode for this
system as well.
So this means that
I can run this as an
MCP in itself that
provides the ability to
have external systems
communicate with it.
Yeah, that runs Claude
as an MCP server.
Yeah, well, I could
add the port. While
you're doing that, hey,
Andy, you asked about
team collaboration,
right? So you could also
use the Notion. A
bunch of people are
using the Notion MCP,
and it has like 19 tools.
So it's pretty rich.
So you could do Slack
or I use Notion
integration and Claude.
I'd love to have a
workflow where I can
just like talk to
Claude, say, go create
personas for these 20
different target audiences,
then have those go
to some marketing
person get approved
by marketing and then
once those are approved
come back to Claude
and then UI starts
to get generated and
the UI goes back
for approval you can
definitely do that with
Notion it would create
a Notion page that's
shared with a bunch
of team members and
it would create a
whole bunch however
you want it and then
anyone who contributed
outside of Claude in
that process, Claude
would see that update
okay
The way I've been
experimenting with that now
is I'm using the AG2
framework, which allows
support for the OpenAI
real-time LLM model,
so I can talk to what
I call Ducky, the
Digitally Unified
Conversational Knowledge
Engine, to orchestrate
my Cloudflow instances.
So I'm still
working on doing it.
I'm sure there's
a better way to
do it. It was just
faster for me.
Yeah, so that's actually
a really smart way
to do it. The A2, what
do they call it? A2
something or other?
AG2, which is Autogen.
Yeah,
Autogen.
It's Python-based,
but it's a really good
option. What I really
like is the Mastra
approach to their MCPs.
So for Mastra, which is
basically another sort
of agent framework,
you can actually call
any MCP as part of the
flow itself, right? So
this is how you call
a secondary MCP directly.
So I can orchestrate
my swarms using Mastra
or inversely. So
this is probably the
mechanism. When I do
eventually publish
the Slack option, I'm
probably going to use
something that looks similar
to this. And so
basically it's calling my
MCP directly from
Claude Flow, which I
apparently broke last
night. Sorry about that.
And I'll fix that later.
And then I can
orchestrate both the
Slack and my Swarm
at the same time.
So there'll
be a secondary
orchestrator here.
It's a pretty cool, so
this is all TypeScript
too. It's a really
nice system. It
connects to registries,
all kinds of stuff.
I'm sure a lot of
the other systems do
similar things, but
I really like the
way they're doing it.
It's very elegant.
They've also got a
memory system. So
I might look at
integrating some of
it. Since I've
already built it in
TypeScript, it'd
be super simple to
integrate Mastra
into the entire flow.
And that gives
me all their flow
systems. And I don't
want to be in the
business of creating
these things. I
just want to create
stuff that's cool.
I'll let someone
else. This handles the
memory flow. I was
very much inspired
by Mastra when I did
this in the first
place, but I might
as well just use it.
Yeah, they got some
pretty cool stuff here.
So you can do the
control flows,
paralyzation.
So that's my next
big, getting the UI
working and fixing my
MCP server will run next
two things. But then
once I have that,
I'm going to probably
integrate this stuff.
Ruv, I have a question
for you. What do
you do in the
instance that you're
running a couple of
console windows running
Cloudflow and then
you have a crash?
Like, is there any
kind of elegant way
to resume that? Because
that is something
I keep finding.
And I am sort of
testing the limits
a little bit of it.
Let me show you
how to resume. I
might actually add
a resume option
to my tool as well.
I haven't done
that yet. That
would be awesome.
But the quickest way
to resume anything,
like let's say you go
to bed and you wake
up and it's stopped
in the middle of the
night or whatever.
you're going to do ctrl c
and then you're going
to oh let's just grab
the other command so
let me help i know
clod help and the dain
living dangerous this
is the heart dangerously
skip permissions
it's so long and
stupid i don't know why
i mean such a but
anyway i think it's on
purpose right yeah so
now i'm going to do
dangerously skip
permissions so the dash c
allows you to
continue and and you
can take it a step
further you've got
the option here for
Or, where is it?
I think it was.
In a multi-task
environment, how
do you pick the
right conversation
to continue?
Yeah, that's a challenge.
Yes, that's, yeah.
So where is it?
There's an option for
that. And I include
that in my memory.
Resume, can you
resume? Here it is.
Session ID.
Ah, interesting, okay.
yeah the the the
challenge is select is
getting the session id
so what i'm what i'm
going to so what i'm
trying to do here when
you look at like uh
where did i put where
did i put this is that
like linux session
id like the process
id or your claude or
your it's claude
specific so we're looking
at the claude settings
right now and i'm
i'm essentially storing
some of that information
I just need to expose
it more easily.
So what I think I'm
going to do with my
memory is I'm going
to include the option
for these session IDs
because apparently
Claude doesn't give
you an easy way to find
out what those sessions
even are. I think
you can go back and
take a look at the top.
Could you include them
in the Slack messages?
Yeah, that's not
a bad idea either.
Here we go.
Yeah, here it is.
but the problem is
when you need to
use the session ID
it's only at a point
where the session is
longer running and
you're not going to
know what the heck
that ID is so it's a
really stupid way to
do it so that's why
I'm going to save it
in the memory and
then all we need to do
is go back to the
memory list the previous
memories which all
have a session ID
and that should solve
the issue I think
And you inject it
into your bash prompt?
Yes, that's exactly
what's happening.
Yeah.
So it's... Right, and
give it a cute
name. Yeah.
Yeah, exactly.
So what I'm doing, I'm
basically abstracting
this stuff, right?
So all the things you
see here and the settings
file is what I'm...
So this acts as a
wrapper, essentially,
for Cloud Code. And
I'm injecting prompts
and various sort of
additional environmental
variables based on
the settings, right?
That's it. That's
essentially what I'm doing.
Can you talk a little
bit about how you
manage context, if
anything, that you do?
Yeah, I'm condensing
it. So each
of these subtasks
uses a to-do
option. So there's,
you can invoke,
well, like let's go
to Cloud SDK for a
second. I'll show you
what that looks like.
Cloud code SDK.
I'm still using Google.
You're not dead yet.
All right, so
Cloud code SDK. So
what I see here
in the Cloud SDK
is you have all
these different
options and tools, right?
To do, yeah, here
we go. so you can
see here that I
can define my MCP
servers and I can
define to do's I
can yeah I can I can
describe those and
I can abstract those
in the file so I'm
inject I'm either
crank temporary files
or I'm creating
prompts I inject one
of the two the benefit
to temporary files
is it's clean and
separate but the
drawbacks is you can't
see it so what so
well because it
doesn't show in the UI
So depending on
what I'm doing,
I do a little
bit of both.
You can see
basically everything
I've done is a
combination of
CLI arguments or
SDK arguments.
So I'm just using this.
And the other thing
I did, which is also
interesting, is where
is that? I think
that's under, I'm
going to find that,
batch tool.
uh they don't do a
really good job of
describing the batch tool
yeah seriously it doesn't
even come up in
their search i i the
batch tool was the
thing i discovered that
really made all this
stuff work i'm thinking
it's on purpose but
that's just check us out
i i do i what what's
annoying now is i'm
like the the first
result and so it's like
it's like a feedback
of my own information.
It still makes it
even more hard.
Here we go. Number
one result is me.
That was my post
I did last week.
Number two.
I'm the first
three results.
That's not very helpful.
Maybe two.
But okay.
Where is it?
I've permanently
skewed the results.
It's all me.
Okay. Okay, so
now I can't even
find the thing
because I'm almost
every single one
of these results.
Click code CLI maybe.
Here we go.
This is the old
command line.
Yeah, I guess it's
sending me back to this.
It's me.
Is Swoom using
the batch tool?
Yes, it's the main thing.
So this is literally
my description.
Thanks, Google,
for giving
me no credit. But anyway.
Are you looking
for Anthropics page
on it? The batch
processing page?
Yeah, that's what
I was looking for.
Doc slash doc slash
build dash with
dash cloud slash
batch processing.
No, I'm not looking
for batch processing.
I'm not looking at
batch processing.
I'm looking at
batch tools.
Batch processing is
something different.
it looks like
they might have
actually hidden
it like they
really don't
want us to use it
that's interesting
I think it's causing
a lot of problems
because I think it's
really slowing them
down look at that it's
gone this was on this
page last I obviously
discovered it somewhere
I think they've
gotten rid of
the batch tool uh
documentation could be
the 50 000 downloads i
had and the 30 agents
were each running
i single-handedly cost
them a million dollars
a day well you kind
of if you think about
what how many lines of
code you're doing yeah
you are i mean they
don't think about the
the cost speed differentiate
differentiate i
don't know you know what
i mean it's interesting
it's really interesting
the price they're
charging us for
tokens is not what it
costs them to produce
it yeah no of course not
there's a there's a
99 markup i'm guessing
um i don't see unless
unless you guys are are
i found that last time
on the batch on the
sdk page they've
totally they've totally
removed any mention of
batch tool yeah i'm sorry
i might have missed
it you were talking
about context how you
met managing it you went
to the sdk side i still
kind of didn't get
what you meant um so
i'm using i'm using
the i was oh i was
hoping to show you guys
the batch tool
documentation which is gone
but basically in this
is what i'm doing
so and you can do this
it's the top of the
hour so i think we're
back i'm back so
we're gonna go and
we're gonna do dash c
actually we're gonna
start fresh i'm gonna go
back here and i'm
gonna live dangerously
and so you can basically
create your own
swarm by doing this
create a I'm gonna
do it to agent swarm
that way use up my
tools swarm using
batch tool to implement
the zero-person
startup system using a
modular file holder
structure, something
like that. I don't
know. I think it's 5 o
'clock UTC, so we
should be active again.
I was only limited
for half an hour.
And I'm not going to
do 15 concurrent agents
because I got work
due this afternoon.
But you see here,
it's thinking.
Here's how it's thinking.
Here's how it's
going to do it. It's
going to look at
my code. Now it's
launching two
agents. This is it.
The basis of everything
that I've done
is based on that batch
tool they apparently
don't want us to
know about you don't
take away this is
the first agent and
this is the second
agent and now they're
running in parallel
a future version
of cloud code will
probably remove batch
tool functionality
outright so they
better not that's the
best freaking part
if you have a really
good prd can't you focus
on this and just kind
of break it up in a
way that you could
have multiple processes
putting it all together
or is that too early
still to do something
that's exactly what
you're doing a hundred
percent no that's
that's exactly what
you're doing so you're
great the better the prd
the better the output
and most times a
client comes to me and
they're and like i do
these hour coaching
sessions and people
basically show up and like
what can you build for
me an hour and the the
key to that is basically
before you even
show up have a detailed
sort of deep research
you did on google or
whatever that basically
outlines exactly what
you want to build
how and what tools you
want to do and then
i'll give it a quick look
over and i'll realize
it's missing something
or other and i'll
and i'll point the
agent to just click news
just to do a more you
know clean appropriate
version of it and
then i literally got
it run for an hour
but do you have a good
process to create a good
prd that you do use or
this is the entire the
entire problem here
is having a really
good prd is it's what i
call the it's what i
call the first mile
problem you know everybody
wanted to talk about
the last mile problem
and like networking
the prd is the first
mile problem you you
you got to be like a
you got to know all of
the different parameters
you don't know the
tech stack you got to
know the market you
don't know that the
the product in and out
that's what but but in
fairness that's what
this is doing so in
terms of this structure
what i'm doing is i'm
again it's minimal but
i'm i'm telling you
know how the agency to
work how the memory
works what what each
step looks like you know
i'm using code to do
it because it seems to
work better with code
definition i'm saying
what the pseudo code
looks like um then
i'm saying what the
architecture needs to
be and how you refine it
and then what's you
know then how you
complete it but yeah but
to david's point you've
you've created a
good prd i mean it's
right basically in a
sense that's a that's
a response that is a
response what we're
looking at here is a
response to somebody
who gave an initial
prd prompt that have
done like you said
spent a few hours doing
some research about
thinking about your
product your your use
cases your your user
stories like i'm a i'm
a product manager by
trade man that's i've
designed complicated
systems my whole life
and complicated prds
i know how to do this
stuff but am i in
my sleep you know to
build a really good
prd i i get paid to do
that it's my day job
yeah and that's why
that's why we still
need you this isn't
this isn't magic
we're somewhere someone
has to describe what
they want to do
and what it is. I
totally agree, man.
That's why I think that
actually product
managers are not going
away in the world of
agentic workflows.
I think for many of
us here who are still
learning how to use
Cloudflow, the thing
that's helped me accelerate
quickly to getting
it running for three
or four hours without
interruption has been
to define in about
three or 400 words,
the application or the
thing I want to build,
and then ask it to list
10 things that are
unclear or need to be
improved and keep iterating
until I'm satisfied
that the next 10
things are irrelevant
to the application.
And then ultimately,
that ends up with maybe
a, I don't know, 300,
400 line markdown file
outlining the project
along with supplemental
documentation.
And that seems to be
enough to get to the
point where I can walk
away comfortably and
come back to a prototype
that i can play with
yeah that's a really
awesome iterative
iterative sort of way to
iterate through developing
a prd i love that
that's cool if you
know if you're not if
you're not a technical
product manager who's
used to sitting down
and writing a 20 page
prd like like i am
that's a good way to
develop a prd i have
people ask me all the
time how do i define my
prd so that I can
actually start with Spark
because they want to
know the first step.
For me, I write a 17
-page PRD out of my
head for a product
because I know how to
do that. And that's
my starting point.
But your iterative
process here, that's
awesome. That's a
great way to do it.
Yeah, yeah.
Oh, and Mandeep shared
a nice little snippet
here. I don't know
where he found that,
but this is the key
to the parallel usage.
Um,
so with less likely
to make parallel
tool calls, four,
four seems to be much
more willing to make
parallel tool cause.
I don't have any
issue. Uh, 3.7 was
a little weird that
way. 3, 3.7 ******.
I don't know what
that was all about.
That was like the,
or something. It
was just garbage.
Um,
so the link is there.
Okay.
Well, feedback there.
feel like I got my guitar
there for that one.
Um, all right. I,
I, you know, some
people are having some
bugs and you know,
maybe let me know,
like you can't get
installed or whatever.
Let me know. I,
I, again, I'm,
this isn't like a
business, a startup.
I'm literally just
creating **** and
seeing what sticks. Um,
so you get what you
get a little bit when,
with these things that
I'm building, but the,
my, my suggestion for
anyone that's having
trouble point, Claude
clone the, the actual
repo and point cloud
at it and say, fix it.
That's literally pretty
much all I'm doing.
Ruf, do you have any
sort of guidelines as
to when to kind of
specify the amount of
agents for a thing or
whether to just let
it decide on the right
amount of agents?
I know I just, to
test it last night,
I tried with 30
agents and it wasn't
such a huge task,
but it was quite
amazing how granular
each agent became
with what their
responsibility was.
It was pretty
impressive, actually.
yes i did i did 50
agents once as you guys
could tell and i was you
know it worked amazing
i cranked out again
i think it was 500
000 lines it was totally
functional and i was
then quote quote
limited after like two
hours but that that did
work but generally the
reason i set five
agents as a default is i
didn't see much
improvement um for most
things when i went beyond
five other than And,
you know, it's, you
know, if I was optimizing
using an MCP, you
know, and I wanted it
to, you know, spin up
a GPU cluster and then
do like, you know,
massive distributed sort
of testing, then I
would spin up like 10
different agents to do
that. And I was using
Hugging Face for that.
But for most things,
I didn't see a
particularly, you know,
dramatic increase in
performance using 5 or 10.
So 5 seems to be optimal.
and then later on
and so i let this thing
like back to that q
dag system i was telling
you guys about and
in that i i would after
almost two days of
running almost non
-stop with a with a five
agent cluster i then
used a much smaller
cluster to actually fix
some build or i use a
sequential approach
to uh where the
heck did i put that
thing i got too
many things open
yeah so So right
here, you notice I
did benchmarking.
So this benchmarking
tool, which I built,
I didn't build this
in Rust. I did this
actually, ended up
doing this in Python
because it was faster.
But this basically
allowed me to
sequentially build and
test and then figure
out where I could
get better
connectivity. So in this
case, you can see here
that I was getting
38 millisecond
average response time.
And then I was creating
a cluster of 50
connections and I
said, did it go up? So
what this was doing
was helping me
optimize the system,
right? So I'm talking
one millisecond
obfuscation and
deobfuscation, which is
what you want to see.
So part of this was
done as a cluster
and then the final
fix is sequential. I
don't know if that
answers the question or
I was rambling at
this point, but this
is a perfect example.
So whatever I'm
building, I don't
actually assume it's
correct. Correct. I
always take a really,
I'm basically, I
think it's BS until
I've run a series
of different
benchmarking and
optimization processes on
it. So in this
case, you can see I
ran, so this is how I
did the benchmarking
for the dark
addressing system.
And I created a
CLI for it. This
is actually built
all in Rust.
And then I get, give me a
final, a final benchmark.
And then I realized
Rust was kind of
a pain in the ***
for benchmarking. So
I switched back to
Python and then,
and then here we are.
I've got I get the
whole system so
I benchmarked you
know deployments and
all kinds of stuff
analysis here's
here's the final
optimization so this
ran all last night just
running fixing running
fixing so and then
and then I ran this
morning and fixed
all this stuff so
I ran some problems
with large message
handling natural
transversal DAG
operations and then I had
some some suggestions
for optimizations.
And then the quick wins,
you know, I could
see a massive
performance
increase here.
Let's see what
that looks like.
Again, this would
have taken a team of
dozens of people,
months or years of work.
So here's my
performance bottlenecks,
variants.
One question, Mark.
Ruv, have you
seen a tendency
for, I see
particularly Claude try
to generate a
lot of mock data.
It defaults to
implementing mock test
cases and mock
data as opposed to
actually running
a benchmark. Yeah.
That **** happens
all the time and
makes me want to
throw my computer.
It does. It 100% does. It
happens. that is
exactly why I'm
doing what you're
looking at.
So not only am I doing
the benchmarking testing,
I'm making sure that
everything I'm actually
doing is something
that I can review.
I assume that it's
bullshitting me at every
stage. So I need to
see here like, okay,
here's a thousand
iterations, here's a hundred
iterations, and I
need to know that the
average time on a thousand
is gonna be different
than the average time
on a hundred because
obviously it's 10
times different, right?
So we can see here that
it struggles a little
bit on some of the larger
vertice operations,
which actually makes
sense, which would
indicate that this is
actually true. So you're
saying I'm doing ops
per second here. What
is that? 152,000. This
is 51,000, which is
again logical given
it's 100 versus 1,000.
So this is all the
proof that's going into
my benchmarking that's
telling me that everything
I'm doing is working
and not just a
hallucination of a
system that looks really
complicated, but truly
a system that actually
is novel unique and
never been done before
so you know this if
anyone goes and says okay
what you just built
is ******** i've got
everything i need to
prove that no it's not
******** this is
actually fully functional
yeah that's huge
explainability is huge and
then there's like the
the step of not just
being able to inspect
the json manually but
than incorporating like
observability graphs.
The problem being
that you have to
essentially vibe
code the graphs
for your new
benchmarks each time
you create a new
benchmark, but.
That's exactly
what I'm doing,
but that's the best part.
I literally
built an entire
benchmarking system
just for this random
thing I wanted
to build, right?
So you're building
the software for the
software. Now, in my
mind, one of the reasons
why I was thinking,
well, I'm gonna build the
benchmarking system in
Python on for a Rust
-based system was a
kind of independent or
Rust-based system. So
I thought that if I
built it separate, it
would be a more independent
analysis of the
system rather than the
original benchmarking
system that I built
here, which was
essentially doing similar
things. But what I ended
up noticing was there
was really tight
integration with the system.
So I ended up not
going down that path.
Where is it? Are you
abstracting to like HTTP?
Like, are you,
at what level are
your test harnesses?
It depends. So this
test harness you're
looking at for
the benchmark, the
Rust-based benchmarks
were direct integrations
into the tool
itself. And then,
but I want an independent
sort of analysis.
So what I ended up
doing was using the API
and the CLI as a secondary
call. So everything
you see here within
this particular
darknet system actually
has a corresponding API
system. And that's
what I ended up using.
That makes a lot of
sense. I feel like the
CLI is kind of now gold
standard for making
things interoperable
at the command line,
especially now that
these terminal agents
prefer to operate there.
so i'm even considering
like moving a lot of
my documentation to
the llms.txt format
and just exposing curl
commands as like the
documentation itself
so that the models can
just run it in situ
um that's a super solid
approach thanks for
that yeah it's you know
it's it's we're we're
living in some crazy
times like i don't
know so that i'm not
even sure how to even
i'm gonna put i'm gonna
do a post this afternoon
maybe when i get a
minute on how i built
this system like using
the swarms and the
benchmarking and all
that for those that are
interested as not
necessarily to use a dark
net i don't know if
anyone actually cares
or wants to use a dark
net system but it's
more like the process
i went through to
build a very very complex
system can you think
can you think about
something about cyber
security for example
something like unison
accounting is uploading
a bunch of stuff to
deep seek how do we
focus on protecting that
because that's a lot
of demand for that
kind of stuff i would
think yeah that that is
something that it's a
little bit worrisome
this clod swarm system
is really really good
at hacking stuff like
crazy good and it
turns out all you need
and i'm saying okay
first with great power
comes great responsibility
don't be an *******
and hack people blah
blah blah okay now we
get that out of the
way this system is
really good at ethical
hacking and i pointed
this thing at some code
i did for a client
project yesterday and
it found crazy
vulnerabilities, not just in
the thing I built, but
everything that they
had already built
previous. And I actually
sent them a list of
like a hundred different
ways I could get into
their system with
proof of how I got in.
This system did the
whole thing. All I did
is I said, do a pen
test on this code. And
then it followed the
yellow brick road back
to their original site.
And it, and it did
the pen test on them
without me even asking
and found all the
vulnerabilities and then
unfortunately it actually
went in when it went
into their system
it was crazy like i
just basically said do
an ethical pen test i
i don't know how going
into their system was
ethical but it did
it what about finding
all those hidden api
points that nobody
documents and they're
there oh yes that's
even that's even crazier
i did that you're like
literally reading my
mind um so what you
what you can do and
this isn't meant to
be like a how to hack
stuff to speak be nice
guys but what what you
can do here is you go
to your network area
and try and yeah so
once you've got this uh
where is it you can
do a search for you
know apis or whatever i
guess this site doesn't
this this type
doesn't have currently
given me anything for
some reason but um
depending on the site
you can then use this to
to sort of inspect
what's happening and all
you need to do is
figure out where the api
calls are and then
point it so here we go
This is a perfect
example. So here
we get, we see
it's using Google.
There's not much
happening on this site.
Yeah, you're on
the docs domain.
If you went to
the, I think
probably the API
URL, it would work.
Yeah, and then I
basically pointed
at the API and
I say, look, you
know, do a pen
test on this API.
Maybe I'm
searching for you.
Was a lot of
the pen testing
examples like just
inspecting DNS?
It was following
and looking at the
obvious locations
for things like
swagger and ports
and structure.
And for most of the
stuff, it basically
found, like, the
open API.json
file. And once I had
that, it just did
a series of different
vulnerability
tests and sort of
brute force attacks.
And it got right in.
Jeez.
Yeah, it was.
And the swarm did it.
and i did i i that's
where again i feel like
i shouldn't be saying
this but anyway that's
where i did a 10 uh
a 10 agent swarm and
it was it took like
five minutes and i was
and i was totally in
wait so this is where
this is where people are
not talking about
the dark side of vibe
coding people who don't
understand this stuff
and what happens when
they go in production
um it's scary if you
think about it right yeah
it's well the ease
and all i and it the
ease of which it worked
and the fact that i
just i all i needed to
say was be ethical to
be unethical was it
was all i needed to do
to get around it
literally the word ethical
yeah well it totally
worked so yeah i'm doing
an ethical pen test
which i was in fairness
but that's all it took
and we can't get the
formula for creating
meth but we can do
that that's that's that's
the funny part i don't
know if you know what
i'm talking about
the llms are all saying
you can't get like
drug formulas right so
uh yeah i mean to your
point you're absolutely
correct yeah i don't
know what you're saying
is i can't get the
formula to create some
kind of uh *******
drug right but i can i
can hack a pharmaceutical
company in five
minutes right that's
exactly what i'm saying
right it's it's it's
crazy just say uh
ethical nuclear bomb and
we'll do it for you yeah
an ethical yeah craig
it's i think the the
uh are the days of like
human-based security
ops might be over that
there's no way a person
can deal with you
know a swarm of agents
that are doing nothing
but looking for
vulnerabilities 24 7. would
you say that's a smarter
approach for places
like super base to
upgrade their mcps to
look for these kind of
things because they're
like a certain line
of defense and that's
an interesting market
strategy for the for
those type of companies
i would think but you
know it doesn't sell
more super base credits
that's a good point
super base is an
anonymous token concept
for most of the access
for their system which
means that you're
essentially relying on
cores for authentication
of the edge functions
and potentially rls
rules for the database
now the challenge you
have with both of those
things is both can
be hypothetically you
know without without
some really detailed um
procedures in place can
be spoofed without a
whole lot of effort
right so what makes
Supabase easy is also what
makes it super what
makes it easy to
implement makes it super
easy to hack so if you
are using using Supabase
make sure you set
up your cores policies
for any edge functions.
Otherwise I'm in and
make sure your RLS
policies are dead, are
really, really strong.
That's why I use the
Supabase MCP. And I
say, you know, do a pen
test on Supabase. And
I let it run for a
while and it secures
the **** out of it.
Is that why you're
interested in the stuff
that you're doing with
DAG? Just to understand
the security side
of the process. Maybe
you'll create a quantum
base or something
you want to call it.
That kind of handles
some of these things.
Well, maybe that's an
approach. the the the
ability to exploit
bitcoin and ethereum right
now is so freaking
easy it's it's not even
it's not funny so once
i realized that you
know basically without
with rudimentary effort
you could basically
exploit their their
system it's like this
isn't going to last so
those technologies are
******** so then i'm
like okay what what
comes next like if i was
going to build a
blockchain today which i
did what would it look
like well it's certainly
not going to look like
a linear blockchain
that drags every
freaking transaction ever
along with it, because
that makes no sense.
I'm not going to use
proof of work, which
makes no sense, or any
of those other sort of
consensus algorithms.
Basically, it's 20
-year-old tech. So that
was all my sort of
thinking in my brain
while I was pondering what
I was going to build.
And so I like DAGs. I
like the sort of graph
structure. I like how
it mimics a neural
network as well. It can
work in various sort
of structures like a
vector just as easily as
a neural net or in this
case a just a
decentralized communication
system that all went
into the thinking process
and and and i also
don't want i also like
the fact that all these
freaking blockchains
require you to buy
some token like why so
i i wanted to build the
system explicitly it
didn't require some
some kind of like token
to access it i want it
to be free accessible
for anyone that that
that was my planning
anyway i like it wait
i want to play i want
to clarify something
you say it's easy to
hack bitcoin you mean by
using quantum technologies
i'm not gonna tell
you guys how to do
it but there there's been
a recent breakthrough
like in the last
month and a half in
terms of quantum
capabilities go go search and
you'll see what i'm
talking about it's never
been easier to do uh
hyper optimize and
crack various forms of
encryption unfortunately
we're we're in uncharted
territory i'm really
actually i'm really
not sure why no one's
really talking about
this so much but they
Yeah, I'm not.
I'm not going to do that.
But yeah, you guys can.
I'd short Bitcoin if I
were you, personally.
Ruv, I've got
two... Ruv, did you
really mean that
all of the RSA has
algorithms are
now under threat?
all the traditional i
would say both ethereum
and unless they have
explicitly implemented
you know you know the
quantum secure crypto
they haven't they're
all under threat and
i would say like within
the next 12 months
we're in some trouble
with those traditional
approaches i'm sure i
have one final question
what is this agentic
.org thing that you
talk about i kind of
noticed you're connected
to it right so what
is that so you might
be asking yeah a group
of us formed a so
back in 2023 we coined
the phrase um agentic
engineering and
everyone's like what the
**** is that and over
time it became a thing
and you know unlike
the work i did early
on in cloud computing
i'm like all right
as soon as i came up
i bought the dot org
and held on to it for
a couple years but over
the last uh several
months you know agentic
engineering is really
blown up it's it's
hot so i figured let's
create an organization
dedicated to the
advancement and fair
use of this technology
and we're working
on learning systems
and we're doing events
we had one in stockholm
in indiana yesterday
um we were we're we
have one coming up in
toronto next week and
we're doing educational
processes you know
we're helping train
you know students
and various things so
it's it's it's meant
to be the the opposite
of open ai it's meant
to be open accessible
hopefully free and
to empower people to
become agentic engineers
which we believe is
like the next big sort
of engineering pursuit
so if the masons have
you know whatever
their their secret club
is we've got agentics
.org it's supposed
to be like the guild
Sorry, someone
say something?
Yeah, you said the
magic word, guild.
I'm definitely in.
I'm going back
to D&D days.
But yeah, that's
interesting.
Do you speak
with regard to
universities,
for example?
Or you guys just started?
Yeah, we got some
affiliations with
the university. And
guys, I got to jump
to my next call.
I'm already late.
It's a pleasure, dude.
thank you so much i
really appreciate you
guys taking time an
hour and a half so that
was a lot of information
if there's bugs i'll
do my best my my
suggestion for any of
the things you guys see
is point cloud code
at it do a pr and just
give me the fix that's
probably the easiest
uh approach here and
just contribute to
my random ideas where
do we give you the
fix in uh on my github
on the yeah the github
just okay because
literally that's all
i'm doing i'm pointing
claude got it henry
about your question
on the universities
right yeah a few of us
are actually doing um
if you are not joined
just take up free
membership a membership
on agentix.org there's
a whatsapp group um
i think maybe if you
are there only but we
can talk there yeah
i'd love to because i
had a large university
approach me asking
to help them design
their ai program
because they're all
struggling right and uh
i don't i don't know if
you know just i'm not
being political but
the The President of
the United States also
demanded that all
the high schools in
America have some kind
of program around AI.
So it's a really good
opportunity to go
down that particular
level. Oh, I'm
sorry, your name
is Mondweep. I will
reach out to you on
LinkedIn and, well, I
don't know if I can,
but I will join.
Also, we've posted
discord.agentix.org
as a URL, you can
join the Discord.
Okay, thanks everyone.
Gentlemen, it's a...