All right,
I remember to go
live on LinkedIn
today. So that's
a great step
in the right
direction here.
All right, here we are.
It's, what do I
say, June 6th and I
managed to upset the
entire DevOps world this
morning. So if you've
shown up to tell
me all the reasons
I'm wrong, I'd love
to hear your input,
but we'll get to
that in a little bit.
we we've had a we had
a really great week
uh rob you on the
call here we had you
got me some shirts
you guys are
looking good i i
see i i see
nick's wearing his
too good good
good job nick
yeah so we we got we
got with some swag
and and we the logo is
extra big to show up
nicely on uh on
these calls so that's
exciting um yeah so
who we got lined up i
know you you probably
sent me an email but
i've been you know my
friday ridiculously
packed so here we are
no uh yeah it's great
we've got so today
we've got a xiao xiao
hang who um and he's
the fellow who built
uh athena ai there's
xiao so um in the
so the lightning
talks we usually get
started around 1230 or
so. So welcome, Xiao.
And the Athena
AI, it's a chat
app that focuses
on displaying
visualizations
for users. So
really successful,
over a million
users. So that
should be neat
to see and to hear
from Xiao. And then
Dami's got a tool
that he's building
for an educational
platform for young ones.
And then Braun's
got an evolution
of his visual
brainstorming tool,
which should be
really neat to see.
So some good,
nice lineup today.
Oh, great.
I'm always excited
to see what
Braun's been up
to. He's always
cooking up
something creative.
And we had another one
of our meetups this
week in Toronto. we
had a great turnout for
that uh we you know
martin and nick and you
know obviously rob you
did a great presentation
uh i'm not sure how
many people were
there but it seemed like
a pretty pretty packed
uh packed room huh
like a lot yeah it
filled up i think we
ran somewhere around 40
some odd um and then of
course we got toronto
tech week coming up on
the 26th and there's
uh there's a lot of
folks registering for
that already uh so
that's yeah that's going
to be that's going to be
a big one indianapolis
indiana cornelius
is all set up he's
launched his uh he's set
his luma date for june
17th uh stockholm is
uh is coming up and
live and and gathering
steam right now some
uh really interesting
folks uh from europe
that are uh already um
getting or participating
in that and then uh
paris and new york
city yeah so we so
we've got uh we're just
starting to get organized
around paris and
interestingly enough i
i saw kelsey uh at the
event on tuesday and
she's just like i'm
going to be in paris in
about a month we should
do an event there
focused on uh sort of
you know creativity
and and art and fashion
and well you need to
meet vincent so one thing
a little tuesday
and looks like we're
going to be organizing
a nice event here in
paris so here i'm not
there but anyway in paris
so that that should be
exciting so if anyone
is interested in
helping with paris uh
where i think we're gonna
probably do a kickoff
call next week on
that that particular
organization um new
york is coming together
right i saw i saw there
was a uh a signup form
somewhere other that
that's uh what do we
know what the date of
that is yet yep we're
just we're just
confirming the dates and
the locations we should
have that today and
then uh we'll have that
that luma set up and
ready for circulation
and also madwit and
bensa they've got
they've got another event
coming up in in london
they're invited to uh
join i think it's the
university of greenwich
is that right
mondweep yeah it's the
university of greenwich
so it's actually a
conference so we just
have been invited to uh
participate in it for
uh for uh basically on
this team so there's
a panel discussion and
we are planning a
mini hackathon which i
would like to get some
ideas from this group
here a remote mini
hackathon uh over a couple
of days and then a
Friday closed session.
Yeah, well, that sounds
like exciting news.
So like a mini
hackathon, so you want
to do something like
in like the run of
like a half an hour
or an hour kind of
hackathon? Is that what
you're looking to do?
So we can basically,
we can introduce
Spark, right? And
then say, this is a
new word. And have
you got an idea?
So now we know,
go and correct the
problem, identify a
problem. You've got one
full remote date
to do it remotely.
And then hopefully if
we can get our acts
together on Friday
evening, there will be a
show and tell of some.
and probably we'll do
kind of an hour, two
hour workshop just to
kind of take people
along, introduce them to
what we are doing here.
So that's the idea.
Okay.
Well, yeah,
well, I'd love to
give you some,
yeah, go ahead.
There are key
results we are after.
So the professor wants
to, the objective
is to spur discussion
on this topic,
right? And on the
SMB businesses.
And what we want to
do is see through the
hackathon, can we come
up with some kind of
a research output from
the university in a
post-even fashion? So
that's another thing
we will see what we can
do about it. So it's
a bit fluid, but that's
the plan broadly.
Okay. Well, that sounds
exciting. Speaking
of, you know, research,
you know, I briefly
did a implementation of
that Wi-Fi sort of see
-through walls research
that came out, I
think earlier last year
actually and I pointed
at the perplexity
lab and and built a
implementation which I
shared last week that that
went viral um apparently
and I think I'm
sitting out of like a
million or something views
on the reddit and
about half the world
thinks it's the worst thing
that was ever invented
you know just to be
clear that's not seen
through people's clothing
or anything crazy
like that it's literally
showing the outline
of like whether
someone's in a house like
and and the momentum
and how many people are
there just so for all
the folks who seem to
think that i've destroyed
privacy well it's
not quite as bad as
you as you think and
the point of that post
just to be clear wasn't
due to infringe on
privacy it was to show
that you could literally
point some of these
systems at research
and get it to build it
in a matter of moments
but you know sometimes
the nuance is lost in
in these uh in these
things so what what can
you do um but speaking
of i I remember that
in DEFCON, man, in
Black Hat, man. I
remember presentations on
Black Hat and DEFCON
that did the same thing.
I think the difference
is you're doing it
at a completely
different scale, right?
But it's... Well, I
did it in 45 minutes.
Well, it wasn't me
that did it. It was
Perplexity Labs. I
just said, go do that.
But you know how it goes.
Anyway, it went viral.
So the subreddit is
doing quite well at
this point. but you
know so the other thing
i want to i'm going
to do today is i want
to show you guys some
of the things i've
been working on in
regards to clod code
which i think is my new
obviously i love rue
code it's a great system
i try you know earlier
this week i was
yesterday actually i was
trying the new version
of cursor it doesn't
even come close to the
the capabilities of
root code but i have
found that clod code
is but it is one of the
best in terms of coming
close It's not as
elegant in terms of
the UI, but in terms of
like capability, it's
very good. And what I
want to show you guys
quickly today is kind
of a workflow that
I've been working on
combining kind of the
lovable and the Cloud Code
system. So for those
that aren't familiar,
the Cloud Code came out
with the CLI, similar
to some of the other
CLIs you see around,
but the ones that it's
kind of reminiscent
actually of Ader.
For those who
remember the
presentations we did last
year when I was all
about Ader, It's very
similar to Adar in
sort of structure.
It's got MCP
integrations.
It's a really great
sort of system for
basically point and
forget. It's not
quite as the components
that we have for
Rue, but it's pretty
close. And you
can use it from the
point of view of an
SDK. You can refactor,
you can build,
you can vibe, all
that kind of stuff.
And one of the nicest
features is it has the
ability to use the
Pro and the Max and
Maxx, I guess, whatever
they're calling it here,
which means you're
not using the API. So
if you're a power user
like me that blasts
through, like, you know,
$100 worth of credits
in a day, this is
a much, much better
use. So it's, at least
for me, it's substantially
cheaper. So I'm
currently using, I think
I'm using Maxx 5,
which, again, for me is
$100 I blast through
quite, quite quickly.
So I want to
show you some of
the stuff I
was working on.
So there's two
approaches to sort of the
development of things.
There's one is the
architecture from the
bottom and the other is
from the top. So what
I want to do here is
create a, you know, a
little website, like a
fake kind of startup
that allows me to
create, you know, these
VS Code swarms. You know,
it's a site I create
in Lovable quite
quickly. And then I had
a back end so that you
can implement it. So
then what I did is I
went in and synced
it to my GitHub and I
implemented the code
directly in that. So I'll
show you what that
looks like. So in this
case, I installed the
cloud code, you can
see here, then I get
it to review my various
components and you can
see that I found some
issues and it creates
some documentation
and it's running and
creating the various
components that it
needs to create.
And what's great about
this, again, let's
go down to the bottom
here. I'm just gonna
I you know I can do
something like you
know the various settings
like bugs or whatever
I can look at the
cost let's let's look
at so the total cost
of the current session
I think I might start
able to see what
that looks like yeah
there's no there's no
worry about cost because
I'm not using the
API that's awesome
auto accept edits on
so now I say tell me
about how to use the
VSC remote so now you
can see here it's it's
doing it's it's
thinking it's not quite
as it doesn't quite
give me as much insight
in what it's thinking
that as as Rucode
does but it does seem
to do a really good
job of building and
following instructions
and really all I did
here was I just gave
it these the spark
instructions that I use
for my other systems
and it just kind of
followed that iterative
test environment.
So you can see here,
like we go here
and I've made some
updates. So in this case,
we've got the plans
folder. You can see
that the core, here's
the core architecture.
It created a VS remote
structure. And this
is supposed to be like
an MPX library you
can install. I ended
up creating it as a
MPM or sorry, an MCP
style component. So you
can see what it ended
up building. there's
some additional plans
in here you know
message formats and
request response so
basically what what this
does well let's just
run the whole kit and
caboodle here for you
I'll go here actually
I'm already running
it I'm gonna go back
here so it created
basically created me a
startup just for today's
call which is kind
of kind of cool I
started this this morning
on my exercise bike
and you know I can
deploy my swarm and I
can go in here and
choose my configurations
and my network settings
and do my analysis
it's all it's all
kind of built built in
looks like I'm having
some font color issues
I guess that's minor
whatever but yeah
it can it's basically
can deploy my my swarms
of VS code instances
so basically what
I've built is an MCP
that essentially you
can build and deploy
other VS code instances
on my behalf as a
swarm of coding agents.
So I basically use
this cloud code system
to build that
this morning, just
for this call. So,
you can see here
that it's telling
me how to use it.
So let's just see
if it works. So this
is the, I can
deploy the instance.
This, well, let's
give it a spin.
live this like a year
ago this would have
been like a probably
a 10 million dollars
you know startup oh it
gave me oh not in the
right folder that
explains it let's go
into the CD vs the remote
the demo gods let's
see if they smile on
me of course it worked
earlier all right
I'm not gonna go with
that oh I'm I'm getting
an error. All right,
well, we'll have to
come back to this.
Oh, it's trying to,
I never published
it. I never published
it to the, to NPM.
So it's not finding this.
All right, let's, let's
ask it one more question.
How, how do I
run this locally?
I know I run it locally,
but how, you know,
run, run the NPM locally.
I haven't published
it. The error is
basically I need to
publish it to my NPM
repo which I never
bothered to do yet.
So it's giving me the
command to run
it locally,
install the
dependency, yeah,
sure, go ahead
and do that.
It's always
interesting to see
how it debugs
it, to be honest.
But it's a great
system. I'm still
trying to figure
out how to make it a
little more automated,
but so far it
builds pretty much
anything I point at
it really, really
quickly and easily.
And again, I like
the fact that I don't
have to pay for
all the API calls.
I did max out the
Opus option, but
then I switched
to Sonnet. So I've
actually come
around to Opus 2, by
the way. It seems
to work quite well
for more complex
coding challenges.
So let's see what
it's running now.
So it's running.
Oh, it's just
running data. Okay.
Let's do that.
NPM run data.
Let's, yeah,
I don't know.
It's with folder M.
Oh, I'm in the BS.
Looks like there's a UI.
Let's see what I've
got going here.
I don't think I
gave it another UI.
Anyway, if you're looking
to save some money,
the moral of the story
is you can jump between
something like a
Lovable or a VO or any
of these web-based user
interfaces, and then
you can go and run
this. Instead of using
BrewCode, which costs
you quite a bit of
money, you can just use
this to do fix-ups or
whatever you need to
do. You just point it at
your planning folder
and other components,
and you're off to the
races quite quickly.
Can you go through
the TDD process?
Yeah, it can run all
the tests. You can do
all the same stuff
essentially Roo does.
And again, you can
actually invoke it
directly from the
SDK as well. So if
you want to have a
coding system built
right into some other
application, you
can do that as well.
so it's kind of a
kind of a cool uh
kind of a cool system
looks like it's
trying to run the ui
my wife thanks you
for um the changing
plans for the weekend
now ru thanks yeah
it's it's it's cool
let's see uh run run the
it's actually running
the ui i don't want
to run the uh mcp
server it's combined
both the mcp server
and the uh ux so i'm
gonna see if i can
looks like there's a
subfolder called remote
vs code here it is
uh no running mcp
all right run it
okay i'll publish
this too later for you
guys if you want to
play around with it
a little bit it's
it's uh it's this this
right here for me is
the biggest challenge
with it I like even
though I have the auto
execute command running
it still keeps asking
me you know it says
yes don't don't ask us
to run again if you
can start it with a
there's a special switch
called dangerously
yeah dangerous dash p
yeah it it's uh I'm not
running that I'm
currently running the you
the interactive mode
but basically you're
you're getting the
idea here all right I'm
I'm out of time anyway,
but it's, it's a cool,
it's a cool little
project worth looking
at. I'm, I'm, I'm so
far, I'm a fan of it.
Um,
yeah. And there
are, there are also
other commands,
as you mentioned,
uh, Claude, what
is it? Claude help,
I think is the
command to find those.
Yeah, here we go. So, uh,
you've got different
modes here. So
in this case,
you've got, I like
the verbose mode
as well, which lets
me see exactly
what's happening.
You've got, you can
add MCPs directly
into the flow, which
is kind of a cool
option. You've got a
number of different
options here. What
was that one you said?
Dangerous mode or
something like that?
I think it was dash
P run dangerously or
something like that.
Yeah, here it is.
Dangerously skip
permissions.
Bypass all permissions
checks. Recommendedly
for sandboxes with
no internet access.
I don't know about
that. that might
be taking it a
little bit far.
Like, I think
you're running into
Codespace, you're
probably okay.
It also supports all
the basically the
same MCPs as Rue.
So you can literally
just use the same
MCPs you set up
for your Rue or your
Cloud environment.
You can run,
you can actually
run this whole thing,
Cloud as an MCP, I
think by running MCP.
Yeah, here it
is, MCP serve.
So once you have this
running as MCP, like
this, I don't know if
it gives you an output,
but you can then run,
then you can add this
MCP to your MCP
settings in VS code, you
know, for MCPs or Roo
or Klein or Cursor or
whatever you like.
And then you can have
those systems actually
orchestrate this as well.
So it's kind of a
cool secondary system.
Yeah, it's worth
looking at. Now, this is
actually running.
It just doesn't give
you a message indicating
that it is, but I
wasn't able to get
it working using this
earlier, so it's kind
of a good option.
So these are your
different options here.
It's cool.
Worth checking
out for sure.
All right, I managed
to get this done in
a record amount of
time this morning,
this afternoon,
whatever we are at here.
Anyone play with
Cloud Code at all? Any
comments on it? I know
someone mentioned that.
Well, I read an
interesting article about
it that was suggesting
using it not just to
work on software
projects, but to actually
be your CLI for your
general, like, computer
use. And he gave it
examples of, like,
telling it to, you know,
aggregate some files
and transfer them,
post them or something.
I thought it was
interesting to
do kind of DevOps
-style tasks.
Yeah.
It's... I think the
MCP integration is
particularly useful.
So all those things you
probably run in the
Claude desktop can also be
run directly through
this as a sort of CLI.
And you can
automate pretty
much anything with it.
So with that
dangerous or the dash
B option, which
was pretty cool.
I'm not sure how
dangerous it actually is.
I don't run this stuff
locally, just to be
clear. I'm a little
paranoid to run this
stuff on my local
environment anyway. it so
that that's why i'm
using these these uh
code spaces or just
spinning up a a container
somewhere and using
that to do this hey
ru have you have you
tried um having them
basically do like a
b testing so you have
root code set up with
your api and then the
cloud code um like
doing a another one and
then kind of a b test
against each other
no but it's an interesting
idea and that's
actually someone brought
up a similar question
on a call i was on
earlier this morning
they're asking you know
if you run the same task
twice like you know
using the same exact
um plans do you get a
different application
or a different structure
or architecture of
that application and
that that is something i
tried a few times and
the answer is yes you
do and what's interesting
is the the approach
to using these
systems are generally
declarative meaning that
you're kind of giving it
broad guidelines but
you're you know you're
giving it here's the
architecture and here's
the pseudocode but
oftentimes there's
difference not huge
differences but different
minor differences in the
way that it implements
those and and when
you start adding like
mcps to go and research
the the results or
leave problems and you
get the results, there's
significant variance
in what the end
application looks like in
that. So to your point,
likely what we're
trying with an A-B test
isn't necessarily just
the optimal output, the
final app, but also
the least amount of
costs and steps to get
to that optimal output.
And that's a benchmark
that a lot of folks
aren't actually looking
at. They're looking
at like random GitHub
issues and saying,
well, based on SWE
Bench, we can solve 70%
of them with one shot,
which is interesting.
But what we're really
trying to benchmark
is, you know, how many
shots does it take
to build a really
complicated application?
Yeah, yeah.
And I, what I've been
playing with is having
MCP set up basically
the boilerplate and
have that in MCP and
then have them call it
and like use the
boilerplate, but then also
get creative with
that boilerplate, like
on top of it so it
kind of helps structure
it a bit better than
it just you know doing
its own thing yeah
yeah exactly and and
that's i think the mcp
infused flow whether
that's dev or devops or
some other process is
is probably the most
interesting part of
sort of the agentic
engineering process right
now where where like
several months ago
a lot of the stuff that
we're doing was sort
of bespoke. We'd have
to instrument each
step. We'd have to
create evaluation loops
and then optimize based
on those loops. Now
we suddenly have the
ability to all these
somewhat random MCPs
as part of those
flows. Now that
induces a whole lot of
security related
concerns, but stepping
from that aside, it
also introduces a
really easy way to
sort of instrument
various types of
multi-step processes
that that becomes
substantially
easier to do at
least test anyway
which is which is
pretty exciting
I was actually
on a call with
I think the founder
of Replit and he said
something super
interesting that adds on
to what you're saying
group which is this
is all a function of
memory like as I'm
building out applications
that are complicated
and you lose context
or VS Code crashes
he talked about the
context of memory
Like if you're a
researcher, it'll take
you seven years to
figure something out.
But if you look at
the function with
which memory is
increasing, right, in
terms of the sessions
that, you know,
AI can hold as you're
writing a prompt or
processing through
something, the complexity
of the task, like
you said, from the
instrumenting, like just
the last six months,
the ability to instrument
and be declarative
and have every
single function, as
opposed to how much
can, you know, the
application hold in
memory to move things
forward. so it'll
be crazy you know to
see you know how what
is the relationship
between memory and
the context window
and your functionality
right because it's
basically what you
have to orchestrate
yeah actually speaking
of those are just
quick question um is
there like a good metric
so like you have a genetic
task to like develop
a complex system
right and you have all
these variables you can
use different set of
mcp you could be like
with knowledge graph
without knowledge graph
how would you evaluate
the quality of the
development system
there that's that's always
been subjective like
when you run scc and
tells you it's worth
x dollars and the
complexity is is some
arbitrary number you know
that that that's always
been a subjective sort
of you know number
and and view right so
it really depends on
what you're doing and
what the app what the
application is right
and so i would break
that down into one is it
an existing application
and the ability for
the system to work
with large existing
complex apps of some some
sort and the other which
is arguably generally
is something net
new and the and the
output and complexity of
of the thing that you're
building so like
the example would be
like the other day when
we did that wi-fi thing
that sort of looks at
people through walls
that that that's arguably
easier and because
it could just build
it and test it based
on something that i was
building from scratch
based on a some research
paper oh yes versus
trying to build based
on existing code
which is easier to
navigate but more difficult
to potentially integrate
so it's they're
different problems
anyway i i don't know if
they're i don't think
we have a red a solution
necessarily other than
how you examine it
yeah um all right
so rob how we how we
doing here you want
you want to bring in
our first guest
Yeah, perfect timing.
Why don't we start with
Xiao. Hi, Xiao,
how are you?
Oh,
there he is.
Hello.
Can you guys hear me?
Yeah, welcome.
All right, so here
I'm presenting
Athena AI. We have
Athena is AI that
initially focused
on visualization.
Can I share my
screen over here?
Let me just find the
share button over here.
So essentially here,
this is Athena chat.
It's kind of like a
chat GPT, by the way,
focusing on visualize
things as much as
in the chat app over
here. So for example,
if I do like generate
a flow chart, I
describe the Google
interview process,
you actually generate
like a chart like that.
Now, if you do that,
essentially what
it does is it does
the Mermaid code and
then you visualize
the Mermaid code with
a Mermaid renderer.
the same thing
we're doing that with
latex now if you do
the if you do the
in the chat gpt you
try to generate an
image instead of like
a detail like mermaid
workflow here so
same thing with
latex here this is
like printing in
latex format over here
right in case i'm
asking like a question
math question or
chemistry question you
will actually render
it in latex format
in chat over here
and other than those
those type of
mathematical
format we also
have like just the
product and the
trip planning
for trip planning rather
than just chatting
about trade planning
we actually display
like travel deals
here in chat
here you see
here this is uh
because i was asking
like uh in three
months you actually
gave me the deal in
three exactly three
months over here so you
see like yeah it
says okay you need to
travel travel in three
months i'm giving
you the deal for
three months and of
course you also have
the flight to the
destination which will
also set it in three
months from now from
Toronto all the filters
already set for me
yeah yeah you can
just look for the
price and yeah that's
and the same here
is the activities I
think you have give
these another provider
over here is called
the get your guide
so you also sets
like to Shanghai here
rise away for you so
and And, yeah, and
obviously a more
trivial one is product.
You can, if you
just prompt,
I need a new smartphone,
it will give you the
smartphone word here.
This we are
bundled with Affili
API on Amazon
and Aliexpress.
So you see, like,
we have the text
-based answer as well.
we have the product
here the text-based
answer and also
the sources yeah so
and uh and obviously
you can do html
and uh those are
really trivializing
other platform
can do that too
for example uh to
give me like uh uh
product shoot of a
gaming chair over here
and this takes
some time to
generate because
it's an image yes
so i can then
say uh pull that
sell the sell that
yeah how'd you
build it i i think
we all get perplexity
but what what what
what makes you
different than the
multitude of sites
that do exactly
what you're showing
Multi-deal sites that
do exactly what I'm
showing you, I mean,
I will just focus on
the convenience,
right, rather than like
publicity, for example,
is a search app, right?
You search for things
on the internet.
We do specific integration.
So, for example,
the travel deal one
is actually bundled
with another startup's
API that we fetch exact
travel deal. If you
do the same, I can
actually do the same
Proplexity right here,
right?
So I have all
the... So why
would, just a
quick, why would
we use yours
over Proplexity?
Because it's
more specific,
right? So Proplexity
is a search engine.
We're not a search
engine. We do a specific
integration. For example,
with travel APIs,
that's a specific
integration that looks
dual for you around the
destination a specific
date so i can do
the same prompt um
perplexity you give you
okay those are the like
those are like the the
business around that
area good love is
that right it doesn't
give you the deal it
doesn't give you the call
to action to book
right so that's uh are
you are you a service
or are you a like
software that i install
and customize this
myself it's more i'd
say like it's it's not
really for technical
people it's for like no
technical people that
you know i get what
they're looking for
right away they can book
they can do any kind
of action that they
want uh without doing
a lot of technical
setup that's like the
target audience we're
aiming for i i think
it's a challenging space
right you're you're
competing with google
which basically does
this on the homepage
now uh yeah we actually
use google behind
the scene too right
we use the google like
search as well but
we're looking for like i
said we're looking for
specific integration
and uh not like the
general things for example
i can again prompt
the same thing on
germany here on google
search you will just
like perplexity you would
give you all this is
roughly what you do
and give you like a
long list of things to
do rather than something
exact right so if i
could if i could just
so you're saying is
that hey we're gonna
we're creating a wrapper
around this that is
that that makes things
a lot more specific
for the users so yeah
what we're going to
and within that it's not
just a specific search
using perplexity
we're actually setting
up uh specific relationships
with vendors in
that sphere in that area
vendors or providers
that would not
necessarily be surfaced
via google or perplexity
is that what you're
saying exactly yeah
okay thanks is it a
shopify app chef uh the
shopify we have a shopify
app too that's even
more specific because
we have a very customized
workflow building
around that uh are
you using shopify's
new new uh new mcp
server that they just
announced last from last
week no we are not used
we're using Yeah, we're
using a mix of NA8
and also DeFi.ai,
which both support MCP.
Oh, so you have MCP
integration here?
Not here, but for
the Shopify one.
So you don't
have MCP support?
You're just using...
On the regular chat,
we don't have it
yet. We only have it
on the Shopify app.
okay i you know my
personal you guys all
know my personal opinion
on rappers i i just
i just think it's a
tough business to be
in personally like i
see this i i see what
you're building i'm
like like i could crank
that out in a few
minutes right so maybe
maybe i'm the wrong
audience right yeah of
course this is not in
for technical people
that's for sure yeah
you know i was uh i
was like playing
around with it like i'm
planning a trip in
december right so like i'm
typical cities in
india right yeah so i
followed your example
but i think this is
great for like people
who are in a traveling
another because it's
come back with like
every city accommodation
wise asking me for
my budget amounts right
and it's very accurate
in like plugging that
so i have multiple
tabs open now so i
can basically very
quickly go and book
things so i think the
audience i think is that
like people like casual
users who are looking
for exactly travel
industry i think is
a It's a big change.
There's a potential here.
That's what I'm
seeing here.
Yeah, like we're not
aiming for take your
people because, you
know, like we are
aiming for no take
your people that can
do this on the go.
I'm showing that on a
desktop right now,
but most of the users
are using our, like,
the mobile version.
So,
and they can do it
on the go. Like,
people are not using
that for coding.
That's not the goal
here. That's not the
point here. people are
using that for like
just brainstorming uh
for example generate a
flow chart uh like then
travel recommendation
and yeah like very
specific uh like needs
that they are looking
for for sure that
that is not for the
technical audience we're
not aiming for technical
audience there are
no developer are using
that so i can i can
uh confirm that part
great question on
deployment can you run
this like for example a
customer could they
say can i run your
platform in in an
environment right let's say
oh just reference i i
think that you still
have an edge and i i
agree with you know the
idea that wrappers are
very dangerous because
you can uh you can
be commoditized but
there's still value if
you can make something
simpler as long as
you move fast, right?
I think the
interesting angle that,
I'm interested to
see how you answer
this, is that
from a privacy
and from a security
point of view,
can you run this in an
isolated environment?
Can the company
deploy this
completely isolated
and then customize or
remove stuff that
they don't care about?
Oh, yeah, like, then
that's the custom
integration, right?
It's not a plug
and play, then we
just use our, like,
No, no, no, that's
not what I'm saying.
I'm saying is,
can I deploy your
entire stack in a
clean AWS environment?
Not yet.
yeah if there's a demand
yeah of course you
can do that but right
now we're more like
a you know consumer
facing uh chat app so
you have one copy of
this yes exactly yeah
we'll have one copy of
this running yeah so
values make a common
you know figure out how
to do that because i
think there's a there's
two things that you
get a there's a lot
of good business
opportunities also there's
a lot of things you
won't need to develop
yeah exactly yeah because
the customer When I
was a CISO, there was
a massive difference
between somebody who
wanted to deploy something
that now I have to
protect where the
**** is running and the
data, et cetera, than
something I could run
in our environment.
Yes, we totally
understand that. And if
there's demand, we
can do that, right? So
we can just deploy
separate instances.
It's not as easy. I
spent three months to
figure out a tech stack
that actually runs
everywhere, right? It's
not easy at all. there's
so many little
curveballs that you'd be
surprised you know like
blow up your entire
aws or whatever you
run in cloud and then
see how fast you see
how long it's going to
take you to set up all
of this from scratch
as yes yeah because
we have we use both um
we use both vertex
and bedrock so like
so we are we we were
familiar with both
infrastructure So
usually when someone
wants to do like
doing AWS, we just use
Bedrock and if it's
Google, we use Vertex.
So,
yeah, so that's the way.
Xiao, also when we were
talking there at the
Toronto Meetup, you
were saying that you'd
like to speak to how
a ChatGPT wrapper can
compete with big tech.
yes i do yes i can i
give several talk on
that actually so my
point of this is you
know like this is totally
branding right so in
fact right if you give
a can of coca-cola or
a kind of pepsi and
then you hide the brand
and you ask most people
taste they wouldn't
tell what what coke
it is or even like even
you can try that with
some local coke brands
right most people
wouldn't even recognize
it same as the rappers
because you can build
your own rapper you
just advertise your
own way on social media
you can be you become
an influencer i don't
know like a career
advice uh gpu rapper and
uh yeah you can do good
with it right because
normally like chat gbt
and like perplexity
and audio big chat
app they cannot find a
thousand different
angle to advertise their
stuff right that's uh
if you can it's kind
of like a branded t
-shirt essentially right
you could you you can
start the same way you
start your own clothing
brand you can start
like your wrapper brand
and this only works
when you advertise it
to a consumer so the
d2c approach because
if you advertise to
technical people then
you know people know that
whatever you can do
chat if you can do it
too worse you know
with with a few line of
code where you've a
few line of adjustment
they can do it uh they
can make it work with
their own wrapper or
something like that right
so uh the audience
will be like the same
with uh like that i
can argue the same as
you if you run a d2c
e-commerce brand you
you're you are not
selling that to eco like t
-shirt makers like that's
like you cannot sell
that to a t-shirt
maker because t-shirt
maker say i can make that
t-shirt in two minutes
and it cost me like i
know 20 cents so how
can you sell to that
to me right so that's
i think the same coca
-cola is a great example
in terms of taste
testing but coca-cola
is is a successful
company because of its
distribution infrastructure
they're actually a
logistics company and
a distribution company
the people who make
the most amount of
money are the people
who own the distribution
rights in the countries
and in the regions
right and there's there's
a reason why google
was paying apple a
billion dollars a year
to be the default search
application on their
phones that so that
would be the second part
like if you focus on
travel and i wrote a
post on this yesterday
i think like yeah
trip advisor is this
massive arbitrage between
seo and sem and they're
they hold they they
have such a big search
engine marketing
budget that they
disintermediate all of the
hotels so i do think
like as the community has
said that there's an
opportunity there but
it's still going to be
distribution distribution
distribution even
if you narrow it and
you focus on consumers
there's uh it that's
what that's what it
really boils down to all
right thank you for
that comment yeah good
and then thanks thanks
for the presentation
it would be interesting
to see how you do
i i found it interesting
that that that your
comment on branding is
a differentiation yet
i see no branding on
your on your example
but so it's almost like
the lack of branding
for you is is your
thing or or something
but but i appreciate
uh you taking the
time to give us the
demo today and thank
you and uh we wish
wish you well all right
thank you yeah uh
thanks uh we have uh we
have uh braun or domi
who's uh who do we
I'm here. Dami.
There's Dami.
Hey, how's it going?
Great. How are you?
Pretty good,
thanks. Pretty good,
thanks. Good to
see you guys.
Hey, everyone.
My name is Dami.
Yeah, so I am
working on a
product that's
focused on also
Shopify's ecosystem
a little bit.
And the product
itself is a
visual editor for
Shopify developers
and potentially
merchants.
So yeah, the problem
being solved here
is there aren't too
many AI tools for
Shopify developers.
So here we have, I'll
show you guys the
landing page. So
there's V0, there's
Bold, there's Lovable,
there's like 10 other
new tools that come
out every week that
focus just on JavaScript.
In fact, I can
actually visualize the
problem area a bit
more. So in this space,
there's quite a lot
of companies building
like for JavaScript
and HTML, but there's
really nobody
building for Shopify
Liquid, which is like
Shopify's template
language for most of
their stores. Some of
their stores do use
JavaScript, but they're
actually leaning
more towards Liquid.
And there aren't many
tools that work well
for Liquid. part of
the reason why is
because um there are
different versions of
liquid that exist that
are also similar to
jekyll so the training
data just doesn't
this is just not
going to get it right
and i think they keep
changing sometimes
keep changing things
um related to liquid um
so i think unfortunately
there probably
won't be any ai models
that actually will
understand liquid
properly so we've been
working in this space
since september and
built a lot of internal
tools and different
things that kind of
pertain to Liquid.
And prior to that,
we had built the
first text of
Figma plugin, which
kind of relates
to this as well.
But the focus now is
building this visual IDE
specific to Liquid,
but eventually
trying to bring
it all back
together into one
centralized design
language for
building interfaces.
But here, this
is the landing
page. I want to create
a hero banner,
about cookies,
about a group called
Agentix, and then
I'm going to generate
the landing page.
Now we have this
canvas that looks
similar to Figma, not
like Figma, sorry,
and it's going to
generate me two
versions. This is a
staging version, so the
designs might not
look the best, but
we're currently testing
stuff. But yeah,
there's two different
versions that are
created. So as a
user, you'll have two
options that are
visually outputted.
I'm not sure why the text
isn't showing
up properly.
This is interesting.
The demo gods.
Demo gods.
That's so fascinating.
Yeah, like
usually it doesn't do
that. It's a thing.
It's a thing. Don't
worry about it.
Just roll with
it. We wouldn't
even notice if you
hadn't said it.
That's funny. No, I
wanted to change the
text. But yeah, at some
point, it should change
the text in the second
version. But, yeah,
the main thing here
is that a lot of these
tools, they end up making
you wait to see the
visual output. Like,
I call it, like, the
slot machine waiting
for, like, the code or
whatever. But I don't
think that's the future.
I think the future
is more visual, in my
opinion, where you
can see the output and
kind of see, like, the
visual things change.
Part of the visual,
sorry, part of the
visuals is also be
able to change the
font size. so we
have like this editor
here where you can go
in and like quickly
change things also
hide layers um
and you can also
prompt as well so here
i can say um make
the colors or purple
and then in a few seconds
or make the colors
well demo gods for
real um now this is
interesting dummy
because like a custom or
one of the premium
templates in shopify can
run you 200 bucks
just for one design
isn't that right yeah
no that's that's like
it's super interesting
how that happens yeah
um yeah like i think
like we want to disrupt
part of that um and
i guess the reason
why this editor is
broken right now is
because we have a new
launch coming up for a
theme store and part
of the idea for theme
store is rather than
paying shopify for
like a premium theme
or trying out a bunch
of different themes
you can come into our
theme store enter your
website url and then
we'll show you what
your website could look
like across a bunch
of different layouts
and yeah like it just
shows you like oh
like this is what
this could look like
and you can look at
your different page
templates to also see
the outputs as well
but yeah this needs to
be a bit more polished
but it's uh it's almost
there uh it's just
one thing that was
interesting is last week
we fixed a bug that
was like a one-line bug
issue that was related
to getting some of
this data to display but
um yeah that's that's
the premise and some
of the cool things
about this is we built
a lot of internal tools
to make this stuff
happen so So if I want
to scrape a website,
I just enter the URL.
And then we actually,
I'll put the stage
in the version. We
categorize all the
data into like the
images, the color. This
isn't new. We're going
to have the brand
colors, the brand
fonts, the brand
radius. And like we
do the same thing in
Shopify. So we have
like this concept of
shops that has links
and some text and
also products and
collections and whatnot.
So building this data
structure internally
has made things a
lot better for us.
One thing that we
also built that's
sort of new is this
Tailwind to Liquid
Generator. So
essentially, like, what
I can do here is let
me go into Shopify
and pick one of
these templates. So
let's say I like
this template here.
And I want to copy
this template.
So Tailwind
is really good
for, I don't know,
copying HTML.
So in here, I'll
make a new cursor
window and say,
make me HTML page
that looks like
the screenshot.
And then we added
these data attributes
internally for,
like, sections and
whatnot. So I'll tell
it to use these HTML
attributes and include
this in the CSS.
I mean, I could have
set this up with a
workflow, but I'm
pretty manual right now.
But yeah, so
AI is going to
go in and make
me some HTML.
And then the cool
thing here is we built
this editor where
the HTML will then
convert to liquid.
So this is an old
version. I'm waiting
for this to generate.
Cool. So we got
this HTML here.
Hopefully that did
correctly. Bam.
Copy the site in
like a few seconds.
So this is something we
just finished internally
yesterday. It's
going to help me with
like improving the
dataset and also just
optimizing things a bit
better. And from this
HTML, we generated three
Shopify specific files.
So we generated a
liquid file with the
section and then the
section index, and then
also some liquid stuff.
It's not liquid, The
theme liquid that has
some of the global
stuff that might be in
a different file after,
but yeah, I mean, this
is a lot of specific
things. I don't know
why the editor download
didn't work the best,
but the main focus
here is next few weeks
is just going to be
data set stuff. So just
scraping a bunch of
designs and mapping it
into our systems and
maybe in a few months,
tie that back into the
figment system. But
yeah, I think funny
enough, I think design
is so fascinating and
taste and whatnot, but
it's all a tailwind is
the answer. i think
funny enough but uh
anyways that's my rant
and also my demo husband
i'll tell you as a
previous shopify store
um owner the the idea
of exploring through
the themes not knowing
exactly how it's going
to translate into you
know my studio's retail
uh lineup and then
committing by purchasing
it and that's it
right and then i gotta
deal with that and
that's the one i own and
that's, you know, very
difficult to modify.
So, I mean, this
is way better.
Yeah, there's a lot
of work to do, like to
make it even more
seamless for merchants.
And like, I have a call
today with an agency
who like, they're a
big Shopify agency in
Toronto, Laser. And
like, I have another call
after that with a
Shopify developer who I
spoke to, he was in
town for additions last
week. And he's still
complaining that there's
no AI tools for him.
So like, there's
this weird spot that
we're in where we have
this powerful tool with
a lot of cool features,
but now it's just
about a matter of
figuring out, like,
who's this for? Like, is
this for a merchant?
Is this for developers?
Like, what does it do?
What problem is it solve?
Is it for landing
pages? And like,
that's kind of like
where things are at.
But in between all
that, there's all
these like technical
things about like,
fixing data structures,
like, and like
whatnot. It's really
fascinating. But yeah,
it's, it's a journey,
but it's, it's fun.
and what do you uh
think of the new uh
figma mcp that was
released a couple days
ago they claim to be
doing similar stuff
thing was weird man
i don't know like
i i'm an early figma
user and i think
there's just too many
tabs going on here
and like it's sad for
them because these
make and design should
be kind of one-to
-one but when you go
into make it's like
i think they let you
copy over our boards
now which is good finally
uh or you can copy
you can copy over assets
which is also a little
strange you can't i
think it's not the
ui i think it's the
mcp that i was talking
about so they basically
just send an image or
whatever and magically
generates someone
online today was like
it's the same thing as
make like like they
should they should make it
more um so like try
pasting a frame instead
of a url like the mcp
i think is going to
be powerful for other
people to go in and
like convert their um
like their uh their figma
stuff into um into
other tools so i think
i think mcp is as like
a whole is it's great
and like they wrote
a lot about like how
they made it work and like
some of the challenges
related to it um
there i think it's a
bit late and it's weird
to me that on figma
people are um making
money from all these
conversion tools like i
can try to pull this up
really quickly someone's
profile i liked
their post yesterday
and they ended up like
let's see reactions
let's see if i can find
her post weekly like
she she had posted about
the fact that um i
don't know if i can find
it she has a figma
plug-in and the figma
plug-in is generating
um revenue and i think
i'm not sure this is it
here and all the figma
plug-in does is um
convert from figma to
react um i just find
it strange i think it's
like there's so many
people who are still
stuck in this world of
like converting from
this figma world to
html css i think for me
the answer is you start
from html css first
and like uh so i can
tell you first and i mean
i apologize for not
connecting with you
from the last time you
presented there's a
company in um austria
their ddc brand super
cool at glorify g-l-o-r
-f-y and they're sweating
bullets yeah uh sorry
it's y it's y r-y-f
-y coolest glasses ever
these guys invented
this stuff themselves
this why instead of i
um and they they're
uh they're uh they've
migrated their shopify
store and they're
crapping their pants
because it's so complicated
to go from one theme
to like another um so
yeah and it's guys the
analogy the analogy
of that that person that
you just showed it's
like when the people
came out with the
flashlight for the iphone
and then apple's like
shoot that's a really
smart idea and then
they just integrated
it into their existing
business right in terms
of the um the ability
to switch i i wonder
how i wonder if you've
interviewed like to
what extent um does
shopify realize that
if they if they if shop
your business risk is
if shopify realized that
if they could make
it less painless for
people to switch themes
and shopify took a cut
off every time somebody
switched a theme
would they be making
exponentially more money
right and like would
they or is it like or
is this like built-in
friction on purpose
right because there's
tons of people that own
the Shopify ecosystem
that just they just
struggle like I could
tell you a a Kony like
one of the top luxury
brands is launching your
Shopify store lots of
people you've got all
of these people who
are not technical who
will never do it right
so um i don't know
about you alex but i've
i found very few products
and businesses that
have built in friction
intentionally it's
normally always a
mistake or an oversight
or just like didn't like
accidental and they
just never got around
to solving it oh but
i have to wordpress
themes it's like migrating
wordpress themes right
like it's yeah no
nobody purposely builds
friction man nobody
for oh no no no that's
actually not right i
think it's intentional
i think it's intentional
uh whether or
not they know the side
effects i think it's
all intentional yeah
we gotta we have to
uh really want to
leave a few minutes
for braun as well i'll
be really fast because
it's big uh if you
look at the other
people in the ecosystem
this one guy says
um i wonder how
many millions i lost
because shopify leaves
a new ai generator um
he makes a bunch of
money on themes and
then they launched
a new framework that
just didn't work that
well uh it works well
but like there's
just issues and like
it just causes like
a lot of problems so
who knows what the
answer is happy to chat
with anyone after sorry
for taking the time
thank you guys yeah
i think i think the
takeaway from today's
call is is none of us have
a moat you whatever
you build someone will
copy tomorrow and do
a better version of
guaranteed so no you're
never going to compete
by being the best
product the only
differentiation you guys
any of these things that
i've seen today will
have is basically having
a better distribution
than than the next
guy that's it it's your
hyper niche targeting
yeah you show up and
say i have a better
version a better widget
no one cares nothing
isn't better you you
obviously have a better
better version than
what was before you
you're the only way you
compete is just to have
better distribution
and get your product
in front of everyone
else quicker faster than
than the next guy
like that's the reason
why everyone uses cursor
not rue it's uh it's
it's just a better
distribution i think to
jed's point um do we
have uh do we have braun
we lost him last week
let's see if we can
get him this week mr
field walker maybe
we'll put him on at the
beginning that's right
next week we're leading
with braun yeah he
never quick makes it
to the end yeah that's
that's a hockey dad
that's what that is yeah
well this is the open
this is the open mic
portion um anybody
have anything they want
to say show tell
whatever this is this is
your chance to show off
your latest greatest
this is it.
Question for the
agentics team, sorry.
What's the coolest
thing that you
guys are excited
about right now?
I guess there's
a few of you guys
here, but what are
the things that you're
dreaming of
building or that you
think is easier or
fun to build now?
I'm looking forward
to reproducing an AI
-powered background noise
cancellation tool similar
to what crisp ai or
neap had uh presented
as their offerings
i found a number of
academic papers which
talk about the methods and
techniques and i'll
be releasing uh ai gi
against it to see if
it can reproduce those
papers for myself so
you're you're like a like
a noise generator like
white noise is that
is that what it is the
other way around the
other way around
removing background noise
from the speaker
using on-machine
AI.
Chris, AI, and
Neap are the ones
that do it today.
Am I giving off
a lot of background
noise currently?
My fan might be
pointed at my
mic.
No, it sounds
like a cool... And
that's like half the
things I do, is I
point it at random
research I stumble
across and say,
go build me that.
So I'm going to be...
technical term i'm very
excited about something
i'm working heavily
on i'm very excited
about semantic knowledge
graphs and the ability
to create ontology
of ontology and graphs
of graphs of graphs
and taxonomies of
taxonomies because that
is allowing me to have
provenance so one of
the things i'm
building is for example
personalized news feeds
where i take news articles
and i create semantic
graphs of those news
articles and then i
basically create semantic
graphs of the target
audience a persona
and then I connect the
dots and I with that I
get exact provenance
of why I'm showing
something to a particular
individual and you
can apply that to all
sorts of different things
so in a way I'm using
the LLMs only for
the bit that I should
be I'm not using code of
course I'm going to
use some of the code
to help create some
LLMs to create the code
but the idea is to
remove black magic and
remove basically anything
that doesn't give me
provenance from the
mix right and there's
a huge amount of work
that's been done in
the past on on semantic
web which was great
but never scaled so
my approach is to
actually use uh sort
of cloud storage as a
database so i don't
have graphed well i have
a graph database but
my graph database is
serverless which i
open source by the way
and it's all about
graphs or graphs files
or files nodes and
edges so it's basically
i create all these
sort of relationships
and i and i'm kind
of moving moving away
from the idea that
there's one taxonomy one
ontology one big
definition is like we could
all have different
ontology and taxonomies.
We just need a way to
start to connecting them.
And that is really
cool because it
brings a huge
amount of provenance
and explanation
to content and
eventually to code
and stuff like that.
So you built this on
what platform? Are
you using how you
handle it? Is it from
scratch or using
some other libraries?
Well, so basically,
well, so it's all Python
-based. I basically
get all serverless.
So it runs everywhere,
right? runs from lambda
function to containers
to bare metal to
locally whatever you
want to run it i can
run it there and it's
it's basically this
this process of um i
take up that i take them
contents i create the
the semantic graphs
and i save it so
everything i use the file
disk as almost my cache
right and and it's
all uh i can you know
i i think i probably
need a bit more time
than i think we we
have now but i've
been published tons of
stuff i'll put the links
here if you guys want
to want to play about
with it maybe maybe
give me a slot next
time and i'll give yeah
yeah we we love we
love exploring graphs
and semantic structures
of various sorts
ontologies and i'm
always curious about sort
of latency that those
systems induce but
yeah i love love to
see love to see what
you're building are you
using network x library
or some some other
library so i i support
that but when i
actually build my own
graph database so
basically the problem i I
always had with, but
first of all, the problem
with most graph
databases is they're
******* late, right?
They're like DMS, right?
And the more you
use it, the more
you lose control
of it, right? So,
and basically my
approach is to actually
store, imagine a
serialized version
of the graph that
is serialized into
disk, right? And
then I load it and I
transform it and
I save it. So it's
almost like my graph
is like this map reduce
function where
sometimes I expand,
sometimes I contract.
And every time I have
like those queries, I
end up saving it and
allowing it to basically
to be retrieved next.
And I use S3 or basically
any cloud storage
as my database. So
when you get the data,
you go to the data
directly. And when if you
do need to make some
more complex queries,
you just load it up in
memory very quickly,
manipulate it and
get results back.
So what I found is
that if you start
from the premise
that I'm going to
evolve my schema and
I'm going to have,
you know, sometimes,
for example, a Python
object. And by the
way, another thing
I open source was a
strongly typed Python
library because the
thing I hate from
Python, I love everything
else apart from
the fact that it's
not strongly typed and
it almost said, you
know, of course I
don't like, I code the
law in .NET and Java
and all that stuff
in the past, right?
There was one thing
about having strongly
typed that helps, so I
build a strongly typed
Python that I can
serialize. So sometimes
that's all you need for
a graph and sometimes
you need action nodes
and edges like you can
get and i use network
x for example when i
need to run more complex
graph calculations
but what i'm finding
is that if you keep
cleaning up the data
and if you keep cleaning
up your schema as you
go along you don't
actually need sometimes
a lot of complex right
crazy complex graphs
because in a way that's
almost a complexity
of the weight of the
graph data that you
pump into it and usually
is because you haven't
cleaned up your schema
and what what's a what's
an ideal application
of a graph would you
say well i i almost
i feel that around
what's not an ideal for
graph look a good
example is is this thing
here can i just show you
can i share my screen
for a second sure all
right so um so if you
look at this right um
let me just share it
um okay so you guys
should be able to see my
screen uh where is it
right can you see uh
yeah right can you see
this yeah right you
guys can see this right
yeah we yeah we can
see okay so very quickly
i'm going to go 100
miles an hour right so
so this is a persona
right this describes
a particular person
this is a bunch of news
articles the question
is how do i go from one
persona to personalized
articles right to
the person so this is
personalized articles
right this is an article
for sister you go for
cto etc this could
be one of you guys
right like this could be
that's the whole idea
right so for every one
of these things that
i have here right and
i'm going to show you
the data you actually
probably are interested
in this more than
more than others so
this is the message that
i have this is a prompt
this description that
you have there right
and this is online and
it's all open source
by the right? The
coolest thing is that,
yeah, you can paste this
into an LLM, but the
coolest thing is that
when I talk to the
LLMs, I always talk in
schemas, right? So this
is an example of what
I mean by my type safe.
It's like Pydantic,
right? There's a variation
of it. So what you
have here is that this
results, you can see
my mouse, right? So
this part here gives
me that code there,
right? And you can see the
connections, right?
So that means that I
actually give it, this
is the type, so I have
an automatic conversion
from here to the LLM
call, right? And that
means that when I get
the responses i can
put it straight away
into these goals right
so there right so the
key question here is
how do i go from this
profile to that right
so how do i say hey i
have a fintech company
here i have a thin cso
etc so this is where
i use an llm and by
the way i only use llms
because the news industry
doesn't give me this
right which is one
of the things that i
would like to change
right because if the
news industry actually
gave me an article with
grabs and intelligent
taxonomy i wouldn't
need to do this right
so it's quite interesting
right so this is the
schema for the persona
so you could see
that i'm going to
transform my persona into
nodes and edges which
again i could run i can
load this into a
network x if i wanted to
right and and here so
i go from the text to
here to that this is a
graph of a persona for
example right and
here's a cto right graph
so just to zoom in right
so there you go you
can see mid-size company
that going to here
that going to that etc
right so a cto looks
a little bit different
right so the cto has
things like microservices
ml etc right it
depends on this so
basically this now becomes
how rich do i want
to make this semantic
graph and also i have
others where you have
ontology and taxonomies
which also help in
defining this right so
it's the cloud migration
ml etc so the question
is you know what how
do you connect so i'm
going to now do the
same thing for the article
so this is the same
equivalent coming from
the articles so that
means that i take one
article and i convert
this right So this is
a semantic graph of
actually just the title,
for example. And I
can do this for titles,
descriptions, a whole
freaking lot. And
then in this case, you
can see critical
vulnerabilities, et cetera.
So, for example,
here, I take that and
that. That gives
me two graphs. And
actually, I actually
get so many good
results. This is
already like almost a
compressed version of
the other two graphs.
But you can already
start to see the
sense of gravity. So
you look middleware,
next to AS, critical
vulnerability,
authorization.
So if you look
another one,
for example,
you got here.
That's the connection.
let's say look cyber
attacks exploit cisco
you got that you got
the cve so you can see
that this is now the
the graph of the news
right that the news
article that was created
so then how do we connect
this with that right
so that's the question
so then that's what
i then use another
llm call to basically
basically take this
persona graph and by the
way this is how i send
it to chat gpt so i
don't say or to lms which
i support all of them
so i don't i don't
just send this i send
that so So that is a
tree version of this,
which I actually find that
I worked really, really
well. So the DLMs
know this quite well.
So again, this guy
becomes that tree. So
then the tree B represents
the nodes and edges.
So that's the edges.
That's the nodes,
right? And then that's
the connection. You
can actually see here
that you've got nodes
and edges, right?
There. And then
that's the system
prompt that I
give, where I
give persona, news
articles, etc.
And that's the schema
that I'm going to give
it. So the key here
is this part here. So
this is what I'm going
to get back, right?
So what I'm going to
get back is a connection
between a persona
entity to an article
entity and the score
and all the jazz. So I
get this back. Right.
So you could say, hey,
that guy from my
persona connects to my
article here. Right.
And that bit connects to
here. Right. And that's
how I can go from
my persona all the way
to the other way. So
I can now show you
exactly. And this is a
simple example. I have
more complex examples.
Right. But I can show
exactly why I showed
this article to that
particular persona.
And every single
transformation along the way
got saved. So basically,
that's how I have
almost a built-in
cache structure, right?
And in this case, it's
quite cool because
so you can see that
connects to that, connects
to that, connects
to this, right? Same
thing. And in this
case, you can actually
say, hey, why am I
showing this? Because this
is actually a bad
article to show a CEO,
which is now I can
reverse engineer, right?
So now I can say, why
did he happen? an O is
because there's a
score here 7.5 because
it's actually not that
and that connection is
actually very weak
because if I look for
example this one is a much
better one right where
I got regulatory bodies
regulatory compliance
blah blah blah or
this article is even
better ci pipelines
github actions but that's
a cool example of from
the persona side my
graph said ci pipelines
my article said github
actions I can connect
that right and that's
fundamentally how you
connect one to the
other and this will
scale for you know almost
just about a lot of
things right i'm doing
a bunch of other um by
the way i'm actually
doing like multiple
startups right now on on
using these open source
technology and and
they are variations of
some of these things
but there you go that's
why i'm excited this
is really cool dennis
i um it's it's it's
super applicable to
the office and studio
management work that um
i've been doing right
just translating um uh
documents to different
stakeholders even
from the standpoint of
like like the
language that they use
professionally is
different from like
your executives
your designers
versus your tech team
this is really really
cool where's your where's
your repo located
can you copy can you
yeah it's open source
right so basically it's
all uh on so you can
go so basically you
get well part of it
is done on the cyber
boardroom which is where
i started right i'll
put the links there
right and then the other
stuff is on this os
bot um os security bot
and and and this is
literally uh you know
here you got every bit
right you got the fast
api the above details
the the this is the
one that has the type
save oh actually but
if you guys want to
do this stuff i would
recommend you to start
kind of here because
i've been writing lots
of documents by the way
i maxed out freaking
chat to keep deep
research right so i'm
actually i'm actually
like feeling with raw
symptoms today because
i got so used to creating
these really cool
documents right where
yeah i can get me here
right and like for
example i can create
these really nice
detailed documents right
about this explanation
and um and actually on
my on my startup you
can actually come in
here and there's a repo
here that has the cbr
investment and then
you can see here every
document i created
right for so i actually
wrote all these documents
uh in fact you know
the question i was
asking the other guy
about the thing it's
about this bit here right
so this is run
everywhere strategy right
um so you i described
how i did it and there's
even one here that
has worldly maps which
is another one of my
favorite topics right
that explains um how
you know how how you
actually like the llm
as a commodity right
so there's there's a
nice worldly map there
there's how you connect
through right you can
actually play with
that right so by the
way every startup
should have one of these
right because you this
is when you show this
is when you say this
is what i'm moving here
so sorry i didn't want
to take too much time
then it's just a
quick question is your
database it's in your
github repo you just my
database is is cloud
storage no no the one
you said the graph
database right you oh yes
yeah it is so the
graph database is this
is called mgraphdb right
and um and actually
uh you you can you
can you can read about
here right um and basically
uh it is sorry can
i share my screen again
so if you just post
the link i think it's
yeah i'll post it
there right and yeah
so i i i use that right
to to create the
nodes and edges and
fundamentally it's a it's
a python it think of it
as a serialized version
of a graph object
that is actually very
easy to convert to any
of the other and i have
an export to an f4j
to i think memory mx
a bunch of others but
it's just a way for me
to code in nodes and
edges right and so
what i found is i found
there's a lot of a lot
of people all the time
teams get very focused
on one thing it's
like they just want to
use graph database so
they just want to use
that stuff. My approach
is sometimes a Python
object is all you
need right because
that is already a graph
right if you want to think
about it but sometimes
you need nodes and
edges and nodes and
edges allow you to
ask questions and get
answers that sometimes
would be very hard
otherwise and I just load
it up and then I convert
them into nodes and
edges and I can save
it and I can even do
graphs and graphs and
maybe next time I'll
do a more deep dive
if you guys want me
to familiar there is a
project called link
ml it basically you
express you like things
in anthologies and
it just creates python
definitions uh yeah
it actually creates
a bunch of stuff sql
tables so like you just
ask it it just doesn't
yeah i look i think
these things about
being pragmatic right
like i the reason i
built that is i needed
the serverless way
to run graph queries
that it didn't cost
me anything right
so so my look my
principle on a lot of
the startups I'm creating
is that there
has to be minimal
overhead. So everything
has to be freaking
serverless, right?
Or everything has to
run in sort of epithermal
infrastructure,
right? So that means
there's no cost when
it's not running. And
then the main cost,
which is going to be
the LLMs or a bit of
compute, you just pass
that to the customer.
That's kind of
the model I'm
applying everywhere,
right? And
now that's
possible, right?
Although it wasn't
easy, right? Because
it took me like three
months to build a
stack that actually
compiled and deploys
everywhere, right?
You think it's easy.
yeah another thing
so you build all this
persona graph are you
building embeddings from
them or you just i i
have a massive problem
with embeddings
massive because for me
i see i i want to
remove anything that's
black magic right so
embedding is magic right
you don't know you know
it's an approximation
right but it's you
don't know it right
so so that's why i like
the semantic knowledge
graphs because if you
think about it you
go for deterministic
but the more important
thing is that you
have to allow the
customers and the users
to customize it to fine
tune the graph like i
was building gigantic
graphs in jira for
example right with my
teams and i realized
i couldn't get them to
freaking agree right
on the terms and then
i realized it's okay
you guys can call what
the **** you want in
your team upset call
something risk call
something etc i just
needed a way to clean
them up to connect them
in the graph so so
in a way i i I don't
care almost, you
know, what intelligent
taxonomy you use. I just
care that we can then
have threads where we
can connect them. And
then you can allow
the users and the
personas to define it.
Hey, so Dennis, I've got
a question for you. So
when you're connecting
all of those
relationships, is it your
code that's doing the
connecting or are you
offloading that with
a prompt to a model?
So I'm using the LLMs to
kickstart that process.
Okay.
Right? Because that
was the bit that I
think the previous
generation of semantic
web crowds did not
have because they
forced everybody to
create gigantic and spend
a lot of time making
the connections.
And I found that the
LLMs are actually very
good at that, especially
if you then do
several in parallel
and you want to check
the other. But my
thinking here is openly
I don't want the LLM
to make the connections
because the ontology
should be good enough
that you then use normal
graph connections.
Yeah, that's why I'm
asking. And also,
if you're processing
a million docs an
hour, that's a lot of
a lot of token cost.
It would be. But the
thing about this is that,
you know, OK, first
of all, you don't have
that problem anyway.
Right. If you have a
million. But my my my
model is always like you
do something, you
save it. Right. I even
wrote a paper called
Let's Right, which is
load, extract, transform
and save. So on your
million documents, I
will do one document
at a time and then I
will do transformation,
transformations. so
instead of having like
this massive black
box or doing the stuff
or loading down to a
massive database i just
do transformations on
on them and then let's
say a document right
so i'll give you an
example i'm doing a
project where i'm creating
a customized version
i'm filtering data
from a website right
so i'm actually taking
every web page and i'm
creating a graph for
every single web
page and the graph is
actually the first graph
is literally a json
version of html that i
save that's it and then
i create another graph
which is a transformation
and i for example
create one graph
which is now type safe
of all the html elements
and then i'm going
to create another one
for example that has
starts with all the
text nodes and then
navigates up right so and
that's how i operate
so um it's almost like
it's really super fast
because reading is
going directly to cloud
storage so read is
like two to twenty
milliseconds and the right
is the only time you
do transformation and
if you go like this
in a way your data
starts to get clean up
right because and and
and if ever because
everything is on a pipeline
literally i i can
rebuild the whole thing
all the time right so
i'm locked to a schema
right i can always say
if i'm half a third
going oh that doesn't
work very well i
can just literally build
all my data sets so
i actually have a i i
i love it i appreciate
it this is this is
awesome because i'm going
to try it with i'm
we were talking about
what we're building
i'm i'm playing with a
locally with a local
agentic model for
basically an AI panelist.
So it listens in to
everybody that's on
the panel and then it
offers its input with
subject matter or
something like that. But
there's a data pipeline
issue there. You got
the text that's coming
in, so voice to text
and you're processing
that and then you're
processing what
does that schema look
like how are how are we
doing short-term
versus long-term memory
and then how are we
you know compiling that
back into like something
back into speech
that's that's has has
a latency that makes
sense you know and i
think this is a this
is a really cool way
to kind of break that
um that knowledge
graph down and and just
the the memory in
general for that for that
particular project so
yeah i appreciate it
i think it's going to
be fun to try out so
the way you describe
it So I have another
project where I'm doing
like an SME policy
advisor, and the logic
is that as the SME
interacts, basically
SME is small, medium
companies in the UK,
right? As they interact
with risk questions, I
build a graph, right?
So, in fact, I'm
using that startup to
really get this. So
my idea there is that
whenever you have an
interaction with anything,
you should be building
a graph, right?
Almost in real
time, right? And the
beauty of that
is that this then
doesn't require you
to be 100% right.
because actually once
you introduce let's
say your panelists right
imagine a world where
as we're talking here
there's these graphs
on the side right and
in a way the graphs
are going to make
assumptions but i'm happy
to correct if that's
if there's a good ui
i'm happy to go oh i
care more about this i
care more about that i
don't care about this
you know but the key is
to have those semantic
graphs right with the
ontology that define
the rules of the game
the taxonomy define
the terms and then that
scales to the point
where i think ultimately
we will bring our
own graphs to the
table right i will have
my own persona that i
bring in and my persona
is fundamentally a
series of graphs right
exactly yeah it's
really cool it's really
cool thanks yeah i see
another application
i'm working on a kind
of very parallel where
i think there's a strong
integration but it's
essentially having a
master document that
is actually flagged
for different purposes,
especially if you want
to have, say, with
this world, here's
documentation that might
include pseudocode
that is appropriate for
AI code generation.
Here's other sections
that are appropriate for
ex-compliance. Here's
ones that are only
appropriate for executives.
So rather than having
multiple documentation,
all spread throughout
your organization,
you have one master
document that is
now flagged for different
areas. Now, I definitely
see a massive
implication because if
those are pre-labeled
so you have determinism
having this matched
up to um essentially
personalized one-on-one
based on your persona
uh as long as you
follow certain certain
rules i see a strong
i think this is a big
way to the future and
the work i start doing
in a cyber boardroom
when i got there because
look i developed a
cyber boardroom because
the biggest problem is
how do you communicate
cyber security to
executives right both
board members, execs,
and peers. And what I
realized was that there
isn't one persona.
Like each persona is
a combination of the
individual, their
language, their culture,
their state, who they
care about. It's this
gigantic graph, right?
The politics between
the freaking board
members, what they want to
do, how they want to
consume it, all of
that. But if you start
to capture that, then
you communicate crazily
effectively, which is
what an exec does,
right? And I think that's
where it gets
interesting, right? And in
your case, the other
element I was just
saying is that think of
also of creating mini,
basically, or
customized versions
of that content
like per individual.
And these days, you can
even create customized
apps. It's not even
just customized
content. But at the
document stage, if you have
at the document stage,
the pre-done flags,
like if you're in a
private organization,
most managers are not
allowed to see global
sales because that's
private area. But the
content for X policy
should be available to
everyone. So if you're
matching up with hard
-coded flags for
compliance matched up with
yours now you're
getting a tailored i
tailored message just for
but i wouldn't do that
in a document man i
i i these days i view
documents as the output
of a graph right so
documents should not
be your data store your
data store should
actually be and think
about it like you already
talked about compliance
and requirements
like there's this is
where i think there's
going to be systematic
**** show with a lot
of this the stuff that
a lot of people are
putting AIs on is
because they're not
taking into account that
those rules for identity
access management,
role-based security,
that is really hard,
right? Like literally
my whole industry was
trying to freaking solve
those problems, right?
And the only sane way
to deal with that is
when the data is not
there in the first
place, right? So I assume
that anytime you talk
to an LLM, you can
extract everything that
is on that LLM. You
can get that LLM to
do 100% of its capabilities
yeah so the next
the next page after
the yeah and by the way
somebody was saying
uh that you know they
don't run their stuff
locally right they run
on dms right i think
uh it was you right um
yeah yeah yeah it was
me yeah you you're
not paranoid man you're
saying right because
you know you have to
run every you have to
run everything in
disposable environments
right because you know
even from a security
explosion point of
view right um well it's
it's also it's also
for me it's like it's a
latency issue as well i
can't have it processing
on the cloud and
then you know there's
a trans there's transmission
and then there's
receiving time that
that's exactly if i
if i want something to
to be as real time as
as i possibly can it's
got to be it's got
to be local it's got
to be vm yeah look guys
anybody want to talk
about graphs and maps
i i'm i'm always game
for it it's i i see
the whole world as great
is this that the the
document that you
shared is it available
for a weekend you know
we can enjoyable read
yeah yeah yeah oh i
have far much more stuff
i would love to go
through i realize you're
in london aren't you
i'm in london yeah yeah
i think we should we
need to catch up uh
we have a we have a group
here absolutely well
i'm in chiswick so
west london right so
okay lovely i'm in kent
on the other side okay
i'm on the whatsapp
group by the way you
know so again oh okay
hey um guys i we gotta
wrap up here but quickly
wow that was really
interesting by the way
uh really i love what
you're doing with with
the graph stuff um
there there's a there
was a new uh mcp that
came out uh earlier
from hugging face i was
playing it with it
actually while you guys
were doing your little
chat it's pretty cool
he allows you to
interact with any of the
hugging face uh spaces
as an mcp so literally
what while i was while
you guys were uh you
know chatting i i
installed the mcp and then
i i randomly connected
to a uh one of the
models to do like image
gen just just to see
how it worked and uh yeah
within like literally
30 seconds i was using
you know a uh the
flux one uh image gen
model within hosted
on hugging face like
in seconds it's pretty
it's it's like it's
pretty it's it's pretty
cool like here let me
show you that some of
the capabilities just
quick for I gotta jump
to another call here
but yeah here so here's
the here's the
extension I've got I can
search spaces I can do
model searches and get
model details papers
various other data set
components this one
here is what I quickly
looked at and I was
able to add that and get
a response So basically,
you can add any of
these models to your
environment. In this
case, I just added a
couple just to see. So
this is an easy image
gen, another image gen.
Yeah.
So you can basically
add these quickly. So
anything that exists
on HonkyFace can now be
exposed and interacted
with via this MCP,
which I did here. And
you can see here, I did
a quick little future.
here's an example of
and within a second
I had this image
and yeah so if you're
a fan of Hugging
Face it's definitely
worth taking a look at
pretty cool
let's go back
to the site here
for a sec I
gotta jump here
why isn't it
letting me switch
screens a bit
of a delay here
hopefully I'm
coming through okay
oh let's try it's
doing this way is this
mcp integration js file
in your gist groove
uh no i just did it
quickly just as a as a
test but basically
you go to h you go to
the site and then you
can then you can pick
your tools and then
you know i randomly
picked a few tools to
add to it so i went
down here and you can
see i picked a few
image related tools
here that that shows up
now so i i can literally
go here and i can
search for whatever
we'll do llama or
whatever and oh i guess
i don't know llamas
but we'll do let's
do a graph just since
since we're talking about
that so i can choose
the graph so if uh
you guys post your
graph i can add it and
basically any gradio
server can can get
turned into a uh mcp
in about two seconds
pretty pretty cool
actually so what What
else can I search for?
I don't know,
let's do video.
I'll just choose a random
video one, text to video.
So then I go here,
jump back into my,
go here, refresh it.
Go here,
refresh.
And assuming the
demo got a smile
on me, we should
see the actual
video option here
at the bottom.
Yeah, here we go, video.
So it's, yeah,
it's pretty cool.
Worth a look.
There's anything
that can be
exposed by an MCP,
I guess will be.
Really neat feature.
My security,
what could go
wrong, right?
Well, you got to
trust, you trust
Amazon, but you
don't trust, I guess,
you know, hugging
face, you know,
somewhere you got
to trust someone.
You're right. I
don't trust them.
That design not
to trust, right?
well you so where are
you deploying your
serverless functions
in on your machine is
that the way you need
to do with this is
i think i think the
challenge with mcp
is mcp is basically
from a threat modeling
point of view right
it's actually over
provisioning stuff right
and i think i think
we'll clean it up
once we get better job
at creating these
environments that only
have the permissions
to do something right
well this this so
this is explicit
permissions based on
the token that you're
getting from Hugging
Face, which they've
done a pretty good job of
explicit permissioning,
time to live, all
kinds of things.
Now, again, it's
Hugging Face, so it's
up to you. But in
the world of AI,
everyone uses it.
It's generally
pretty trusting.
I'm saying, my
fundamental problem
there is not,
for example, the
Hugging Face, right?
It's the fact that
you now just create a
connection to a model
that is receiving
data that could be
malicious or all sorts
of stuff to now
connect to another
capability. is literally
is the API of the
connections of APIs,
right? It's literally
is the problem that
we've been having.
That's not an
MCP problem.
No, no, no,
no, no, no, no.
That's every API
ever, right? It is.
But MCP is just
an abstraction
of APIs in
general, right?
Yeah, it's like
Postman. Like I can go
on one of these
rapid API sites and
randomly choose an
API and they steal all
my information.
That's on me, right?
And if I'm super
paranoid, I can create
an MCP server in
Gradio in literally
30 seconds, right?
And I can run it
completely locally
if I wanted to,
just clone the space
and run it myself.
But for some things, you
just want to
test it quick.
So it's cool. I like it.
It's very powerful.
Yeah. And I like the B
-sides. Like,
you're OG, huh?
Yeah, it was another man.
Nice. All right.
Thanks, everyone. I
got to jump, you know,
if, if, if anyone's
interested, you know,
gentix.org, we're
all, we're, we've
got, you know, come
several different meetups
coming up around
the globe. I think I
got wind that there's
one happening in
Kuala Lumpur and
Singapore as well. That's
being organized. We
got a, I think we have
a sponsor for that.
So if anyone's in
that part of the world,
I know it's been a
little night there
right now, but you're
more than welcome to
help organize that.
Just a shout out to
the Stockholm team.
Their event is on
the 17th. I think
we're maxed out.
So if anyone has a
lead on a bigger
space in Stockholm,
we could certainly
use it. I know the
Ericsson guys have a
really nice space that we
potentially could
use. It fits hundreds.
But currently our
space is limited to 12.
It's kind of unfortunate
and it's maxed.
So if you've got a
lead on Stockholm,
feel free to
reach out and we
could use a bigger
space there.
and uh yeah that's
that's it for another
ai hacker space it's
always the highlight
of my week really
appreciate everyone
that's taking the time
to present it's i learn
more from you guys
in this hour and a
half than i do from
anything else i do all
week so i really
appreciate you guys taking
the time um so thanks
everyone and thanks
for the shirt yeah
i was about to ask
like you guys are
making us look feel
jealous now i mean yeah
um how about this how
about how about if
you help organize a
local event we'll get
you a shirt and maybe
maybe the logo won't
be quite as big but
you will we'll uh we'll
figure out a way to
get get you some shirts
and maybe we'll we'll
do some more hacker
style shirts with a
hoodie or something more
more like the b-side
shirts that dennis is
has all right gotta go
jump yeah i need totally
need a hoodie i i
with with a bear what
we need a mascot maybe
it won't be a bear
maybe it'll be like a
like something crazy like
a mongoose or something
all right i just
totally made that up all
right i'll talk to you
guys next week yeah
see you guys thank
you okay thanks again
yeah dennis i've basically
messaged you i believe
you mean the london
agentics group right
sorry you you mean
the london agentics
whatsapp group right yeah
actually i'm not sure
there are a few so i
didn't realize there was
a i can't see your
name in no i'm not on
that one i think i think
that was a time where
there was so many
agentic things i like i
subscribed to a couple
and it was like okay
enough man uh so if
there's a london one i'll
join in i have messaged
you on on linkedin
let's connect up and
then i think i'll let
me bring introduce i
think you know mark d
ridge i think he's he
mentioned i mentioned to
you him about you just
now he said he knows
you so is there london
is there a london
thingy um yeah yeah so
uh why don't i i drop
you my phone number
here and just message me
that's my number um
just message me and
i'll connect you and
you got you have a
whatsapp channel too
right don't you yeah
we have but i think
denis is not there on
the group is what i
realize now okay so
all right i'm i'm
late i'm late for my
next call guys i gotta
go i'm shutting this
down thanks everyone
okay thank you bye