one and go live so
it's been uh i'm just
gonna let everyone's
uh bots in it's been
an interesting uh
week lots lots going
on one of the things i
want to show today
was the work i've been
doing with a number
of different tools um
in particular i've
been playing with this
tool called uh come
a composio i think is
what they call it and
it it's done a really
good uh it's it's
it's a really a job at
sort of connecting
different uh you know
basically building and
connecting different
apps in terms of mcps
and one of the things
i did is i use i use
that to create a mcp
that allows you to
use perplexity and
basically in rue what
i did is i created a
kind of deep research
system using perplexity
that allows it to go
and and search and
find so here you can
see here i've got my
I'm not sure why
it's not showing
my MCP servers,
but we can
go and create,
I don't think.
All right, guys,
don't forget to
mute yourselves.
And I think there's
a setting I can
use for that.
Holy call.
All right. So,
all right, I'm just gonna
mute all, there we go.
Yeah, all right.
So in this case,
if you're not
familiar with
Composio, it's a
pretty cool service.
So in essence, what it
does is it allows you
to create these MCP
servers. So in this
case, I can go in here,
I can create a new MCP
server, I can give
it a name, we'll call
it Vibecast, and then
we'll go in here next.
So if you want to
check it out, Composio
.dev, and it connects to
a whole lot of different
options, so I'm
going to go Composio
.dev, here I'm going to
pop it in the chat as
well. So anyone that's
joining on LinkedIn,
you're more than
welcome to join
our chat as well
here on Zoom.
So I'm just, for
those who are joining,
I'm just going to
copy the Zoom chat
and pop that into
the LinkedIn crew.
I know some of the
folks here watching on
LinkedIn, so you're
more than welcome if
you have a question.
I'll try to keep,
I've got both open,
but there's a lot going
on and sometimes it's
hard to keep track
of all these things.
So what I'm starting
off today is I'm
just going to show
you a little bit about
Composio, So then
we'll go into VS Code
and show how I connect
this to Rue Code and
use the orchestrator
and different
options. But basically
what the MCP dashboard
here allows you to
do is connect various
services as MCPs.
So in this case, if
I wanted to connect
Twitter, I guess it's
called X these days, I
could connect it and
you see there's various
tools I can select. Or
if I wanted to connect
Firecrawl, I can
connect those. You can
see I have different
options for connecting.
now i went with a
super a relatively easy
one today i went and
chose perplexity so in
this case i can go here
and choose perplexity
now once once you go
in here and choose
perplexity it'll prompt
you to go and add your
api i'm i'm not going
to do that because i
don't feel like sharing
my api at this point
which i might have
to in a moment anyway
but in in this case i
i i'm what i'm going do
is I'm going to show
you how to use this as
a structured deep deep
research using the
orchestrator and boomerang
tasks within Rube
so for those that
aren't familiar you
essentially have the
ability in Rube to go and
create these kind of
boomerang tasks now these
boomerang tasks kind
of work in the form
of you know it makes
a request to the mcp
server and I've got a
structured prompt essentially
it tells it what I
want and how I want
it to work now in the
case of Rube you've
got two different files
you need to sort of
enable it. You've got
this RooModes file that
sits in your root
directory of your repo.
And you've got a MCP
folder that sits in the
folder called .ru, if
I'm not mistaken. And
then the two basically
allow you to sort of
orchestrate. So what
I'm going to do is I'm
going to walk you
through that process. So
I went ahead and And
Betty Crocker this
beforehand, so you won't
have to watch me do all
the configuration, but
I'll quickly go and
set that up. So I'm
going to jump into VS
Code. So I created a
VODcast. This is just a
blank generic sort of
repo here on GitHub. You
know, I just created
it a few minutes ago.
And what my plan is to
create each week, I'll
just create a new
branch, and that'll be
the branch for that
week rather than that.
It's simple, easy. I
don't want to create a
million different repos
if I don't have to.
So then what I did is
I went and I created
a code space. I like
code spaces. I find
it's a nice way to
keep everything clean
and separate so I don't
have to mess around
with my local
environment too much. But
you can just as easily
do this locally.
The drawback slightly
is sometimes there's
a bit of a delay.
And if you're doing
really long-running
root code instances,
like the other day I
ran one for 12 hours,
it'll crash. It'll
crash. It'll close
after I think about
eight or nine hours.
So it's something
to keep in mind.
But there's also
a number of other
services out there
that allow you. You
could literally run
your own VS Code
space on AWS or other
services as well.
All right. So I
went ahead and did
that. So I'm just
going to pop that up.
Let's jump into
where I've got that.
I've got to find
which of my various
ones I have. I think
it's right here.
All right.
Welcome.
Why isn't it loading?
So I'm going to
go, I'm going to,
it's not, I've got
too many monitors.
Here we go. Bring it
to the right monitor.
All right. So this
is a basic, you know,
code space, nothing
much running. You can
see I've got Roo
running here. It takes
a second for Roo to
initialize. So I'm
just going to let that
start for a moment.
Now I'm going to
do a new terminal
instance. Now this
is the part that some
people are having
trouble with when
using Spark. So I'm
just going to walk
you through sort of
the initialization.
and maybe I need a
better message or
something because
everyone seems to ask
me the same question.
I got an error.
I don't want to
sound like a ****,
but if you read
the error, it
actually tells
you how to fix it.
So now when we do,
MPX creates Spark
init. That basically
grabs a, I guess you
can do a temporary NPM,
which is kind of a
cool feature of the
NPM library. And
assuming you have NPM
installed, this
will just create all
the files you want.
so let's take a look
at the folder see
there's nothing much
here but there are
some files the reason
i didn't let it
just write i didn't
want to overwrite
stuff you already had
so when you when
you do an issue when
you first initialize
it you'll see
that there's an error
if you don't add
the force function
now in this case
i didn't add the
force function so it
yeah so you see here
it failed it says to
use the force option
you that's my that's my
shout out to star
wars a little bit too
but anyway um so we go
in here if you add you
the force option and
maybe i should make
it more obvious i
don't know there's also
a help by the way if
you just type this
without it it'll guide
you through a little
wizard and there's
options for setting up the
mcps and other other
little uh easter eggs
that i i put put on
there i created this
on easter so i figured
it needed an easter
egg um all right so
i'm gonna put that in
there and this time
i'm going to add force.
So I'm going to
use the force.
And then we're going
to go in here. So
now you notice
that it created the
files, right? So create
a Rue modes file.
And you see here, I've
got the architect.
Now, if you want to
replace the generic
orchestrator that the
guys at Rue have added
recently, you'll see
here that you've got
different options. I
noticed they apparently
like they like my
use of emojis and
decided to go the
same way. So props to
those guys. But if you
want to change any of
these options, you
can go here. Now, it
takes a second to
initialize. You notice that
my options aren't
there yet. And you see
that I've got a bunch.
For whatever reason,
if you want those
initialize, you have
to click. Oh, usually
you have to click.
Let's go.
I guess the demo gods
don't want to work today
for some reason. Oh,
there we go. See,
that's a strange quirk
of brew. Like you just
saw it. It took a second
for it to kick in.
I have absolutely no
idea why it takes some
clicking around to
initialize, but it does.
That's probably a bug
in Roo, I would guess,
that it doesn't
initialize, or maybe they
have like a 30 or 60
second interval between
checks. Who the heck
knows? But anyway, moral
story is I've set up
the orchestrator here.
Now, if you want to
make it to your default
orchestrator, all you
need to do is change
this slug to orchestrator.
I kind of want to
keep it separate so
I'm not particularly
concerned about that now
this morning I created
a new deep research
and I'm using the MCP
to do the research now
when I installed this
you'll notice that I
included some files for
you guys it sort of
you get up and running
quickly now let me just
show you the ones that
are important now when
you're using models
that aren't sonnet
and are let's just say
a little bit more stupid
you need to be more
explicit in telling it
how it needs to work
right so in this case,
what I discovered,
like if I want to use
like Gemini or some of
the other models, I had
to create rules that
basically say that I
wanted to use, you know,
certain structures
for applying the diff.
One of the things I
hate about Rue is when
it sort of defaults
to this write to file
option, which basically
writes every line. And
I don't want to, I
don't like that. It's
inefficient. I don't
want to, it's like
watching paint dry as it
goes every line. So what
I told to do is to
use apply diff by
default and this is how
i did it basically it
it uses that then i
told it sort of what to
do what not to do so
this basically improves
it now the drawback it
uses more tokens the
benefit it works a
heck of a lot better um
so you can see here
that i've got the core
rules file now each
of these folders are
basically the rules for
each of the modes so
you'll notice here that
i've got a mode for
mcps now this mcp mode
basically gives it
and tells it how to work
with MCPs better than
the default Roo mode.
So we're going to
come back to this in a
moment, but basically
when you're using
MCPs, you've got two
options to sort of
improve the performance of
the MCP within Roo.
You can use the rules
directly within the
Roo mode file here that
you'll see, and you
can basically tell it
explicitly how to use
the MCP. Like I've got a
MCP integration option
here, and I'm basically
telling it how it
needs to use the MCP.
Or, in the case of
the deep research
component I created this
morning, we can create
a new mode
specifically for deep
research, which is what
we're going to do. So
in this case, if we
go to the repo that
I created this
morning, I might, maybe
I'll add to Vibcast, I
don't know. But we'll
go here to, where
is it, a specialized
research assistant.
You'll see here I've
got a Rue Modes and
I've got an MCP. So
the first thing I'm
going to do is I'm going
to go here and I'm
going to add this.
all right then i'm
going to go back here
now it's it's json
so when you're adding
it remember the last
item in a json array
doesn't have a comma
this is like i think
that's i know dozens
of people have emailed
me it broke it broke
because you included
a comma so when you
so i'm i'm going to
add a new entry i'm
going to put go in here
and i'm going to
paste that in now that
you notice the last
one here doesn't have
a comma, right? So
that's how I'm going
to indent it because
I'm I'm an old school
Python guy. But now
we've got deep research
and we've got the
instructions for but
we haven't set up
the MCP just yet, but
we've given it
instructions. So now we're
going to go back to
Rue code for a moment.
And again, it takes
a second for it to
initialize. It's
odd. I don't know why
it doesn't show up
right away. This is
this again, this is
a quirk. It could be
because I have too
many things in here.
I'm not really sure
exactly why, but here
we go. It did show
you click and scroll
and whatever.
Eventually it shows up.
So basically whatever
you see in here is what
is being fed from
here, right? So if you
want to see it more
clearly, all you need to
do is go here and you
can see all my rules
and you can customize
these rules if you don't
like it. I, I made
these rules to sort of
act kind of like the
open AI or Google deep
research component where
it can search and it
can go back and forth
and and find what it
needs right so you can
see here that included
the structure of how
i want the files i
wanted it organized i
don't one of the things
rue in particular
doesn't do well is isn't
really really long
files so i wanted to say
basically separate
them into you know more
logical structures right
and you can customize
this if you're if you're
working with let's
say a data data out you
know a data analysis
system or whatever,
you could change this
up and just make it the
way you like it. And
you'll notice that
anything I type in here,
so let's just put in here
something like
one, two, three,
will,
and I'll click outside,
will show up over here.
Basically, it's an
interface to that. So
once you've added
this, you want to
customize that. I
suggest customizing
it here. It's
just a bit easier.
All right. Next thing
we're going to do
is we're going to set
up the MCP server.
So to get the ball
rolling, what I did
is, and of course,
it's not showing
up right away because
it, oh, no, still
not showing up.
Let's go to edit MCP.
Now, this is another
quirk of Rue.
Maybe I need to restart
VS Code. I don't
know. Maybe I just need
to copy and paste it
a couple of times.
It takes up, and this
is one of the things
that when you're getting
started with Rue,
it's the quirk of it.
It's because it's
like, why are my MCP
servers not showing
up? Now, keep in mind,
there's two modes. So
in this case, I'm just
going to copy this
for a sec. This is
totally a hack. It's
not elegant or anything.
I'm going to go
to MCP Global
for a moment,
and I'm going to
copy and paste
this in here.
All right.
And usually, if
I go back and
forth a few
times, it works.
Apparently, if I'm
going to do a demo,
it's not going to
work all the time.
Oh, it worked. All
right. So you notice
now I have it. Now
it's redundant.
I've got it twice.
So I'm going to undo
this, I think, but
it should stay. No.
Now I don't know why
the project specific,
the project ones do
work eventually, but
the global ones seem
to show up immediately.
So that's good.
That's fine. I'm going
to jump in over
here for a moment.
Most likely you have
to restart your VS
code. I think that solves
it but global doesn't
seem to require a
restart this used to
work by the way about
a week ago they broke
it um so maybe we
should do a bug report
to the routine and
tell them it's broken
but anyway so i'm i'm
now i'm in global mcp
and i've just copy
and pasted my example
so reflects the ai
search all right
now let's give it
a sec to initialize
this does this does
take a moment to
initialize again
and that's hopefully
it will all right
come come to life
uh i'm gonna click
around i guess
i don't know see
if i can get it to
you know you we did
see it work a second
ago well let's let's
try something else again
the mcp integration
is quirky it's i don't
know what to tell
you if anyone has any
suggestions on how
they can get it to show
up more quickly let
me know i'm not really
sure why it's not
showing up probably
because I'm doing a
demo or something. Maybe
that's probably the
only reason. I don't
seem to have that kind
of issue with Klein.
It shows up quickly.
Yeah, so Klein does
show up quickly as well.
It's the same thing.
Yeah, if we go
into Klein. But you
guys saw a second
ago, it was there.
Yeah, it was there.
And I've got no errors.
But you only
see it with Rue?
Yeah, I only see
it with Rue. So
the other thing
I can do is I'm
going to go back
here for a moment.
I'm not sure why
it's not trying.
It doesn't want to
show me anything.
So then I'm going
to go back here.
Oh, it showed up.
All right.
Okay. Let's see.
Let's see if
I can go here.
And I'm going to
paste this in.
Apparently it
wants to only
work with global today.
All right. So we're
going with global.
I don't know why.
All right. We'll go in
here and I'm adding this.
All right. Now
I didn't add my
endpoint.
So I'm going to quickly
just grab my endpoint.
I don't think this
is like one of those
keys that's probably
okay to share. You
guys, if you guys want
to use that, I don't
really care. I might
just turn it off later.
All right. So I'm
going to go and
grab it from
another repo I
already have running
just because.
So I'm going
to grab that.
And all right.
So I'm just on
my other screen.
I got too many.
You guys don't
want to see a
50-inch monitor.
Everything would
be super tiny.
Yeah, it looks
like my other one I
actually did as
well using global.
So again.
I was going to say
you can use Cloak
to hide the environment
variable file,
but I got to look
into modifying Cloak
so that it works
with any JSON file.
It actually is
specific to, you know,
I showed you that
before, it'll hide
the environment
variables, but it
doesn't work with
just any JSON yet.
Yeah, I think I've
got Cloak running.
Yeah, but it won't
help with our MCP
work because we're
putting keys in those
and it needs to be
modified to be able
to work with specific
JSON files because
it's only going
to look for your
.env file. That's how
it actually works.
Okay, well, I'm not
using a .env file.
I'm going to stop
just for a moment.
Okay.
I know you guys love
to hack my stuff,
but all right,
I'm just going
to stop that
for a moment.
What I did a moment
ago is I went into the
Composio system here
and I just generated
a server and
then I copied the
URL from that
basically, just
if you want to
do it yourself.
Okay. So now I went
in there. So now I'm
going to go back
here. So now I've got,
I've got my complaint.
Oh, now it's twice.
Thanks for
doing it twice.
All right. So it, it,
it worked now. So now
I'm, now I'm going
to go in and remove
my, my secondary ones.
It shows one's global,
one's project in the
settings there on
the left. Yeah. But
it confuses it. Right.
Sure. Yeah. You
can't, you don't want
to. Sure. Yeah. So
I'm just going to do
that. Now, I'm just
going to use global
now because I'm too
lazy. I actually actually
use local or whatever
they call it.
But all right. So now
we get perplexity.
Now we've got now
we can check that
it works. We can
see that it's green.
We can see that we
get the perplexity
search. Now, I went and
set up perplexity before
the call. So but
you're going to have
to go get perplexity
API if you want to use
it. But you see there's
parameters. Now,
the key thing here is
of these parameters
is actually looks
like it's using it's
using the wrong one
puppy yeah it's using the
wrong server it's
really struggling today
sorry guys one second
i'm gonna go back
to my file i'm gonna
i'm gonna stop sharing
there looks like
there's like massive
delay in when i make
changes uh i'm I'm gonna
look at my global,
just to double check.
Yeah, well,
it's, sorry guys.
There's like
a five minute
delay on anything
I do in this.
So now I gotta
do the, I gotta
change the global
one one more time.
Work.
Yeah, so MCPs
are a little
quirky, not gonna lie.
All right. It actually
worked a lot easier
earlier working
the first try. It
probably has something
to do with me like
live casting or
something that it, you
know, it's like Murphy's
law or something.
All right. So now we,
so now we go back, let
me do one more check.
I'm going to, I'm
going to refresh this
and I'm going to go
back here. Now, the
reason I know it worked is
because I see one tool
and I know that the
MCP that I'm using
only had one tool and
I set it up to only
work with the one tool.
So now we see that
there's parameters that
you can pass. Now,
these parameters are
important. These parameters
are essentially what
I'm going to define
here. So when we go
back to my actual area
here, you'll see here
that I gave it guidance,
right? I told the
architecture, I gave
it all the parameters.
It doesn't know what
the heck the parameters
are by default. So
you have to go and
tell it what those
parameters are. That's what
this line is doing.
It's basically not
only telling it what and
how it needs to operate
but it's telling it
the parameters it
needs to operate so if
we scroll over to the
right you'll see here
that i've got different
uh you know structures
that we saw earlier
and and how it needs
to run again this
is way more visible if
we go we go here and
then we go to the uh
prompts and then we go
to deep research we we
can see exactly what
what i fed it but
basically i'm telling it
exactly what how it
needs to run and more
importantly i'm telling
it what the parameters
it needs to know
so you see here the
example usage okay
tool name and so on so
without that it spends
a lot of time trying to
discover the other
thing you're going to
want to do if you're
creating mcp based
workflows don't put read
read kills it it spends
all this time trying
to read local files
and all i really want
to do is read the mcp
so do not put read in
there you edit edit
allows you to edit
files like to create the
research files and mcp
allows it is it's MCP
is basically like a
replacement for read.
So if you don't
really wanna use
read and MCP
together, if you
do want it to
read local files,
use the orchestrator
and tell it to read
local files using like
some other mode and
then to orchestrate and
switch back and forth,
but don't combine
them, it doesn't work.
And I've struggled a
lot with that as well.
All right, so now I
think we've got it to a
point where we're
working, we're gonna go
to deep research mode
and we're going to go
and I'm really interested
in learning about
the new MCP protocol
from Cloudflare. They
came out with a really
cool MPX library
that allows us to build
and deploy serverless
MCP instances, but
locally and remotely.
I figured that would be
a fun little project.
So I'm going to do a
little research. I'm
going to say research
the latest MCP MPX,
library from,
I don't know, I
guess we're going
to say Cloudflare
and create a
basic research
plan in slash plans
to implement. And
I'm not really
giving a lot of
guidance. Now, Now, in
this case, I'm using
Sonnet 3.7 for
the deep research.
Now, there's one of
the problems with
Sonnet 3.7 that you'll
run into if you're
doing really, really
deep research is it
doesn't really
handle large context
windows well. So if
you think this is going
to be more than 200
,000 tokens, don't
use ***** Thinking.
But if you want it,
there's a workaround.
you can say for each
for each part use you
know use a different
model or use a
different plan and then
just change the model
for that particular
use case but in this
case i don't care
i'm just going to let
it go so research latest
i'm choosing
research mode fingers
crossed this worked 10
times before i started
the call this morning
i'm going to close
this and we're going
to see what happens
all right so now we're
in deep research mode
you can see that
that it's going to do
initial check I've got
MCP and edit now if all
is well it should
automatically determine
how to use the MCP
without me telling it now
in the old version
I would have to like
copy and paste it and
give it examples you can
see here it's thinking
about what it wants
to do it's looking at
the instructions so
we can let's see what
it's thinking about so
it's thinking about
making directories I
never gave it the ability
to make directories
so maybe I should add
the command option
but let's let's see what
happens it it's it's
thinking about what
it needs how it needs
to create it this now
what it will need to
do is actually eventually
research so it's
it's doing a lot of
thinking all right now
this is a drawback to
thinking mode is it
sometimes overthinks
this is a perfect example
of an overthinking
just do it if i had
chosen sorry is it
necessary to have thinking
if you're already using
perplexity does its
own thinking well no
if it ever get if it
ever finishes thinking
you'll see why thinking
is important now it
overthought the initial
step i know what i
could do is i could
stop it and tell it
to just start with a
research but I'm gonna
let it go for a minute.
It's really
thinking here.
This is actually
the most it's
thought about it.
Usually it starts
with a research,
then it thinks.
And that's one
of the drawbacks
to thinking as well
is it sometimes
takes on a life
of its own.
All right, keep,
all right, that's
really overthinking it.
Okay, I'm gonna cancel
that for a moment.
And we're gonna
look at what happens
when I don't use
thinking mode.
I don't, I don't
have all day
for it to think.
So I'm going to
go, I'm going
to go back here
and I'm going to stop.
Oh, it was about to do
a subtask. Of course
it was. I'm going to
go back here and I'm
going to switch to
a non-thinking mode.
So let's choose sign 3
.5. And let's see what
happens when I don't
do a thinking mode.
I can always switch
to thinking later.
Now this isn't an
orchestrator in the
traditional sense,
because this is
an orchestrating
subtask. it's it's
it's basically
orchestrating the mcp
all right so
now do do your thing
here we go this is a
perfect example of why
thinking mode see
see how it see how it
sort of like needed
to figure itself out a
little bit if you had
read on it would have
tried to read all
your local files and
do all this crazy stuff.
In this case, because
I gave it the exact
thing it needed, it
kind of figured itself
much more quickly.
You can see I've got
always allow here for
the perplexity. You
can see the request
it made. So this to
the person who just
mentioned it, this is
kind of its thinking as
well. You're right. It
is kind of thinking.
Now it made the
request. Now this is the
response it got. You
can see here that it
got a bunch of
information. It's, it's
relating to, you know,
the MCP information.
Now it's going and doing
some more thinking.
All right.
And let's see.
Now the, this, this
will, the, this
will take a, this
could take a while.
Now this is really
good when you
integrate it as part
of like a development
flow, especially if
you have like, you
know, problems it's
trying to solve.
oh it's still waiting
for a response i guess
we'll give it a sec
the other thing is
interesting check this
out i find this really
interesting um notice
that it's changing the
the temperature parameters
automatically it
and so based on whatever
it's searching for
it changes and optimizes
its own temperature
which is really a
unique i never i never
saw a model sort of self
-optimized temperature
before that's that's
a that's a new one
um so anyway it's going
down here and it's
continuing now it's
saying what was it doing
now it seems the
response was cut off let
me try again with more
specific query that
now that might be a
limitation uh yeah here
we go that's a limitation
because it didn't
actually include the
uh token count i think
and and it defaults
to a certain value. So
what we might wanna
do, and I gotta look at
the parameters here.
Let's see if we can see
if there's a parameter.
Yeah, max tokens.
So now I know there's
a potential problem
with max tokens, we
can go here and I can
tell it to adjust the
max tokens as needed.
So we go here, we
go to research mode,
and maybe I go at
the bottom and I
say something like,
you know, adjust,
oh.
adjust max
tokens to prevent
truncated text
or something.
All right, so that's
gonna fix that problem.
Guys, I built this
this morning, so
I'm still, I'm
in for this call,
so I'm still sort
of optimizing it.
So you can see here, it's
automatically sort
of tried again.
It's making additional,
you are specified,
you know, a specialized
technical
documentation writer.
all right now the other
thing i might want
to consider doing is
limiting the amount
of times it asks oh
here we go it's already
uh it looks like it
looks like it's already
figured out the token
issue all right so
now now it's writing
the documentation now
notice it's writing
the documentation in
the structure and format
that i wanted that
matches the requirements
of the spark
specification that we'll
use later to actually
implement whatever
we're building. Now,
this is a crazy detailed
research, but the
more detailed the
research, the better the
result is going to be
in the complexity of
what you want to
build. So the way that
I've set this up, and
I'm going to turn on
the right so it just
writes automatically.
Now, what I'm setting
this up to do is
to do really long
running complex code
development. So what
this is setting up is
the ability for this
to build something
that will likely run
for several hours.
The other day I did
a test and I ran
it for I think 12
hours, including tests,
and it was about 30
,000 lines of code.
I did basically the
same thing, but I did it
manually. I went and
created a, I used
ChatGPT's deep research.
I did a massive research
report. Then I went in
a room and basically
said, take this research
and structure it
basically like what
you're seeing here. And
then once I had the
plan in place, you'll
see here, there's like
a folder or whatever,
you know, then I
basically, I set it to
implement, you know,
each phase one at a time,
testing each phase
and only testing one
function at a time before
moving on to the next.
And then iteratively,
it basically built
out the entire application
again it took i
think just shy of 12
hours cost about 70
dollars but it literally
ran non-stop for 12
hours i got up in the
morning and it was done
and fully functional
i showed my customer
and their their mind
was blown it was like i
thought this was going
to take you months
and you did it in an
evening i didn't do it
in the evening ruko
did but so when you uh
was the research done
and as you said you
have instructed it to
proceed uh function by
function and to when
before you proceed right
where do you specify
that like is it is
it in one of the md
files that you say that
i so i i specified that
so there's when you're
using the orchestrator
there's two ways
to use it one is like
go do it and go figure
it out which is which
would be kind of vibe
coding i call that
declarative programming
you're not really
telling it so much how or
what you want you're
basically saying go
figure it out, which is
fine. As long as your
plans are good enough
and structured enough,
that should generally
work. My approach
involves me giving it a
bit of initial guidance
based on whatever
it is I'm trying to
build. And the initial
guidance is generally
me telling the initial
orchestrator that I
want you to only implement
each phase one at
a time and then test
or build and test each
function one at a
time as subtasks. So I
type in, I basically
type in exactly what he
said. And then at the
very end, I say, use
subtasks. And then I
say, use new underscore
task for each subtask.
And the new underscore
task reminds the
orchestrator that it
needs to use that new
underscore task for
each subtask because
sometimes it forgets the
other thing i would
know for really long
running processes don't
use the thinking model
for the orchestrator
because you'll run out
of uh context after
about three or four
hours and and about
you but i'm not sitting
in front of this thing
watching it for three
or four hours so if
you if you use just a
regular um a regular
instruct model like sonic
3.7 not the uh you
know the the medium or
long or whatever they
call it it'll it'll
work better on a long
long running process.
Is the new
underscore task
enough to try
to switch modes?
Sorry, can you say
it again? Is the
new underscore task
instruction enough
to prevent me from
trying to switch
modes? I find
roughly after six or
seven turns, it tries
to switch modes.
Well,
are you using
subtasks or are you
using because those
are two different
approaches. I'm
trying to use subtasks
so I can let this
run overnight, but
it usually stops
at an hour or two.
Yeah, so that stops
that. So that's
exactly the
problem, it stops.
So by explicitly
saying for all subtasks
in your original
request or prompt
or whatever you
want to call it,
always use new
underscore tasks for
each subtask,
that won't happen.
If you don't, sometimes
it gets confused and
it'll start switching
modes after a while
as you discovered and
the modes is not clean
it it's it's more
expensive because it you
it all the context has
to load the subtasks
is substantially cheaper
because you don't
have to load all that
all all the previous
context and then and
the other thing i did
if you're just for
you guys if you're
curious i added a memory
option in the uh Rue,
where did I put it?
Yeah, in the
rules file here.
Is this a memory bank?
Yes, I had a memory
bank. It's working
pretty good. I think I
cracked on that. So in
this case, we'll see.
Where did I put it?
Memory.
Yeah, here it is. Here's
the memory bank
integration.
You customize this
further. I kept it
minimal, but it works.
And it creates a memory
bank. Depending on
what you're doing, it
can increase the
cost quite a bit. you
know, because it has to
update the memory and,
and sometimes the
memory bank will create
a sort of, I don't
know, a confusion at
some points. So I made
it a minimal memory
bank. The other thing
that I did for my
memory bank, just for
you guys, if you're
curious, rather than
using that, I actually,
and maybe this is a
demo for next week.
I've got a integration
here, you'll see
Memzero.
So the Memzero integration,
which is pretty
cool, this allows
you to use a Memzero
vector style memory
bank rather than MD. And
the benefit to that,
I find, is it doesn't
create a billion files
in your, I mean, exactly
a billion, in your
repo. Because most
of these files you don't
care about, but you
might want to refer to
it later. So by using
Memzero, you can
actually just do a lookup
and then you create
a and then you just
update your prompt to
say save each of the
sort of memory bank
components to mem zero
and then you give it
the example of how to
interact with mem zero
similar to what i just
showed you for the
perplexity api and for
this what i'm doing
i'm gonna let this run
for a minute i'm gonna
jump back here i i'm
actually using composio
as well composio
is actually great for
this sort of stuff so
if we go here to
composio and we choose i
think it's mem zero
yeah here it is mem zero
now i can create mcp
here that does all
this stuff for me all
in one so i can add you
know so i can add
both the perplexity so
i can go here and choose
30 so i can choose
memories i'll just
select all the memories
i get 15 memories
then i can go here and
i'll choose perplexity
i've been i've been
thinking about maybe
using fire uh fire crawl
so let's let's do that
instead oh i guess
spell it right crawl
there it is down here
all right so now i'm
i'm going to use the
extraction option which
is the best option
so i'm going to select
extract and extract
now extract with llm
is is interesting but
i don't need it because
we're using a in
this case we're using
root which acts as my
llm so it's pointless
so I'm gonna go down
here I'm gonna add the
search option which
is basically the same
as perplexity I can I
can crawl and scrape
and the web tools are
kind of cool as well
so I think we're good
I'm gonna I'm gonna
add those and let's
see what else what
other things do we have
here that can add to
my MCP server we get
Supabase so I want to
save it to Supabase
maybe I want to maybe
I want to integrate a
Google Drive which is
kind of cool like then
I could save all to
a google drive which
would be a cool feature
so in this case i
could go and i could
edit a certain file let's
say i want to save
it to a google sheet
or something i could
do i could add this
option google using
google doc option which
allows me to directly
work with google docs
you know so lots
and lots and lots of
options here if i want
to uh update my client
i can go in here and
i can add slack this
is cool i i've got
my own personal slack
bot so as it works
i'm kind of lazy so
what what i was doing
was i was looking at
a way to interact
with rue through slack
which i think i figured
out and basically
what happens is rue will
then make notifications
to my slack channel
i respond to it
and then i can interact
with Roo independently
of being in front
of my computer so
all i need is my phone
and i use the slack
option of my phone
this is how I do it.
Twilio is up next
then, right, Ruf?
Yeah.
Twilio is an option
here, I think.
Is it Twilio? I
think there's options
for generic API
integrations as well.
Here's a SERP
API. It's kind of
cool. I'm not
sure why there's
so many mix
panels coming up.
Weird work here.
They've got tons of
them. If you're curious,
if you want a better
UI, here's here's
teams Shopify calendary
all kinds of stuff
if you're looking to
get up and running
quickly with different
types of MCPs this is
by far the easiest
what's that like here's
whatsapp that's cool
let's see what we do
whatsapp I can send
a message how's I my
my bot can can have a
channel or something
i don't know meta ads
anyway anything you
can dream up right
these are all mcps and
but this example i'm
showing you guys running
is a perfect is is
just a really good
example of how you do
it like now now that you
see how i did it with
perplexity you can
pretty much replace this
with any mcp like you
know run and you know
here's a folder full
of stuff go figure it
out kind of approach
let's see how far it's
gotten all right so
now we've gotten quite
far let's close the
room I don't want to
go there, we see plans.
So now I separate,
so what I did is I
separated the research
from the plan.
Now the research allows
for it to really get
a deep understanding
of whatever the heck
it is that it's trying
to do. So let's just
look, let's look at the
executive summary and
see what it's actually
done because I was
busy blabbing here while
it went. All right.
So this is basically
the executive summary.
It's a model content.
It actually made model
contacts correct.
It always dreams up
other acronyms for MCP.
All right. It's
still running.
All right. So
back. Come on. All
right. So it's
creating a worker
OAuth, MCP agent,
MCA adapter,
WebSocket. So this
will build, again,
whatever crazy things
I want it to build.
And you can see that
it's got all the
detail. So later,
when it's going to
implement all these
different steps,
you can see
that it's going
to do the
initial queries.
It's going to do
all these things.
This will be
how the system
understands what
it needs to build.
So here's the plan.
So most likely
what I'm going
to do is I'm going to...
No, I want this one.
This one I want to show.
So the plan that you
showed, that phases
plan, I'm presuming you
had already asked it
to do in your NPX,
basically, init function.
When you define the
mode definition in the
orchestrator mode,
you'd already specified
there, right? So it's
out of the box kind of.
Exactly.
So what I, yeah,
exactly. So
what I did here
in, if you go back
to the prompts
for a moment,
you can see the
logic is here.
This is the core logic.
Now, you can see
that I defined the
structure and it's
following that research
structure. And I made
this really deep.
The whole point was
to do deep research.
Maybe what I should do
is shallow research,
right? Give me enough
for an MVP or something.
But in this case, I
wanted to show you
that I could basically
recreate some of the
functionality found with
Google deep research
or open AI research,
but take it a step
further and actually
implement it, you know,
actually implement it.
So where deep research
will tell you how
to build something,
it won't actually build
it. This will research
it and build it, which
is, which is cool
and potentially
even optimize,
test it, secure
it and deploy it.
Like if I want to go
back here and if I
chose AWS, I think
there is an AWS, this
is the site, this,
this, this is a better
site here let's go
to let's go to this
one so this is an
easier way to see all
the stuff they have
and there's you there's
hundreds of other
mcps you can choose
here but um they've
got a nice little site
that organizes it
better so we can see
here we got you know
ai and collaboration
these are some of the
tools they have we
you know there's devops
tools and then or
we can just go to
the mcp servers that
exist there's like it's
the highest thing in
the world right now
so i I thought there
was an AWS one, but
maybe I was mistaken.
There is an AWS MCP, I
guess they don't have it.
Is there a GitHub?
Yeah, they have a GitHub.
So yeah,
these are the ones that
they have, I guess.
Let's see what they
have, data analytics,
they have people labs,
fireflies is cool, they
got that integrated.
whatever
Microsoft Clarity
is, Google BigQuery.
So yeah,
lots of stuff.
Let me take a pause
for a moment. This
thing's been running
for 45 minutes.
You can see it just runs,
right? It just
goes and goes.
Now, once this is
complete, and this is
probably my demo for
tomorrow or something
that I'm going do
on the AI hacker
space. And, you know,
basically I want to
build something new.
So in this case,
I'm going to, I want
to show maybe how to
build and deploy
your own, you know,
custom MCPs, you know,
maybe you want to
want to do an AWS one
or whatever it is.
This is exactly how,
how you do that. So
this is just a crazy
amount of detail.
Once this is done, I'll
point it, I'll point
it at the implementation
plan in the Spark
Orchestrator. And then
the Spark Orchestrator
will then take this
document and all the
research and then go
build it iteratively.
Given how much,
how deep it is, I
would guess it would
take two or three
hours, but keep in
mind, I had this
running for several
hours of 12 hours
the other day and
that cost me $70.
So two or three
hours would probably
be about 20 bucks.
I would guess
it, this isn't the
cheapest approach. And
I like the analogy of
like, if using Klein
is like a Fiat, this
is like a Ferrari,
right? This, this is
going to go into as
much depth as it
possibly can and, and,
and organize and so on
until it, until it's
done. What it hasn't
actually done here
is done a kind of
like testing plan and
that's where spark will
take it and kind of
run with it so this
would be like how to
set up your initial
framework to build
whatever crazy thing
it is that you want to
build the other
interesting thing i noticed
and i don't know if
this is i should be
saying this or not
but this can do
polymorphic versions of
other people's patents
so you can point
this at a patent
database like google's
patent database
for example and
basically say build
me a polymorphic
version of a patent
that doesn't infringe
on that patent
so someone else's
implementation or you can
point it at some you
know research report
from a university or
whatever and say build
me that and it'll go
and it'll look at it
it'll figure it out
it'll use perplexity and
fire crawl and aws
and whatever it is it
needs to do to build
whatever and it'll just
build it from soup to
nuts until it's done.
Is there any reason
why you're not
mentioning GPT-4L
search preview?
You're talking the
GPT, sorry, which
one? Is there any
reason why you're
not suggesting GPT
-4L search preview,
the web accessing
model from OpenAI?
That was my demo
a few weeks ago.
It's great. I like
it. It's easy.
Perplexity was just easy.
All right. it's
done. It finished.
So now I've created a
comprehensive research
plan. And so, sorry,
to your, just to answer
your question
quick, you could use
perplexity, use fire
crawl, you can use the, uh,
open AI, you know,
web crawler. They all
kind of do the same
thing at this point. Um,
it really doesn't matter.
I just happened to
have my perplexity one
up and running this
morning. So it was
easy. Um, but it really
makes no difference. So
now I create that. So
now that I have this,
it created 53 files.
I'm going to, I'm
not going to publish
this just yet because
I think I have to
check for any environmental
variables, but
I will publish this
later. What I'm going
to do is I'll create
a branch for you
guys. And then every
week we do this, it'll
just be that week's
branch or something.
Okay. So last
part, how do you
take 53 files that
it's created and
create an actual
implementation.
So now I'm just
going to go back
here. I'm going
to show you how to
create a long
running process with
it. So I'm going
to close this.
All right. And now
I'm going to switch
from deep research mode
and I'm going to go
to, and by the way,
the guys at Roo have
implemented their own
orchestrator, which
is basically they
just took what I did
with this Spark
orchestrator and called
it orchestrator. Kudos
to them, I guess.
But I'm going to
stick with mine.
We're going to go here
to Spark Orchestrator.
And we're going to
build this thing
that they just told
us to build. So
this is the part
where we could be
simple or we could
be complicated.
I'm going to go
middle of the road.
phased implementation,
build each of the,
I guess it's each of
the phases, I guess,
at what the heck was
that called? The cloud
player implementation
plan using a modular
structure. It's kind
of obvious structure.
Don't create any
more documentation.
It will if you
tell it to. It
loves to create
documentation.
Don't create any
more documentation.
Just implement
each file one at a
time. test and fix
before moving on
to the next feature
or function.
Then I'm going to
say, use subtasks
for each step with
new underscore task.
continue until and
this is the part
that's important
because remember this
is the core guidance
right continue
until complete and
no and no errors
all right so i get
orchestrate i'm gonna i
get thinking mode now
this isn't the most
complicated app in
the world so i'm gonna
i'm gonna use thinking
and let's let it go.
Now, this is kind of
like starting a boat
motor. Sometimes it
takes a few poles to get
the thing going. So
we want to watch it
for a minute and make
sure that one, it
properly creates the new
subtasks. If it decides
to go and do a sort
of second, say the
subtasks was created,
that means it's working.
Notice the bottom,
it goes and says
autocoder and switch to
Sonnet 3.7. this means
that I started the
boat in the first pull.
Doesn't always happen.
Different models will
perform differently
as well. So if we
had saw it not going
to auto-coder mode
or going to like
specification writer
or something, then we
probably would have
wanted to stop it and say,
don't do this or that
or the other thing.
But in this case,
it looks like it's
actually figured it
out on the first try.
Now, the other
interesting
thing to see
here is the task.
So we can kind
of take a look
at what tasks it's doing.
So it's creating
a package for the
necessary dependencies,
setting up the
TypeScript configuration,
writing a Wrangler
CIL. Yeah, it looks
like it's correct.
So I'm going to
let that continue.
Now, I'm just going
to let this, I
don't have enough
time today to let it
run. Maybe I'll
let this run in the
background when I go
on to my next call,
but basically this
will run until done
and we just let it
let it watch now
again I we could take
this a step further
and I'm thinking of
maybe updating the spark
to actually incorporate
perplexity but the
problem with with that
is the spark was meant
to be sort of generic
enough to let people
take it and run with
it and modify it so
I'm worried if i start
making it too specific
to like certain mcps
or certain language
models or technologies
then it'll be it'll
become too narrow so
maybe i might just do
like flavors of spark
that are particular for
different problems or
verticals or something
i don't know so one
that mentioned of
making a generic right
i also noticed maybe
this was there i hadn't
noticed but cursor
has also introduced the
custom modes option.
So currently, I think
Spark works only through
rule code, right?
It can be ported across
to like the windsurf
of the world and the
cursors of the world.
Yeah, the one thing
I haven't done,
what I've struggled
with Klein, and
you can use my
Klein rules, I think
I've created some
Klein rules as
well, or Klein
and Kursher rules.
They don't have the
the level of automation
that you're seeing
right here and
specifically it's this
let me show you show
you guys you're
going to want to take
a screenshot of this
by the way this is
the part that this
is the magic right
here or where is it
right here oops until
klein and cursor
have the ability to
explicit they do okay
klein does all that
i haven't been able
to get client to run
autonomously for
extended periods and it
doesn't I don't think
I see I think all they
have is the ability
to switch modes not
subtasks unless they
had unless they added it
well so subtasks is
something that I actually
use prompt engineering
to work with so
I think maybe I'm maybe
cheating it a little
bit do you know what
I mean like I'm I'm
I'm doing that but I'm
using more advanced
prompt engineering
for it rather than
relying on the tool itself
or some feature within
the tool the client
tool does that make
sense yeah yeah and
so when I looked at it
it was basically
switching modes which so
like has only plan and
act modes as far as
I understand unless
I'm mistaken uh the way
I use it it's only
plan and act and I can
I like that because
I'm a bit OCD and I
don't want it to actually
start writing a bunch
of code that I can't
afford it to write
so I do act as
the human in the
loop and turn
it on to plan
mode when it asks
but I can also
type to it you know
use a natural language
to say I approve your
request to switch to
plan mode or rather
from plan to act mode
and it'll switch
automatically but otherwise
everything you
have there and most
operations on the file
system I have it doing
that automatically so
the only thing that
really requires me to
step in is when it needs
to perform a delete
operation which i've
specified individually
that's one thing that
i isolated um and
you have to do that
yeah you you don't you
didn't include what i
call i include rm in
mine yeah i know you
do yeah i i included
i i p kill i i didn't
include kill i maybe
i should i the kill
those aren't those aren't
bad those are a bit
i would use those
before i used rm i mean
well the reason i i'm
comfortable with rm
is because each one
of these that you're
looking at is its own
code space so who cares
yeah yeah of course
you've got it isolated
that way and that
makes it plenty safe
yeah that's understandable
for sure yeah the
other thing that the
other so for those
that are using cursor
i did build something
specifically for cursor
that that basically
gives you a lot of
the same functionality
Where the heck did I
put that? NPM packages,
Spark 2.
Spark 2 is kind of
a cool library that
I built. The Spark
2 library basically
exposes almost all
the same functionality
that's now been
built in the subtask
orientation. But it
uses the E2B environment
to basically create
sort of isolated
subtask and code
interpreters. So basically
what this does,
rather than running
all the sort of
subtasks locally, it
runs them remotely
and then feeds back
into the system,
which then Cursor can
sort of orchestrate.
So in that scenario,
Cursor becomes an
orchestrator of a
secondary sort of
agentic coding library.
I haven't really
promoted this too much,
but this is what,
if anyone's using
Cursor, this is how
you're going to do it.
And I've got a new
version too that
takes this even
further. I haven't
pushed that out
publicly. I think you
can probably find
one of my branches.
Is it called
Spark 2.0 just
because it's
for a cursor?
No, it's because I
built this before the
Rue guys came out
with their subtasks.
So I built this last
month. And then when
they came out, I just
ported it over. But
I did Spark last
year. so my original
spark project was uh
what the heck where
the heck is that i
guess it's punk spark
so this this was the
original so this this
does everything you
just saw and but it did
it from the cli what took
place in the security
scanner repo that is
very similar to spark
um but is called
something else so the
security scanner that
you developed you know
i'm talking about yeah
yeah the yeah if you
go if you look in there
that's what i started
with you you had
created this distributed
um development model
it's the security scanner
yeah um is that it
there i've built a lot
of stuff like it's
hard for me to keep up
with all right so uh so
if you look at the read
yeah the read me uh
it it describes the
way uh down maybe yeah
here yeah so was this
before even the spark
stuff or no no this is
i've been using sparks
since since last june
so that's what i
thought so how did this
evolve what what became
of this way because
this is what i've actually
been kind of running
with so so everything
you see is uh you
guys are sort of watching
my learning in real
time right so of
course yeah we all are
right yep yes so when
you go to my the roof net
here and you see like
a billion freaking
projects you know i
didn't build this i didn't
build this for any
reason like this stuff
is not built for any
reason other than just
for me to figure out
how to do stuff so if
you look closely you'll
notice that there's
kind of an evolution of
how i'm building things
autonomously right
okay yeah i see yes so
for example the dspy
ts library you know is
you'll see that in
this scenario i i also
in this this is a few
months old at this point
three months so you
can see that a few
months ago i started
adopting this kind of
phased approach and i
remember i remember yeah
it turns out the trick
was it was combination
of test-driven
development iteratively
leaning back on itself
and phase and narrowly
defined phases once i
determined that i could
create i could get
really narrow phases and
have each phase
iteratively test itself i
suddenly was able to
build anything at any
level of complexity
okay okay and this like
this this is a perfect
example this is like a
a fairly complex
implementation This is like
basically DSPY
implemented in TypeScript.
Yeah, you've shown
this, talked about
it before. I've looked
at that code. So
if I'm starting out
right now as I am,
I went to Roof
-Dev to look at
the Create Spark
code there.
Is that correct?
That's the most current,
I guess you'd say, right?
Yeah, so Roof-Dev is
basically my initial
starting point for
generating project that
I'm doing. now because
i'm lazy i create
the mpx because i
didn't feel like cloning
every time i started
so i just create the
mpx create spark and
that allows me to
basically bootstrap
my environment and and
there's a few easter
eggs in there that i use
to sort of you know
customize it to my
particular needs but
basically before this
was all python so if
you go back in time
look the history
you'll see how my my my
environment has evolved
over the last year okay
but yeah this so this
this is basically
how i built and then
rube uh a quick question
when you are are you
on a regular basis
now uh spotting um
vsc or ide instances
for each mode for each
excuse me for each
module or microservice,
like breaking into
10 parts and doing
them at the same time?
I'm not sure if
I published that.
What was the question?
So yeah, so this
is how I'm doing
it. I was thinking
of actually
integrating this
into my CreateSpark.
What this does,
I'm using that
too now. That's
a beautiful
thing. I love it.
Yeah, I haven't really
promoted this because
it's crazy complicated
and I get a lot
of hate for things that
are too complicated.
So I posted a couple
of stuff about it.
Yeah.
So this creates
multiple VS Code Docker
instances, both
locally and remotely,
and then interacts
with it as a swarm.
So all the stuff you're
seeing here, I can
create like dozens
and dozens of VS Code
instances. And what's
cool is you can
actually log into each
one of those VS Code
instances through a
web-based dashboard.
Yeah, I got it to
work with Windows
and WSL Docker without
Docker Desktop.
Oh, nice.
100% locally.
So however much
RAM, like if you
bought a laptop
with a lot of system
RAM, or you're
on a workstation
that's got a lot
of system RAM,
and you want to
take advantage of
that, you don't have
to do it remotely.
There's actually,
the reason I did
it isn't for RAM,
it was for GPU.
Or that too, yeah.
Yeah, so what I can
do with this is I can
spawn VS Code instances
that have GPUs. where
there's gpus on the
edge yeah yeah and then
then i then i pair and
then i can go parallel
paralyzation paralyze
i don't know whatever
concurrent um running
tasks and then i
can hyper optimize my
um my language models or
whatever i'm doing
using the gpu which
basically cuts the dev
time down by orders of
magnitude and i was using
uh fly.io gpus which
are super cheap and
i can spin up in like
seconds do you know if
they're cheaper than
run pod are you familiar
with run pod yeah
same thing same okay
yeah they're the same
they all they all and
i think railway also
has them versell i think
is getting into the
game they all kind of
work the same i i just
i was just familiar
with fly yeah this thing
is awesome it's just
when i was looking at
implementing it i was
like okay you really
have to take a that 50
000 or whatever foot
view at your project
structure and if you're
a solo developer it's
it is a lot like you
described more complicated
to try and implement
something like this
it seems like you
know freedom and magic
when you get it but
then I'm like okay this
is a lot of effort to
actually try and put
to use as a single
person like you know what
I mean you really have
your branching strategy
you know like how
it's writing code and
so you don't step all
over yourself like
you would in a real
software development
team essentially yes and
this is i think as far
as far as my state of
the art goes this is
it this is about sure
this is as far as i
can push the boundaries
with current tech and
it's even pushing the
boundaries beyond i
think where i can even
grok it but you can see
here that you know here
you know it can do
the analysis so i can
i can yep yeah i've been
using and stuff yeah
you can do anything
and it works and it
works great too it does
it did look like a bomb
had went off in the
repo in this in the
directory of the repo
but uh after i tested it
out and everything
and uh did made some
modification it worked
great yeah it does yeah
right out of the box
too yeah the only the
one issue i have and
maybe someone else on
this call can help me
figure out the problem
the mpx yeah i i can't
get the mpx to work
to use the or i can't
get the mcp in ru to
see the mpx i have to
run it using node slash
the command and i don't
understand why the
mpx would be any different
than running node
slash you know the
location i i ran into
that exact same issue
and it's it's pathing
if you should be able
to give it the path to
mpx and it should be
able to work but when
i actually asked the
the model uh for more
information about that
issue it said although
npx is popular using node
is the best practices
so yeah i want it go
ahead sorry i want
to work with npx because
i think that'd be
super easy but it does
but you got to give
it the path you should
be able to and just
give it the path yeah i
i went when i gave the
path it works so So
without the path, I
just can't get to work.
But if you are going
to use it, where's my
MCPJ? It's because your
environment that you're
running in doesn't
have the binary available
in its path. And
you can check that when
you're running a VS
Code instance in the
terminal. If you hover
your mouse over the
lower right where the
terminal's launched,
it'll tell you what
environment variables
are actually available in
the path and everything.
It's all in there.
Yeah. Oh, and by
the way, you can
integrate this
directly into your code
base if you're
creating an agent or
whatever. So I made
an SDK as well.
Yeah.
So, yeah, I think I
need, like, a group of
us to get together and
sort of hack on this
together. It's like I
know it can do crazy,
complicated, powerful
things, but I'm not
even sure where to
start how to like
articulate in a way
that people other than
you and I maybe could
even understand.
Yeah, I mean, the best
way I could describe
it is like, you know,
you really do have a
team of software
developers. So you need to
have a project that is
already or is ready to
be broken up, you
know, and branched out.
Maybe you've already got
issues. Like it would
be great if there's a
large enough project
that we could actually
apply it to, to test
it out. You know,
one that's already in
place like that um i
could probably come up
with something i just
haven't got to it got to
that point with it
yet actually you know
what i was thinking i've
got so much **** that
i've put together and
and i mean that in
the nicest way possible
um that maybe what i
could do is like go back
in time a little bit
and find something
that i've already built
but re re-imagine it
like this onyx agent
for example it's a super
cool idea it's like
a embedded local uh you
know a language model
and AI models, you
know, stuff like that.
Maybe, maybe it uses
that format. Yep. I'm
familiar. Yeah. Maybe
add like some kind
of like embedded agent
system. I don't know
that that'd be
again, half the stuff
doesn't have like a,
any practical uses this.
So just basically
ask it the MCP server
to spin up a VS code
instance, pointed at
that repo and, and,
and ask it to try and
do some first and
analyze analyze it and
then do some development
on it. Yeah. Yeah.
Like this, this is
probably a cool idea.
This was like real
time, you know,
in flight AI. So I
could, I could operate
within the structure
of the stream
itself using, this
is all created rust.
so uh i don't even
know like so basically
think of like think
of like a real
-time stream
processing let's say i
have a million users
all at once using
my app i could do
you know real-time
introspection of the
stream and interact with
the stream itself so
let's say i was doing
like real-time stock
trading or information
analysis iot whatever
this this would where
a lot of the data
needs to be sort of not
in flight this will allow
you to operate while
it's you know transacting
yeah nvidia had
a solution for analyzing
log information for
cyber security incidents
so to find um uh
what do you call it
um like personally
identifiable information
like social security
numbers and things like
that within uh network
traffic logs but the
information had to be
converted to a not just
a json in particular
but json file or um no
is it json line json
l uh so i i get around
you know what i'm
talking about yeah i i
get around the json l
requirement i don't
need that i i can i can
do real-time adaptive
analysis on any data
stream no it can be
completely unstructured
and because it's rust
i've got sub millisecond
uh sub second millisecond
response time so
uh yeah if you're into
rust this is uh this
is how you know i i
i how i built it but
yeah it's all all rust
stuff but i did i just
wanted to play around
rust that day i guess
so this is still
building by the way
let's just let's
see how much it's
built you see that
it's built we're
up to 67 files
you can see the
structure it's
building the resources
right has it tested
anything do you see
evidence of it
testing along the way
no it's still building
the structure okay
so now it's you can
see that's moving
on to the resources
section so these are
subtasks so with the
way spark works is
it builds out the the
scaffolding first.
And well, if you
start from scratch,
it would build up
the pseudo code
first, but I told it
to skip the pseudo
code when the
original instruction.
And then what it does
is it goes and then
builds out all the
files and structures.
Once all the core
functionality has
been built based
on the research,
it'll then build the
test frame and then
it'll do each test
one at a time.
But it can't
test until the
scaffolding is
done, right?
Otherwise you'll
just get errors.
so now it's you
know it's creating
document tree will
do a little search i
don't know what the
heck is building
balance i wasn't paying
that close attention
but uh it's it's
building something
no i asked basically
because i have always
been consistently
stuck in the unit test
part because it keeps
going on and i think
what i'm missing from
what you're showing
today is that whole
perplexity research that
you did first because
i generally been vive
oh no no no that no
no that that uh that
um test part could could
last hours potentially
days so you're you're
basically expecting
something to to
result more quickly
than possible and i
actually did a linkedin
post a couple hours
ago on this very topic
some things just take
time to to finish now
the the the real
question is, are you
willing to wait six days
for the application to
finish and spend
several hundred dollars
in the process? Now,
if the answer is no,
then you're probably
going to want to create
a more iterative,
smaller structure to
what you're building.
Now, if you don't mind
it just running and you
trust that eventually
it'll finish, it will
eventually finish.
Now, have you ever
waited 12 hours or
waited three days for a
project to finish? And
if the answer is no,
So then that mostly
has to do with your
confidence in the system
being able to do what
you told it to do.
From one instance, it
did last overnight.
It was keeping on
thinking. But where
I am, I am more
focused on the persona
of a product
manager or a project
manager, a program
manager. So the intent
being the outcome
means you got an idea,
you got a validated idea,
say, in 24 hours
with a view. So not
necessarily a full-blown
product, but a VP or a
point-of-view app that
is fully tested and
you're going to
demonstrate the breadth
and spread of the
whole thing. So that is
kind of the foundation,
may I say, the spark
foundational level
that I'm saying is that
how do we, what is
the most optimal path
for someone to take along
through that journey?
You want to break
it up into pieces.
So one of the
things I did here
is I said to do
all the phases.
What you probably
want to do is tell it
to do just one phase,
then stop, review
the phase, make sure
it's exactly what
you want and then
create a new message,
thread, orchestrator,
whatever the
heck we call it
and then get it
to the next phase
and then stop.
What I'm doing
right now in this
is I told to do
all the phases.
When I get working into
more complicated or
technical solutions
and having the agent
assist writing code,
I'll actually go all the
way down to individual
functions so just
like he's describing
but i'll actually break
it all the way down into
individual functions
or a couple of
functions yeah that's
that's a good way to do
it actually and sometimes
you have to yeah
and when you look at
what what this is building
it's it's done this
it's done the same
thing right these are
functions those are
functions correct yeah
right so that's what
it's looking for and it
and if you don't know
that though about
software development
you will run into some
difficulties sure well
what i just gave you
guys today you don't
need to know that so
i've i've given it the
structure so a novice
vibe coder who has no
idea about modular or
you know you know the
way that it should be
limited in terms of
size scope you know
length of characters
those sorts of things i've
told this i've prompted
the system to do
that so if you go to
my my my rules folder
that's what this is
doing this is this is
giving it all the
guidelines for how it needs
to operate and structure
it right is the
rules folder only in
that repo that you're
in right now the vibe
one a vibe cast one or
or is it another repos
it's the when you run
the the npx okay it
creates all right yeah
yeah it does that
okay i'll i'll do that
when when I ran and
it's missing commander.
So I actually have to
run in npm install first.
Command, oh,
that other...
Yeah, the
commander module.
Yeah, I haven't really
used that one. It
was a little bit
outside of the way I
do it. I should
probably investigate it.
I kind of, you
know, again, I just
kind of, you guys
are getting what I
do, like how I
build my stuff, so.
Do you mean you
don't really
use the commander module?
yeah well i the yeah
i don't really use the
commander module at
all got it i follow you
okay yeah understood
um i i probably could
um there there there's
also a command option
within um the Roo system
which is pretty cool
that allows you to
sort of bypass using
mcps if you if you
prefer a more cli driven
approach i've actually
sort of do you mean like
actually call in
command prompt yeah yeah
you could do that
from within and i was
showing you that i think
you can do that from
within like an mcp
server is so simple like
you can i was showing
you how you can just
literally throw in uh
the vs code cli command
which is code and then
a period so code space
dot in an mcp configuration
and it'll launch
a vs code instance
you can put in command
The issue with
that is it doesn't
have the correct
response format.
So to get around the
response issue, if you
use the command group
within Rue code, it
bypasses the need to
use an MCP at all,
which will solve that
response issue. And then
it just takes the
response from the...
What's the response
issue? When you don't use
the Studio or SSE or
HTTP stream response,
it doesn't see the
response correctly.
right so it solves that
it solves that issue
otherwise you you're
going to have to
think i know what you're
talking about yeah
yeah otherwise you have
to format the output
to use this the correct
studio forms yeah
anyway i don't even
have to do that yeah i
i haven't had much luck
with that myself but
um i'm interested to
see what you did to
dig around that maybe
i'm just doing it wrong
who knows um or i
could be mistaken yeah
yeah we're just we're
kind of making it up
as we go so who knows
um yeah it's pretty
cutting edge all right
so looks like this
finished uh so now
i'm almost out of time
guys but it's now it's
creating a new sub now
it's setting up the
tests yeah here we go
this is what i wanted
to see now it's building
the tests so it's
built all the core
scaffolding and you so
you see here all the
core scaffolding for
tools and resources are
now built now what
it's going to do is
going to build all the
tests and now this part
this could run probably
for another couple
hours to be honest
it could take a while
but it's going to build
it's going to review
it's going to build
all the tests so you
see how it refers to the
original implementation
so that this is in
essence the memory
right this tells it what
it needs to build and
where the files are
and tells it you know
how it needs to operate
And then once it does
that, it's going to
go and it's going to
look at the core files
and understand what it's
going to do, the MCP
and all that sort of
stuff. And once it's
done that, it'll go and
build the test. Once
all the tests pass
green, now it might take
another 20, 30 minutes
for the test that'll
be built. But once they
all pass, this will
be done. It'll all
work. I'll be good to
publish it. And I would
have built a comprehensive
CloudFlare MCP
implementation that I
can use to build, you
know, and deploy my own
custom MCPs, which will
probably be next week's
live coding demo.
I just double checked
and you're right,
Ruv, on each one of
them, I am setting
transport type
standard input output.
Yeah, share
that. It'll be
interesting to see
what you're doing.
Okay, yeah, I'll
copy one here.
one that doesn't have
it one does doesn't
have my key in it yeah
you know join the club
if i i i i'm probably
the guy that's got
the uh the most open
ai hacks ever but it's
i think it's part of
the you know one of the
things i added to the
community when yeah
exactly never hard
code envs is like in
almost every single one
of the uh rules folders
you'll see that and
that's because I've
been burned a million
times, but whatever.
That's part of being
early, I guess.
All right, so now
it's looked at,
now it's creating
the first test file.
So you're seeing
the utils tests.
We're watching, I haven't
touched this in
over an hour.
It's, you're
watching real-time
automated coding
at its best.
This is highly
structured.
It, this ain't
vibe spaghetti
code. this is
highly structured.
This is production
quality.
And eventually,
the Spark system will
even run security
tests on it before
it finishes.
So one of the final
stages is hardening.
So it'll completely
run and check for
any kind of
vulnerabilities, SQL
injections, whatever.
It'll do all those
things for you. So
when you're done,
am I 100% confident
that the thing is not
hackable obviously
not but has it been
thoroughly vetted for
you know most obvious uh
you know exploits well
more than than if you
didn't look at it at
all yeah and that's
something you could i
actually add that in
as a cyber security
professional that that
is a step that i don't
see everybody adding
in but it is one that
i add in and i can
verify it does actually
help and it does
work you can ask the
model to improve the
security posture
because maybe the first
suggestion isn't the best
and that's often case
often the case too yeah
and you can you can
update the security
rules right here and
if you go to this the
security review and
you can see you know
i i've included pretty
broad it basically
allows it to sort of
figure out what it should
secure without it's
you know without
explicitly saying but as
you can see here these
are the security audit
workflows and things
like that this these
are the most important
there's obviously
other ones but i think
i'm out of time i
gotta prep for my next
call uh hopefully this
was helpful for you
guys um yeah thanks
thanks rob um yeah shout
out to the Roo guys
for creating a great
product i i i'm very
much enjoying using the
tool so it's they're
definitely creating
some good good stuff
Again, if you guys
are looking to
help support the
cause, this is
where I'm shamelessly
plugging us.
The Agentics
Foundation, there's a
group of us that are
creating a kind of
non-profit that will
help support the
sorts of stuff
you're seeing today.
Keep some of the
lights running. If
anyone's in Toronto,
we're doing a live
session, I guess Agentic
Meetup next Tuesday
at 6.30 at the Tribal
Scale offices in
Toronto. ping me,
I'll get you the link.
Otherwise, there's
interest for
doing meetups all
over the world.
We've got an ambassador
page on the Agentex.
I think it's agentex
.org slash ambassador.
If you want to host
one of these and kind
of do what I'm doing
today, feel free and
we can get you some
support. We're also
looking for corporate
sponsors. So if you know
a big name somewhere
that might be interested
in slapping their
logo on this and
helping us keep the
lights on. You know, we're
open to any kind of
corporate sponsorship.
We've got a doc,
right, Rob, now that
we will – you've
got your logo on
it. I don't know,
something like that.
Yeah, the
companies have done
a really good
work on putting
together the
sponsorship deck,
the events kick
off, the ambassadors
program, for the
chapter management.
There's a bunch of really
good stuff there coming.
Yeah.
all right thanks
everyone till tomorrow
we're doing the ai
hacker space if you have
something you want
to show or show off
uh reach out to
spots roof yeah okay
otherwise i'm sure
we'll we can we can
improvise and i by the
way i'm broadcasting
this to linkedin so
there should be a uh
recording there and
we'll probably get a
copy of this on the
website somewhere too
all right thanks
everyone thank
you thank you
next time okay bye