it's april 25th which
means it's our one
year anniversary or is
that birthday i don't
know i'm not sure what
which was the right
one to describe it
but it's been a year
we've done i think
something like 52 uh
episodes of the ai hacker
space live we've we've
had all kinds of
interesting opportunities
i think one point
over the last year
someone said that we
were uh the fastest
growing ai hacker
collective according to some
five eyes group so
we've had an exciting
year of ups and downs
you know and so yeah
here we are one year
in your birthday roof
fantastic you know I
just want to take a
moment I mean you're
going to hear it from all
directions no doubt
but first of all you
know a huge thank you
to everybody in the
community across all
channels like everybody
who's here every week
who comes to the Thursday
coding events and the
Hacker League that
you run, Roof, and
everybody who does demos,
all the long-tail
audience that are
watching all the
recordings after the fact,
you know, by the
tens of thousands,
and everybody
in LinkedIn,
Discord, WhatsApp,
the works.
It's been an incredible
year. So many
neat things, new
companies being formed,
great new projects,
collaborations, joint
ventures, all kinds
of cool stuff. So a
huge thank you to the
entirety of the community
and everything that
all you folks do, but
also specifically,
you know,
without embarrassing
your roof, I want to
express on everybody's
behalf our great
gratitude for the work
that you've put in
over the last year.
It's a pretty historic
year in terms of
technology and the
economy and what's
formulating and come to
pass. And over the
last year, every week
you put in an enormous
amount of effort in
order to integrate
and put on display
the implications of
new tools as they drop
in real time. And
that's given so many of
us an opportunity to
really have a front
row seat as the
technology has evolved.
So on behalf of
everybody, I would like
to say thank you
for the incredible
work. And 52
consecutive weeks of the
one-hour event is a
spectacular thing.
And this one is going
to be spectacular
as well. I'm really
excited about it.
Congratulations.
I appreciate it. And
thanks for the kind
words. And this is fun.
This is, it's like my
highlight of the week,
right? It's a really
nice way to end the
week where you get
to show all the crazy
things that are being
developed by the
community and our partners
and whatever. It's just
mixed, it's a great
vibe to end the week
with, just to say
it really is. Sail into
the weekend, right?
Yeah, exactly.
And a lot of
this is like, we
work so closely
with AI and
AI, we love AI.
obviously, but the
human element is
just as important
or more important
than the sort of
artificial, you
know, element that
you get with AI.
And this allows the
sort of connection to
real people, real things,
real opportunities.
And it's great. It's
fun. And we get to share.
So let's jump in. We've
got a great lineup today.
We do.
We've got our beloved
craftsman has got some
tools going to show
us. john petty from
enable is here and uh
and to uh really to
help celebrate the one
year uh mark we've got
um anise from uh
arguably one of the most
popular open source
agentic engineering tools
on the planet right
now ruko thank you
for having me yeah thank
you yeah pleased to
have you here with us
yeah we're we're as
you know big fans and
not to toot our own
horn but we i am Some
of the companies we've
discovered over the last
year have done quite
well. I think notably,
I remember reaching
out to the GPT
engineer team probably
about a year ago now
when they released their
initial client and met
the team from Stockholm,
which I think was
two guys at the time.
And now they've raised
a crazy amount of
money. They're arguably
the fastest growing
startup of all time,
zero to 20 million or
40 million or something
in annual revenue.
And hopefully our
friends at Requestee and
Ruko and a few others
will do equally well.
Makes you wonder, maybe
we should start
a startup.
But all right.
So for those that
are familiar,
we've got a format.
So generally, I'll give
you a little demo of
some of the stuff that
I've been working on
this week. Then we'll
jump into, you know,
Hannes and the work he's
doing with Rue Code.
But there's a good
topic because I actually
just came out with
a Rue Code component
that will probably
align well with what
he'll show here in a
minute. So hopefully I
don't steal your thunder
too much. But here,
I'm going to jump in
and just show you some
of the stuff. So as
you guys are familiar,
over the last year or
so, I've been working
on this concept of
Spark, which is a
methodology that basically
guides the AI in a
kind of recursive loop,
right? It provides a
mechanism to understand
the specification,
the pseudo architecture,
and then implement
that and then sort of
refine that through
a kind of repetitive,
recursive test
-driven development
process. Now, as a big
fan of the work that
RuCode is doing, I've
set up a structure
that allows you to
implement that not
through my CLI, like the
Spark infrastructure
you might be familiar
with, but using RuCode
to actually create
that kind of recursion.
So last night
I launched this
create Spark approach,
which will essentially
create all the different
components you need
to let this run.
So I got a little bit
caught up in this,
to be honest, and
I probably created
more stuff than I
needed because, you
know, why not? But
basically what this
is going to do is
it's going to create
all the various parts
that allow you to
sort of hyper-optimize
your environment
for the sort of
autonomous operation
of the root code system,
which does a really
good job of sort of
creating a kind of
boomerang of sorts. So
in that case, if you
want to run it, all
you need to do is run
this command MPX spark
init. it. Now the spark
in a command essentially
will then generate
all the files that
you then customize.
It includes all the
recursion, the spark
methodology. It also
includes all the different
modes. The most
important mode probably
being the orchestrator
mode that basically
allows the system to
sort of spawn subtasks
and have those tasks
run. It's optimized for
costs because I'm cheap.
So I've spent a lot
of time trying to make
the system use less
context so you're not
spending more money
than you have to, but
operate continuously.
Now I love analogies.
So just so if
you guys are just
so you're aware, if
the traditional
approach is a Fiat,
this would be a
Ferrari. And that means
it's going to cost
you a lot more. It's
going to use super
premium gas. So if
you're looking to
cheap out, even though
I've done my best to
try to make it cheap,
it's still not the
cheapest approach.
Using requesty in terms
like that or tools
like that will help,
but it's not going
to be the cheapest
approach. But that said,
it's definitely the
most automated. It's
how I'm doing a lot
of my development now.
And a couple of
things I've also
added, just as I
threw in a kind of
nice little freebie,
I've included a
default Supabase
MCP implementation.
I did this for two
reasons. One, most people
have no idea how to
set up a Supabase
or even an MCP for
that matter. So what I
did is I set up a mode
that basically allows
you to use the Supabase
MCP, but it also
allows you to basically
use other MCPs.
So there's another
MCP mode as well that
you can kind of follow.
I added an MCP wizard,
which I probably
should have a little
wizard icon or something
here. But basically
the wizard will actually
guide you through
the process of finding
and implementing
your own MCPs. You can
create your own registries
using the agentic
robots text format
we came up with a few
months ago. So if you
have a repository of
remote MCPs, you can
connect it to that.
You can use a variety
of different third-party
registries for that.
It creates the
configuration. So here's
the example of the
Supabase configuration.
And it's secure,
so you can use your
local environment
variables and other
various things. Now
the other problem
you're going to have
with MCPs, I'm going
quick here guys,
is it's not secure.
So I created a
mechanism to not only
configure the MCP workflows
and various parts,
but I also added the
ability to do security.
So here's advanced,
there's a ton of
options. I'm going
to jump in and just
show you guys, but I've
got security auditing.
So not only can it
check your MCPs, it
can make sure that
those MCPs are secure,
not stealing your
personal information,
no leakage, it warns
you about things
like that. So lots
and lots of stuff.
You can integrate it
with various other
services like AWS
and GitHub and things
like that. So lots
of options. But let's
show you what that
actually looks
like. That's enough
of me looking at it.
So we're going to go
in here. So the first
thing you're going to
do is if you want to
run it, you're in the
main folder or you can
go to a subfolder if
you want to test it.
So I'm going to test
it in a subfolder.
So I'm just going
to make a folder and
I'm just going to
call it Spark Test.
And this works in
your root folder, just
to be clear. You
don't want to create
it in a subfolder
unless you want to sort
of mess around with
it and not overwrite
what you've already
done. In this case,
I've already done
it, so I'm just going
to create it in a
subfolder. So to
activate it, all you
need to write is MPX,
create, spark,
and then init.
Now, there's other
options as well if you
want to see them.
And to see the other
options, all you need
to do is type help.
So the help will then
sort of give you an
idea of what the
different options are,
and then there's
different options for that
as well. so you can
see here that I've
got the wizard mode
then I've got configure
MCPs so if I want
to see what those
options are I'm going
to write help for that
as well and that'll
give me options for
you know adding servers
discovering MCPs
and lots of different
options for that so
my development style
is really sort of
integrating this idea of
autonomous development
along with the
ability to sort of
integrate third
parties through MCPs or
command line tools
in this case I'm just
going to, I'm just
going to activate it.
So I'm just going to
go back here and I'm
going to type spark
init. Now, if a file
already exists, it'll
warn you'll see a
warning. I don't
have any files. So it
shouldn't, the warning
shouldn't come up.
Now you see that it
created a new spark
project. I didn't give
it a name. I could have
gave it a name by
putting something like
this in here. And then
it would named it.
It's up to you depending
on how you want to
organize it. I didn't
bother in this case.
And then you'll see
here in my file explorer
that there's a spark
test folder and now
in that folder you'll
see that there's a room
modes file this room
modes file is what
basically sets up all
the custom modes in ru
and you'll see you'll
see here this little
drop down so spark
orchestrator you see mcp
specifically specification
the most important
place to start most
likely is a spark
orchestrator a couple
things to note this works
best you'll notice here
that it automatically
switched to thinking
mode it works best
with 3.7 thinking It
does work with the non
-thinking model, but
I only use the non
-thinking model for the
other modes. For example,
the code mode. So
you see here that it
should switch here in a
moment to sign at 3.7.
And just for anyone
starting out, you go in
here into your prompts,
and you have the
ability to switch
different modes. So you'll
see here that I've got
3.7 for this mode. and
if i switch to let's
say uh the let's go
to the orchestrator
you'll notice here that
i've got a 3.7 thinking
so in your settings
you can add multiple
multiple configurations
so i i switch around
depending what i'm
looking to do you know
i might i might use
gemini but for for like
set and forget site is
by far the best and and
i'm i'm using in this
case i guess i'm
using anthropic but
sometimes I'll switch
and use different models.
So for example,
in 3.7, I'm using,
I think Requesti,
which is a great
model that does
most of the work.
So the last thing you
wanna look at is how
do you actually use
it? And I went ahead
and Vibe coded something
just for today.
So how are we
doing for time?
So I'm gonna
show you quickly,
using the new API from
the guys at OpenAI,
the new image API, I
created a quick little
design creator just
to show you how that
looks. this was created
yesterday in under an
hour so this is what
you can do and i let i
literally set and forget
it kind of thing so
in this case i went i can
choose an advertisement
or logo let's call
it the ai hacker
space birth birthday
industry we'll call it ai
we can choose different
image sizes square
is probably fine
let's go next i've got
different color options
we'll go with something
vibrant we can choose
font colors i'll go
with vintage uh yeah
it's too handwritten for
the heck of it and
different styles clean
minimalist different
layouts you know i basically
it's basically a uh
an image generator
and again this shows
you what you can build
in under an hour so in
this case we'll choose
this option then we've
got different additional
options my tagline
is going to be ai
hacker space brand
description modern and
friendly which i think
contradicts with my retro
thing i just chose but
whatever so we'll go
next and then we have
different logo types
and i there's i'm you
i'm on the logo option
if i went through the
ad option there's all
kinds different ad
options as well so i'll
just choose you know
a few different random
options i'll let's
choose a typography see
what we got here oh
found an error uh it's i
shouldn't have made
the modification right
before okay i'm just
gonna i'm just gonna run
this quick i'm just
gonna go quick and just
make sure uh we're
gonna do the ai hacker
space and maybe we'll
fix the here in a sec,
but AI hackers space,
space logo, whatever.
I'm going to
create the design.
Yeah. The issue was
I added additional
UI components right
at the very end.
And, but when, when
looking at the system,
I remember, I always
output exactly what
I'm doing in the
console. This, this gives
me a sort of ability
to fix any errors and
see what's actually
happening this is actually
being sent to open
ai and see that it's
it's it's being sent
correctly and in about
30 seconds we will
see the response but
basically while that
works i'm going to jump
back and i'm going to
show you exactly what
what what what how
how that was built so
again the system uses
basic this is a really
simple one it uses
a plan structure so
you can see here that
i've got a ai generator
we we've got the
various components but
basically it just used
this plan So I created,
I gave it the OpenAI
sort of guidance.
So this basically
says, you know,
how to use the
new image library.
Then I gave it
the architecture
and see it uses
some of the,
let's render that to
see what it looks like.
It is basically
guides it.
All right, it might take
a second for it to work.
There we go. So this
is what's guiding
the development.
Then I just went
into Roo here. I'm
going to go to new
and I choose orchestrator
and basically
then I just point
this at you know
build the at what do
we call it architecture
or whatever it is
you know the AI
generator
right there and then
I just go and build
it and then I go have
lunch I come back
and we've got
this system built
it's that easy and I
can build pretty much
anything this is
obviously simple but it
there's no limit to the
amount of complexity
to what this thing
can do so again if you
guys are interested go
make sure you install
root code so go into
your your extensions
type in root code
and find it from here
that's already installed
then type in mpx create
and you've got everything
everything that
i do and i i didn't
give you any demo the
security or the mcp
stuff that'll be uh
for another day or maybe
later this afternoon
when we have time left
in the end you said
it works on everything
very complex have
you tried to uh apply
any improvements to
rue and use it on the
rue code base i did of
course of course i
did i and and i i have
a whole i called it i
I called it Roof code,
but yeah, so what I
did for that, and I
don't have that running
currently, but what
I did is I forked the
Roof code repository,
and then I modified
all the sort of
UI components to
basically, before you
guys added the
ability to do those
Roof modes, I
basically created a UI
that essentially
did the same thing.
And then once you
came out with the Roof
modes, I didn't have to
do that anymore, so I
didn't bother maintaining
it. but used exactly
the same approach cool
the i think my i'm
gonna let you jump in
and describe what you're
doing with rue and
some of the things that
i probably didn't
show but um it's it's
amazing it works well
but you know i think the
subtask components
were a huge improvement
um and yeah yeah the
boomerang was was incredible
and uh just i mean
fantastic roof to add
that mcp wizard that's
going to be very
helpful for a lot of
folks the good idea it's
the missing piece of
both klein you think you
think we should add
a custom mode that is
not um accessible from
the other modes so the
other modes don't jump
into it by accident
while they're doing
their thing but when you
go into it um you can
basically orchestrate
mcp related duties uh
installing mcps and
such uh no you you already
have it so you don't
you don't need that
and if you look at my
um my mcp mode you'll
you'll notice that that
that mode essentially
does that so when in
your custom or advanced
modes option in the
root code you have the
ability to do groups
you've got read edit
command mcp and a couple
others i think now
the key is to to limit
the amount of of
options in those groups.
So you might, the MCP
mode works best when you
have read and MCP.
You can get almost the
exact same functionality
by using command,
which then will use
the, like a CLI in place
of the MCP, which
essentially does exactly
the same thing without
having to, the headache
of having to sort of
figure out why it keeps
trying to figure out
where the list tools
option is for MCPs when,
so to get around the
list tools option, and
anyone's played with
MCPs will know the
list tools options is a
pain is a total pain
that will essentially
tell it the tools it
needs to use that'll
happen to go discover
what tools it needs yeah
if that makes any sense
no that makes sense
absolutely fantastic
why don't you take it
away highness okay so
um i guess i get my
four minutes starting
to watch um you guys
are already so familiar
with boomerang tasks
so um but it's still
the thing that i'm
choosing to talk about
boomerang tasks is
uh one of the things
that truly differentiates
us there's a whole
lot of you know we
have tweaks wonderful
um and people can say
oh well what's different
about this software
and that software
our ability to build
an orchestrator
within Roo, which you
have done, is exactly
what we wanted when
we released boomerang
tasks. We purposely
didn't include it
as a default mode
because we don't want
to tell people this
is how you have to
use boomerang mode.
That being said, we
are easing it in and
we're going to be
releasing it as a
default mode, an
orchestrator mode today.
But we want to be
very cautious to point
people at this as the
mode no this is a mode
that works it works
it's fine it's good it
doesn't do everything
for everybody we
really um and there's
the the out of the box
mentality well it's got
to work for everybody
out of the box well
our users are in in
two silos ultimately
I mean many silos but
we have the silo of
of uh people who are
newer or truly don't
want to learn how to
code possibly you know
you could call them
the straight vibe
coders and then you have
the the actual you
know the engineers the
the tinkerers the the
coders those ones uh
really really I think
they can handle that
it's a little more
complicated that they can
tweak and refine their
orchestrator and i
think they can understand
that too so we're
trying to find this
balance between an
out of the box where
people can click it and
use it and and really
that's a preview of
what it can do because
what you've made with
spark uh is a prime
example that is what
we want people to do
um to create these
types of things because
you guys test it and
play with it and and
i'll be honest, we
don't spend all day
refining boomerang tasks.
Uh, you probably spend
all day, some days
monkeying around
with this stuff,
um, refining it. And
that puts you far ahead
because we're, we're
working on, on all
the different facets,
uh, of, of what makes
through code, root
code. So, um, that's my
spiel about boomerang.
The other point, uh,
the other thing I wanted
to bring up oh and
uh we are we are going
to be we are working
on boomerang tasks uh or
boomerang orchestration
2.0 um and and i
will surely get some
input from you roof
um you know before we
as we're working
on that we have a
bit of a roadmap
but it's still um
it's still still
in the works the
other thing i wanted
to bring up or
outline is uh the
root code community
we uh as you mentioned
are an open source
project and that's
something that really
really excites us at
root code we don't we're
not trying to take
advantage of the community
to make tools so we
can profit up your
off your backs absolutely
the idea of making
money is in the picture
um but not through
charging for the things
that the community
makes the community
is making a tool
for the community and
so we're we're basically
orchestrating um uh
the building of rue
uh through the community
people often say
well i want this feature
i want this feature
and i look and my
first thought is
defensive and i'm like
there's already lots of
features like you're
just making my life
and then i look and
i go no that's a good
**** idea like that's
a really good idea and
then it the thought
is well i should bring
that to the lead dev
and it's like well
no i know what
he's doing today
and tomorrow and the next
week and this
is important but
it doesn't that's when
i shift and i go hey
well is there anyone
in the community that
can help with this
and quite often people
pull their socks up and
actually get it done
it's it's amazing that
the number of things
that uh people have
made even even uh
boomerang tasks was
actually the new task tool
was built by a community
member and that's
something that we
think is really amazing
and we don't want
to lose sight of the
community and the energy
that's around that and
we do our best to
appreciate them even even
this morning on
reddit i i uh i was a
little prickly to someone
yesterday when they
were like well you know
basically the system
task um or the system
prompt is is too fat
and and i was sort
of in their face like
well then change it
yourself and test it and
let us know what you
come up with um and
i sent them the foot
gun mode documentation
and that was rude of
me and so one of the
things that we're
willing to or i'm willing
to do especially is
go yeah no you know
what that's not the
kind of community we
want we don't want to
know it all community
and uh and and and i
own it and we try to
improve so we want to
be a community that
looks at our mistakes
in how we act and how
we develop too and
improve continuously.
Continuous development.
Oh, that was a good
idea. We rolled it
out. It did work. It
didn't work. And that
doesn't mean we want
to turn everybody into
beta testers. But if
we do roll something
out and it isn't the
best to roll out, we
are willing to take
input. And anybody can
contact me anytime.
So I think, I guess
what I want to say
is the Roo community
is amazing and I
am eternally grateful
for them. And it's
very exciting to
work on this project.
If it makes you feel
any better, I get that
a lot as well. Like,
why didn't you, you
know, I put out millions
of lines of code
and someone's like,
why didn't you, why did
you do this this way?
Or why didn't you do
that? It's like, you
know, it's, you can't
get every, you can't
make everyone happy,
right? And especially
when it's like a
benevolent approach
where you're giving your
stuff away. so you know
it's it the fact that
you're putting it
out there is is in my
book in my opinion is
amazing you're where
everyone else is trying
to create billion
dollar startups you're
you're taking the
opposite road and i i
think you're i'm also
cognizant the fact that
it's a fork someone
else's work in the first
place right it's you
know we have to give
props to the team a
client who awesome
inspired all of us so you
know shout out to
client to make this in
you know a thing in
the in the first place
and all the various
you know versions of
climb that have now
popped up so yeah they've
really done an awesome
job yeah exactly
you know you know that
uh it was actually
born on in a hack uh
hackathon eh yeah i i
think i think we we
started using klein last
summer if i'm not
mistaken yeah that's
about the time we're
early adopters around
here um if If something
new and exciting
comes out, I think
it somehow shows
up in our AI Hackerspace
weekly calls.
And some things we
adopt more broadly and
other things kind of
disappear. But Klein
and Rue and Winsurf
and a few others have
sort of stuck around.
So that's a good sign.
Yeah.
And how does...
You actually,
just to give you a little
kudos, uh i understand
uh the handle boomerang
uh was yours it
it you know and and
i don't know how long
it will last it's a
description it's sort of
a catchy thing but it
doesn't fully say what
it does um and and i
was pushing for naming
uh the mode boomerang
but when somebody picks
it up what is boomerang
uh right so the
team at rue is coming up
with a better solution
than calling oh no
no call it boomerang
it's great it's perfect
it's it it's the basis
of a feedback loop that
so when you look at
agentic systems what
makes a really good
agentic system it's it's
you know orchestration
is obviously important
and the the idea of
tasks and subtasks are
important but ultimately
it's a feedback loop
that the the feedback
loop that you find
within the structure
of a sort of test driven
development is actually
what makes autonomous
development work.
It's not the model. Like
you could use pretty
much any model, as
long as there's the
ability to say, I'm doing
a task, did it work?
If it didn't work, what
went wrong? And then
feedback to the
orchestrator or LLM to fix
that and only move to
the next step once that
task is fixed. That's
the heart of basically
any agentic system.
And by calling it a
boomerang, that's exactly
what's happening if
you're just giving a
less nerdy description
of a recursive feedback
loop what what we're
going to go for is
something that's clear
and it doesn't lose the
uh the process internally
it's it's boomerang
but the the specific
mode we're adding
isn't isn't going to be
called boomerang um
because you know we want
people to be clear if
they when we're trying
to balance the out
of the box versus the
the the dock deep diver
um you know we do want
people to be able to
pick up the software
and get some access to
it and the cool features
without having to
read a book yeah you
what you boomerang for
dummies so yeah my last
comment but just one
one last comment well
since i have you here
and i can i can give
you all my ideas what
when i saw your PR for
the sort of potential
addition of the, you
know, primary, what you're
not calling boomerang
mode. Right now, to
make the subtasks
efficiently work across
multiple non-thinking
LLMs, you have to be
explicit in how the
subtasks are created
using the new underscore
task. And I forgot what
the completion task is,
like the assigned
completion or whatever.
So make sure you include
that as part of the
actual prompt that is
being fed otherwise
you're gonna have to
be explicit for things
like gemini and lesser
capable gpt models we
are um probably going
to release it as the
one on the docs page
and then you can make a
pr and tweak it um i'm
gonna i'm gonna throw
it back at you uno
reverse because you
absolutely you've probably
played with the exact
wording that works best
for that process and
tweaking it a little
bit right now it's
working people are using
it and so we'll put
that one out there and
then we'll we'll tweak
it tomorrow for all
that yeah exactly we are
really interested in
using evals to try to
measure which works
better though that is
we're trying to apply
evals to these sort of
unique tools instead
of just can it solve a
coding problem smart no
you guys are i'm a fan
i think that you guys
are doing everything
check out open evals.
That was actually
going to be one of
my demos today, but
there's not enough
time to do everything.
Open evals is amazing.
It uses the open
telemetry approach
as well. If you're
doing any kind of deep
agentic engineering,
you have to have an
evaluation framework.
Otherwise, you're
just vibe coding,
right? So the absence
of an eval is the
absence of engineering
hmm all right
well really appreciate
it and if we have
time maybe i'll jump
in and show you guys
a bit more of the
stuff that i was
building in in there
um who else we got on
the agenda today
rob fantastic thank
you hannis um thanks
for uh john had to
step up for a second
we have Craftsman.
Craftsman, you
with us, Mr.
Dishabh? Hey,
John. Hey, guys.
Hey.
Yeah, I've found a
new interesting tool
called Agno, which
has been my personal
favorite currently
of how to convert
non-reasoning models
and reasoning models
and a bunch of
tools. It's more of a
really good version
of langchain which
i've been liking a
lot i've been playing
with it a lot and
so let me share my
screen um and the
best thing is it does
really well on this
one give me a second
i hope my screen
is visible
beautiful so
basically this library
agno is one
thing which makes
just one
interesting thing is
called reasoning
agent they have
and what i like
is basically
you can make it do
anything you want
so i just give one
very tough question
which a lot of even
4.1 fails is this
question uh let us
find the question oh
sorry one second
my bad guys
i'm trying to
find the question
okay i can't find it
but let us another
question so let us say
we have two train tracks
and one train track
has one old guy
and other track has
five kids let's say
okay chat GPT likes
me you know if I
gets which thing
would you hit first
and the thing is
display with with ASCII
art and for me who's
been creating a lot
of reasoning LLMs and
fine tuning reasoning
LLMs and I found this
libraries because
two things is I just
find you know model
to do really well in
DPO direct preference
optimization and
then I'm like okay
i can create a reasoning
model but why do
i need to create a
reasoning model because
i would like to have
a reasoning model to
do internal tools and
i found this really
interesting tool
which really does good
reasoning and it thinks
a lot and thinks really
a lot so it finds the
old man you choose
this one it finds the
justification i might
say hit hitting one
saves life this one
okay this one I think
that rice I guess okay
nice weird but this
really good tool can
convert any LLM or
straight model into a
thinking model I was
trying to get this work
with through code
because I can stand it
kind of this open
AI format open API
compatible format and
run through code I want
some interesting is this
but I broke it I was
like running it through
an API trying to
but the API doesn't
work for some reason.
But I found this
a good tool,
and I just thought
like, I wouldn't like
to share this, guys.
I just thought,
let me make this
an API tool, but it
didn't work much,
sorry guys. But yeah,
this is what I
wanted to show to it.
This is the tool,
it's called Agno,
and it's a
pretty cool tool.
Looks like a
Python library?
Yeah, it's a Python
library,
unfortunately, yes.
But it does one good
job, and that one
good job is converting
normal LLMs into
reasoning llms but
is it it's basically
an agentic library
right i mean way
to build agents or
it's just having a
reasoning loop react
loop outside in
yeah it's a that's
a react loop inside
react loop itself
which can do
internal tool
calls and it's
really well built
stable it's not
******** out of
out of a lot of
dependence errors
but i thought
it's a pretty cool
tool which does
good things.
Do you think it can
replace the land graph
or can you use it for
having more control?
I wouldn't go as far
as replacing land
graph. Land graph has
its own perks but it's
really good and one
thing is being stable.
While land graph has
strong integrations
with land chain whether
we like it or not
but the good thing
is just one good
thing is it has really
good internal React
tools and works stable
unlike Langchain.
But yeah,
I want to shout
out there to them
and this one, but
sorry guys, couldn't
get the API
running. I was just
getting a bunch of
validation errors.
You know, it's
interesting to get your
opinion. There's been
some debate this week on
the value of graphs
within sort of these
agentic systems like
LangGraph as an example
and the uh the folks
uh you know lang chain
obviously came out and
said basically you know
it it's it's a
prerequisite for any of
these complex systems
and and i think you guys
know that i'm not a
particular fan of graph
structures for for
sort of most agentic
flows i think it's
overkill it it adds you
know overhead where
none is needed for most
applications you know
and what i think what
you're describing is
doing a lot of the the
sort of you know things
that you you think
you need a graph or
without a graph if i'm
understanding what what
it's doing is it or
isn't it based on a
graph so yes you can do
graph things and stuff
uh if you want to use
but i usually just
can code it out myself
through light lm but
i think on the debate
of using graph or to not
using graph it's more
like this i believe
if you want consistent
outputs and even if
you just say like spark
right sparks like more
of a graph but you
create a graph on the
fly you just say like
finish step one step
two step three step
four you have a branch
you decide which branch
you want to go then
step five step six
step seven you don't
then you find like okay
this branch is a bad
branch you regress back
and go like this right
but when it comes
to customer user
applications where you want
more consistency and
you want to have it to
go through a predefined
workflow no matter
what i think graphs
are the way but in the
case of like in our
case everywhere like
brookline spline or
using ai tools i think it
just doesn't make sense
graph graph is the
right way it's you
can spin out your own
graphs on the fly and do
stuff so it comes down
to the question of the
use case do you want
stability do you have
a narrow use case
and you or you have
a use case which has
multiple graphs but you
always want to with an
x input you always want
to reach the x node
then graph makes sense
no matter what that
would be very true with
stock trading or you
want to can be very
true with financial to
have agent financial
tool applications right
like one with the demo
which i was intending
was to build and i
have wanted to have
and use agnor to build
a financial tool as
it's getting errors on
authorization but if i
had to build a tool like
that it is basically
go check this it's
a certain condition
yes otherwise no hit a
certain condition yes
if that this moment
has yes or no it's a
binary graph so you so
let me ask you the million
dollar question are
you are you pro graph
or against i i think
you i think you like
them if i'm not mistaken
no it's i'm saying
it's more on the use
case it's dumb to say
graph for everything
and it's dumb to say
graph or nothing right
it's just yeah what
the client needs if the
client needs stability
i want to give x
input and get y output
one good example would
be like this let's say
we have a hr use case
or saying that we have
20 different scenarios
and that 24 different
series could be put
into a graph just
rather than giving the
chance to the llm like
hey llm choose whatever
you want you just
say reason through it
find is this coming
under this subcategory
is just come here as the
subcategory you just
traverse through a
graph your outputs will
be much more stable
and it would make sense
for you i like graphs
two aspects in this
use case it does really
work well when you're
using weak lms like
gamma three you give 20
options it'll be like
doom i'm not going to
give a **** but you
give it three options
and ask it to traverse
through a graph it
performs much better
because you're decomposing
the problem to be
much smaller to a gamma
but i can't say the
same for sonnet 3.7
sonnet 3.7 if you give
it 20 different things
it can define its own
agentic graph and
navigate to the problem
that's effectively the
ai coding tools like
root client client sub
tasks all those things
so it comes down to
the tool it comes down
to the llm it comes
down to the use case
so no pro not against
at this like use case
customer yeah yeah
that makes that makes
sense so in yeah
um thanks for the
presentation i think
it's it's it's it's i
always enjoy seeing
the latest things
you've you've discovered
you know yet yet
another uh
interesting uh day of
discoveries here and
is that agnew is an sdk
Yes, it's in
Agnos and SDK.
Excellent.
It's my current LangChain
alternative for
wipe coding stuff.
It doesn't do really well
with light LLM sometimes.
I'll be like, okay,
I've given you
the Agno
documentation. Now wipe
code an agentic
application for me.
If it works well, if
my proof of concept is
really well with Agno,
then that's what I
convert into production
ready code with using
light LLM, setting up
fallbacks, all those
things, right? so it's
more like you want a
proof of concept,
Agnor's my guy then going
production, Light
LLM is the guy. It's
always stable. Light LLM
stable no matter what
Nice
Fantastic Thank
you Justin
Do we have John?
John actually got
called out so he's
not with us. He's
hoping to get back
in before the end but
My name means John I mean
what's that my name
means john and my
father's name is john
so i mean i can stand
in there you go
hannes yeah open open
table we got some open
time yeah well there's
if anyone wants to
present or has anything
they want to show
this this is this
is your chance um you
know obviously we we
uh we love uh to
see whatever you're
working on you know
and even if it's half
baked or vibed you
know this this is the
open mic portion of
our presentation um
anybody have anything
they want to show or
discuss or this is it
this is your chance
we got we got a quiet
crew today all right
i mean if people have
any questions i i find
that when i say hey
does anyone have any
questions they they
always seem to never run
out so i have questions
yeah i always have
questions but it's nice
to always have them
um all right uh do you
guys is there is there
any like kind of
business model associated
with you and incline
what do you mean uh
i do we are fine at all
for them like is there
any sort of like
interconnectivity there
or is it just open so
we talk to each other
okay they pull stuff
from us we pull stuff
from them but our code
bases have diverged
to the point where it's
not as easy as just
pulling it straight
across ever for sure yeah
it's just it's an
interesting it's interesting
seeing both of them
grow and you know
as the speed of development
and like iteration
takes place with all
these repos and all
these tools i'm just
kind of curious about
like the nature of the
agreements that are
happening between these
these different groups
where everyone gets
to kind of have maybe
some financial upside
or just trying to
understand like kind
of how the evolution of
these sorts of relationships
with very small
teams that are moving
very quickly, like how
that might look. And
you're in a very unique
position to, I guess,
maybe see what that
looks like. So I was
just kind of curious.
Went straight for
the heart there.
So I'm sorry.
No, no, that's good. Are
there any difficult
questions?
are there any kind of
about like the business
model of like what
you're seeing kind
of change in the
business model side of
things well one thing
we want to shy away
from uh fully is is
selling uh ru for use
paper use we are
looking at um enterprise
support and uh rolling
that out also some
tools that might be
unique to an enterprise
to enterprise that
aren't uh useful for
the general user so
you know they could
still use the software
but you know a more
focused version locked
down things like
that you know one of
the ways i think the
client guys are making
money is they they
offered like a client
proxy server for
like llms kind of like
requesty that that's
an obvious monetization
i we don't want
to be in the provider
business and we don't
to compete with
requestee or open router
or glamma or you know
whoever we just we
want to focus on
doing what we do and
doing it as as well as
we can and so i'm not
saying they're not
doing that i'm just
saying that i don't
know uh we we did look
at it and and when
they did it and went
you know no we we
don't we don't uh well
i was thinking compete
with requesting
i was thinking a joint
venture with a joint
venture with open
router where they
because i'm sure that
uh recode sends them
a significant uh
chunk of traffic and
even if we just took
one for some of that
uh might help hmm well
i mean um we we uh
we have a great
relationship with open
router uh we like that
when we say hey we need
this or this isn't
uh working how we're
expecting they jump
on it any time of day
and that's really nice
so they're getting
paid for it so did
that relationship
originate from like i guess
was it was it traction
that ultimately
gave you that access
to that relationship
or was it something
that you had to develop
independently and
like did the relationship
come first and then
traction or did the
traction come first
and then the
relationship kind of deep
attraction and then
relationship it seems that
everybody we go to
um as soon as soon as
we have something
they want uh everybody
wants to talk it's
hard to get anyone's
attention beforehand.
I'll be honest, with
Requesti, I was sort
of difficult for them
at first.
And they've proven to
be agile and willing
to adjust their
product to make it work
for our users.
Yesterday, I talked to
them on a video call
about something called
Rubux. We like to
give our contributors
$100 API credit when
they make a PR. It's
not payment for doing
the work because
quite often that's
not very good payment,
but it's just a little
thank you. Right.
Um, and they built
something, uh,
overnight that
actually, instead of
me giving an API
key out, I'll be
able to give out a
Rubux coupon code.
So we're excited
for that.
Oh, it's good. It's
good. Yeah. Like a, like
a way to recoup some
of the costs. I'm sure
a large portion of
your contributors are
probably using the tool
itself to contribute
some of the yeah so and
and as we know there
is inherent cost in uh
you know running any
of these models for a
substantial period of
time so yeah it's a
nice a nice way to get
back quick question so
i was looking back at
our first reference
to rue code and it was
uh i think november
mid-november last year.
How early were we in
terms of our discovery
of your platform? When
did you guys go live?
Okay, so the
story of Rue Code.
Rue Klein, I
guess it was, I
think, the 1st
of November or
thereabouts was
when Rue.vet,
our company that
birthed us, they had a
whole, you know, 20
plus engineers i think i
i don't know i wasn't
there um that were
using klein and they
wanted this auto approve
button so that they
could build their tests
and they you know it
turns out that engineers
really don't like
writing tests they
like building the stuff
not writing tests so
uh the auto proof
would be really cool so
they they built this
and i built it a few
days later um It was
about mid-November that
they made the poll
request, I think, the
16th. And I built it,
I think, on the 23rd.
They did better than
me. And I closed my poll
request down in favor
of theirs. And I
think they borrowed,
like, the hazard symbols
I had in the warning.
You know, like, I
didn't contribute to
it. I wasn't the founder
by any means. Mr.
Matt Rubins or Mr. Mr.
Ubins, as he goes by
on Discord and Reddit.
And I was talking with
them. And, you know,
we were in a group
chat. and basically it
just kept rolling from
there and it was just
a volunteer thing we
we i would i would
use both back and
forth and uh one day i
started using uh root
klein more it just did
all the things i didn't
need to switch back
anymore when i would
switch back i would
miss the things that
i was doing so i stuck
to it and uh then we
started a reddit and a
discord and we we, we
changed our name and
it became a thing. And
then they hired me.
I wasn't looking for
a job. I was just
sort of having fun
in my spare time.
Well, I like to think
that we had a small
part in our, our
Reddit, which has done
pretty well. And I
think we've been a
heavy promoter of, of
your, of your platform,
including the various
bugs. So there's
a few rants, you
know, every, week or
two as it went from
being my favorite
to my least favorite.
But you're currently
in my favorite book.
So that's a plus.
Thanks.
Sorry.
Sorry. Go ahead.
Yeah, I was just
having a thought
about the question
Alex was asking about
the monetization
potential, right?
I guess Microsoft, if
you look at it, they
are embedded in
copilots. I mean,
enterprises, big
enterprises, like these are
great, all of the
Roo's clients, but the
key thing is that for
enterprise adoption,
data privacy, data
security, these are
leakage concerns for
LLMs, they can't prime,
they take primacy,
right? I'm just
wondering whether there's
a space to provide
assurance in that
space from an IDE
point of view, because
whereas, you know,
engineering would
always want to use the
latest tooling,
they're constrained by
concerns about data
leakage, privacy,
et cetera, et cetera.
I'm guessing that's
probably an area because
it also allows, and
i'm probably thinking
kind of you know we're
like how do we include
a competitiveness in
this market because
microsoft has an
advantage to always i'm
a go by that but i mean
that's an area i think
we should look at
that how do we provide
that assurance and
that means so obviously
you could offer things
for free which is
what you're doing the
community but this is
probably the area that
helps monetize with
the enterprise that is
100 what we're working
towards a a version
of Roo that has those
features. For example,
a business, they
might have a specific
provider, so locking it
to that provider, not
having the ability to
connect to every MCP.
If there are MCPs,
it would be the ones
that that company has
opened to. Making it
so that it is secure is
absolutely what we are
working towards for
enterprises, enterprise
-first solutions. So
we are actively planning
that and working
with a few clients to
help forge that. Instead
of just coming up with
it and then selling
it, we're actually
working with some top
secret clients to
tailor it to them. And
then we're going to
move forward with that.
yeah the the one feature
that i think that
i've been working on
that probably would if
i was to commit
something like useful and
and the move the needle
for you guys would be
the mechanism i use to
orchestrate multiple
vs code instances and
there's a uh for those
that aren't familiar
you have the ability
to interact with
things like code spaces
and or other remote
versions of vs code right
to docker or just
hosted on in the cloud
somewhere and you can
then orchestrate based
on the interface to the
api to those systems
including the the
configuration of extensions
the terminal the the
code and other parts
of the vs code environment
what's interesting
is is this platform
provides a kind of
unified interface to
sort of create each vs
code instance like
its own little agent,
right? And once you
start looking at that as
a kind of distributed
swarm of coding bots,
you know, the traditional
approach to coding
bots looks more like,
you know, something
like a code interpreter
or the OpenAI agent
framework and things
like that. But what
this does is provides
a kind of, you know,
interface to all the
ecosystem of all the other
extensions that exist
within VS Code as
well, which none of
these other sort of code
interpreter type
libraries do really well
at right because you you
run a code interpreter
it's executing python
or node or whatever
but it's not using
all the other linting
capabilities and and
other tools that exist
within vs code so
suddenly you've got this
ability to sort of have
a uniform entry point
using something like a
root code and they're
potentially mcp or
eight and maybe an
hua in integration that
allows you to spin up
50 vs code instances
have them all work in
different parts of
your project project,
much like how I leave my
laptop running overnight,
you know, working
on whatever project
I need to get done.
But you could have that
kind of in a headless
kind of environment.
You do that and you
create swarms of VS code,
coding, you know,
much like people. But,
you know, anyway, random
idea. Right now with
our evals, when we
run them, basically,
we can, you can run 20
instances of eval you
know it'll feed that
through the uh back-end
api you can control
ru um and so we are
working on evals to
actually uh orchestrate
the evals with the use
of the new task boomerang
feature and so what
you're saying would
be entirely possible
with that with a tweaked
version of of that
workflow and so is the
eval stuff published
yeah it's in the uh
it is not documented
well, but it exists.
It's in the evals folder
in the main project.
The readme is
lacking, but you'll
figure it out.
I don't need
readme. That's
why I got AI work.
I think Guy
had a question.
We are still working
on the readme
for that, by
the way. It's
still a bit beta.
Sorry, go ahead.
One of the challenges
I've had is modularity,
right? So if I'm,
as an example, I'm
building this thing
that's like a board of
directors, right? So it
has three parts. One,
collect the database on
a person like Einstein.
Two, create an animated
avatar. And three,
replicate their voice.
And then put that
together as an avatar
that goes into things.
And I found that
that was too big to
do in one project. But
I really don't want
to create three sub
repos. What I want is
root code to just focus
on the module that
I asked to work on,
you know, and have APIs
that it doesn't mess
with that the other
modules use, and
basically use the same Git
repo to store things.
So it's kind of along
the lines of what
you're saying that, you
know, Ruv, about
running multiple VS Code
instances, but, you know,
I'm not that concerned
about doing them in
parallel, that would
be good but getting
the right decomposition
and then also the
others that's one topic
and the other topic
is you know who who
gives the evaluation
function for the test
code so what i found
is like the evaluation
function for the
avatar part of that is
completely **** right so
there's no like quality
feedback on on the
test code generation
to to verify that
it's going to do the
right thing yeah so um
go ahead there for me
anyway there is and
that's what the unit
tests and the integration
tests do right
that that's the
verification and the you
know right now i've
got several vs codes
running on several
different projects that
i'm working on as
we speak while i'm
talking to you and the
reason i'm confident
that they're working
correctly that we
actually leave and
looking at them at the
moment is the fact
that I know that the
actual combination of
unit tests and evaluation
and optimization
that'll happen after
will result in
a functional
application. So as
long as I have...
If you're doing
something more
bespoke, the
problem is that
nothing is evaluating
the test quality.
The tests help evaluate
the code quality,
but what is the feedback
eval function that
says this is actually
a good test or you got
a good test coverage
oh that's me i think
we have the ai to do
that entirely and that
i i think it screws up
on that sometimes yeah
there's this isn't 100
automated i'm still
the human in this loop
i need to be able to
describe the structure
for both the the the
test pattern which is
the London school I
use. And then the second
part is the form of
recursive optimization.
So once my tests
all pass and I get 100
% coverage, I probably
don't need 100% coverage,
to be honest, I get
usually somewhere north
of 80%, it's probably
good enough. I then
have the evaluation
framework that can
self-optimize. And the
benefit to the ability
to have these systems
like Roo and others sort
of auto-approve means
that as long as I
have the ability to
feedback on itself,
meaning that I'm looking
for coherence on the
result. So if I'm doing
a data science project
and I need to get to
a point where the
coherence is 95% and that
might take a day or
two of just running it,
the choice I have at
that point is one of
concurrency or parallelization
of that, meaning
I can use a GPU and
run a thousand or a
million simultaneous
runs of that particular
problem. Or I can
take a more sequential
approach, which is
basically just let it
run and figure itself
out and let the system
create a kind of
declarative approach,
meaning I'm not telling
it how to solve the
problem. I'm just saying
what the problem is
and what my optimal
output is. But everything
in between A and Z,
it's up to Roo and
the LLM and the prompt
to figure out itself.
So those are the
two approaches.
Chris, you got a comment?
Yeah, so one cool
methodology I've
been using over
the last couple of
days that's been
really, really helpful
to me is, let me
share my screen.
So I've got programs
set up in VS Code that
will copy all of my,
say, my Knowledge
Graph files or all of
my AL files or all of my
back end or all of my
front end. And I can
combine all of these
files, right, into
like a single notepad
file. And you see here
I've got 980,000
characters, 15,777 lines
of code, right? And
I can take this and I
can put this all into
Google Gemini Studio.
and for some reason
this is only 333,000
characters and with
Gemini Studio you can look
for bugs you know like
you can do all kinds
of stuff and it's
amazing actually at all
the stuff that you
can do with this like
you can literally put
in up to 50,000 lines
of code into Gemini
Studio and just ask
questions about it or
have it come up with a
plan or have it try
to identify bugs or
improvements to the code
like you can do so much
and then with these
programs like as things
get updated i just
hit a button and boom
it puts all the new
files and how it's
changed into it i can
slap it in here and this
is just a good way of
debugging that i found
that is working
extremely well for me or
building plans on top
of what you got etc
cool nice big context
what's the content it's
like two million is
that is that what they
have for the context
i'm gonna run to
another meeting sorry no
good thanks sir thanks
for joining us today
really appreciate
it. We're in the after
hours portion anyway.
Great. Well, we'll love
to have you
back sometime.
You, Pat. Thank
you so much for
having me. Take
care, Hannes.
You bet.
Thanks, Hannes.
Oh, we got David.
Do you want
to give us a
foundation update
since we see
you on screen?
Well, for sure.
Hey, everybody. We got
a really good group
today. It's basically
marking the one
-year anniversary of
this group that was
founded by Rude and
a bunch of other
individuals such as
Robert and Brad and Ron
and a bunch of other
refined individuals.
Just to reiterate that
everything that we're
doing, you probably
got a feel here, is all
about trying to share
with the community,
get people up to speed
on agentic development,
and also how agentics
are going to be
incorporated into uh into
businesses and society
so um there's a lot
of opportunities
for us for people to
participate in uh helping
us service that mission
so i think brad uh
posted a link to sign
you up for volunteers
we're looking for
volunteers to help out
um so if brad is still
around he can post that
again we'd be really
grateful to that um we're
also going to be for
people that are in
toronto um we're going
to be hosting um
either next week or the
following week our very
first meetup and those
will be coming up
monthly and uh that will
be uh that framework
will be a the meetup um
framework for other
cities as well so also
for people that are
looking to um uh host
meetups uh on agentics
in their cities please
again um uh reach out
to us um there's forms
uh there's this
different form of robert
right for for um our
for the ambassador
program the ambassador
program right through
that it's um agenex.org
backslash uh ambassador
i believe is the link
they um dropped your
name right in there
and uh yeah if you want
to if you want to start
hosting live events
locally locally we've
got alex uh gross
has put together a
fantastic events guide um
and there's some uh
great support there
fantastic all right so
um and and if i'm on
whatsapp i'm on discord
um i'm on linkedin uh
if you have other
questions you can link um
obviously reach out to
me or anybody in the
board is really highly
responsive um so please
get involved uh and
um uh that's that's
that's what i would
say please get involved
thanks david one
more thing about the
events real fast yeah
so there's just one uh
one kind of update
here we're planning on
so um i'm working on
a a series of events
right now for agentics
but we'll be um
trying to launch these
in a number of cities
so across i'm working
in about 15 locations
right now so
that's ranging nine
different states here
in the western united
states i know a lot of
you are up in canada
so if there is any
interest feel free to
reach out to me
directly too and i will
i'm happy to kind
of hop on a call and
figure out how we can
make sure that you can
organize and and uh
and connect with people
in your local area
around agentics and
and uh we have a whole
framework for you so
feel free to reach
out and our um rob our
plan was to do a little
get together maybe
next week but probably
the following week
uh in toronto is that
uh yeah that's right
so in toronto we're
just uh waiting on
confirmation of the
availability of the
location um on wellington
street so either
this coming tuesday or
the following tuesday
and yeah we'll do it
90 minutes in person
uh live rube uh you've
uh uh signed up to
to do a deep dive on
agentic engineering
and then same thing
we'll open the the floor
to lightning talks
and get a chance to
meet each other in
person and there's uh uh
yeah a number of firms
that are interested
in coming down too
so it should be a lot
of fun and it's you
know not a the uh uh
overly structured you
know it's our first
time of actually having
a chance to get together
in person and meet
each other so we want
to um yeah uh keep it
in a familiar structure
uh but enjoy it It
should be fun. Yeah,
and Sanal has
suggested using
a different tool,
Spatial Chat,
I think is what
he called it.
It's like more of
a webinar sort of
structure rather
than using Zoom.
So I think on Thursday
of next week, for
those that don't do our
Thursday vibe coding
sessions, it's even more
technical than this.
but uh so we tested
some of these different
uh platforms and give
that a spin next week
if you're interested
in joining that's
thursdays at 12 eastern
um and my apologies to
anyone in you know uh
east of india because
it's in the middle of
the night but uh you know
can't get all the time
zones um and as for
next week uh yeah this
is impromptu so we're
just a bunch of us
going to get together
you know order some
pizza and talk agentics
and if if others are
interested in doing that
i know there's a lot
of interest to do that
in london because
london seems to be a hot
spot apparently for
agentics so i i um bentz
is your guy i think
to talk to in london
um and i've got several
more people who i
should probably introduce
you to events in london
um i don't know why
london's so hot for
agentics right now at
least it is for me but
it seems to be a hot
spot yeah that's true
and uh we are meeting
with one week after this
goal and um get it
going perfect fantastic
benson and yeah so you
know we're we're uh
we're building we're
we're we've probably
taken on more than
what we should have
which is like you know
probably my my bias
towards action um
it's easier to start
things it is the finish
things but you know
i think i think
we're in a good spot
here we've certainly
got a lot of a lot of
activity and momentum
and opportunities.
Yeah, so we've
got a few minutes
here. Is there
anything you guys
want to cover,
look at, discuss?
I've got a question for
you, Roof, if it's okay.
You had a post
last week that
I thought was
fascinating.
You said, instead of
memory banks, all you
need are unit tests.
Can you expand on that?
Well, actually,
we were talking
about this before
we kicked off the
hackerspace earlier.
We have a pre
-show as well, right?
We get set up.
And, you know,
Hannes was showing
us his setup and
his memory banks.
And there's a lot of
people like the idea
of sort of this
iterative saving of every
step that you're doing
when you're coding,
you know, using,
you know, agendic
systems. And I've not
been a fan of it. And
there's a couple of
reasons. One is cost.
The every step requires
an additional step
to save the information,
which requests
makes the request to
the LLM is is is adds
a lot more cost to
the process. And two,
there's a tendency
for the AI to
sometimes go down the
wrong path, right?
And what happens with
these memory banks
is once you go down
the wrong path,
that becomes the
sort of, you know,
whatever reason,
the new path.
And I don't
want that path.
So it's like, I don't
necessarily care.
This is back to the
idea of discriminative
or declarative approach
to development.
A declarative
approach means I'm
giving you the
guidance up front,
here's what I
need, and here's my
expected output,
here's what I want.
Now, in between A and
Z, I like to leave
it up to the AI to
sort of determine
how to solve those
problems. But what
I don't want is when
it reaches the step
10 to change the
entire plan. The plan
didn't change between,
you know, when
I told you to do it
and when it ended,
the deliverable
is the same. But
what happens with
these memory banks
is it almost corrupts
the structure
and then it
reinterprets it and it
goes down these
crazy rabbit holes.
So using the test
-driven approach allows
it to understand, is
it doing it correctly?
You know, the plan.
So, you know, when
I'm showing you
these things, it's
creating a kind of
detailed multi-step
plan. That plan
doesn't change, right?
So I'm implementing
each step of the
plan sequentially and
then using the test
to say, is the
plan functional and
complete? Yes,
great. Move on to the
next. Now, there's
a chance that the
previous steps in the
plan and the things
that were built
previously will break.
But the plan doesn't
change. It just
needs to fix those
things that broke.
And that's where
the tests can
provide that kind
of memory. It's
basically saying,
is it still working?
And if it isn't,
go fix it. So
for me, the tests
are the memory.
And the navigation. That
makes a ton of sense.
Yeah.
So that's why I don't
use it. And like
Memzero and those sorts
of things, you know.
The closest thing I
have to the memory bank
would be the
implementation I did about
a month ago of the
Spark 2, where I was
vectorizing each step
of the coding. And then
I use the similarity
structure based on
saying, have I done
something similar before
code-wise and what
did that look like?
And should I
solve the same
problem again
or should I just
recycle what I
did last month?
But that's a
different thing than
the memory bank.
The memory bank
is just basically
itemizing what
am I doing now?
What am I doing?
What's been
done? And sort of
recreating the plan
iteratively over and
over and over
again, which is, I
think, a silly
approach. But anyway,
that's just me.
Fantastic.
Thank you, Riff.
Quick question
regarding that. What
if the memory could
be saved without
the additional
overhead of the costs?
Like, for example,
every chat that is in
Rue code sits in a
JSON file for VS Code.
What if we could use
that JSON that has all
the tasks, the details
of that and the
headers and vectorize
that and maybe give
that contextual long
-term memory only to
the orchestrator or
the commander so it can
learn to create
better plans from the
previous projects that
it already executed
without the additional
overhead of running.
writing the long-term
memory because the
writing happens by
VS code and root code
and the data is already
there in the JSON.
Well, the issue
I've run into
with that is in
tools like Cursor
and Roo and Klein
and whatever,
every action is
initiated and facilitated
by an LLM request,
Right. So what you're
describing means
there needs to be an
intermediary step that
bypasses the need to make
the request to the
LLM, which is which
is possible. But that
requires a procedural
component that
basically says, here's a
list of actions that need
to happen independently
of the AI, which
most of these systems
don't take in
consideration. So, for
example, if you're
going to try to do that
with, you know, Klein
or Roo, for example,
the system just
doesn't work that way,
right? And you'll
notice that when you
try to use tools
like MCPs as part of
your dev flow,
there's a tendency for
it to sort of do
discovery on the MCPs,
even though you're
explicitly saying,
you know, here are
the tools available
to it, yet it's still
trying to discover,
well, is there a
tool list or is there
a discovery endpoint?
even though i've
told it what it needs
to do and that's
that's a byproduct
of the llm trying to
you know and maybe
it's byproduct poor
poor prompt
engineering too i don't
know but it's it's
possible but would
require a different
system i think
that that's what
i was thinking
as well like
this is this is
a separate agent
kind of like
the enablement agent
that runs maybe based
on a cron task every
night just goes
into the task dump
file which has a json
of all the llm calls
and all the actions
and tasks completed
that day and asks the
question like is there
anything that was
learned today that
we should remember
and that gets fed into
either like a memory
bank or into a
database that the
orchestrator or your
main commander accesses.
That is an
interesting point.
You know what
we could do? I'm
just thinking
out loud here.
Hypothetically, there's
a option for one
for using something like
Olama locally, which
would increase any
inherent costs. And
you can have smaller
targeted LLMs just for
things like memory
and internal tooling.
The other option,
hypothetically, could
be a combination
of that along with
like a pseudo
completions API endpoint.
So what you could do,
because it expects a
certain structure, both
in terms of the way
it makes the request
to the LM, so, you
know, completion slash
whatever, and the JSON
format that goes along
with it, you could
create like a fast API
endpoint that accepts
the completion style
request, but doesn't
actually ever make the
request to the AI. And
based on that, there's
some kind of, you
know, heuristics or
regular expression that
parses the sort of
intent of the request and
then acts as a kind
of intermediary proxy
that says if certain
requests are made in
a certain way, it just
doesn't bother to ask
the LLM and then makes
the request to like
a vector store or
some other, you know,
someone that just posted
the Redis type approach.
So it queries a
database either in terms
of getting or posting
information And then
that there's no inherent
additional cost.
But the response from
Redis in this example
looks exactly like
the response you'd get
from LLM, but it's not
coming from an LLM.
yeah i'm thinking a
lot about like cost
optimization and i come
from a building people
organizations and workforce
planning background
and i'm trying to
see if there is a way
to orchestrate a
workforce that escalates
upwards when tests are
failing or troubleshooting
tasks are failing
more than two times
like let's say you are
first assigned a test
to a junior which has
maybe a local coder
model run the code
twice like try to do the
thing that you need
to do if you cannot
troubleshoot using a
browser mcp troubleshoot
like try to implement
what you found and if
you still cannot solve
it if the test fails
another two times
escalate to the next
level developer which is
maybe either like clod
or something in between
and just keep on
escalating upwards until
the test passes but
always start with the
dumbest model quote
unquote like the lowest
level employee that
has the lowest cost you
know it's that's that
makes sense and i
said i see a number of
comments that braun
had in chicago arc and
the you know i think
the more targeted you
use the more targeted
the smaller language
model is the more useful
it is for for that
sort of intersection
between procedural tasks
like you know the the
sort of traditional
um you know agent
structures of the past
before llms were a
thing right and and then
hyper targeting it so
it doesn't need to be it
doesn't need to be
good at everything like
arc trying to do arc's
basically saying is
it agi like can it do
everything and everything
really well most of
these small language
models don't need
to do everything or
anything in particular
they need to do one thing
very well and that
one thing could be
literally do a sql query
or uh you know save the
information in a certain
way or or reinterpret
the information in a
certain way and that
and those types of
really tiny language
models that don't even
need a cpu might be
perfect when you kind of
can embed that as like
a you know and what's
the onyx structure
for example which uses
web assembly you can
literally run that
you know without a gpu
and have it do that
whatever that task is,
like what you described,
memory, for example.
I don't know, random
ideas on a Friday, but
there's so many different
ways to do this.
I got to jump
to, but Adam, you
got a final
comment, thought?
Oh, I just want to
say something. We were
thinking about adding
procedural things
into Roof. Some of us
talked about it, not
in context of memory,
but in context of
doing get commits
without using the LLM.
So basically as tasks
got the, the task
completed tool got
called in Roo, we would
create a get commit
right there. And that
was planning that
maybe one day we would
be able to roll back
tasks and you would
sometimes roll back
each complete. If the
agents went off
the track, it'd
be easy way to,
you know, redo
everything
after, you know,
well, how did it go
off the track? Well,
it went off the track
right here. It started
hallucinating,
roll back your Git
commits, roll back the
tasks and start over.
So anyway.
I have that built.
And that's what I
did with my Spark 2
system a few weeks
ago. And basically what
I did is I integrated
the essentially a
kind of interface
between, yeah, here, let
me share my screen
quick. I got to jump
to a new call here
in a sec, But I want
to show you guys
quickly what I did here.
And basically,
the Spark 2 has
a component.
Where did I put that?
Yeah,
so that's my Git
integration. So it
creates checkpoints,
and then it can
autonomously roll back
at any point. So the
Git commit is actually
a vector. So what
I'm storing is the
vector of the diff,
in the root terminology,
the applied diff.
I vectorize the
applied diff and then
if something breaks
in a subtask then I'm
able to say okay was
this you know one
where and how did it
break and two what was
the either the previous
solution to that
problem and can I
recycle that just using
the diff that that
bypasses the need
to use the LLM altogether
because I'm just
grabbing the diff
and applying it again
potentially and it
also has automatic
rollback because I'm
using the E2B sandbox.
So I'm executing
each bit of code
independently of
the overall code
base remotely in
each E2B sandbox.
But what I should
probably do is integrate
this into Roo and
that will give you
all that capability.
This is already
built in TypeScript.
So it's pretty much
everything you need
to make that happen.
But that's a conversation
for another day.
Yeah. Another
interesting thing that
some web of PR out
saying we're trying
to land, I would
like to land it. It
exposes the internal
VS Code APIs to let
you treat another
extension as an MCP.
So it basically
lets someone else's
extension discover
that, oh, Rue
can understand
my commands. I'm
going to tell Roo
about my commands.
A guy did it to
implement Jupyter
Notebook integration
into Roo.
That's cool.
Yeah, you sent
it over to me.
That would work
well for A2A.
Yeah, exactly.
So it's very VS Code
local, but like I
said, it had a very
specific purpose, but
it's like it could
be generally used for
a whole lot of things
that don't involve
LLM, but you want
to do with VS Code.
Yeah.
Okay.
go sure yeah can we
just give it up to rube
and the rest of the
squad here at agentix
just for putting this
together this one year
of ai hackerspace i
just think like if
everyone has found this
to be valuable we're
trying to grow this
thing if there's any kind
of post you could share
about the birthday
on linkedin that'd be
amazing but like just
want to give props
to to these peeps and
um there's been a lot
of a lot of work done
every single week to
to put these events on
to organize to continue
to grow and uh just
want to have everyone
wish it a happy
birthday that's all okay
and thanks to everyone
else because it's
better than talking to
my ai and having you
guys you know appreciate
all the contributions
from everyone involved
so this is great
happy happy birthday
everybody including
you alex as a major
contributor to this
group right so yeah thank
you all right till next
week and if anyone's
in in toronto reach
out we're going to try
to get together next
week or two all right
till till next time
thanks thanks rave okay