Here we are.
So this was quite the
week. It was like the
week of every AI new
announcement. There's
so many announcements,
I don't even know
where to start. It's
been absolutely crazy,
spectacular, amazing.
I think we live for
these types of weeks
on the AI hacker space.
It's been nothing short
of just astounding
in terms of some of
the tools that have
come out from Google
and others. just i
i don't know where
to start rob how's it
going great great yeah
it was epic uh the
vo3 video with sound
uh crazy stuff out
of google um and
somehow in between it
all with the new tools
um and and all your
clients you still get
you still drop spark
bench and some
incredible new stuff so
i'm looking forward
to this week we've
got uh we got three
guests so um ****** v3
is with us this week
and then uh braun our
our good old member
uh braun field walker
he's got a a new um rapid
audio to text conversion
tool that he wants
to show and then uh
bensa and mandweep are
going to uh recap we
had the uh big london
uk event this week
and it was a great success
it's it was the week
of google it would
seem and and and big
big thank you to google
london and and benson
mandweep for putting
all that together and
and our friends at
requesty who were critical
in in sort of the
organization of it i
think london is going
to be a really good spot
for us for sure yeah
so we'll see some
pictures and get a little
recap from those guys
on that so huge yeah
for sure and so well
you know we we've got
a lot to cover today
and i think in my opinion
google won the week
um you know if you look
at this if you look
at the stuff that was
put out not just you
know bs but real things
you could try you
know whether it was
that flow video system
which is just mind
-boggling the way that they
handle both audio and
video and adjust it
i don't know if anyone's
played with it but
the the output i'm
getting from it is nothing
short of spectacular
um it's expensive like
yet another 250 dollar
uh you know thing
you have to sign up for
i'm hoping martin we
can get a uh a cheaper
non-profit version
of the google uh ai
stuff so martin by the
way thank you for setting
up all these uh non
-profit things for us
we're getting lots of
uh good deals actually
martin why don't you
give us a quick over
some of the non-profit
deals you've been
able to spin up for us
yeah so i i guess the
main one um well uh
github was first so we
got um the github non
-profit account um
essentially that allows us
to add people to the
organization without
paying the four dollars
per person that makes
a huge difference for
us um a second uh the
google workspace um so
google workspace for
domain we were on
business standard that's
like i don't know 17
a person but we get
several hundred i can't
remember the right
number um users on the
domain for free um and
that's that's a really
good uh basis point
and beyond that we can
actually take a um like
a subscribed version
and get 72 off again
makes a huge difference
for an organization
like ours where really
it's volunteers that
pile in that um help
us get things done and
get the things done
that you want done right
because you you can
basically put your
actions where your heart
is um beyond that uh
we also now have
subscription to TechSoup.
TechSoup and
Goodstack, each of
those provide
the gateways into
multiple software
partners.
It's no secret I used
to work with Atlassian
software and they
will give you 75%
off for non-profits
which again if you're
using something like
Loom which is one-to
-one video chatting
and they'll do the
compression of chats
then you can basically
email back and forth a
little video conversation
that's a great
enabler to mean that
you don't have to be
in the same room and
always have a meeting
because you can just
basically swap ideas
over these little
videos. I think that
Confluence, Jira, Jira
Service Desk all
those sorts of things
so yeah I mean
there's a lot in there
I will try and
prepare a little
summary next time and
give you an update
I definitely
appreciate all
the hard work
you've put into
saving us quite
a bit of money.
So we got GitHub
essentially for free,
which is amazing,
which includes
code spaces and
other capabilities.
We're getting various
cloud services.
I think some of them
were like 75% off
for AI and related
tools. So what we're
going to try to do
is figure out how
we can get others in
the organization to
also take advantage
of some of these
non-profit rates that
we're able to get.
Because I'm not going
to lie, a big part
of the reason for us
to be a non-profit was
to get discounts on
these tools that we
use that are really
expensive, especially if
you're trying to do
a benchmarking system
or just trying
everything under the sun.
It really just adds
up quickly. So really
appreciate you putting
the effort in. And
I know a lot of this
was like a lot of busy
work and back and
forth with Google and
whatever. So thanks
for making that happen.
We appreciate that. So
what else is going on
this week? A lot. And
let me just jump in.
I'm going to give you
a quick rundown of some
of the stuff. I'm
going to try not to go
too long because we've
got a lot to cover.
We've got some really
good people presenting
and a lot of stuff to
cover. So like always,
if you have questions,
feel free to pop those
into the chat. I will
try my best to keep
an eye on that. But
I'm going to go quick.
So here we are. So
let's start with cost. I
always like to jump
into Requesti. I love
Requesti. And I made a
big mistake yesterday.
And you'll see it
right here. I managed
to spend $225 of my
own money, I might add,
because I mistakenly
used the Opus 4 model
for my testing rather
than using Sonic 4.
And a couple of
things to note,
avoid Opus 4 for
right now. There's no
prompt caching or if
there is, it *****,
as you can tell by
my cost. So once I
realized that only
I've just spent $224,
I switched and removed
Opus 4 from it.
But look, if you look
at the actual number
here for a moment,
you'll see that I
used 42 million tokens
yesterday and today
so far, which I've
been really busy
day building random
stuff, I've used about
50 million tokens.
The difference in
cost is dramatic.
Today, I've spent $55,
and I've saved $105
in terms of context.
And so to figure
out where the issue
was, I went in,
I got to figure
out, I think it was
cost management.
And then that
allowed me to
go and see the
model details.
And we go down here for
a sec. yeah we'll see
here the different
models so opus 4 was the
killer and when we
look here you see i'm
spending a dollar 29
per request versus sonic
4 10 cents and so my
93 93 requests ended
up costing 120 bucks so
that that's what killed
me essentially i
think but what was
interesting i'm And like,
so once I realized that,
you know, I'm like,
why was Opus so much
more expensive than
Sonnet? Well, it turns out
that you'll see here,
the cash rate is 0%.
So that was like a
spark in my brain that
said, well, I need
to be able to measure
not only the performance
of these systems,
but the cost versus
performance of these
systems. And what
if I could actually
optimize the system on
both sort of dimensions
of both prompt cache
and other things,
which then opened up
the whole avenue of
thinking, I don't
know what you want to
call it, that basically
said, well, I need
to be able to measure
the effectiveness
of these systems in
something that's more
than just me arbitrarily
trying to do it.
That's where I dreamt
up this idea of a root
code evaluation and
benchmarking system.
Now, when you look
at some of the source
numbers, like I think
Martin shared a benchmark
within the text chat
for those who are
interested in on the
Sonnet and Opus models.
And one of the ones
they're using is something
called SWE Benchmark.
So the SWE Benchmark
essentially are, I
think, around 2,000
or 3,000 random GitHub
issues that you can
go and test against.
And now they give you
that as a giant JSON
file. Well, yeah, there
it is. Thanks, Martin.
And basically what
this does is allows
you to sort of run it,
test it, and see what
the result is. And
it's random. So what I
thought, well, what if
I can integrate that and
create a specification?
And this will do
two things for me.
One, I've been exploring
this idea of long
horizon agentic
development. These are
things that run for
more than several hours,
right? And one of
the problems that I
have with long-running
agenting processes
is often they finish
because it's hard to
give an application and
know that it's going
to take you 36 hours
to build. But when
you have 3,000
different problems to
solve, that can run for
weeks, to be honest.
So it's a nice way
to have long-running
things, and it allows
me to randomly test.
The second problem I
ran into is I've yet
to run this test
and have it not be
able to complete it,
which I think is a
good thing. So I'm,
I'm literally running
a hundred percent
on, on the tests and
the benchmarking,
which is pretty amazing
as well. So let me
show you that quick.
All right.
So I, I, so I went
in here and I created
this, you'll see how
I've got an SQL light and
we got a database.
We got two different
databases I created. I,
I parsed. So I, I'm using
the SQL bench system
and you'll see there's
data sets, these data
sets, I'm not going
to open this cause
they're huge, but these
are basically JSON,
which is terrible format
to work within. So I
converted the JSON to
something a little
easier to work with which
is SQLite I was thinking
of using DuckDB,
but I ended up using
SQLite. It's just
easier And and you can
see here that I've got
the completion summary.
I've got the various
tasks So these tasks
essentially let me
let me make this a
little easier for you
guys to see so these
are basically random
Tasks and I and I'm
doing blind tests I'm
not giving the answer
to the to the problem,
which these also
include both the
problem set So this
would be like, you know,
here's the problem
statement from GitHub.
And then we have,
here's the hints, you
know, giving you some
details on what the
problem is or whoever
submitted saying, you
know, how and what
the problem is. Then
we've got the, you
know, the patch that was
given to fix it and
other things to qualify.
But what I really
want to know is, you
know, tests to fail and
test to pass, right?
Right. So then what
I can do is I can go
in here and I have
a whole variety of,
again, of different tests
I can run, you know,
based on the Spark
framework, you know,
includes, you
know, auto curve.
Now, what's cool for
this beyond just the
basic test is I can
use this to optimize my
my Spark protocol to
do a test to see if I
can improve the
performance of the actual
prompt itself. So it
does it maybe rather than
taking 10 steps, I
can get it down to two
steps or three steps
or one step. maybe.
I can also measure,
you know, security and
other various vectors
like, you know, time,
cost, and complexity,
which is all the stuff
that occurred to me
when I saw a $225 bill
the other day. So now
I'm going to go back
in here. So then I
created as a mode. So
for those who are, you
know, familiar with
my Rue modes approach,
I created a mode here
called benchmark. And
you see here, I've
got different details
on how the benchmark
needs to work, problems
to classify, what
the SQL looks like, how
to interact with it.
I then created a number
of different actual
files to actually
implement it. So you can
see here, I've got
scripts that can begin
to comparisons and
the benchmarks, but I
don't want to have to
run all those scripts.
That's a pain. So the
Roo actually does that
when you go here.
So now I choose the
benchmarking
orchestrator. So I make
an orchestrator
that basically is
dedicated to that.
Fingers crossed. It
worked every time until
I want to do a live
demo, but I'm going to
say run a, you know,
run one random task.
Let's just keep it and
we'll see what happens.
All right, so you can
see I'm using Sonic 4.
And if all goes well, it
should orchestrate
a sub task.
So it's going to
figure itself out. Here
we go. It's going to
look at some stuff,
thinking, all right.
Now it's going
to switch to the
code mode it didn't
do a subtask,
I guess it doesn't
really matter.
I'm just asking it to
do this mode. So I've
actually updated
the autocoder to be
specifically relating to
the benchmarks. You can
see that it's now
running the benchmark. So
what this did is it
actually is getting a
task. So you can see
here it ran the helper
and now it's randomly
getting a task out of
the thousands that
exist within the SQLite.
And then what it's gonna
do once it gets the task,
it's going to
say basically I'm
starting the task.
so it's another
command. So what
I'm doing is I'm
integrating a
combination of Python and
benchmarking as part of
the automated Spark flow.
The reason I'm doing
that is I'm not so much
interested in, I am
interested in the benchmark
and the cost, but I'm
more interested in
the optimization of
the flow itself. So by
doing this, I can
recursively optimize the
actual Spark system to
say benchmark yourself,
then optimize the
actual rules and code
based on the benchmark
until you get coherence.
So what I'm looking
for is to go from 10
steps down to something
less, right? But at
the end of the day,
what's interesting about
what you're looking at
right now in terms of
this benchmark is out
of all the times I've
run this, and I've run
this probably 60, 70
times at this point,
I've yet to find any
problem in the more than
3,000 problems in the
database that this
system hasn't been able
to solve, which means
that using Spark, we're
basically 100% capability,
at least according
to the SWE bench. Now,
I need someone else
other than me to take
a look at it and find
and poke holes into my
benchmarking philosophy.
But in In terms of
capability, we are
now, if you believe
this to be true, I think
I do. It's a little
early to go out there,
but I'm going to use a
bit of hyperbole here.
We are at a phase
where AI and AI-based
coding is at the level
of any senior developer,
without question.
This is solving any
problem I put at it.
You could take this
also, not just use
this against the SWE
bench. You can literally
point this at any
PR on GitHub or JIRA
or whatever and do it
that way and you'll
get the same result.
So here you can see
that I'm getting
my tests. So it
automatically tests.
It tests itself.
All tests pass.
And look, it costs $0
.33, which is, you know,
not that expensive
unless you
run it 30,000
times. But, again,
nothing I point
at it, you
know, it can't be solved.
So this is actually
a really good way if
you're looking at
integrating this into your
dev flow, you could
actually take what
I've done here in terms
of the benchmarking
and use it as part
of a kind of project
management flow. We could
point it at different
websites and kind
of create like an
angel bot where it goes
and fixes all those
issues you see in NPM
libraries, whatever.
It's basically
a self-fixing
system that I built
as a benchmarking
tool, which is
pretty cool.
Now at the end,
you can see here,
so it's using a
combination of, oh,
it looks like this
one failed. So
let's see if it'll
fix that problem.
I need to fix the
test function. Oh,
the test function
failed. Okay.
But anyway, moral
story is it can fix
anything and it
just kind of works
and which is pretty
cool. All right. That's
one thing I built. I'm
going to jump to the
next thing. We can come
back to that later.
While we're on the
topic of, and this is
something I'm going to
post this afternoon.
You guys are going to
get a little sneak peek
of it. I hate RAG.
RAG *****. Retrieval
augmented generation
is probably the worst
possible way to integrate
data into an LLM.
It's slow, it's cumbersome,
it's really hard
to update, and it
doesn't work well with
tools or MCPs. It's
like it was built for an
era that didn't have
the concepts of function
calling, tooling or
MCPs. So it occurred
to me literally this
morning while I was
on my exercise bike,
what would a retrieval
system look like that
was actually optimized
for the current
generation of LLMs,
specifically cache, right?
So these LLMs now have
the ability to have
prompt caching built
directly into it. So
as you saw earlier,
prompt caching is what
makes these systems
really cheap and
affordable and fast. So by
prompt caching, I'm able
to get substantially
faster response
times. And I built a
benchmark, of course, to
prove this process that
allows me to use a
kind of time to live.
So I'm pinging the thing,
giving it the data,
and then extracting
the data directly from
the prompt cache in
the LLM for things
like Sonic 4, as well
as various things like
the latest open AI and
stuff like that. So
the architecture
basically is similar to
RAG, but I'm bypassing
the need for any kind
of vector, which again,
vectors, because of
the similar research,
have a tendency to
not give you the right
response. So this is
explicit. Then I can
call a tool registry,
MCPs or other
sort of tooling,
and then process
directly that
into a sort of data
structure, both local,
like a SQLite or DuckDB
or whatever, as well
as injecting that
directly into the caching
mechanism of the LLM,
which is substantially
faster. So the benefits
to that include,
in my initial test, which
I'm going to go here
and show you. So let's
go to my next one.
So I ran this just
before the call this
morning. I did a quick
test. I was able to get
a 91% cost reduction
versus RAG, 91%. So the
problem with RAG is
the data has to be
inserted every time,
which causes differences
in the prompt. Because
it's a similarity,
those differences mean
that it's hard to cache
because there's minor
inconsistencies in
it. And it just doesn't
work as well. And I
was able to go from a,
what was my, a 3X or
a 320% increase or
decrease in latency in
terms of speed. So I went
from 160 milliseconds
down to like 20
milliseconds and I was
able to save 91%. And
the other benefit here
is I've got the ability
now to integrate
any MCP as part of
the RAG process, both
locally using studio, as
well as remotely using
any MCP that exists
on the internet. So
anyway, I'm calling it
fact because it kind of
works. And I'm going
to do a blog post
later this afternoon
about this. You guys can
try it if you want um
again like everything
i created a benchmarking
you can see this
was entirely built
between um me getting on
my exercise bike at
8 30 this morning and
now so it's caught there's
quite a bit of stuff
here you can see here
that like you know
here's the structure
of the folders and all
the all the components
that's built it's
it's substantial zero
shot like sonnet for
for building complicated
things is spectacular
might not be the
right word it's it's
phenomenal anyway you can
see here is how I built
it here's my docs
you can see my in my
initial planning so
basically I started with
basically a readme this
is the sort of here's
what I want to build
here and I want to
try the new arcade dev
system which is really
a cool system so you
can see how that works
where the heck what's
that image I don't
even know what that
even is but it looks
like it inserted a weird
image you know anyway
you can get a feel
for it check out the
scripts folder if you
want to see all the little
benchmarking here's
the benchmark read
read me i think i think
on my exercise bike
in a matter of three
hours we reinvented the
idea of rag all right
i'm done that was me
going at super speed
here this morning how
does the cash get
injected into the model?
I'm using two approaches
right now. I can
do direct request of
the MCP, which induces
significant latency
depending on whether it's
local or remote.
Studio would be faster.
But for the actual
benchmarking, I'm using
SQLite. So I'm taking
the data as a separate
process running
independently of the actual
request. So I generally
know what information
I can show you guys
quickly what that
looks like and let's
go back just a quick
and again I'm trying to
this is this is a art
of the possible sort
of thing by the way
you know I don't know
and I looked around I
couldn't find anyone
doing anything quite
like it so let's just
go here I'll show you
what the data looks
like there we go so in
this case we have a
folder called fact demo
and this is a SQLite,
so let's look at
what the data
looks like. So I'm
inserting the data into
a sort of a persistent
structure. So in
this case, I did
financial records,
just as a good example.
So these are like
test companies.
Then these are the
records. So these
would be data
relating to it, just
simple quarterly data.
And then I've got
a sequence that
basically just tells
you the results. I'm
using this in place
of what would
normally be a vector
and I'm essentially
running structured SQL
as part of the
RAG process itself
rather than a vector
similarity search.
Let's go back
to the diagram
which illustrates it.
Here we go.
Where is it? Here we go.
So it's this layer
here in the middle.
And then I'm passing
the information
from the database
to a prompt cache.
And that's what
gives it the speed.
Cool. So you're
using the caching API
of the LLM vendor
to inject it? Yes,
exactly what I'm doing.
And then I'm using
TLS and pinging it
every now and then I'm
having multiple concurrent
prompt caches running.
And then this works
best for things at
scale where, you know,
you were trying to save
money, you know,
because you're doing a
lot of the same sort
of stuff. Let's say you
have like a finance
bot or something and
people are asking what
their, you know, latest
stock portfolio looks
like or whatever. And
then I'm just keeping
that cashed or, you
know, so if you're if
you're working at scale,
you know, 33 cents
adds up quite quickly.
What happens if
somebody asks a
question that's
not in the cash?
it will then make it
in the same way that
you instantiate the
tools, it'll make the
request update the
cache and subsequently
anyone else that makes
that request will
then get that if they're
approved, that is.
So you can, it's
all the same
general concepts
of a sort of rag
style approach
without the vector.
So I'm using as a
key for the cache?
The prompt?
it's a yeah
it's prompt yeah
it's data i'm
just static data
i'm just injecting the
data directly in the
in the prompt i'm
using the prompt cache
so you're saying that
you take that entire
sqlite database and
you dump that into the
cache and then flooded
that into the into the
cache of the model
yeah and then and then
every so every subsequent
request at that
point is free yeah
because you overloaded the
model's token cache
with the entire database
of data and then and
then if it's beyond
the 200k limit i just
i just chunk it into
multiple prompt caches
okay yeah so so this
is a this is a known
strategy where model
vendors say yeah just
put all your data we
have a million million
token cache or two
million token uh you
know you know context
window so just dump
all your data into the
into the token context
yeah sort of but i'm
because it's cached
it's not it's not doing
the the context
interpretation it's it's doing
the because i'm
predetermining the output
because it's cash so
what the the issue you
have a prompt with
uh prompt stuffing is
you've got the u-shaped
issue with with the
interpretation of the
data i'm doing zero
interpretation i'm
giving it explicit a
deterministic response
that's what the cache does
right i know exactly
what the response is
going to be i've
explicitly told it and and
then measured it so
and there's no variance
like you do with rag
you and with rag you
you can insert the data
10 times and get 10
different variants on
the output there is
no variance that is
true with rag there's a
major problem with
duplication and that and
uh you have to go
through a lot of the more
do you deduplicate the
data the higher your
answer performance
or your retrieval
performance exactly and
in this scenario i know
exactly what the output
is going to be and
i can measure it i
can it's because it's
deterministic i don't
want any variance on a
rag based system that's
the biggest issue
with rag is both speed
it's generally pretty
slow even the most
optimized systems are
pretty slow and there's
always this kind of
variance in the output
no matter how how much
you try to make it not
vary there's always
slight variance and for
certain applications
especially things
that involve numbers
mathematics and code
there's no room for
variation this solves
that problem true because
reg is a semantic
search not not and not a
deterministic search
so this is really well
i'm sorry how do you
predetermine the you you
say by predetermining
you know what is going
to be asked well i know
i know what's going
to be asked and what
and then i also know
what's going to be
output and i can and i
can create recursion
that allows me to either
measure and optimize
based on it based on
the sort of initial
which is basically going
back in here similar
similar to what i did
with the other
benchmarking tool i've got
different different
approaches that can define
you know my my structure
my my and the sort
of output and i can
optimize that so i get
the coherence that i'm
looking for like it
always gives me the same
answer based on what
i need it to be so i can
i can i can basically
benchmark it and
evaluate and optimize it
basically using almost
exactly the same
approach i use with the
spark benchmarking tool
it's a different
implementation for different
purposes but
conceptually i'm doing
reinforcement on it
yeah and and by the way
there's a really
cool new feature i
discovered it's not new
but new to me live share
have you guys seen
this you can uh you
guys can log in and
take a look at my uh
my live running git
uh code space oh i can
i can take control of
your of your terminal
right now yeah here
i'm gonna let you
guys do that share
read only terminal oh
that's pretty funny
all right rmrf we're
gonna have we're gonna
have 50 50 people
hacking on your uh on
your shell Here we go.
Let's do it. I'm going
to give you guys access.
I'm going to slap
it in the code.
There's nothing too
worse. There we go.
This one's the one. Let's
see what I have here.
Yeah. This is
just a feature.
Actually, before
I do, I'm going
to stop sharing
just for a sec,
check my biometer
variables
before I do
that. Yeah, yeah,
yeah. I was about
to say that.
It's all right.
We're here.
Thanks for having me.
Maybe later.
We'll come back
to that one.
I'm like, how long has it
been since we've
been hacked?
24 hours. There we go.
No. Anyway, how about
next time I do a live
coding session, I
will share the session
using that feature and
you guys will be able to
log in and we can do
collectively fool around
with the coding
instance or maybe I'll
just remove the environmental
variables and we
can do it a little
later but anyway that's
we can do code
roulette just have code
roulette whoever
gets selected has
to write a line and
we just keep going
oh man peer coding
vibe peer coding en
masse I know right it's
so fun yeah take a shot
exactly oh actually
know what i'm gonna
do i'm gonna i'm gonna
share the one where
i don't have any uh
environmental variables
i'm worried about but
we'll come back we'll
come back in the after
show we'll we'll uh
we'll do some collective
vibe coding or or
more like hacking roof
anyway the after potty
man that's really
that's really action
is in the after potty
all right i i want
to go 20 minutes by
somehow i managed
to go half an hour
so uh i'm gonna let
uh braun or whoever
else we have going
here take over
yeah we uh uh thanks
ru oh awesome um
we should give uh brad
a moment here he's
got some updates
for us and then and
then uh we'll bring in
uh ****** v3 uh brad
hey thank thanks a
lot i'll be really
quick uh The big, big
news is we're going
to be updating our
agentics.org website,
especially the member
services portion.
So we're calling
on anyone
that wants to help out.
We need tons of
tons of help.
We want to make sure
that we have an amazing
site. So when you go
in, you log in for
your free account, paid
account. We'll have
the events, the different
learning, learning
aspects, have these
videos available,
all the committee level
information, chapter
information. So it's
a big project looking
for anyone and everyone
that wants to be
involved. We're just
starting the process,
identifying different
vendors that should be
confirmed next week.
We're all ready to go.
I'll post the link in
the website and pre
-thanks to everyone that
wants to volunteer.
Thank you.
And just a reminder,
now that we have
the free GitHub
and Codespaces, is
there's a benefit
to you get some
free GitHub access,
at the very least.
Hopefully, I
think Martin said
he's working on
potentially getting
substantial
discount on Google
-related API and AI
-related tooling.
So 75% off, maybe
we can do something
there to get anyone
that contributes access
to those APIs as
well so you don't
have to work out your
own money on that.
Go, Martin.
yeah yeah do we
have possible
to form a company
oh sorry form
a company and
get a company
uh team access to
codex be a lot cheaper
than individual 200
bucks a month mark do you
need me to hire you
as an intern actually
actually funny you
mentioned that we that's
one of the reasons
why we created a non
-profit literally was
for that reason so the
by having a non-profit
almost all these
big companies, Amazons
and Googles and
whatever, all have non
-profit rates, which are
sometimes free, but
generally it's somewhere
between 25% to 75% off.
So we're leveraging
our non-profit status
to get cheap AI.
Right?
The other is
pushing forward
democratizing AI,
right? So I don't want
um those entities
to think that we're
not serious about
our mission we very
much are it just
happens to be that it
also you know the
collective will benefit
um the mission
that we're putting
forward all right
wonderful wonderful
okay do we have ******
hey guys i'm here
hey how are you good
good good good thanks
for uh for letting me
share y'all this is uh
super cool to see uh
what this is turning
into you know i just
like came in uh via a
linkedin post you know
like uh i don't know what
was it four or five
months ago and like
it's super cool to just
see how much this has
grown and how much
it's taken off very
validating my recent
career choices uh anyways
guys uh i i did something
uh like over the
last couple of weeks
kind of silly not as like
really serious or like
groundbreaking and
things just uh fun uh
for me i i've always
been into music um and
um i just got into coding
so um you know i
learned that uh you can
write music uh in python
code with like midi
right um and i was
like hey wait if the AI
can write code and the
AI can execute code.
I mean, all I have to
do is have it play the
MIDI file it makes
afterwards, right? So I
like totally vibe coded
this knowing nothing
about like synthesizers
or anything like
that. And what it ended
up doing was we used
an SF2 file. i'm sure
if you guys know about
this but a fluid synth
is like a like a old
school like python
synthesizer library and
what we do here you
guys hear it no no no i
didn't share right
hold on if you go back
there's an option to
share with audio yeah okay
cool all right i'll
replay that first so
so what the agent does
uh real simply um is
she takes your your
your request uh and then
And she starts writing
iterations of the song,
right? So the basic
one, I just pushed
enter on it. And that'll
give you like a basic
sort of electronic
upbeat music. So here's
the first beat. Lays
down the drums for us.
Everybody hears
that? Yeah.
We need a theme tune now.
Good to have Friday.
Okay, cool. So she threw
down the drum
beat for us.
Now it's going to
take that same code.
It looks at it and
it's like, OK, I need
to add another
instrument layer on
top of it. And it
needs to be cohesive.
It needs to like,
you know, so you can
imagine the amount of
like prompting like I
had to go through to
like get this thing to
do this right. So there's
like there's the initial
agent that writes
the code. Then there's
a validator agent
that goes through and
validates the code that
the agent wrote for
musical cohesiveness.
Then then it pushes
it like through and
it'll play the music
for us. The second one
usually takes a
little bit longer to
load, and if there's
an error, if the code
hits an error or
something, it'll actually
push it over to a,
oh, here we go, guys.
Oh,
right?
Not bad.
No, we are not
good hearing.
You guys don't hear it?
No.
The previous one.
I understand.
Yep.
Okay.
Here, I'll play
this. so here was the
second run for you
guys uh yeah i did hear
the first one i'm not
hearing the second one
okay here's the
second one yeah same
right same song right
another layer of uh
music on top of it another
layer of instrument
kind of cool right
still vibing it's
a little bit longer
i had it doubled the
length of music with
each time right um you
know that that was
a real fun thing for
our non-deterministic
AIs to figure out.
But I'll give you a
little peek into the
prompting here, guys.
I'm not blackboxing,
and it's open source.
Y'all can go to it.
I'll post the repo
after this. But we've
got an instrument list,
right? And this has
to follow. If you're
using this SF2 thing,
you have to look up
Weed's GM3, right? And
you have to learn
their instrument list.
Oh, we got another one.
This is a ******.
Wait, I'll play it for
you guys after it's
done playing locally
actually you're
creating waves as well
can you yeah yeah so
it turns the mini into
a wave file uh let's
say it's almost done
easy integrate pro
logic and you and you
you're now just get
the ai to create
every you know pop hit
for spotify yeah right
um so so it goes to
Okay, so here's the
third version, guys.
All right, another
layer on top of it.
So, yeah, that was
my project this
week. It works
pretty good with O3.
It's a lot of
fun. And then this
will just keep
going. It'll just
keep going and
going and going.
And then some improvements
I want to make.
I discovered this
library called Sonic
Pi. I don't know if
anybody's ever heard
of it before, but like
some dope like some
really dope synthesizer
sounds and stuff
william yeah please
forgive me for asking uh
what was the bottom
line theory on creating
this you you said in
the beginning and please
give me i was
distracted you said you
realized something and
that that was the bottom
line theory that led
to all of this yeah i
also said uh as a
disclaimer that this was
not a serious project
this was like a real
creative thing uh like
everybody knows that's
okay my my toddler is
dancing to your music
in the background oh
okay let's go so yeah
no i mean the idea was
like um we i was at i'm
at work and you know
my nine to five and
we're like really pushing
for like ai adoption
all this stuff so we
put together a little
crew of uh people to
to have a little agent
contest right um i
lost because i couldn't
get my midi agent up
in time but then i took
it home and kept building
it right i was like
hey wait if uh if the
ai like can run code
and midi you can write
that in python then
like theoretically
couldn't my agent sort of
write a song for me
and like be a sequencer
and like sort of develop
this musical thing
and i get it it's a
relationship between
midi and python correct
yeah yeah yeah yeah
and that and that i
could have the ai sort of
do that for me right
like because now it can
run code like autonomously
and execute it
so i was like oh well
i'm gonna make it you
play music for me why
not right so what did
you use root code what
did you use um i i
primarily use cursor um
i'm just a big fan of
cursor i keep a uh
language agnostic system
prompt sort of in the
cursor rules i'm still
a little old school on
that i haven't upgraded
to all the other stuff
but um and i utilize
a lot of the the
custom modes in cursor
so i'll make myself
like a you know python
mode a streamlet mode next
js all these different
modes and then um and
then yeah just kind
of vibe out like that
is is the model picking
the key and the
progressions and everything
yeah it picks everything
um and but you
can tell it uh in the
beginning that there's
like a prompt i just
i clicked enter and
it'll give you like
the the generic sort of
style which is just
upbeat electronic music it
never it never makes it
bad for me that one's
always good for demo
but um you can flip
it to classical you
can say hey play a jazz
song in a minor it
actually does pretty decent
with jazz because the
drums are like you
know sort of like the
same beat and the and
the bass line is just
uh you know walking
quarter notes so it does
pretty decent with jazz
it gets a little wonky
with the uh soloing
and stuff and syncopation
but well you know
we all say this not
country it's not music
who said that you
know back in the 90s
i i'm certainly um
aging myself for a
moment but But back
in the 90s, I used
to be a trance DJ,
like, circa 1996.
And my spot was,
like, 4 a.m. when
everyone was kind
of, you know,
drugged out and
done for the night.
My job is to come on
stage and basically
get everyone, you
know, out of their,
you know, ecstasy
phase, you know,
blown out phase
and do the big drop
and get one going
again. But anyway,
this would have been
amazing back then.
Thanks, guys. I
appreciate it. It was like
a silly thing. I
thought you guys would
appreciate it. So, cool.
I'll post the repo.
Hey, thanks, David.
Thanks, David. David,
the archivist, young
blood. Question.
Is LLM listening to
the music or just
working on the code
and refining the code?
Originally, A, I said,
hey, I need the AI to
listen to the music,
right? and i like and
i fiddle around trying
to get um the audio
to pick up on the the
open ai api like wow
like the so my my
speakers are playing music
and the microphone
listening doesn't work at
the same time i don't
know if anybody else
knows how to figure
that out but i could not
figure it out every
time that the um the
music played the
microphone turned off like
it like my system wouldn't
let it happen have
you tried sending
files have you tried
sending like um like
exported files no no i didn't
try sending the wave
file or anything but
dude you guys are like
super like welcome
to contribute i would
like yeah my son my
son vibed a uh an
interface for you he was
working on a very similar
uh project that he
wanted to create like
a he wanted to create a
sequencer that allowed
him to play his guitar
with a kind of band
yeah so and and what
he did he was using
i don't know what he
used actually but what
he did is he he allowed
the system to listen
and then it would
synchronize to how he
played because he his
his uh beat was not
constant so it would
basically much like a
band sort of changes its
tempo as you're playing
he managed to do
that and he's got a
whole little uh app that
does that i should
i should get him to
send it over yeah that
sounds cool that sounds
cool and we have
that we have this is
unrelated but you you
wrote in the chat you met
with the folks at long
shame and they want
to get can you explain
that a bit more
yeah yeah of course so
um i'm out in new york
guys um and um i'm i
work my nine to five
is at a company called
just works we do like
hr payroll and stuff
and we're doing some
things with langsmith
internally and uh
harris and chase was
in town and they were
you know of course
trying to get us to you
know sign the contract
so um they're like hey
come have coffee with
us and uh harrison's
gonna be there and i
was like hey i'm going
too so um yeah i
asked you know humbly
and i was like they let
me go um and i got to
shoot the **** with
harrison i told them
about agentix.org
everything that we're doing
i said hey you know
google like sponsored
the uh the agentix
.org uh meet up out in
london they had a great
turnout i think it'd
be a cool um you know
opportunity for you
guys to kind of, you
know, get involved
into more, you know,
really lock yourselves
into the grassroots,
open source, you know,
nonprofit thing that,
you know, where real
people are coding.
I also asked him the
question, somebody asked
me to ask him where he
thinks that OpenAI
went wrong in their
implementation of agents.
And I also asked him
how he felt about
getting dissed in their
documentation with the
land graph thing. And
he said that OpenAI is
just a consumer company
at this point uh it's
not really paying
that much attention
to them uh it doesn't
think that there's like
a lot of like developer
focus going into like
the product and this
is more so just like
hype and i disagree
he's obviously not
using the latest models
just defending himself
too so yeah yeah so just
it's the third time
this week i've heard
that just a quick just
a quick update if you
guys haven't seen
the responses api and
their integration with
their tools and now the
MCP integration
directly within both the
response and their
agentic system. Oh, sick.
I'm using it
all this week.
It's spectacular.
Like anyone telling
you that they're
not paying attention
to developers
is not paying
attention to OpenAI.
Oh, yeah. Let's go.
So anyways, that's
what he said. But so
I also mentioned, so
JustWorks, we are open
to having like events
here, like for this
AI kind of thing.
So I was thinking it
would be dope to have,
you know laying chain
uh with the agent
x.org have their new
york meet up at the
just works office here
we got a great space
for it so it's trying
to set that up we
have folks in new york
city where they at yeah
so real sorry hang on
about the background
noise my bad um uh
real quick sharing a
link just you reminded
me uh ****** of uh
and great great stuff
by the way and your
new website updates
also pretty fly uh with
the bel-air theme on
it um but there's a
link here there's a
project somebody did
and they used a an
old uh library called
jitterbit and they what
they did was they you
know programmed ai
to talk to itself and
it started to create
its own language and
so it's using like
high frequency sound
yeah to allow ai to
communicate and it reparses
the sound into, you
know, its own language
and it's able to
have a conversation.
And there's like a
future application
of this where
AI is going to
be able to
communicate, you know,
interoperably within
systems through,
you know,
Internet of Things type
technology. And you're
like microwave and
fridge and computer and
watch and phone are
all going to be able
to help you like get
through your day. Like
that's that's what's
coming when people put
this together. but this
jitter bit's kind of
a preview to how it
can use like you know
hypersonic frequencies
to communicate it's it's
absolutely crazy that
was actually that was
like six months ago
that thing came out that
jitter bit came out
and it never really
took off but it was
pretty impressive like um
i think it took off
yeah the the demo i saw
i saw was when um some
guy was on his phone
talking and and an ai
answered and he was
like they they he
recognized that there were
the two ais talking so
they said do you want
to do you want to talk
jitter and he was like
yeah and so they just
they just started
talking wasn't that a
concept piece though i
didn't think it was real
yeah it's real there's
code i think it's real
okay there's a link
it's a link it was a
mock-up demo yeah it's
on gay happen it was
concept all right um
guys we we we got we
got we got some we get a
bit of backlog, but
before we do, I see an
old buddy of mine on
the call, John Willis,
who is like the
godfather of DevOps. Hey,
John, hopefully he's
paying attention because
I'm putting him on the
spot here. You there?
If he isn't, we'll
have to come back to
him. But it's always
amazing the people
we get on these calls.
And the folks you
don't actually see
or hear are sometimes
the most interesting
crew we get here.
Hopefully I'll ping
John and see if I can
get him. He's about
to do audio right now.
Yeah.
All right.
I think we have Bron up
next. Yeah, that's right.
Bron. Yeah.
All right.
Let me see here.
Screen share.
Okay.
Desktop.
This one here.
All right.
Okay. So I don't know
if you guys have been
following NVIDIA. If
you haven't watched
their last keynote,
I'd go through it. some
pretty insane stuff these
guys are saying things
like million parameter
model on desktops
but video is going
hard i guess trying to
sell hardware so
they're also working on
models and if you look
at the current asr
leaderboard their their
model is crushing everyone
this parakeet is at
6.5 word error rate
but its output is 30
to you know 100 times
faster than anything
I've ever seen.
And if you, you know,
when you're coding,
usually it's pretty
hard to beat the cloud.
So let me see, I got
to move this out of the
way. But, you know, if
I looked at, I looked
at, where is it here?
So these are like
the top current audio
to transcript systems
you know deep gram open
ai whisper so right
now i'm hosting that
nvidia system on my own
uh stack with a commodity
card rtx 3600 and
this is this is like
40 to 300 times less
expensive uh than the
major tiers and you know
their their takeaway
summary 120 times rtf
and you know this their
summary is pipeline
currently enterprise
great accuracy two orders
of magnitude lower cost
than any mainstream
sas state-of-the-art
so i took it and i i
talked i got these
clients that want to build
a transcript system
for medical dental so
here i'll fire up the
recording and uh clear
this and let's see
here i'll try to get uh
some text
going. So, okay.
All right. We
are live testing
the speed of
speech-to-text with
AI Hackerspace
Friday, May 23rd.
Let's see. This pipeline
delivers enterprise
-grade accuracy at
hundreds of times lower
cost than any mainstream
cloud with state
-of-the-art speed on
commodity hardware.
I can even do
timestamping. So,
this will do real
-time timestamping.
I can turn
that on or off.
So,
at 6.5% error
rate, that is super
low, which means
it's usable. And
after this is
done, you can
combine your audio
to make a wave.
You can also go through
transcript editing,
so you can load up
your old transcripts,
take a look at them.
These would be
your audio, so
when you talk,
it's chunking it,
it'll recombine
it into these
audio systems, so you
can replay, you know,
replay your text.
And this will,
I'll do a one
-up, this thing
can do a one-hour
audio, so I took
this podcast,
let's see here I'll
grab it uh so this is a
one hour podcast because
I had another guy
that wanted to do um
podcast summaries so
that's why I was kind
of in this space but um
this we can do a live
uh transcribe of a full
hour of audio you
gotta remember this is
like a regular graphics
card this RTX 3600.
Okay so we'll fire
it up and this is
starting the processing.
What I had to do is
all the audio has
to be converted
to 16k mono and
so first what
it'll do is
it'll convert it
with FFmpeg
then it'll chunk
it into 30
second chunks and
then it'll feed
it into the LM.
so pretty soon
you'll see the
chunking starting
up that's how you
can fit it into
a commodity card
so we're at what
do we have here 30
seconds so this is
every you can see it's
going at more than
one chunk per second
so that's feeding
um you know i don't
know five minutes
every half second or
something into this
thing so we're at 46
so hopefully we can
break a minute 54 55
getting close okay so
there we did it we did as
a full hour podcast
transcribed with time
stamps in one minute
and this machine cost me
30 cents an hour so
you can imagine i can
do 120 hours of
transcribing for 30 cents so
this is pretty insane
like most like you take
llama or any of these
regular models and
usually they're getting
crushed by clod or open
ai but that's why i'm
saying you know we
gotta pay attention
to these guys because
these guys are building
star center 200 billion
dollar data centers
and looks like they're
saying well how do we
get more people to buy
nvidia well let's make
uh models that need
hardware right so um
i don't know if we're
getting to trillion
parameter model on a
motherboard in the next
year i think we're getting
pretty close to you
know agi or whatever
you want to call it
but uh you if you are
into uh speech to text
um like i say you can
you can do a rundown
with oh three uh this is
pretty nuts you know if
you look at the costs
like uh these top
ones would be like you
know three hundred and
fifty thousand dollars
to do the same thing
right as opposed to 30
cents yeah it's just
you can it's almost
free like it's it's you
know like the it's the
surprising thing is
the quality right at 6
.5 percent word error
rate um this is top
level like you you you
know i can't name one
other uh open source
commodity runs on your
graphics card lm that
can totally wipe out the
major players like
that's that's the first
time i've ever seen it
and you know usually
you try it like i tried
the sesame they only
released like the 1b
version of sesame and
it ****** like it was
terrible i most of the
things you try when
you have a guy saying
here you know try my
try my model out it's
nowhere near enterprise
grade it's it's sort
of there's you know proven
there's an interesting
approach that i've
been doing and you
guys probably can't
hear it because i've got
my noise canceling going
on here but it sounds
if you were to step
into my office right
now it sounds like a
jet plane and what what
i've been doing is i've
been daisy-chaining
low-cost mobile GPUs
using the eGPU enclosures
that I ordered from
AliExpress in China.
And then what I do is
I connect that to my
system using
Thunderbolt. And I can
basically run, I think
it's six mobile GPUs in
parallel independently
of my core system.
And I can get all kinds
of crazy stuff out
of it. And the fact
that I could probably
use not mobile GPUs,
but mobile gpus are
cheap out of china
you can get them for
like 50 bucks and um
yeah and then then i
just run those in
parallel but what braun's
showing would be was
like a perfect sort
of application for
that kind of thing if
if you're interested
in that in in those
types of uh structures
here pick their standard
like uh 3600 um gpu
do you think that
the performance you
get out of a higher a
higher price one would
give you a higher
performance or Or is
it better today? No,
I'm using the Snapdragon
or whatever. It's
the GPU you get in
like an Android device.
And it's dirt cheap.
I can get them.
I think I can
get them for less
than 50 bucks,
which is like $30
American. I'm using
Canadian money.
Snapdragon's a
Qualcomm chip.
Yeah, you get them
super cheap out of
China. And for most
things, you just need
parallel, right? So
GPUs, they don't need
to be really
particularly powerful at
this point. They just
need to be paralyzable,
right? I need to
be able to send a
bunch of a bunch of
things to it and get
it done in sequence
versus, you know,
my CPU is kind of
bound by by running
Windows or Mac or
whatever. Can we share some
actual product things
like which GPU?
Because I've been
shopping around. And if
you find what I found
a reliable supply in
China, I'd be up for
it. Yeah, I just sent
a I sent a link to the
site. It's in the text
chat. i just go to
aliexpress now i i
someone told me i was
i was telling this to
someone else here this
week in the united
states apparently
there's like some kind of
crazy tariff they slap
on for americans right
now so if it's 50
dollars it'll end up
being like 100 for you
but if you're outside
of the u.s it's definitely
cheap should make
it cheaper for us yeah
that's right that's
right well just before
we uh we wrap up
for the main hour uh
guys we're uh we've got
uh bensa here he's going
to give us a little
recap about the london
uk and just a note
for for folks that are
thinking they would
like to establish a
local chapter or have
some local events
there's the agenex.org
slash ambassador page
that's got the form to
become an ambassador
and there's the
ambassador's channel in
the discord uh and in
there all there's all
the key documents are
pinned as well so please
feel free to put your
hand up there's about
uh there was over
60 originally and then
30 have come through
the process. There's a
bunch of places around
the world that are
about to get started.
So we welcome everybody
to hop onto that.
Bensa, you've
got some pictures
and a review there
of the big event
you had at the
Google office.
Yeah, I'll be quick.
It is a wonderful
venue at Google, and
we made a perfect
teamwork with
Mondrip and rocky and
mark and so on um so
i'm gonna share my
screen uh yeah can
you guys see it now
wait the desktop
yes yeah yeah yeah
so that this is
the reception with
uh requestee co
-founder the Tibo.
This is the building
outside. It's
a very nice area of
London, very sunny
and summer, real
summer afternoon.
This is the prep
before the event.
And then Tibo is
giving an intro.
The room was
very interesting.
Mark sponsored us
the roll-up with the
logo and the message
then Ruv joined in
via Zoom, that was
cool as well and then
Chris had a very
nice lecture
live teaching of Spark
and other methods
that he found useful
and people enjoyed it
a lot and we made the
interviews as well
we're going to
publish them
in this style you
know the one-to-one uh
interviews with
participants wonderful uh
yeah so a lot lots
of pictures videos uh
it was a incredible
uh you know like vibe
and feeling uh to to
do this live there
are some learnings uh
for other cities we're
gonna uh publish
them that's cool nice
that's awesome good
good job on that i i've
got several people
reach out as well that
said they learned a
ton and it was a great
uh great time you know
so thank you um you
know for putting all
that together well
cool yeah i just wanted
uh to share recently
i've built a 30 agent
agent orchestration
in root code that
basically codes out
anything you could dream
of and so what I've
got it set with is
building a better version
of itself and what
that ends up being is
a symbiotic coder you
can kind of think of
Venom from Spider-Man
that's a symbiote but
instead of giving you
superpowers it turns
you into a super coder
you know it talks
to you it teaches you
it guides you on top
of being a coder and
I've been live streaming
the thing building
itself on YouTube
and so if you want to
check out my YouTube
channel or LinkedIn I
put some links in the
chat and uh cool
there's like 20 hours
plus of it running so
far it's quite amazing
yeah so let's you you
have something to show us
put you on the spot
here yeah sure i mean i
have it running right
now yeah let's see it
i i love your experiments
they're always so
exciting yeah so so
it's got a a shared
memory system that it
um through that i used
through the super base
mcp i kind of just set
that up last night but
what it is building
is actually a neo4j
knowledge graph it's
already built out the
brain that was like step
one and essentially it
it documents everything
right the research sets
up you know testing
documentation high level
testing documentation
like architecture
like everything is
documented out and
it can access all the
documentation through
the super base mcp tool
and this is a way of
being able to share um
like say a 50 plus
million quote-unquote
synthesized context window
amongst all 30 agents
and they can just
and the orchestrators
then have access to this
and then the orchestrators
there's like 10
orchestrators and they
all have access to say
like 20 workers and
these orchestrators
then can use the the
documentation to be able
to guide the workers
very very precisely
with full context and
uh and you can shift
the entire orchestration
you know you can you
can you can maneuver
it in any way you want
because it basically
it follows a memory
system and a document
registry and like like
for instance it was uh
it was coding this
thing out and then i was
like hey let's let's
see if we can make
this more autonomous
you know i had it do
research on abstract goal
understanding creative
problem solving
ethical reasoning novel
architecture design
and so then it did a
complete shift reworked
the prd redid all the
tests and now it's
um getting this fully
implemented into the
system as well you know
it's got like a github
deep researcher um
it searched github for
templates and that's
how it pulled up
its front end it's
identified a front end
that would be suitable
this is essentially an
ai powered ide but it's
a coding symbiote is
ultimately what being
goes you know you
know what you should
consider i love what
you're doing by the way
but you know what you
should consider just
to save some money on
your contacts window
because that all those
md files likely are
going to be loaded you
know into the contacts
for um you know it
looks like you're
using Roo, I think.
If you switch to like
SQLite or DuckDB, you
can take all that data,
stuff it into a
SQLite, and then
create a really small
Python CLI or MCP
that basically
queries it. And then
you don't have
to parse all that
and it'll save you
probably like 80%.
Yeah, I could. But
I mean, this is just
temporary because really
it's just building a
better version of itself
and the new version
is is being basically
graphed out in neo4j
in like a multi-dimensional
graph that graphs
out functions like
all the relationships
between code in
different languages um as
well as you know everything
that you're telling
it gets graphed in
and uh through like
the multiple layers of
the graph through like
cosine similarity
and a bunch of other
stuff it it basically
brings it to life and
like that's how it's
like basically sentiment
or is going to be
sentient to be able to
fully understand your
code identify security
tech debt like
everything cool so and uh
what model are you using
these days i'm using
so for every part of
my orchestration i'm
using gemini except
the test writer and the
coder that's the clod
for clod clod just banks
this stuff out of the
park i know yeah don't
use don't use opus
it's it don't use no no
not do it yeah don't
do that i spent three
hundred dollars so you
don't have to yeah yeah
thank you but but
gemini is cool because
you know it can take
all the context from all
the documents and
then you know use that
context the larger context
window to then issue
the commands and then
you see like the tasks
and and also you know
the coder and everything
is everything is
doing self-reflection
everything is doing ai
verifiable end results
like um so it's being
specifically told
you know to self-reflect
and by ai verifiable
end results it means
that like the end result
is something that ai
100 knows i've reached
this point there is
no subjectivity in the
entire 30 agent
orchestration whatsoever
that is very important
so that there is never
any miscommunication
and then like and then
it even tells the modes
it's like okay i need
you to do this do this
do this this is the
exact document where
this is documented these
are the exact files
where the issue is going
on like my workers
know have full context
of every move they're
making right it's like
having the software
developer giving full
context but my orchestration
is able to just
autonomously do that
right it's like Like,
it is the software
developer, right? That's
pretty much why it took
10 orchestrators to,
yeah.
All right.
We got with Shep.
We'll have to
come back to your
sentient thing,
I'm sure, but I'm
not going to touch
that just yet.
But Shep, how's it going?
It's going well.
I have a couple things
that I'm keen to
share here. I know we've
kind of been working
on the AI Hacker League
in the background
for a while. it's
been a minute since i
checked in but um as
part of my hunt for a cto
for penumbra i'm doing
a like hyper agent
olympics where it's
basically a one hour
challenge that is you
know imagine leak code
but for like an agentic
engineer so it's a
timed challenge of
like how much of this
crazy agentic spec can
you build um and it's
like scored based on
points and stuff i'll
bring up the uh the
notion page really
quickly so you guys can
just see idea neat what
that is but i'm
mentioning it because like
it's this group right
this is very much
like our dna thinking
about this kind of
thing and also it
could be an interesting
application of like ai
hacker league collaboration
um let me see can
you guys see this i
will assume yes it's
warming it's warming up
it'll it'll it'll take
a sec okay drum roll
if it takes too long
i'll just uh i'll give
up and i'll talk to
it i'm not sure why it
uh seems to be it might
just be my computer
limited bandwidth or
yeah i don't know i'll
talk you guys through
it basically it's got
uh four components
where you know you're
building a specific like
agent ecosystem called
neuronexus it's like
a live agentic system
that includes agent
orchestration so you
implement a multi
-agent system using your
orchestration library
of choice you build a
few different like design
patterns so planner
executor orchestrator
tool user you have to
demonstrate like an
mcp integration bonus
points for incorporating
a2a agent to agent
there's a second section
for knowledge and
retrieval so So like
build a knowledge graph
and graph rag into it
and a vector search.
There's like multi
-modalities. So can
you integrate more
than one thing,
like not just text?
Can you incorporate
vision? Can you
incorporate audio?
And kind of build out
some demo pipelines
for searching across
different modalities. And
then the last two are
kind of like tool use.
So building like a
plug-in system, like a
dynamic plug-in tool
calling suite that you
can hot swap tools in
and some personalization.
So like build a
memory graph into it.
it's honestly like the
full bag of things that
you can do with agents
but i'm really really
keen to see can
someone actually build
this thing this crazy
aspect in one hour and
kind of try and build
like an elo score for
it right we've got uh
the lean ai leaderboards
like all these different
leaderboards and
ai i feel like uh
this is kind of a cool
thing for agentic engineers
to sort of try their
hand at try their
system right because
we're all building our
own sort of tweaks on
these setups like spark
and pharaoh mind and
you know the cursor
agent um so yeah i just
thought i'd share that
with you guys because
it's it's kind of cool
and i would love to
you know figure out how
ai hacker league fits
into this too i think
the um there's two
two opposing thoughts
right now in terms of
speed and output you
know and and as you guys
know a lot of times
people hire me for an
hour to build some crazy
idea that they have
and that's all they
get from month for me.
And so when all
you have to do
the challenge,
Reuben. Yeah.
Yeah. Like they literally
hired me to VibeCo
for an hour. Like
I get this idea for
a startup that I'm
going to pitch a VC
tomorrow and I need you
to build it for me in
an hour. And I'm like,
all right, let's do
this. But to do an
hour build means that
I need to skip a lot
of the upfront planning
and structure, right?
So when you look
at Spark, it does a
ton of documentation,
phased implementation
strategy, the London
School of Test-Driven
Development, which
is essentially a test
-driven scaffolding
that basically allows
for the test to
determine the architecture
of the application.
That allows me to run
these things in what I
call a long horizon,
meaning that hours or
potentially the longest
one I've done is about
36 hours, but they
don't want me to run
for 36 hours. So I do
the inverse i i skip a
lot of that and i i go
right to the sort of
test strip excuse me
test room development
and then work from the
top down so yes you
could totally build
that an hour but you're
you're going to get to
a sort of rudimentary uh
you know test output
um it really depends
what you're building
but there's a little bit
you know the the demo
i gave you guys earlier
of that fact system
you know i was able
after i did the actual
implementation of the
plan and the structure
that literally took an
hour and and when i
ran sec against it they
said it was two minute
two and a half million
dollars worth of value
if you believe that
**** yeah i think the
testing phase obviously
is like super important
and part of the
challenge with hopping
in the saddle with like
a one hour challenge
is you have to already
be opinionated a little
bit about how you'd
like to approach it
and like designate
those things up front
you know it's i think uh
you have to have
your your mileage
on the road to
actually sit down
and build something
that's like
effective in an hour
uh system yeah exactly
can i have a quick
question yeah go ahead
yeah so the speed uh
maybe in europe is a
little bit different
but you know close seven
and now close four 3
.7 and now four uh is
a little bit slow
you know you you chef
you mentioned an hour
and ru was speaks about
speed but i i'm at
least personally on my
side i i limited by
time you know that as
the as the code is
streaming is extremely
slow that uh you know
stop and go stop and go
uh how do you handle
that oh well there's
if you're using ru
just make sure you here
let me you're talking
probably klein or
cursor which is doing
a sort of line by line
writing in rue make
sure you turn this on
and i i i try all of
my times i kind of want
to try other ones that
are but i can't find
anything that's as
good but if you go in
here into where is it
so i keep mass precision
somewhere in this
general ballpark that
that speeds it up but
editing through dips
that this right here
is the most important
thing so and what i
noticed with um sonnet
three four it's now
able to do dips that
are i did a dip earlier
this morning that was
800 lines in a single
in a single go so
this is this is if
anything else other than
like the orchestration
capabilities this is
huge make sure that's
on cool thanks and
and precision so so
the lower the position,
the larger the depth.
So if you want to do
like a 1500 line dip,
pop that down to 80%.
Yeah. And by the way,
and by the way, guys,
there's eight people
currently logged in.
Let's see. Oh, can
we, we can chat here.
Let's, we should sort
of figure out how to
do some live coding
with this approach.
Maybe next week
we could do a,
use this live
option here to
do like a like
a collaborative
vibe that would be
a real hackathon
how do you open
the chat window
I just found
it a second ago
let's see here
is it shared? no
I guess I'm in now I can
see what you
guys are doing
by the way you may
want to rotate that
Composio link later
I rotate it every day
yeah a quick question
on um aliexpress do
you only buy enclosures
on aliexpress or
graphics cards as well
oh i buy the i buy
the graphics card
i um the cheapest
graphic card you can
get is actually in a uh
one of those desktop
tv boxes you buy you
can buy like a tv box
with android 15 and
inside of that comes
a little snapdragon
25 bucks okay so i
should look for a
snapdragon No, you
should look for a, like,
what the **** they call
it, Android TV box.
Okay. And the great
news is now that the
U.S. has banned China,
you can get these
things in, like,
three days in Canada.
So the best thing ever
for, like, AliExpress
was when they stopped
shipping to the U.S.
It went from,
like, two or three
weeks to two
or three days.
Thank you. Would
that give us a big
enough RAM on the
graphics card?
Because Brian was
saying like 20 gig.
Or do you disagree?
Yeah, it depends what
you're doing. It's
like if you don't
mind running parallel
processes, you're going
to have to probably
create a – you can
vibe your own driver.
Like, you know,
I'm building
custom stuff. One can.
Not necessarily I
can, nor does that –
should be that my
priority. So it comes,
like, for $36, I see
here, 8 gigs and 128
gigabytes of storage
and a Snapdragon.
Here, I just randomly
found one while I was
on the site. You
can do all kinds of
hacking with this stuff.
And it's Android. It's
literally just a
mobile phone in a box.
Sure.
Those are good for,
like, any cloud. But if
you don't have NVIDIA,
CUDA, you can't do
nothing with it. That's
what I was saying.
nvidia is only building
stuff for their
hardware with and they
don't yeah that's how
they crushed amd and
everyone because if
you don't have cuda
you can't run lms yeah
you can and you you
could but you can't run
enterprise crushing
lms with when you're
not going to run in
you're not going to run
the enterprise crushing
on on a 25 android
box so if you want to
do what i was saying
just to clear but i
won't do what bram was
saying so what i'm
looking for is a graphics
card that needs that
criteria oh you'd have
to go i mean i wouldn't
buy one uh martin
i can i can show you how
you could just borrow
them from the cloud
you get them on google
amazon anywhere like
you've done you can
get you let's i mean
the 35 cents include is
basically the cost to
rent the card that's
it so like you that's
how because it's it'll
be like if you want
to rent uh high-end
graphics card it's
about let's say 150 of a
a month but you can
borrow you can rent them
per minute literally
or per hour right okay
well i don't have
enough load to justify
uh purchasing it but i
have you look at yeah
well okay i'll put it
up i'll put up the api
per minute api and give
you an api then you
can run it it'll it
costs nothing and it'll
just spin up the vm
fire up the app and
then run for 30 seconds
and die simple perfect
yeah yeah it's you
guys i'm just hacking
for the sake of hacking
i'm not looking to
you know i just want to
see if i can you know
throw out a a daisy
chain series of android
boxes that i can do
various you know tasks
with like i'm well
those are cool those are
like the raspberry pi
and all those small
hardware boxes can
do like i used to use
those for pcs you can
put ubuntu on those or
sometimes even windows
and now you've got a
25 desktop eight gigs
is enough for i mean i
used to do that on
four gig four gig four
gig ram boxes and they
could run windows so
yeah exactly it's it's
sometimes you're just
doing stuff because
you can there's no real
reason other than
just to see what what
you can do uh scott you
you got a comment hey
yeah so i've been
trying to do a lot of um
like automated builds
but like the one
thing i keep running
into is documentation
is like usually behind
where like if i'm
like say hey i want
to make an open ai
calling app and it'll
like try to use the
wrong api do you
guys have any like oh
yeah bulletproof ways
to handle that because
yes always limits
context context seven
context seven is
probably the best mcp
bar none for just
massive amounts of up-to
-date documentation what
i do i use a combination
of context seven
and perplexity and
then i just point at
that and see before i
even start i'm like
give me all the most up
-to-date information
on whatever API SDK or
whatever and then I
pointed at context seven
and I said go go create
a docs folder with
everything I need to
know or whatever the
API needs to know and
then I combine that
with the other
components and then I let
spark or whatever I'm
using go do its thing
context seven that'll
is that like pulling
all the latest
documentation throwing them
into like dot md files
for you and then yeah
here let me it'll go
read that as you fun
yeah it's it's it's
spectacular okay cool
that's great um and
then like for like stuff
where it's like very
specific i guess i so
like if you have like
a very specific like
scientific library
that you need to throw
in so you can do special
stuff can contact
seven do that too
or is it worth just
grabbing the docs
themselves and throwing in
their manually a lot
of my projects are
ridiculously complicated
scientific work right
i you know i demoed
that uh multiplexing
5g uh you know asic
chip thing you know
and now i'm working
on a drug a drug trial
there's no limit yeah
yeah it's it's uh you
can do anything good
cool awesome thanks
for that i appreciate
it yep context seven
is the way to go it's
the i think 12 000
different docs is pay
attention to the version
or be specific about
the version of the
library you're using
with context seven.
Okay. Yeah. Well,
here's what I do. It
brings up a really good
point. Point context
seven at your
requirements.txt or your
package.json or whatever
and say basically
create the documentation
based on that.
Inversely, if you're
vibing it and you're
using like deep research
or something get it
to you know suggest
the most recent package
and then point it at
that you just ask it
hey what's the latest
yeah exactly and and
the if you if you're
vibing the member when
you're vibing it's likely
going to vibe based
on the stat that what
it was trained on a
year and a half ago so
when you add context
seven or even perplexity
as part of your
initial sort of research
phase it'll it'll give
you the most recent
version and what a
perfect example of that
is is when you are using
like open ai it has
a tendency to give
you the chat completion
or chat completions
plural which is also
right no one's building
with chat completions
unless you don't know
what you're doing if
you're building right
now you're going to
build responses because
it's better it's
faster it's got better
tooling but basically
it was invented after it
was trained so these
language models don't
even know that it
exists okay oh yeah all
right we're almost at
a time and i've got a
hard stop at the bottom
of the hour because
you know non-stop calls
today one of those
days um anything else
you guys want to cover
any comments any anyone
want to this is this
is the open mic
portion we got a couple
more minutes that's
going to be so fast okay
can i yeah go for it
okay uh i just want to
ask about uh what has
been written in the
whatsapp about cloud
with sonnet plus oppos
for not using the api
which is you know you
are confirming that
oppos is so expensive
but i think there is a
way that i think pascal
wrote it wrote it down
in the whatsapp to
link club code with uh
you know with the pro
or max account with
cloud you know something
about this how you
can save it you know
on use i've done that
it's definitely saved
me a ton of money i'm
starting to hit rate
limits now uh but it's
been absurd how much
i can get away with
with just the hundred
dollar a month planning
cloud code uh so it's
that what pascal wrote
down right how to do
it uh you link like
the two accounts and
then you can use it and
you save a lot right
yeah when you set up
cloud code for the
first time it'll ask
you do you want to
use the api or do you
want to hook it up
to your account but
you do need a max
one of the max accounts
to do that. Okay,
fine. Thanks a lot.
Now that it's
confirmed. And by
the way, I did
the same thing
with the Codex
project last week.
And Codex is unlimited.
So what I ended
up doing was jumping
back and forth
between Codex and a
sort of code space
that was connected
to the same GitHub.
And then for certain
things, I just get
Codex to do it because
it was cheaper,
like run the tests or
whatever and uh i i
was able to greatly
reduce my costs by having
codecs do some of the
grunt work now certain
things it's just better
to get you know kind
of the spark approach
but what once you've
got the roof of files
in codecs it kind of
picks up on your
preferred development
methodology and kind of
adopts the same general
structure uh guy no i
was just gonna say joseph
if she if he knows
uh what is the amount
like 2x or 4x you know
between using or not
using it how how much
is saving you i mean
how percentage i just
started using it this
month so i'll tell
you at the end of this
month but you know again
the drawback right is
like i'm not using
klein or rue which you
know has a little more
control over things but
i don't know i've been
really enjoying cloud
code it's actually
doing most of what i
need to do but if you're
trying to do stuff
like rubs doing right
where you just like
leave it and let it go
forever that's not what
this is for this is more
for like refactoring
existing things or
kind of working on
existing things not like
starting from scratch
yeah which is what i'm
doing yeah okay thanks
a lot yeah and keep
in mind you know i i'm
i've got to a point
after years of trial and
error to be able to
run things for 36 hours
generally speaking
i'm not running for 36
hours as i pointed out
earlier i'm running
for a couple hours maybe
three hours testing
fixing adapting you
know if if you're if
you're thinking you're
going to run this for 36
hours and build the
next biggest app ever
you're probably not
you know there's most
things don't need to run
more than three hours
on opening as acquisition
of johnny ives company
nothing nothing
positive it was such a
nothing video like there
was there was nothing
that they said that
was worthwhile in
that video it reminds
me of like my daughter
her best friends
video where they have
little hearts coming
out and oh it's a love
fest okay great good
good for you guys.
I guess it's
who you know.
There, that's all I got.
Yeah, OpenAI is
like a love-hate
relationship. Generally,
they're freaking
evil, but they do
some really nice tech.
I know to willie's
point earlier, they're
doing some great
stuff with their API,
without question, but
they're also doing
some bonkers stuff
with their partnerships
with the Middle East
and government and
stuff that really
rubs me the wrong way.
Yeah, that's it.
That's all I'm
willing to say
at this point
before I end up
in a foreign jail.
So just as a quick
snippet while it's there
and before you close
it, there's two files,
actually three, Shep
threw one up too, but
there's two files that
are tools that I've
created with AI. They're
drafts. You can, you
know, refactor them
all you want. But
basically just wanted a
streamlined, unified way
to, regardless of
project, regardless of
library, regardless of
languages, et cetera,
create a universal
source of truth as a
catalog of technology,
libraries, versions that
can be pointed to when
prompting the AI to
make sure we're going
for the latest docs via
Context 7 or other
things. So those two
files are simple little
tools as file to insert
to your repo that can
help out with that.
all right oh by the
way for all the people
that are logged into
that session i only
enable read only um
just as an fyi all right
so we next week let's
maybe on thursday
we can do a joint uh
hacking session using
the live options see
what we can collectively
create together when
is your o'reilly
uh oh uh yeah i should
probably promote
that i think it's on
29 i'm doing a i'm
doing a live data
science um session with
o'reilly next week and
it's pretty cool i'm
just going to show you
how to do basically
vibe data science
and i created some of
the guys tuned in
yesterday you saw the
presentation and like so
there's a whole system
i've devised to do
that if you're in the
afternoon what's the
time of it i have no
idea i'm a robot it's
um it's 11 eastern
well that's the
whole session
but Ruv's just one
of the speakers
I think I'm like
I'm middle of the
pack, I think it's
three hours I'm
a couple hours
in or something
I'll post it to the
chat and also to
Discord
gotta go guys,
I'm late for my
next call thanks
everyone again
thanks Martin,
Robert, everybody
alright, till next time
thank you, bye thank you