All right. Top of the
hour. And my apologies.
I know I sent this
out literally a half
an hour ago. Usually
I try to get this
out a little earlier.
Maybe we can get a
better weekly cadence
where maybe I publish
the Zoom and whatnot
ahead of time, maybe on
Mondays or maybe for
the next few weeks.
So anyway, let's get
right to it. Another
amazing week. Not
quite as crazy as last
week. When you look
at all the things that
came out last week,
last week might have...
reuben's frozen
oh there you go
we got you back
we got your back
my internet connection
is unstable oh you
know i'm not doing i'm
not live i'm not live
streaming this either
this week's is is
just i'm i'm i've got
a little too much on my
plate i'm not gonna
live stream today i
guess i hopefully i'm
coming through okay um
so can you guys am i
am i am i am i good
now you yeah okay so
there was a bit of a
rant there about the
last week being the the
craziest week ever but
anyway this week is
is is obviously uh i
i'm exciting one we've
got a great lineup of
folks on on the show
today um rob good good
to see you who did
you uh manage to line
up for us this week
yeah you too roof and
it was good to see you
on the on the super
stream that was a heck
of a thing i think there
was what 600 people
or was it 1700 i
can't remember i don't
i don't pay i don't
pay that close just do
your thing yeah a few
breaks along the way
there right we've got
uh so today we've got
arcade dev and um
uh and then as well
defang so a couple different
um deployment tools
and um and connectivity
tools and then
we have a braun field
walker and braun's got
said the next evolution
of his visually
enhanced brainstorming
platform so some pretty
neat stuff that we're
going to see today
nice yeah i was i
was hoping we're
going to get a
chance to see a
little bit of
fact is that right
yeah then that that seems
like ancient history
at this point that
that was done on on uh
monday and now it's
friday it's like you
know and and these are
projects that i'm doing
when we we actually you
know over the weekend
so this is a perfect
example of a kind of
long horizon uh type
of application and you
know what I don't
find if long horizons
like a thing that's what
I call it maybe some
other people call it
other things but yeah
long horizon is the
idea that I can build
something over an extended
yeah yeah extend a
period of time oh getting
some feedback here
all right sorry that
the the feedback loop
feedbacks in my brain
stops in the brain from
thinking anyway um
long horizon so when
when you have something
that needs to run for
an extended period
of time now i'm i'm
constantly getting this
this call that are saying
how can you can run
this for for for 36
hours and i can't get
this to run for more than
two hours and now i
get garbage and i and
this is something i've
been struggling to
answer like i and i don't
necessarily know you
know it the the answer
of like it works for
me but doesn't work for
you is an interesting
one. And I think
there's nuance in the
things that I'm building
and the way that I'm
prompting it that
allows it to sort of
iteratively build these
components. Now, when
I'm using the idea of
long horizon development,
there's still a step
-by-step process. I'm
not just saying run
for 36 hours. I might
get to that point at the
end where it runs for
36 hours, but to get
to the 36-hour run,
I'm actually doing
several things that lead
up to that. And the
first is obviously some
sort of deep research
and structure that
allows the system to
follow a cohesive path,
strategy, structure,
architecture, and so on.
So for me, that generally
is like going and
using deep research or
something along those
lines, right? Where
I go out there and I
figure out what I
want to build. More
recently, I've integrated
the Context 7 MCP and
Perplexity MCPs into
the development flow
as well, where it can
go and sort of make a
self-determination of
what should be built
and how in which it
should be built. But
when I get to the point
of like, okay, I'm
ready to build this
thing. What I'm doing is
I'm creating a structure.
And let me actually
show you some of
this. And I'm going to
show you last weekend's
project just as a
sort of a little insight
into what that is.
Oh, actually, I've got
the Gen.ai SuperStream
open here. This is
what I did. I'll come
back to this in a minute
but basically last
weekend i had an idea
and this and to be
honest our friday calls
are a gold mine of
really interesting sort
of ideation and just
you know idea generation
for me so a lot
of this stuff comes
out oh we we spoke for
an hour and i had this
idea this is one of
those sort of things
so last week you might
remember i accidentally
left my uh my opus
four running i racked
up a four a three
hundred dollar bill and
i'm like oh man that
***** and so now what
what what what occurred
to me it's like no
sorry guys I'm kind of
I'm not sure why people
are being unmuted
but anyway here we
are um so the idea you
know I I could use
prompting or prompt
caching as a mechanism
to both improve the the
speed in which I
can make requests as
well as lower the
costs. And to be honest,
RAG kind of *****.
You know, 30% of RAG
requests are basically
wrong and that's the
state of the art. And
so all those things
were sort of, you know,
got me thinking, what
if there was a way
to sort of improve
that? So, and then,
so like, like I always
do, I went in and
created an initial plan.
So in this case, we can
go to the plans folder
and this is, you guys
can always go and
see this. What I want
to really show you is
kind of the idea,
right? So in this case,
we've got, I think it
was, we got plan. And so
this is gonna sort of
go through the details
of what I'm gonna build.
We've got the docs
folder, and the docs
folder is extensive.
You can see there's a
lot of stuff in here.
Now this is all being fed
and recursively defined.
So there's a
project overview,
there's various
parts. So to build
all this stuff,
What I basically
said, as I said, a
number of phases.
You can see the first
10 phases essentially
was built. Then
there was iteratively
more components that
were built, you know,
for caching and other
things. And eventually,
you know, I wanted to
integrate the Arcade
Dev guys because I
was curious how their
system worked. And
I wanted to give a
little bit of a, I know
they're going to give
a presentation here
in a bit. So I wanted
to, you know, at least
speak intelligently
about how I could
integrate third-party
tools and structures.
But ultimately, this
ran from, I think,
Friday evening until
Sunday evening. So
give or take around 30
hours or so, all total.
The entire development
process probably
cost me around $100,
but it built a
substantial amount
of components and a very
complex series of
components. Now,
most of that
weekend process was
actually the process
of optimizing,
benchmarking, and
refining the architecture
based on everything
you see here. So you'll
see here that there's
a folder, there's a
DB folder, so I'm
loading test data, and
there's benchmarking
folders and other various
things. And all this
is basically driving
the components that
allow me to sort of
optimize. So you can
see, I've actually kept
all this for you just
to sort of give you
an idea of how I'm
optimizing, but I'm just
running tests over and
over until I get the
sort of output that
is expected, right? So
this would be an
example of one of the
tests, iterating how
many concurrent users and
cache hits. These are
the things that allow
the system to sort of
bounce back and forth
in recursion between
is it working, is
it working right, and
how can I make it better?
and so it's grading
itself and this is
this is a key part so
of the 30 hours probably
20 hours was just
this self-optimization
so but so by the end
of the process and
and what i'm really
trying to do here you know
this is an interesting
idea right i i i
thought that i could
you know prove the
concepts of rag to be
smarter cheaper and more
efficient so you know
this is the concept
right rag uses embeddings
and i don't want
to use an embedding i
want to use a prompt
cache or natural
language, then I want to
make sure that it's
periodically refreshed.
One of the biggest
challenges you have with
RAG style implementations
is once you have
the index in place,
it's okay. But if you're
dealing with data that
changes frequently,
let's say like patient
data or something,
the fact that it's not
incorrect is secondary
to the larger the
data set, the harder
and more computationally
heavy it gets. So
I'm trying to solve
several different
problems. So So I'm trying
to solve the problem
of retrieval, data
freshness, accuracy,
and cost and latency.
So I've got four
different vectors that
I'm trying to solve
here, right? So the,
basically speed, right?
I want, I did some
basic benchmarking. I
saw that on average,
I'm seeing around two
to five seconds, you
know, to do the entire
rag approach versus
50 to 200 milliseconds
to do sort of this
approach that I needed
to prove it. So then
the rest of this
is basically just making
all this components
work. And ultimately,
what I use, let's
jump to the quick
example here. I know this
is really technical,
and this is more
technical than you guys
probably appreciate,
but whatever. I'm
going to stick with it.
All right, here we
go. So then what I did
is I created a series,
I created a CLI. And
the CLI, rather than
MCP, because I just
found it easier to go
back and forth, The CLI
basically allows the
system to interact
with it programmatically,
right? So in this
case, I can pass
variables and have it sort
of optimize and output
what's happening and
get to that point
where it's actually
working. And the demo
itself is the recursion.
So you'll see here
that I'm actually, you
know, it's doing quite
a bit here. And you'll
see a very verbose
output, right? So I'm
initializing, I'm using
SQL-based approach,
which basically takes
language, natural
language, and converts
it to a structured
query language, which
is SQL in this case.
And then I'm trying
to sort of optimize
based on different
structures, right? And,
you know, the amount
of information, the
type, you know, the sort
of semantic customers,
a happy growth
opportunities, and things
that would normally
be done in a semantic
search and effector.
I'm applying within
the structure of more,
well, more structure.
And I'm also including
security scans
as well, because a
lot of the times you
don't want, you know,
ejections or you want
guardrails. So I'm
actually doing a threat
detection as part of
the process, but I'm
measuring each part
of the process. So you
can see here that this
ran in 0.6 milliseconds.
So a human blinks,
I think 100
milliseconds. So one
-tenth of a second. So this
is happening one-tenth
of a human blink,
so it's ridiculously
quick and fast. So
to get to this level
of speed, I had to
run this several
thousand times, measuring
things like my
querying and my latency
and all these various
things. So what
you're looking at is
sort of a subsector of
a long-extended self
-optimizing system.
So let me pause
for a moment.
scale with the corpus?
Yes, exactly. So
what that means is,
okay, so now I've
got the basis for
measuring speed in a
multidimensional structure,
temporal, which
is time and date,
size, and scope and
other vectors. I needed
to say, well, will
this scale as I get
more data in it? Like,
yeah, I can do this
really fast with a
record that has five
results. Well, what does
5 million look like?
So what this does is
continually builds
on it and optimizes
as the data structure
increases. So this
is a glimpse of what
self-improving AI
looks like. This is a
visual output, right?
So you can see it's
creating queries and
things like that. Now to
get, let's get out
this for a sec. I'm
just going to run the
CLI directly. This is
going to happen so
quickly you're not even
going to be able to
see it. But in this
case, I'm just going
to grab one of these
examples here. Let's
scroll up here slightly.
Like it happens so
quickly that you won't
even be able to see
the but i'm going to
do it anyway so here
i'm just going to do
a query list all
financial records for
q1 and the oh of course
it's it's not gonna
it's not cached
whatever they the uh the
prompt gods aren't
smiling on me but um
normally that that
would have been
instantaneous but for
whatever reason i broke it
i guess but um basically
this this process
is essentially um
creating a again
reflective feedback
let me go back to the
previous version I ran.
I used a bad query.
Sorry, guys.
And by the way, if
something's going
to break, it's going
to break when you're
doing the demo
live. Here, let's
use this query. So
I ran it before the
call because, you
know, here, let's do
this one. I think
this one's cached.
I actually used a bad,
I purposely include
bad information that
isn't, I just didn't
know that I chose
that one. So let's do
one. What's the highest
revenue core? All
right. So that is
one that's cached and
instantaneous. So it's
cached both locally and
remotely. So this
request won't cost me a
cent in terms of the
information I'm sending
to the AI itself.
So long story short,
using this approach
is both faster, more
efficient, more
effective, but most
importantly, it's 90%
cheaper because I've got
direct control over
the caching mechanism
itself, where if
you're using the sort
of default prompt
caching found within
these language models.
It's kind of random.
And the nature of
language means that you
could ask the same
question in different ways,
like what was the
highest quarterly revenue
quarter? You could
actually ask that not
only in different
ways in English, but I
could ask that in French
or other languages.
And each time I ask it
with minor differences,
the cache wouldn't be
hit because it doesn't
generally recognize
that it's the same
request so a lot of
the prompt caching that
you're seeing in these
systems are dedicated
to the system prompt
that guides the system
but not the user prompt
that requests from
the system so this adds
the sort of semantic
context that says that
you can ask the same
the same question
you know a million
different ways and and
get the same response and
i cache that long
story short it's faster
shorter and better and
this is a good example
of long running systems
so if you're curious
about how to do it
take a look at this
this uh repo you can
kind of dissect it a
little bit i've i've
got a little easter egg
here for you fact memory
um this is something
i've built also that
basically implements
a memory system similar
to mem zero this it's
hard to explain
because it's kind of
complicated so i'm not
gonna spend much more time
on it um last thing
i want last thing i
want to jump to quick
diffusion models i'm
really into diffusion
models yeah If you guys
have seen these, there's
a new state-of-the
-art system coming out
of Google, and they
haven't really given
access. I don't have
access. If you guys have
access, let me know.
But being that I'm
like, well, if you're
not going to give
me access, I'm going
to go create my own
**** diffusion model.
So that's what I
attempted to do.
So you guys can take
a look at my, and I
called it agentic
diffusion because I call
everything agentic
apparently. I haven't really
broadly shown this
to the public yet.
But basically, I use
PyTorch to create a
diffusion model. So back
to the examples I was
showing you earlier
of this sort of self
-improving AI, that's
exactly what I'm doing.
So my initial tests,
and I haven't run this
on a GPU, so the
quality improvements are
going to be limited
until I spend the money
on a GPU. But so far,
it even runs on a
CPU, and I'm seeing a
20% increase in terms
of capability and
benchmarking. So basically,
just for those who
are not familiar with
a diffusion model,
a diffusion model
basically synthesizes
a result from noise. So
it basically takes
everything. So if you've
ever used like an
image generator, like
OpenAI or, you know,
image generators that
you'd see, video
generators use the same
approach. So you basically
synthesize the result
all at once, right?
So when you get a
video, you're getting
the entire video. You're
not kind of incrementally
getting each
frame. You're getting
the whole thing, and
again, it's done. and
same goes for an image.
But in this particular
scenario, I'm
synthesizing the
entire code base.
And because it
doesn't use a context
in the same way a
language model does,
I've got no limitations
to the amount.
It's just a time
-based problem.
So in that case,
I can synthesize
very, very complicated
applications.
We're talking
potentially millions of
lines of code all at
once. Now, millions
of lines of code might
take a few minutes
or an hour to
result, but I can get
everything. And then
as part of that,
what I was attempting
to do is integrate
sort of all the
components of the Spark
methodology, which
includes the testing
frameworks and other
components as part
of that. And then
because a lot of
these systems, you
know, expect traditional
components, I'm
like, well, can I
integrate a kind of
hybrid approach that
uses both the T style,
you know, guidance
along with the
diffusion itself.
sounds good
so uh all right guys
i i'm i'm gonna stop
here there that that
was a lot of random
brain craziness for a
week long story short
trying to build all
kinds of interesting
approaches and i'm a
big fan of what the guys
at arcade dev are doing
so i think rob you
you invited them to
the uh yeah i think we
have nate nate barbitania
hey nate how you
doing hey rob uh reuben
how are you doing
good good good to
see you good to see
you as well good to
be part of this today
yeah it's a little more
technical than normal
i apologize you know
sometimes we try to
keep this a little less
uh you know obscure
but you can bring it
back down to planet
earth for us i was i
was actually really
hoping that you were
going to say you did
have access to gemini
diffusion because i'm i
think i'm on the wait
list like everybody
else and i'm really
curious to try it out.
It's really interesting
to think about
generating text with the
diffusion model. I did
kind of a double
take when I first saw
that, but I think a lot
about it makes sense.
Yeah, for sure. Yeah,
I don't have access
to it. But the
benefit to not having
access, I was forced
to go create my own.
The mother of
invention, yes.
Yeah, exactly.
I don't know if it's
state of the art. I
need to have some better
funding to actually
run it across a GPU
cluster, but whatever.
So yeah, let's see what
you guys are doing.
All right. Let me
make sure that Zoom
can share. I think
I did the proper
incantations, but let
me just double check.
There we go.
Yes. Okay, so
what I want to
show today real
quick, I know it's
only like four
minutes or so.
What I want to
show real quick is
what is possible
when you can combine
tool calling, like
LLM tool calling,
with fine-grained
permissions.
So this is something
that is not quite
possible in MCP yet
today. I say yet because I
hope it will be possible
soon, and I'll give
some more info on
that in just a second.
But just for some
background, so my company,
arcade.dev, is
building a tool calling
platform that makes
it really easy for
devs to go beyond
kind of the, you know,
hello world, get weather
type tool samples
and do something really
useful with tools.
And it turns out most
of the time doing
something useful tools
means that you got
to wrangle with
OAuth, OpenID Connect,
authorization schemes,
you know, maybe API
keys, stuff like that.
Because all the most
useful APIs that you
might want to call
or interact with are
generally behind some
kind of authentication
or authorization.
So that's what our
platform does, we make
that really easy to do
for developers so that
you don't have to
burden your agent with a
bunch of OAuth plumbing
or callbacks or a
bunch of other additional
services just to
do the thing that your
agent's trying to do.
But I think demo
speaks a thousand
words. So let
me just show
you what that kind
of looks like.
I have a really
simple sample app.
This is just like
a Vercel sample app
that was built on
top of our platform.
So I can do
something like I want
to interact with
my live data. So
I can say like,
what recent emails
do I have about
my GitHub repos?
Now, in order to
answer that question,
the agent has access
to a bunch of tools,
GitHub, Google,
Slack, LinkedIn stuff,
but it understands
that it needs to use
the Google tool to
answer this question.
And in order to use
the Google tool, I need
to actually authorize
Google. I need it
to give authorization
to access my email.
So it's important to
note that this is this
is real authorization.
This is not, um, you
know, hard coding a
credential in there or
using like a personal
access token that's
hard coded into the
agent. Um, this is, uh,
just in time kind of
live, uh, live permissions
happening between
the agent and Google.
And I can get some
information about
like what's in my
email today. And
this is, this is
live. So I actually
have a couple of
emails I need to
deal with, uh, from
this morning. Um,
something about a,
security update
that I need to do.
So I'm going to
take a look at that.
I'll say something
like, tell
me more about
PR399 on GitHub.
Now, it starts to
get really powerful
when we can combine
or compose different
things across
services. So we also
have tools here for
GitHub, for example.
So requires a different
set of authorization,
so I can go reach
out to GitHub. Same
deal, I can go
authorize with GitHub,
do the OAuth dance
there. Again, the agent
doesn't have to
actually do it itself.
It's handled by the
platform underneath.
And I already approved
it earlier while I
was testing this demo
to make sure it works.
So then I can say
something like, great,
send a DM to
Nate on Slack,
raising a flag
about PR399.
And this lets me move
even into another
service and, you know,
properly get authorization
for Slack, for
example. I can send
a DM real quick. So
how does this work?
Under the hood, how
this works is RSDK lets
you take a function
like, you know, send
DM to user and then
start to annotate it
with the OAuth scopes
or the, you know,
authorization information
that actually is
needed to perform that
action. So nowhere,
like I said before,
nowhere in here is
there a hard-coded
credential or like a
super user token
that like vastly over
-provisions the agent to
do way too much. It's
actually truly scoped
to exactly what the
agent needs to do for
this specific tool.
And I mentioned before
that this is not
yet something that MCP
can do. MCP has tool
calling in the
protocol, but it doesn't
have this concept of fine
-grained authorization
or fine-grained
permissions. And I
think that it really
needs that because being
able to do this kind
of authorization for
tools unlocks a ton
of use cases for
securely taking action
on behalf of the user.
So I have a proposal
to MCP that I'll
link to here in
the chat. I'd love
to get some
community feedback on
it. It's kind of
our attempt to help
MCP get this kind
of functionality.
I'll drop a link to
that PR. We'd love some
comments. And in the
meantime, you can check
out arcade.dev. I'll
drop our docs in
there as well. We have
a bunch of tools that
are already pre-built
for doing this kind of
thing with many popular
services and such.
But yeah, that's a
little demo of what
we're building. And
I'd love to get some
feedback. If anybody
has any questions
or anything, I'll be
around for a while.
I see we had a
question in regards to
how does your
OAuth authorization
and expiration work? Ah,
great question.
How long is the
OAuth authorization?
Does it expire?
That's somewhat
dependent on the
service. So every
OAuth server has its
own rules about, you
know, token expiry
and whether they
issue refresh
tokens or don't
issue refresh tokens.
so part of it's up
to the OAuth server
but what our platform
does is it handles all
the refresh stuff
for you so most OAuth
servers will give you
a refresh token to kind
of let you have like a
long-lived authorization
in that case our
middleware component
just automatically
refreshes that token for
you so your agent doesn't
have to worry about
it as long as the
upstream server says it's
still okay that the
refresh token is still
valid just keeps
refreshing for you You have
a, as long as you want
to have that available
to the user, it's
available. Of course,
unless the user cuts
it off, that's a
different story. It can
always be revoked by the
human, and that's super
important as well.
And that was something
that I was struggling.
So I, as you guys saw,
I did a rudimentary
implementation of
ArcadeDev. And a lot
of what I was focused
on was sidestepping
the human interaction
components. and for
example so i had to
authorize it you know by
manually invoking like
a link in my cli or
something but what
what what i struggled
with was this idea
that i actually don't
necessarily want user
input for let's say long
horizon types of
projects where it just
needs to you know six
hours in it determines
it needs to go and
do something and get
something somewhere and
i'm not paying attention
and it and it stopped
and it basically
says you know you need
to invoke this link,
click it, go and approve
it before it'll go
and continue. How do
you get around that?
Yeah. Yeah. I think
there's, there's
really, um,
there's two broad
authorization
models or approaches
and whether,
uh,
broadly speaking, like
kind of just in time
authorization where
there is like a human
at the keyboard who
can click on a link
or, or approve something
really fast. And
then there's more what
some people call like
ambient agents or long
running agents where
It might actually
go do something for,
like you said, minutes
or hours, and then
that might be in the
middle of the night. The
human might not be
around to go click
something. So I think
what's important is to
be able to do both, just
-in-time authorization
and also pre
-authorization. So you can
imagine if you're
building a long running
agent or like a background
agent, being able
to say maybe on user
onboarding, like the
first time setup, say,
hey, this agent is
going to need later,
it's going to need to
be able to look up
this repo on GitHub, or
it's going to need
to be able to do this
search or this API
call. So go ahead and
click the link now
during setup, you know,
approve, approve or
connect so that the agent
has those tokens, has
that authorization
available down the
road when it needs it.
Yeah. And so a lot
of the agent systems
you see are taking that
approach where they
sort of have an
initial sort of sign up
process. You authorize
your GitHub and
other sort of integrations
and then assuming
that those integrations
remain, then
it'll just be able to
leverage those. and
a lot of the remote
MCP services are doing
similar things like
the Composio guys.
Basically, they've
got a little dashboard
that you can go in
and authorize. And I
think you guys have
a similar dashboard.
Yeah.
And so that's
the intention
of that dashboard, right?
Yeah, the dashboard,
I didn't show it just
for the sake of time
because I know that
there's a lot of other
stuff we want to talk
about today, but the
dashboard kind of serves
as your single pane
of glass to see all
of the authorizations.
You can kind of do
the backend connection
management in there.
Yeah, actually, I
know we, if you have a
minute, I want the crew
to see your dashboard,
actually. Oh, sure,
for me. Yeah, it's
pretty cool. It's a
nice sort of interface.
We were previously
looking at, like I
said, the sample app
that we built, but
the real meat and
potatoes, so to speak,
is back here in
our kind of backend
dashboard. So you
can see the couple of
services that I
connected to just in
the course of that
demo show up here. I
have like, this is
my user. This is me.
I'm connected to those
three things we were
interacting with GitHub,
Google, and Slack.
And I can see that
there's like, you know,
certain scopes or certain
permissions approved
for each one of the
services. I can also
go in and revoke those
and say, you know
what, let's be done
with this connection. We
want to kill it. And
that lets me do a lot of
management back here.
I can also manage
like, you know, which
services are connected
uh to it which are
available i can like add
them for oauth or add
and other mcp servers
and stuff like that
so it's quite a bit of
quite a bit of like
back end back office
functionality if you will
and and i can tell you
guys have a background
in off right is that
you had to get the
founding company you
guys were part of like
a major enterprise
authentication company
if i'm not mistaken yeah
yeah we uh a lot of
the folks including
myself uh came out of
okta um and And then
previously to that, we
were part of a smaller
startup called Stormpath
that was ultimately
acquired by Okta. So
we've kind of, the team's
been together for a
while. We were in the
authentication API
space for a long time,
kind of did it at a big
company at Okta, and
then got the band
back together, so to
speak, to tackle what
to us looked like one of
the kind of biggest
problems facing agents
today, which is we saw
a lot of people doing
cool stuff with agents.
But if you kind of
take a peek under the
hood, it's all based
on a hard coded
credential or, you know, a
super user admin key
that's baked into the
agent or, you know,
paste in your personal
access token kind of
stuff, which is kind of
where where a lot of
MCP servers are today.
Almost all of them are
like, OK, step one,
paste in your super
user key here and save
it into the agent and
or save it into the MCP
server. And that's
just not, we learned 20
years ago, you know,
through the trials and
tribulations of security
on the internet,
that that's just not
the right way to do
things. But we wanted
to make it easy to not
just say, hey, don't do
it that way. It's easy
enough to tell people
that's wrong, but
we want to show people
how easy it can be to
do it the right way as
well. 100 percent and
and what you're
describing is exactly how
like the super base uh
mcp works put in your
your service uh key and
which gives basically
unlocks complete access
to all your super
base and that's the
first step it's the
the keys to the kingdom
as as step zero yeah
yeah exactly so you're
you're suggesting a
more uh role and a more
enterprise friendly
stance.
And yeah, make sure
to share that PR
for what you're
doing with the MCP.
At very least, we
can give it a spin.
Absolutely. Yeah.
I think I'll share
the PR in the chat.
I think without
something like an
idea of fine-grained
permissions added to
MCP, every MCP server
is going to remain stuck
in exactly what you
just said, like stuck
as step one, paste
in your super user
token to get started.
And I think if we're
able to help MCP take
that step into kind
of the OAuth world,
nothing like not
reinventing the wheel, but
just using all the
stuff that was developed
over the last couple of
decades in the internet
to solve these kinds
of problems, it's
very applicable to agents
today. We just need
to make sure it fits
right into the agent
world. So yeah, I
think there's a good
opportunity to add
that to MCP. And
in the meantime,
it already worked
today on arcade.dev
shameless plug you can
check it out um the chat
sample that i just was
playing with is also
public you can try it
out i'll put the link
to that in there as
well and and how do
you guys make money you
charge you for this or
what's what's the uh
what's the business
model yeah we're we're
planning on staying
around for a while so we
do have to charge some
money for something
um we uh our platform
is like free to try
out free for like hobby
projects and and uh for
low volume stuff but
we ultimately make money
on volume so if you
use our platform to
power like a big agent
that's doing a lot of
a lot of requests and
it's really unlocking
a lot of usefulness
for your customers
then we charge uh just
based on volume we have
some like pricing on
our website and then for
like big like enterprise
level production grade
uh agents we have
you know obviously we
can have enterprise
deals and enterprise
support as well okay i
see And one more
question from Philip,
contextual auth aspect
versus just-in-time auth?
What does, can
you clarify what
do you mean by
contextual auth?
Hey, guys, can you hear
me okay? Yeah, yeah.
Okay, great. Yeah,
hey, thanks for the
demo. It was really,
really interesting.
I was wondering if
you were thinking of
looking at like a
contextual analysis,
plugging that into a
risk engine for a more
granular, let's say,
least privileged
just-in-time auth? Is
that something that
you've considered? Is
that a roadmap kind
of thing? If I'm
understanding right,
plugging it into
an enterprise
risk engine type
of solution that's
making even finer
-grain decisions on
authorization? Yeah,
basically. And I
have the enterprise
case in mind, but,
you know, as I'm
thinking about this,
you know, it could
be a task for a
specialized LOM as
well. I don't know.
Oh, yeah. Yeah. How
shady does this request
look? Yeah, exactly.
Right. Yeah.
Right. Like, hey,
let's look at 100 data
points and see. Yeah,
that kind of thing.
It's funny you
mentioned that, Philip,
I know I gave a sort
of discombobulated
demo earlier, but
one of the steps
in the tool
selection that I did
with the arcade dev
folks was I did a
risk analysis as
part of the input.
And then what I'm
doing is I'm trying
to determine whether
or not there's a
risk associated with
prompt injection,
full style injections
and other related
information as part
of that and you and i
was showing off the
little speed component
and that was taking one
tenth of a millisecond
or of a millisecond
whatever that
equals so yeah that
that's all part of the
process at least what i
do as sort of avoiding
prompt injection
yeah okay yeah if you
don't measure it you
don't know how to
you know how much time
it's going to take
right so it's for
me it was all about
measurement right right
that makes a lot of
sense i would i would
add to that to say our
platform and our SDKs
are kind of designed
to play well with all
the other frameworks
that people are
using. So playing well
with something like
guardrails or prompt
injection mitigation,
like layer inside of
your stack. We don't
have a direct integration
with like a risk
engine or risk
management type of call
out right now, but that's
definitely something
that we're considering.
I would love to
actually connect with
you to get like kind
of your ideas on what
the shape of that would
look like, at least
for your case,
because that's a super
useful signal for us to
gather as we're thinking
about where that
goes on our roadmap.
Yeah, awesome. Yeah,
let's connect. Great.
Thank you. Thanks
for the demo. Awesome
stuff. Yeah, it's
great to be here.
Yeah, cool.
Yeah, I really
appreciate it.
And arcade.dev
or arcade-dev,
what's your website?
You had it right,
arcade.dev. I'll
just drop the link
in the chat so
everybody can have
the canonical URL.
and then I'll
put that link
to the NCP
proposal as well
happy to connect with
anybody on LinkedIn
too if you have
other questions or
something shoot me
an email or I'm nate
at arcade.dev or
we can connect on
LinkedIn and keep the
conversation going
yeah shoot your
LinkedIn actually
sorry
actually it works right I
actually posted a
post on LinkedIn
connected to GitHub
withdrew and then
posted it from the chat
platform so it works
really seamlessly
the only feedback is
that the video posting
it goes as a link
but you should post
it you know the
video generally comes
up as an embed in
linkedin posts right
so maybe i can i can
show you later on oh
yeah yeah excellent
for marketing
professionals if that were
to be a video yeah
i think i'll have to
double check i think
there's a way to do that
in the LinkedIn API.
But we haven't done
that yet. It's worth
mentioning that all of
our tools are also
totally open source on
our GitHub. So you
could also fork it and
add that capability.
And we would definitely
accept that PR. That
would be awesome.
Awesome. So if anyone
wants to connect on
LinkedIn, always pop
your LinkedIn address in
the text area here in
zoom and maybe you'll
get a few more uh you
know connections to
to share your your ideas
with um nate really
appreciate you taking
the time to give us
the presentation day
it's really cool what
you're working i think
you're i think someone
saw us on the text
area that your your
timing is absolutely
perfect this is what what
the what the industry
needs i think it's
really really interesting
work you're doing
and i it was easy to
use so the the important
part for me is i'm
up and running in in
less than 10 minutes i
know it's it's it's a
good product so I
didn't have any trouble.
As you guys know, if
it takes more than
15 minutes, I move
on to the next thing.
It passed the 15
-minute test in flying
colors. I think I was
up in two minutes.
That is critical. I
think anything that takes
a dev longer than a
couple minutes to figure
out is probably too
complicated. I have
a really aggressive
stance on developer
experience over here yeah
you know you've done a
great job my only my
only request for you
guys is you need to
create an mcp for your for
your documentation you
you add you add you
add that we're good
to go like here just
point it at my dev flow
build me an arcade app
and i'll go have lunch
that is actually my
my co-worker who's
sitting downstairs right
now actually built
that already so that is
uh that's coming
imminently i will i will
shoot you an email as
soon as it's available
perfect love it all
right rob who's up next
so next we have uh kevin
kevin vo from defang
and uh uh david gratton
has uh brought uh
brought defang forward
kevin it's nice to meet
you thank you nate
uh kevin how are you
uh yeah i'm good can
everyone hear me yeah
yeah no uh yeah i met
uh So I've been at a
convention in Vancouver.
We're based on Vancouver,
Canada. I did a demo
for him in person.
He loved it so
much, he told us we
should demo for
everyone else here, so.
Great.
Yeah, so I, so we are
a deployment tool.
Basically, like,
let me share my
screen before I
start, so there's more
contextual,
something to look at.
Sorry, okay.
Everyone should be able
to see my desktop. Yes.
Okay.
Great. So this
is our website.
We're called Defang.
Develop anything,
deploy anywhere. That's
what we do. And we
have a MCP tool, but we
also have a CLI
tool, however, first
started. So I'm just going
to not waste too much
time because I
know we have a time
constraint. So we're
just going to go forward.
If you wanted to see
our MCP tool, you go
to the docs and then
right under concepts,
there would be FCP
server. I will give
this link, so you
don't have to go like
searching for it,
but I'm just showing
you, you could get
from our main website.
So we basically
like a lot of
people, the Vibe
code, or maybe they're
not so technically
versed in
like deployments
to like AWS GCP.
So they're kind
of stuck to Vercel
and lovable,
right? Like these
Vibe coding like
websites, right?
And you're kind of
locked into these
like, these clouds
now for Vercel, and
they're kind of the
middle man. Like I
think Vercel uses AWS
behind the scenes.
and um at that point
they're kind of like
they're charging you
and you're not sure
what's like your actual
cloud class or they
can just they're just
kind of like charging
you then for their
cloud class and
hosting it for you and
also like when you're
using their platform
like lovable and
stuff you're locked in
so a lot there's this
whole market with like
other um a vs code
like vs code cloud
um uh windsurf cursor
that don't have easy
ways to deploy and
you're kind of like
have to no DevOps
information, like how
do I start EC2 instance?
How do I after finish
this, like bring online?
So we made an MCP tool
that can plug into
your cursor, windsurf,
all these things.
And once you're
finished your
project, you can
just say dfeng up
and it'll bring
it to the cloud.
So there's no
finicking with,
with, you know, like
doing toggles on AWS,
like learning how to
like use like the portal,
and then we also do
gcp and stuff but for
right now um our tool
only supports playground
but uh multi-cloud
is coming into the
future um and our
command is really easy
to install so i'm just
gonna show everyone
how to use it here so
uh depending on what
you have uh we have
the four ides we can
easily add and work
but right now i'm
probably gonna use
windsurf today uh because
i've been using a lot
of them for development
uh and though the one
thing i do i don't
like about mcp right
now for the spec is
because um these uh
we could build our own
mcp like clients right
but the thing is like
it's not really far
reach so uh we're
kind of at the mercy
of these like big names
that to implement the
mcp spec but they're
kind of slow so like
you know like mcp has
like um sorry uh
resources and like uh
prompts and stuff
right but these clients
actually haven't reached
that point yet the i
think most of them
just reach tools right
now so i want to develop
more on mcp uh to
make it better uh on
our server side but we
have to wait for the
development side i
think streaming is the
biggest one i'm waiting
for the streaming uh
mcp protocol uh making
a tool right and not
stream back is uh
hurting me sometimes
so um but asynchronous
yeah asynchronous
streaming yeah yeah
yeah but uh they
haven't put into their
um their clients yet
so we we can't do
anything until they've
done that so um
anyways i'm just gonna
show you how install
it. So, you just
run this. As long as
you have mpx or no,
you should be fine.
So, you run this. It'll
configure your
mcp config.
Once you have
that, you can just
bring it up. So,
I have it here.
Sorry, I gotta
drag it down.
All right. And you have
mcp tool installed.
Just one command,
really quick.
So, what we're
gonna do is we're
just gonna make
a quick game.
Just like
everyone's this.
Just a quick, simple
snake game with React.
All right.
Hopefully, this is
the longest part
of the demo. It's
just waiting for
code generation.
But if it takes too
long, I do have a
snake game ready.
So I'm trying to
install it while you're
doing your demo.
And I'm getting
hung up on the log
in here. It doesn't
seem to, it doesn't
seem to respond.
Can I pass a key or
something directly?
Can you, are you
writing this exact
same command here?
This one here?
I'm running the
command that was output
from your setup, you
know, VS Code, client
equals VS Code. Here,
I'll pop it in the,
you know, studio, but
basically it seems
to get, at least in
my environment gets
hung up on the login
i i think you jumped
over the login quickly
i just want to make
sure everyone is able
to get past the first
step did you put
into the chat sorry i
just didn't see it uh
and maybe i can also
uh leo is also one of
our uh team members
he's our cto here
so yeah maybe i can
help you uh rafa uh
maybe kevin you can yeah
continue your demo
and maybe i can help
Okay. No,
no worries.
Keep going.
So what's being
requested from your,
like, what are you
getting from your
MCP? Like what data
is coming back?
You're providing like
a knowledge base.
Like I see you've
got a few different
endpoints here.
You've got this idea
of deploy, destroy,
deploy and log in.
Yeah.
And so what's happening
with deploy and destroy?
Yeah. So there's
services too, I guess.
Yeah, exactly. So
basically deploy is
what happens is,
well, our engine
relies more on Docker.
So your application
has to be Dockerized,
but usually
the LM will just
package it for you.
And if you can't,
you should just, it's
better if you write
your own Docker file. uh
i mean most uh places
do um sorry let's see
if this starts uh most
place most uh people
do dockerize the
application eventually
right so it just it
avoids like it works on
my machine doesn't
work on your machine
um and what happens is
we have a compose file
so if you have multiple
services like a
front end and back end
and database uh we're
able to deploy the
whole stack in one
compose file as well
so uh what happens when
you do deploy it it
takes the compose file
and then um reads all
the services and then
generates the
infrastructure uh code uh
the stack uh onto our
playground for right
now and then spins
everything up uh online
so let me let me see
if i understand so
you've got a playground
so you're hosting
this in some kind of
serverless environment
or doctorized container
environment that
you're deploying my
application to and
then you're providing
a means of easily
gaining access to it
yeah yeah well So during
the demo, you'll see
like a portal will
come up and like a
whole interface will
come up and you'll
be able to see like
the whole way to like
retrieve your URLs
and look at the
deployment and everything.
So why, so I'm gonna
ask you a straight
question here. Why
not use something like
Vercel or fly.io or
even AWS to do that?
Well, like if you
use, sorry, Kevin,
if you want me to
do your demo. Now,
so the tool is
actually that, right?
We create the
infrastructure code
based off of your
Docker Compose file.
That's kind of
what the tool does.
The playground
environment is just to get
you up and running in
no time and you don't
have to have AWS accounts
or Google accounts
and stuff ready.
So that is really a
playground to show what
the tool does without
you having to trust
that we are going into
your account. But the
tool itself goes to
your account. we deploy
to your aws account
to your google account
your digital ocean
account that's what
the tool does and i
want to also clarify we
generate infrastructure
code under the covers
based off of your
project but that is
not actually done with
an llm so we do have
this mcp server that
is our new kind of
the the main interface
has become the main
interface to our tool
but the the actual
engine that does the
conversion from compose
to to infrastructure
code is all rules
-based so which services
do i need do i need
a gpu yes or no what
compute do we pick uh
all of that is just
rules-based per cloud
right so you could deploy
to google and to
amazon the same project
you wouldn't have to
make any code changes
so so i think i think
the question i have
really is is you know
why why wouldn't i
just use the aws mcp
or the or the versell
mcp or whatever the
infrastructure i'm using
mcp it seems like
you might be the man
in the middle and so
how do you avoid being
that man in the
middle and any kind of
security concerns the
name defang is actually
especially that right
to to get away from
the fangs so we want
you to be able to
build projects and not
be tied into one of
the the hosts so that
is kind of where the
whole philosophy of
the company came from.
So we will...
Are you hosted?
Are you the...
We are a tool.
We do not want...
Okay.
All right. I'm
just, I guess in the
most simple terms,
and I'm not trying
to be difficult with
you guys because
I see a lot of this
stuff every day.
I just want to
figure out like where
do you go over like a
native MCP for whatever
service that I want
to deploy to you? Like
a doc, for example,
the most obvious one,
maybe like the Docker
MCP or something, or
just getting windsurf
to create my docker file
for me and click
that's fine right you
should totally use that
but then when it's time
to deploy docker
doesn't help you deploy
deploy to any provider
your account you have
an aws account you
might have credits there
your enterprise might
have the iam rules set
up that you want to
you know you want to
conform to so we just
deploy into your account
we are we're not hosting
anything we're just
uh creating uh also
maybe the value is
maybe not entirely clear
there that conversion
from composed to uh
to infrastructure code
that is being done
according to best practices
according to the
cloud recommended ways
we our company we have
gone through amazon
reviews to ensure that
the code that we create
i don't want to say
generate because there
is no language model
in that translation
uh the that the code
that we emit rather
uh is um well
architected that is the
term that amazon
uses and the same for
google so when we
create a project based
off of your compose
file you can be
sure that that is
the way google would
recommend you to use
their services including
security Do you
see my credentials?
No, we do not.
Actually, we use
an OAuth flow
similar to what
Nate, that's why I'm
very interested in
what Nate built.
So I'm passing
a request to
you. Here's my
package.json.
It's your CLI, your
MCP server, talking
to your account. There
is no, our backend,
which is serving,
sure, a website, it's
not talking to your
account or anything
it's your cli talking
to your account okay
um i appreciate you guys
giving giving us the
overview and uh the
devops space is hot
lots of questions i'm
sure um the security one
would be my biggest
question mark for you
guys i i and i was having
that chance to play
with you did you press
the did you enter oh
no i was just waiting
for everyone to like
um but anyways i was
gonna say what leo was
talking about was uh
There's a, this is what
we mean by well
architected. We have stamps
approved by AWS itself.
Like we work with
them and GCP where our
code is well architect.
So we're not just like
re-optimizing your
cloud. We, we have
really good optimization
and our infrastructure
staff and we spin out.
Guys, we've all,
we've all seen the
partner program.
They don't do
actually any audit
of code, right?
You know that. So
those are logos.
The only thing that
really matters is the
flow of information
between you and me.
Right? Right. So,
and, and that's,
that's, that's
what I want to see,
right? Like what
information are you, am
I sending you and
what information
are you sending me
and what is being
obfuscated in, in that
trans translate, you
know, that, that
communication channel.
And that, that's the
part that I'm just
struggling with with
trying to understand you
guys, because to be
honest, a lot of what
you're showing me could
probably be relatively
easily created just by
prompting, you know,
cursor or windsurfer
in the right way to
do or interact with
various MCPs or literally
just creating an mcp
on the fly as needed
so i think i think
your value prop is
needs to be articulated
slightly differently
and again i don't want
to give you guys a
hard time on a friday
afternoon because this
is your baby i just
i just think you need
to explain it in a way
that's a little more
easily uh grokked
all right i but i do
appreciate you giving
us giving us your time
to show all this um we
got to move on to the
next presentation
rob who's up who's up
next well braun has
actually found himself uh
uh immersed in post
web summit activities
so he's that he's
different to next week yeah
okay no no worries so
we have a little bit
of yeah we got okay so
let's finish up what
you're doing here what
so what what's the
last step here what what
do you got we're just
deploying to our
cloud so you're seeing
it's making a darker
file compose file for us
and it's going to deploy
on our playground so
you'll see in a second
um hey kevin could
you answer i asked the
question in the chat
like a while ago like
um like so you're
deploying to like assuming
it's somebody just
create an account but
would this work in a large
enterprise where there
are like rules and
sort of regulations
how you deploy deploy
stuff make available
like you couldn't can you
put like custom sort
of like instructions
uh for example like uh
we have to like like
have to use century
for the air catching or
whatever the data dog
for logging you have to
put all this like
things like yeah so it's
all right if you have
a huge infrastructure
set up right you're an
enterprise and you want
to make an app which
this will have problem
right developers can
make an app now with
cursor or whatever the
client very quickly
right and it takes weeks
to actually take it
to be available to
users because they have
to be compliant with x
y and z enterprise like
it's so you don't
have a full con i mean
you people can create
an account for you on
amazon even but you have
to be compliant with
the lots of cooks and
the organization like
do you guys support
that uh leo do you want
to answer it yeah well
that i I think that
is where the tool
differs from your Vercel
and your others, because
we deploy to your
account. Your CLI is
actually ******* off all
the builds, all the
deployments from your
account to your account.
So all your policies,
your SCPs, your
security policies
that were set up,
they all apply.
So not even that,
because you want to take
users, for example. so
when you're developing
on your laptop right
you're what you're
doing with client you
are the only user of the
app right but when
you're deployed to the
cloud you have to take
user base from the octa
or zero or whatever
things like can you
support that so it
depends how users log in
into the app right
because the app you're
developing on your local
machine it's not how
it's going to taken so
that's yeah well okay
so and maybe i'm not
understanding the
question so the the we
will deploy if your compose
file specifies for
example a database where
you would have your
your user user account
stuff like that no
but they have to use
octa or zero like so it's
not that the database
with user accounts
you go right it's the
authorization service
you have and you only
At this point, those
become configuration
values to your
application, right?
Once deployed, it
will use the Okta,
whatever has been
configured by yourself
or by your team in
the cloud. It will
use whatever
configuration you have.
Right, but you have
to configure the Okta
for this application,
right? They need to
create an application
there. so this is at
that url and like this
user group is like so
does it still have to
be done manually and
somebody has to like
bug the devops team or
it sounds like that
depends whether that
is uh done in the same
compose file you could
probably do that in
the same compose file
or no you cannot do it
in this okay i guess
okay because you cannot
do it on the same
compose because when
running locally you
don't use these things
right sorry we're just
yeah okay you will
get i i get it yeah so
sorry we're closing up
on the top of the hour
there gents so all
right i'd like to invite
everybody to to uh to
connect and continue
the conversation for
sure and then we'll
have a chance to
explore a bit more over
the course of over
the course of time but
welcome guys and uh uh
thank you for for getting
the demo ready and uh
for being here today
and and nate as well
i know there's uh um
uh a lot of stuff uh
yet coming that we
want to see coming for
next week what do you
what do you think you
have on the on the
board for next week
reuben well we've got the
toronto uh another one
of our toronto meetups
uh happening so if
anyone's in in uh
toronto canada you're
you're more than welcome
to join us we're
downtown at the tribal
scale offices on john
street just near the uh
rogers centers where
the blue jays baseball
team plays right right
in the heart of uh
heart of the city i
think we've got how many
people get signed up
now we're close to 80
i think for that
yeah that's right and
that's um that's 6 30
tuesday night and uh and
absolutely everybody
is welcome um that
should that's that's
the the second toronto
uh in-person meetups
should be a lot of fun
and there's some
really it's it's great
because in the first one
uh last month Reuben,
there was a whole
bunch of new, nobody
had used Rue codes
before, Rue Spark.
So they get introduced
to a new set of tools.
It's going to be
really interesting
to see them coming
back after a
month and what kind
of questions are
emerging. It should
be really neat.
I've been playing a
little bit with the new
updates to Cursor,
which are really
interesting. They've got
this sort of asynchronous
agent capability. It's
rudimentary, to be
honest. And it's
actually very similar for
those that played
around with my Spark 2
implementation, where I
have a kind of asynchronous
agentic development
flow for coding.
They've implemented
a similar approach,
although not quite
as in-depth. But it's
interesting because
they've integrated directly
into the cursor UI,
which is kind of cool.
So if you've
got a chance to
go check that
out, basically it
spawns their
own code spaces.
And again, my
question is actually
similar to what we
saw from our friends
here at Defang is
like, you know,
I guess I trust GitHub
with my code. You
know, like you have to
trust someone, but, you
know, should I trust
the guys at, you know,
Cursor with that same
level? I think the
answer is yes, given what
they're doing already
with my, you know,
environmental variables
and whatnot. So a
lot of the questions
I have with these
applications really comes
down to like security
and the leakage of
data to these providers,
right? And whether
or not I trust them
with my information
or not. And whether,
you know, just because
they're making some
exorbitant money at
Cursor doesn't necessarily
mean I trust them,
right? And that's an
intangible problem.
This is the open part
of our call. So if
anyone has anything
they want to talk about
the demo display show
whatever this is this
is your chance um
would love to see what
you're you're up to
um feel free i would
like to pick your brain
on that last one like
what would you consider
a good amount of
um of trustworthiness
there like uh the
oauth similar flow to
oauth that is kind of
what the flow that
kevin showed but i don't
think it was clear to
anybody there was a
login step there that
opened the browser
and returned to the
MCP server, logged in.
And for me, that
failed, by the way. It
doesn't work in at
least Rue or Klein.
Okay, so I would
love to... Yeah,
to be honest, most
MCPs, if I have
to invoke a CLI to
open up the URL,
that's kind
of problematic
for agentic flows.
So what I... And I
think I mentioned this
to the guys at Arcade
earlier as well. I
think the better
approach would be to let
me just pass a key.
And if I can explicitly
put the key into the,
you know, the MPX
command or whatever
it is that starts up
the whole process,
at least I can just,
you know, get ignore
the MCP.json, right?
But if I'm forced to
do an OAuth as part
of an agentic flow,
that kills the flow,
right? Unless I go
in and then use your
dashboard or something,
and then I just got
to pass some kind
of key in the URL, I
guess. but it doesn't
look like you guys do
either so it's just
it it's it looks like
it's made for like
a more sequential
implementation of process
i don't know what i
would love to let's
move on i i i think i
think we let's let's
let's let's move on
to i think alan you've
got a you've got a
question here i do i
have a quick one um
i thought we were
wrapping so mine is more
administrative in
nature i have a question
for um some advice
from any canadians
traveling to the u.s
i don't want to make
it political but is
there any tips um for
how to get through
security at the border
in the tech space you're
talking to the guy
that's got the secret
room with his name on
it um you know i so i
i've spent more time
in in the uh in that
interrogation room than
probably most people
spent in the united
states at least from
canada and so you know
obviously you know you
got to you got to go
along with it you know
when they ask for your
password you know you
have no choice but
either to either give
it to them or or you're
basically being rejected
for the kind from
the country for an
extended period of time
potentially years so
there you really don't
have much choice so
you're if you're really
concerned about
security and working in
the ai space or you
happen to be the guy that
created something called
the ai hacker space
then you're there's a
there's high likelihood
that they're going
to give you a pretty
good, you know,
review, which generally
involves them taking
your phone, your laptop,
in my case, both and
running it through some
kind of secondary
system. And then after
about two to three hours,
not letting you go.
You know, I'm currently
not going to the
US because I just can't
take that room anymore.
So, you know, the
only other option you
have is to get a
letter from either the
company or whatever
you're doing in the US,
assuming it's business
related with, with, with
explicit, you know,
here's why you're going
and what you need to,
you know, what, why
you're, what you're
doing, how long you're
going to stay. But if
you're going without
that and you work in AI
or anything involving
infosec, you're probably
going to, you're,
you're at risk. And,
you know, for me, I
think I'm just loud and
boisterous and I have
a tendency to kick up
a stink about things.
So I'm probably on
some kind a list which
is why they always put
me in that room maybe
you'll just blow through
it's not pleasant
currently hey hey this
is Dennis Hunter if
I could just interject
really quickly um very
quickly uh if you can
see my picture you
can notice that I
probably don't look like a
Mexican so I was
coming back across the
border from Mexico one
time and I got challenged
on my identity now
I was in the Navy at
that time. And I looked
at the guy and said,
look at me. I was born
in Harlem Hospital.
You can't get
any more American
than being born in
Harlem Hospital.
It's not like
there's two of them.
But to answer your
question more directly,
I wear my little
funny red hat. And I
have an invite from
the president when
he was back in his
previous administration.
Not that it's political,
it was business,
but between the
little red hat and
the invite, they tend
to leave me alone.
Yeah, it depends.
You're you're
you're you're you're
also American,
which is different.
Like, I think, I
think, Alan, you're
not you're you're
not American.
So you're
looking at. Yeah.
I it's ambiguous.
I mean, again, this
is not meant to be a
political statement.
It is what it is.
Right. it's ambiguous
and that's that's the
that's the challenge
we have right now
especially for the
type of work we do well
the beautiful thing
is and trying not
to be political myself
um i always remind
myself that this is
a temporary situation
and you know this
will not last forever
we have this thing
called the midterms
coming up in the united
states and i believe
that will change things
well the dust the
dust will settle and
you know the best advice
probably is do
everything properly play
by the rules if you're
going down by work
make sure that you've
got all the paper
proper credentials and
if you're going down
for a vacation keep
your hotel bookings
yeah most people let's
just say let's be
honest most people have
no problems like yeah
i i'm i'm the exception
to the rule and
and that's probably
mostly my own doing um
but i think most people
on this call i would
say 99 of people
will have no issue at
all yeah yeah yeah
so my past experience
i've only been one time
in that interrogation
room i was driving
from montreal on rainy
weekday afternoon
and the shift just
started so i was the
only guy on the highway
they just saw me
and said hey like go
board here let's have
fun with this guy
but i think time of
day and how busy they
are, it kind of
plays a role in that.
I have a tech question.
Happy to move to
tech questions.
Yeah, so at least
once a day, I type
in AWS SSL login
in my command line
window, and it
pops up a browser.
I have to re
-log into AWS.
Is this tool that we were
looking at earlier,
arcade.dev,
can it help me
there, or is it some
other layer? Why
are you using the
SSL login directly?
Are you going to
an EC2 instance
or something else?
Well, okay, here's
the backup one step.
Several times a
day, I want to type
in AWS S3 LS to look
within a bucket,
or I have a script
that does such
to see what's in
various S3 buckets,
which kind of
orchestrates how our
cloud service
works. So, yeah, for
those scripts to
run, I need my AWS
command line
credentials cached.
Make a new IAM
role that only has
S3 read or list
object access
and use that.
Yeah, or use a key.
Right.
that feature you're
using is kind of like
a simple way to do
the export within your
environment, I think,
if I'm not mistaken.
So what you could,
and that has like
an expiration on
it, probably a short
expiration, I would
guess. So you can
explicitly create
those keys and define
the expiration as
long as you want.
Okay.
So, yeah,
there's, you know,
I would say
that you could,
there's also a number
of different, you know,
AWS MCPs that do
exactly that. They help
you manage your AWS
infrastructure. If you
are going to use one
of those tools, make
sure to use the ones
that are studio, not
remote. Those remote ones
are basically stealing
your information.
So when it comes to
like DevOps MCPs in
general, if you can't run
it locally in studio,
then you probably
shouldn't use it this
general security guidelines
for for devops
related work it's the
reason why you use this
it's the reason why you
use a cli locally right
um right okay great
great good good tips
for thought thank
you i will um stew
about this yeah mark is
that your personal
account or you're in some
organization no this
is inside my work and
said well yeah because
okay because Because
some people, like
security people and
organizations, they don't
like IAM keys because.
Yeah, there's a few
different ways to
handle it, though.
It depends on the
dev environment and
the integration.
Yeah, there's so
many different
ways to handle
it, you know.
I mean, there isn't
they don't like
if that key gets
stolen, right?
You have the key
basically floating
around because
it's a store key.
don't don't have a
never-ending exploration
that's why that's
why you have to
that's why you have to
log in temporary every
now and again yeah
yeah but that's why
you have to log in
every eight hours
right so if somebody
still is the key at the
end of the day they
have 15 minutes to
do something exactly
and that's if you
look at the github
uh api keys they do
the same thing right
they've got you know
the different time
frames for expiration
of those keys same
same same scenario
can anyone share best
practices for prompting
against an api so
i have data apis
that i consume and when
i use spark or aigi
it usually creates a
mock that's wrong so
the way i've been
doing it now is just
running the api calls
manually and then use
feeding that into a
test folder for the
process to pick up i
don't know if there's
a better solution yeah
well i'll tell you
how i do it i use open
api.json and then i
just point it at that
and that basically
tells it what the
structure needs to be if
you don't give it a
structure it's going to
hallucinate the
structure and that's all
that's always going
to be your challenge
with any of these auto
dev tools you know it
doesn't tell you i
don't know it almost
never says i don't know
it's going to try to
solve the solution
where ambiguity lies
right so anything that
that isn't well defined
it'll attempt to
invent a solution too.
And an API is a perfect
example of that,
right? Some APIs are
well known, right?
Pun intended, but in
this particular scenario,
if it's your own API,
it's obviously gonna
have no idea what that
API looks like. Or
if it's something
that's been built after
the training materials,
like a perfect example
of this is the responses
API from OpenAI.
If you ask basically
any, you know, you know
i have these models
to build against that
it's just because it
was only launched like
a few weeks ago or
maybe a few months ago
anyway and uh so so
you said point to point
to report sorry for
that yeah yeah so i use
context 7 to solve that
problem for sdks yeah
context 7 works
particularly well and we
talked about this last
week a little bit you
know it there are some
limitations on things
that aren't indexed or
whatever but generally
speaking for the major
projects it works
there's like 15 000
projects in there and
uh for the ones that
aren't included or for
things that are more
nuanced in what i need
to discover or fix i
use the perplexity mcp
and then the
the two together
solve that those
problems they
just kind of go
figure it out
did you say as well
yeah so my way of
dealing with it you say
the mark is wrong right
so i always make
sure that the mock
actually match so i
ask it to make the mock
and out of the json
api whatever the open
api ask it to make the
mock and also write
unit tests and that
way you can actually
direct the unit test
temporarily to the real
api and see if they
work if they don't like
you go and basically
tell like fix unit
tests and then you say
fix the mock so that
unit has passed away
so it only takes like i
don't know maybe 20 30
minutes to get it right
and once you have the
accurate mock like
it you basically can
go on attendant like
forever like you're
what you're seeing is a
side effect of a test
-driven or a london test
-driven development
process right the entire
approach of a london
test-driven development
process is a mock
-driven scaffolding now
the the issue that
you're going to face at
some point is you're
going to want to go from
a mock to a functional
implementation of
that mock and what
sometimes happens in these
implementations is the
is the ai struggles
to go from the concepts
of a mock to uh
implementation that but
generally is resolved
by the uh guidance the
planning folder and
giving the right guidance
exactly but that's
my very early steps
is make sure like that
the mock is right so i
always point the unit
tests to the real api
and if they fail then
i say go fix your mock
i mean fix your test
first and then you
ask it to fix the mock
to match the tests like
you you can also mock
you can also use your
mocks if that's that's
the right term api
right but the the
challenge of that is usage
related and potential
security vulnerabilities
that that will
incur from it but if at
a later stage what you
could do is a more end
-to-end style testing
of those endpoints so
you're not you're not
just running the mocks,
you're running, you
know, a unit test
against real endpoints.
Oh, yeah, I do it like,
but not all the time,
because otherwise,
how you say there is
implications, but I
always like usually go
against the mock, and
then I flip to real
API once in a while to
make sure it's legit.
Yeah.
There's definitely,
yeah.
And I think there was
a comment about the
mcp.json, is that was
someone mentioned that?
no yeah there's there's
certainly lots of
uh you know considerations
right now in in
this and i think the
one thing and i sound
like a broken record
but the one thing i
want people to sort of
remember is most things
aren't going to run
for extended period
like you're when when
you look at the things
i'm running most
times the the longest
things i'm running are
two maybe three hours
tops mostly like sub
two hours and and then
i'm reviewing and
looking exactly what was
built and then deciding
either to to spawn
a new orchestration
or to revise what had
previously been built
and so i'm taking an
active role in whatever
that is being built
throughout the process
you're never going
to be in like go build
me this thing and
let it run for three
days it's It's not it.
All right.
Oh, it's not getting some
clicking there, guys.
All right.
Yeah, we're almost
out of time here.
Anything else
you guys want to
cover? Anything
exciting you're
working on? This
is your chance.
Very quick update,
Rub. I think I'll speak
separately, but very
quickly. We probably
have another event
around mid-June here in
London at Greenwich
University. university.
So I will, Ben or I
will, one of us will
be in touch to chat
about that with you.
Okay. Yeah. The
last one went really
well. The, I think
the biggest takeaway
we've had for some
of the events that
we've done yours and
the one in Toronto,
oversubscribe. When
we, we noticed that
there's a, there's a
pretty high drop-off
when it comes to free
events. So if your
venue you can hold
100 people get to
250 people signed up
also i'll i'll um just
throw out that uh
stockholm is now uh
got a tentative date
for june 17th and uh
****** v3 and some
of the folks i know
ocean you're in uh
in new york city as
well ****** v3 is
pulling things together
for a New York
City event as well.
And then Toronto Tech
Week is June 24th
here in Toronto. So
lots of stuff going on.
Vincent, I'm going to
be hammering you for
a Normandy date.
Yeah. The D-Day.
Right.
There you go.
Fantastic. That's
what I want
to go to, too.
I'm going to let you be
the first on the beach.
okay that too soon for
that joke i apologize
um we also have uh
amsterdam quite a bit
of interest uh in in
the netherlands to do
something i spoke to
our crew in malaysia and
singapore yesterday
looks like looks like
they're thinking july
for possibly kuala
lampor and uh sometimes
shortly after for
singapore um so if
anyone's in in that part of
the world tons of options
and interest there.
I think we have a
sponsor, which is nice.
And oh, by the way,
we have an open
solicitation for
sponsorship. So if
you know anyone
that's willing to
help sponsor our
various activities,
please let us know
and reach out.
Yeah.
All right.
I'm going to, I
think we're going to
call it a little
earlier today. I'm
a little bit swamped.
I've got another
six hours some
non-stop meetings.
So I really appreciate
everyone and
everyone who's
contributed today.
You know, ArcadeDev,
the DFAN crew.
Next week, we'll
get Braun on.
And if you have, like
always, if you have
any questions, feel free
to join our Discord.
Martin's done a
tremendous job of sort of
whipping that into
shape, right? Right.
I have a real quick
tech question here.
I'm scrolling
back madly on the
chat here to
try to take a
screenshot of some
interesting URLs
because they're going
to evaporate and
I can't see them
through Zoom anymore.
Is that something
we could automate?
I'm sure.
I'm copying it now
and we'll put it up
in Discord for you,
at least this time.
Yeah, I did see an
option in the Arcade
Tools for Zoom. We
should take a little
dig into what the tool
does. maybe we could
integrate some sort
of agentic flow
that grabs all that
information or we also
have a million of
these uh you know bots
reporting the call
but i don't know if
they look at the text
i think i think some
of them do so i'll
have to review my
fireflies and see if
it grabs information
all right yes okay
thanks everyone good
luck with the next six
hours of calls roof
i'm gonna put more
blockers or something
in my calendar i
think i need to
actually get work done
or something blockers
have a good weekend
everybody all
right thanks everyone
appreciate it bye