Hey.
How's it going?
Good, how are you?
I'm good.
Hopefully I have
more luck with
my live cast
than last time.
That's my first
time joining, so.
Oh, okay. Welcome.
It's going to
be better than
nothing, so, right?
Yeah, I had trouble
with my live cast
yesterday. The
live streaming
didn't end up working
for some reason.
now i'm trying to
figure out why i can't
even see today's live
cast as an option
it's always
something yeah
oh i think i might have
chosen no linkedin live
yeah so i show i
show up early because
there's always
something that breaks
i always i i'm just
sitting here you know
crashing out on stuff
at work so like i was
like yeah i'll just
join now and when when
everybody's when people
start showing up and
i'll i'll jump on yeah
we we uh we've got
like a a pre a pre-show
here the simple show
it's it's it's a
thing for sure right
yeah yeah i i like
doing these so yeah we
we do these obviously
every week and uh
people get a
chance to show what
they're what
they're building
and yeah it's fun
very cool where
where are you uh
based uh indiana
actually okay i'm a
i'm a midwest child
i i i've flown
over indiana
many have
it's the most flyover
of flyover states
no that that that's like
wyoming or something
it really is what's
what's crazy is
like like the i mean
it has like the gdp of
like colorado right
like so it's not small
but everybody
everybody's like oh it's
it's indiana it's got
to be small no not
really uh i mean
salesforce has headquarters
here eli lily's
headquartered here uh
really i mean yeah
like oh wow it's you've
got it you've got
a you got a race i
think and we we have
a race there is a race
uh and i think it's
coming up here soon
And I was actually
going to reach out to
one of my buddies. He
works for the sports
agency that runs it.
And so he was offering
people up a tour
together the last week.
So I might go down
there and check it out.
Yeah. No, it's –
I don't mind it. I
lived in Colorado
for a long time and
really, I mean,
enjoyed it out there.
But Indiana is
not terrible.
Yeah.
yeah i'm in ontario so
not too far away you
know i'm sure i'm sure
it's fairly similar
maybe maybe slight
slightly warmer you're a
bit further south but
yeah i mean are you like
toronto area yeah i'm
just i'm just outside
toronto okay all right
well i mean that's
like four hours away
three three and a half
yeah where you go so
well it depends that they
if they stopped me at
the border and asked
me about ai but uh
have they done that all
the time and really
yeah they they love and
and like so the last
time they asked me what
does ai stand for i'm
like i i and i'm i'm
now a **** right so i
said adobe illustrator
i see writing it down
didn't crack it didn't
crack a smile or
anything i guess those
border guys aren't
too uh aren't too into
the jokes oh man that's
too bad did you see
uh did you see the uh
the buffalo bills they
you know like all
the all the nfl teams
are doing their like
schedule releases or
their things like that
so they've been doing
a lot of creative
things with those and so
the buffalo bills they
did one and they're
like so josh allen
says hey let's use ai
right and they go and
find alan iverson he's
just pulling up papers
of their schedule
yeah it's so funny i
actually saw that i saw
that somewhere it's
morning funny enough
yeah yeah you know and
there was and another
football team got
in trouble for doing
something with like
minecraft or something oh
yeah that was the colts
that was indiana so
it was indianapolis
yeah yeah they build
it out with basically
and in a in a minecraft
looking uh way and
they're like we should
take that down yeah
and the colts haven't
done much since peyton
retired is that is
that the story there is
that yeah pretty much
pretty much it's sadness
oh yeah you had a
good run there yeah
yeah we'll we'll see
there's always there's
always hope for the uh
the next year right
that's how sports yeah
it could be worse you
could be the browns
i don't yeah
no i'm i'm good
with not being the browns
you know they're
the perennial losers
yeah but you're close
to detroit so i mean
that's a i i kind of
want to you know i i'm
only i'm only an hour
from Buffalo here, so
I kind of want Buffalo.
Oh, really? Okay.
But last year, I
wanted Detroit,
and that was kind
of a letdown.
But anyway,
you know,
you kind of want the
teams that are nearby.
Detroit's probably
about three hours away.
Oh, okay.
Buffalo's not
part of all.
Assuming I don't get
stopped at the border.
Right.
It's an hour when
I can fly through.
but what can you
do yeah i like
detroit i like i
like the i like
the city like
the architecture
uh you should
check an eight mile
yeah you ever been to
troy you know you know
eight mile yeah yeah
i everything i know
about eight mile i
learned from the m&m movie
well like like it was
it was like i think
it's really the 80s
and into the 90s like
they were just i
think i don't remember
i haven't seen that
movie in a long time
but like on on halloween
they would people
would just go burn
abandoned like
buildings and there's
so many abandoned
buildings so it's just
a thing that they did
in all on halloween
it was absolutely
crazy to me that that
was kind of a thing
yeah have you ever
been to rochester
new york kind of the
same sort of vibe
no but i have been
i have been upstate
new york to a couple
different places so
yeah i know the feeling
yeah rochester is
one of those cities
that you could tell
was was a big deal
like 100 years ago and
everyone left so it's
it's anyone stayed is
not there necessarily
by choice yeah they
couldn't they couldn't
leave yeah for one
reason yeah they
couldn't leave they don't
have the money or
whatever it's it's a
weird it's a weird
down there's a fair
amount of that in in
indiana i mean there's
there's definitely
good and definitely bad
yeah where's the rust
belt start um that's
a good question i would
say like wisconsin
would be the rust
belt the start of the
rust belt and then
ends in pennsylvania
so kind of comes
might be minnesota
so yeah so
wisconsin Wisconsin,
Illinois, Indiana, Ohio,
Pennsylvania,
those would all be
considered Rust Belt.
Just getting
my setup here,
just a little testing.
Today, I'm going
to – are you
a developer?
What do you do?
I do not claim to
be a developer,
but I dabble a
lot. And I'm in the
AI space. I do a
fair amount of AI
consulting and
strategy work mostly,
but I also, I'm
a generalist.
I build my own stuff.
I like to dabble.
I like to build things.
I like to problem solve.
So that's really
where I sit. So it's
more about how do
we operationalize
and really build
out true strategy
around AI is what
I'm focused on right
now that's ethical
and sustainable.
there's there's so
many different so
many different tools
and in my opinion
that are that are out
there that are just
junk and they're
just junk wrappers
of chat tpt they're
not optimized they're
full of holes
security and otherwise
and they're really
not delivering the
business impact that
they that they claim
that they they can
deliver and so So I kind
of focus on trying to
find the right tools
for the right time,
for the right strategy,
and help companies
take care of that.
Okay, cool.
Yeah.
And I'm building
some of my own models
right now for
different applications
that I'm working
on. so yes uh
you probably know
i do i do a lot of
the same sort of
work um yeah yeah
business is good
right now for
agentics that's for
sure yeah sure is
so it's it's it's
funny the whole world
mocked me when i
changed my linkedin
title to agentic
engineer a couple years
ago oh yeah you know
but apparently uh it
was the right move
so yeah yeah let that
be a lesson apparently
yeah i'm partnered
up with like i
actually just left my
full-time position to
go out on my own as a
as a somewhat lone
consultant i'm i'm part
of a collective and one
of the one of the people
that i'm working
with she's she was
marketing for 20 years
and about three years ago
she was like um
marketing is going to get
trashed by ai and i need
to switch that direction
and so she she really
focused hard in the
space and has really
created a solid solid
little niche for for
herself in in ai literacy
and and market use of
of the of generative
ai so it's pretty cool
i'd say that the one
suggestion i'd have
if you're independent
that that i i've done
that's worked really
well for me is this idea
of like being able to
book your you know
have people book their
time on their corporate
credit cards you know
so i've i've got this
this this booking thing
that i put together
and basically every
day i i random people
from all kinds of big
companies or small
individuals whatever they
go they go on the site
they book a session
with me they they click
whatever and that take
that takes them to
this uh calendary page
and they put in their
credit card and it's it's
spectacular and
there's no there's no
friction like i've got
the i've got the biggest
tech companies to again
just entrepreneurs
they go they yeah select
the time that works
and you know put put
in their uh they put in
their credit card whatever
and boom nice nice
right yeah yeah yeah
i definitely need to
set that up yeah it
works it works great and
um it basically it's
self-selected yeah anyone
anyone's willing to
pay for your your time
you know and to meet
with you is is basically
willing to pay right
right and then you
just fool around with
the the price to figure
out what demo you want
right if i lower my
price i get a lot
more people i can fill
every hour of the day
but it it's it's just too
much and so i i ended
up finding a like an
equilibrium of like
being expensive enough
that you need to have
the money and but also
you know limiting you
know the amount of time
i have to do it yeah
yeah i worked with uh
i was you know i was
testing the waters a
couple months back
and i i worked with i
worked with one that
was a uh one client that
she wanted me to build
everything for like
150 and i'm just like
yeah no that's we're
not going to do that
yeah or this is not
the this is not the
type of engagement that
i want to i want to be
involved with exactly
all right i'm going
to do the pre-stream
so just as an fyi the
means that some of
what will be said
might be starting to
stream so I just want
to give you a heads up.
Oops, I don't
have permission
to live stream. What?
What's going
on with this?
Let me try one more time.
That's why I test
this stuff beforehand.
Zoom's been giving
me trouble lately.
Worked.
Yeah, that's why
I show up early.
Never works
the first try.
All right, who
else we got
on the call here? Yeah,
nice to meet you, josh
you too and hi i'm
also here for the
first time so looking
forward to attending
it live i've saw a
few recordings but
yeah i find it very
interesting uh to the
very interesting topic
well thanks for joining
i i i i i hear three
times this week long
long time listener
first time caller it's
it's like it's it's a
it's become a thing
which i i guess if it
doesn't work out in
agentics i can be like an
am radio host or
something yeah i'm always
trying to keep up with
the latest developments
i'm not uh in the in
the field of uh coding
but yeah i think it's
really now time to
to basically step up
or miss the boat yeah
well it's it's gotten
absolutely crazy um
this this especially
over the last i'd say
like month and a half
two months the world's
gone just uh you know
absolutely bonkers for
agents and mcps it's
definitely the hottest
thing going if if if
uh my if my uh linkedin
inbox is any indication
anyway yeah i can
imagine yeah and i'm
also starting now with
root code and then
spark so i'm really just
learning but uh yeah
the resources you you
make available it's
really uh yeah it's a
gold mine so thank you
so much for it no my
pleasure and uh you
know i again i share
this stuff just as much
for me because i you
know it's uh it's a way
to sort of share what
i'm learning and it
sort of solidifies the
things i learn and
you know so and i also
joined the the whatsapp
chat and i already
mentioned that i'm in
texas but mostly in
education i uh work for
the university of curacao
uh so i'm uh teach
tech law there and i
also want to help the
university make some
steps in um yeah getting
to grips with all
the developments that
are going um but um yeah
if you the genetics
or uh organization
still needs more more
volunteers i'll be happy
to help oh for sure
yeah we we're always
hoping to volunteers
no question we do we do
really be happy to help
okay oh so Rob who
do we got lined
up I see Sandy good
to see you Sandy
Sandy Dunn yeah
fantastic so today
we've got Alex he's
got some interesting
stuff in his workflow
that he's been
working on as he's you
know building towards
the AI integration
on the fulfillment
side and And I think
David's got a few
minutes as far as the Web
Summit. And we got
some open air time.
There's a ton going on.
Brad has some
updates. And then I've
got some updates on
chapters as well.
Okay.
Great to be back. I
finally had to just
block this on my
calendar and just say, do
not put a meeting
over this meeting. so
fantastic
congratulations on
the fundraise I
see you guys are
killing it so
that's exciting
yeah it is really
it's super I mean
just like you
said Ruv super fun
space everything
is going so fast
and it's yeah it's
exciting to be part of it
yeah it's high
velocity is is i think
the uh the key here
it's and uh it's you
know for me it's
like i i sort of put
myself out there
with the with like
anyone can book my
time so it's just crazy
the things i see
you know random drug
companies showing
up and you know uh
it's it's like like
the breadth of the
opportunities
are so broad and
crazy you never
know what's
going to show up
on any given day
yeah in conversations
i i've had with people
this week with health
care facilities
where i talked about
don't just throw you
know if you don't
have good data access
policies in place and i
gave a couple uh examples
and i could see faces
going white on the
phone you know um yeah
it's it's crazy um
but super fun and and
you know as i always
said ruben um i
appreciate so much of
what you share i mean
you are so generous with
your knowledge and
and a trusted source
well appreciate that
yeah it's no it's
good it's good to
have a community that
supports each other
right make empowers
us to do and try
and push ourselves
forward right so it's
it's exciting i i
really this is like
the highlight of my
week all right we
have two minutes so
if you want you can
take a minute uh you
know to uh when we start
to uh introduce what
what your company's
doing if you want to
shout out oh absolutely
happy to to share talk
a little bit about my
my journey with how
i got to where i'm at
perfect we love that
yeah you guys have
kind of been part of it
you know trying to you
know i have trying to
jump into different
channels places that i
i felt like were
knowledgeable where i could
figure out like how
do i adapt how do i
know what's going on
how do i how do i make
sure that um i'm
knowledgeable and you joining
this community um
has was a big part of
it yeah it's it's it's
it's been at least a
little over a year so
it's been a wild ride
for us you know we're
we're we're a little
more technical but you
know it's it's it's
been it's been fun oh
and i could talk i mean
just a little bit to
kind of add on to what
you were talking
about ruben um i did a
presentation to our local
isaka team yesterday
and i thought it was
so smart because i
put all of i always have
tons of books podcasts
groups people i
recommend to follow and
typically i put it at
the end of my slides
and instead this time
kept my slides shorter
and just made it a
really nice github wiki
so people could just
go out find all of the
information and as
i shared and then i
created a qr code so people
could just take their
phones, go get it.
Like I'm trying to
make it easy. And in the
room I could see when
I talked about just go
out to my GitHub and
go get the resources.
I could tell that
they had no idea what
I was talking about. So
that's, that's how big
the gap is. You know,
people who have these
long careers and
audit and doing
compliance and things like
they've, I mean, they
don't even know what
GitHub is. That's how broad
the lack of information
and the surprises
that are out there.
All right. Well, we're
going to jump back.
We're at the top of
the hour. So I'm going
to, just to warn
you, I'm going to hit
the record button.
So everything will be
used against you from
this point forward.
And here we go.
We're about to go
live. Let me hit the,
it looks like We've
already been
recording the whole
thing. So somewhere
someone's going to
have to trim this
week's. I'm going
to go live here on
LinkedIn as well.
All righty. Here we are.
It's May 16th, 2025.
And this is the AI
Hackerspace Live here.
So I'm excited.
It's been another
crazy, wonderful,
busy week. Lots of new
things to show and
new things to discuss.
I'm just chatting with
Sandy here, a
long-time fan.
Rob, who do we got
lined up today?
We got quite a bit,
quite a few folks lined
up today, Ruben. A
couple of things. First
of all, we have Alex.
Alex is in the eyewear
industry, and he's
going to show some
of the elements and the
tools that he's been
building as he's developing
his AI workflows.
And then David's got
some stuff in and
around the Web Summit
that's happening in
Canada. Of course, we
have Sandy Dunn, who's
with us today and
has been a longtime
member. It's always
great to hear from Sandy.
We have a couple at
Brad as well. He's got
some updates on the
Eugenics Foundation.
And I just wanted
to let everybody
know that that UK
London event is
coming up. That's
coming up next
week. I believe
that is on the 21st,
and the UK event,
London event, is going
to be held, last I
heard, at the Google
offices there in
London, arranged by
our friends at Request
E. So we're really
looking forward to
that live event,
but also we have now
ambassadors that are
arranging and beginning
and coordinating
for their live
events in Singapore,
Tokyo,
Washington, D
.C., Virginia,
Florida. we've got
Colorado, Columbus, Ohio,
of course,
Normandy, France,
I'm not sure
which town in
Normandy, several
cities in Italy,
Frankfurt, Germany,
all around the world,
events are lining up
and we're beginning
the process of
getting them set up.
So it's going to be
a really exciting
summer as Agenic
Engineering and the
Agenics Foundation
starts to spark local
cities and communities
around the world.
Well, there's a lot of
information to unpack.
I think the most
interesting thing
that just came out,
I don't know if
you guys have been
paying attention,
is the ChatGPT just came
out with a coding system,
like literally
hot off the
press, something
like that,
whatever the
right acronym
or metaphor is here.
Let me give you guys
a quick look. This
is brand new. I
just got this in my
inbox literally 10
minutes ago. So this
is ChatGP launches
Codex and AI online.
So not to be
confused with their
tool that they
had, which is
like a CLI tool
for VS Code.
This apparently is
built into actually
the system. I'm
not sure. It's
rolling out to
starting data scribers
and ChatGPT Pro
enterprise and team.
It plans to
expand access.
Now, I don't know.
Let's go take a
look and see if it's
actually available.
I don't know.
This might be too
new to even tell.
Let's see here.
Where the heck do you
think we'd find that?
Let's see if I can
find it. No, I don't
see it yet. I
guess I don't have
it. If anyone has
access, let me know.
I'm seriously interested
in that. One of
the things that I've
been using a lot this
week, actually, is the
integration here of
GitHub, which is one
of the coolest new
features that they've
recently rolled out
that allows you to
basically integrate your
GitHub repo directly
into deep research.
So in here you can
see I was pulling
around with my agent
naming service earlier,
so I'll give you a
little demo there.
So we're at the portion
of our little weekly
event here where I'll
show you some stuff.
So let's get going.
This week's been
interesting for me.
I've been focused a
little bit on trying
some new systems,
one of which was
this system that I've
become a pretty big
fan of called Mastra.
Mastra, Mastra,
Mastra, Mastra up
your Canadian, Mastra
up your American.
Basically, it's
an agent-based
framework that
allows you to create
complex agents
in TypeScript.
And basically, it's
really powerful.
It allows you to
create MCPs and tools
and other various
capabilities. I
really like the
separation between the
way that they handle
an agent and the
these workflows.
Now, one of the big
things that actually
jumped out at me in
using this was how
they've actually integrated
the MCP directly.
And so I built a
prototype using a new
project from the Onsap
folk, Onswap, Onsap,
something I got yesterday.
So they came out
with this agentic
naming service. So I
figured I'd give that
a spin, but I want to
try it. I want to try
a new framework as
well. So what I did
is I went in here and
I loaded actually.
So this is root for
those who are unfamiliar.
This is root code.
You can install the
root code extension.
And I went in and
set up the Mastra
MCP. So you see
there's a Mastra blog,
there's a Mastra
docs. And most
importantly, there's
a Mastra example.
So in this case, what
we can do is I created
a memory, but I
also updated my MCP
option. So the MCP option
in Roo allows me to
sort of interact with
these third parties
and things like that.
But what's cool about
the Mastra, and this
to me speaks to the
sort of future of
potential integration of
MCPs within the
structure of websites and
commerce and sort
of this idea of the
separation of the human
part of the Internet
from the kind of
agentic or agent-centric
part of the Internet.
This is a conversation
Robin and I were having
actually last night
on one of our weekly
update calls. And
the idea that right
now the Internet is
essentially built for,
you know, the data
-centric parts are APIs
and DNSs and HTTP and
that sort of thing,
but it's not really
optimized for this kind
of agent-style approach,
right? when you look
at the agent part
of the website, so
usually saying, here are
the things we don't
want you to look at.
So what the Monster
guys have done in terms
of their MCP is that
they basically made it
really easy for me to
just point at their
documentation and say,
how do I build stuff?
So let me show you
exactly what that looks
like. So I'm in my MCP
mode. I'm actually using
GPT 4.1. It's got a
much bigger context.
When you're using
MCPs, sometimes context
matters in terms of
size. so what so this
case I'm using that
so this I'm gonna say
tell me how to create
a master a workflow
you and I'm sort of
mind it using the master
master MCP now this
is so what what you're
gonna see here is it
if all goes well and
the reason why I've
updated to this to
sort of know about the
master MCP and if you
look over here you'll
see it I got a bunch
of descriptions that
basically tell you
how to use it this will
automatically invoke
the master docs right
now in this case
it's looking at the
doc pass it's it's
discovering how to use
it but what's cool is
because it also has
the examples endpoint
which i can go here
and and i can i maybe
i'll go tell it to use
the i'll go back here
for a moment oops why
isn't that i'll go
here and i'll just
remind it i want to use
not the docs let's
let's help you use the
examples so i'm just
going to say use this
and i'm going to
go back and i'm
going to say
uh i'm going to
i'm going to say
uh give use the
use master examples
to find an example
see let's see what
that comes up with
so basically what
this is doing is
sort of interactively
going back and forth
with their
documentation examples
and then I can get it
to easily implement
whatever it is I
want to implement.
So in that, now it's
using, it didn't give
it an example, which
is interesting. Maybe
I'm going to need a
little more guidance. And
now it's saying, here
are the different
options. You've got
agents, AWA, you've got
memory systems, you've
got mem zero, all these
different things. And
now it's looking at
the different options.
So it really makes this
kind of autonomous
development super simple.
So what can you build
with that? So in
this case, I built, you
know, another agent,
it built out all the
code. What does that look
like? So I'm going
to jump in a lot of
time. So I'm just going
to jump and show you
what the front end looks
like. I created this
agent naming system,
but more importantly,
Master has this really
nice, elegant sort
of UI that you can use.
So I'm just going to
go with the weather
agent just as an example
of how to. What's the
weather in Toronto?
Now I'm going
to go back here.
Now two things are
going to happen here,
right? It's going to give
me the weather obviously
but i can also i can
also go back here
and see what what's
happening on the command
line so it's well i guess
i guess in this case
it's not showing me
for some reason but
that's okay we've got
the trace the trace will
also show me each step
along the way so this
this shows each of
the of the steps so if
you want to sort of
optimize or or see what's
happening behind the
scenes it gives you
that you can run in
evaluations which i don't
have currently running
but you can have
different ways to evaluate
the the components
you've got various different
options for tooling
so you got the master
blog tool that i
created i and i've got
a uh the weather tool we
got these workflows
that are created that
allow you to sort of
create a kind of visual
element here to the
uh the system which
is which is pretty
cool so i go in here
i can see that there's
different steps.
So let's just look
at this step for a
moment. It creates a
little graph. You know,
I can, I can run
those. I can, I can
interact with all the
end points. This is a
hundred percent. Like
literally last night,
the guys at came out
with this project,
the agent naming
service project,
which basically
creates this, the
structure. I, I, I
basically fed it.
I did deep research
in chat GPT,
fed it my research and
then said, go build
me that you can see
the research here.
This is, this is how I
go ahead and build it
purpose. and there
you go. Next thing you
know, I've got an entire
functioning system
with certs and
databases and protocols
and threat analysis,
everything you need
all built and ready to
go. I got in the morning
and I'm good to
go. It's about as
exciting a way to get up
when you have something
new waiting for you
that was building
all night. And that's
essentially how I do
it. A couple things
to note here. In this
case, I was using a
memory bank structure.
So it saves some
of the information.
So there's lots of
different ways to
deploy it. But
everything you see is
available if you want
to give it a spin.
Really, really cool
system. You see the
different endpoints
here. So here's another
example. There's the
OpenEye documentation.
There's a Swagger UI
if you want to see the
API itself. it's it's
elegant it's fast it's
light everything i'm
i'm i think i'm a pretty
big fan of maestra
you know after using
it here for the last
day or so you can see
here there's there's
options for speaking
there's voice there's
listening options tool
selections there's
networking if you want to
cross networks there's
mcp registrations
telemetry tons and
tons of stuff so it's
pretty pretty cool it's
worth worth uh worth
taking a look if you're
interested um but what
i'm really interested
in is is trying to
get this working but
i guess maybe hasn't
been fully rolled out
yet i'm curious has
anyone been able to get
uh the codex is there
a secret is there a
secret site i'm not aware
of or i'm trying to
figure out where where
that is i love i love
a new a new coding
system that's there's
probably nothing better
maybe maybe i'm gonna
go old school and
just uh do a quick
search because i'm dying
to find out open it it
was a chat gpt codex
yeah gpt code codex
anyway what maybe i'll
have to come back to
that anybody comes
across it let ruv know
Oh, hang on a sec. It
says, let's see here.
Loading.
There's got how
Codex works.
How do you get
it to work?
Is it, is it?
No, I don't care
about the stats.
Anyway.
There was a try button
at the top there.
Oh, there was.
Oh, let's go
back to that.
Ruben, I went in
through the, where
did I, I went in
through the login to
the API, and it's
over on the left.
Okay.
It's on the left?
Yeah.
All right. Let's
go back and chat if
you can see him so
you can find it.
Try Codex.
Oh, right. Okay.
So one of these
options on the left?
No. I went in. you
know how you can log
into ChatGPT either as
you can log into the
Playground or you
can log into ChatGPT.
It's only available
for pro users now,
not for Plus yet.
I've got everything
under the sun. I've
got seven different
accounts on Tier
5. I'm sure I'll
figure it out. I just
need to go find
where the button is.
So I think it's platform
.openei.com I think.
It's the API platform.
there's a platform
URL
here's where I
found it right
here it's in the platform
alright let's go there
and see if I can find it
I need to ask ChatGPT
where to find it
it's like
why call it ChatGPT
if it's not in ChatGPT
that would be the
more obvious option
we'll come back to
that I'm going to
fool around with it
in the background.
I see Sandy. So this is
your opportunity, Sandy.
You're one of our
early supporters.
And I'd love to
hear more about
your story and
what you're up to.
Yeah.
Great to be back. I
was telling before
the call that I have
been so busy that
it seems like I
always have a conflict
with this. Every week
there's a conflict.
And so I finally
had to block it
and say, do not put
anything over this
time so that I can
attend this meeting.
So I used to come
to them all the
time and then got
super busy with
some other stuff,
but really glad to
be back. I'm the
CISO at Splix AI.
I shared some
resources. I don't
know. Did you look
at our agentic
radar that we open
sourced, Riven?
Yeah, about a month
ago, I think it was.
Yeah, we just did some
updates so that it
manages MCP too. So you
guys, if you haven't
looked at it lately,
that might be something
that allows you to
scan and see your
dependencies within
your different agent
things. I'm part a core
member of the OWASP top
10. So I talk a lot
about AI security and
all of the things. I
shared a great book
that I thought people
on this call might be
interested in that my
friend Philip Dursey
just published on.
And I just got it, so
I made it through the
first chapter, and
it's already heavily
redlined. It's so good.
But it's on AI
Red Teaming.
So I'm happy to be
here, happy to talk
about anything that
I can help you with.
Yeah, so tell us
more about what your
release was, like
what to focus on,
what problems you
guys solve with it.
Okay, so also I
shared my calendar.
So what Splix does
is we actually
automate your
AI red teaming.
So I'm sure you, you
know, Ruben, you've
posted about this. I'm
sure other people have
talked about, you
know, the importance of
being able to go in and
making sure that, hey,
you can't trick
whatever deployment your
chatbot or your agent
into doing something
it's not supposed to
do. So we automate that
process. We allow you
to actually create
your own custom probes
are what the tests call.
are called and then
we align it with a
dashboard so you can
see you know as a CISO
that's what I loved
about it when they first
talked to me about
joining the company I
was just like you know
I love the dashboard
being able to have
visibility into it and see
my alignment with
different frameworks and
get great reports very
easily so if anyone's
interested in that
please book some time
on my calendar i'd
love to show you what
we're doing okay yeah
so it's uh the security
part you know is probably
the most you know
uh the biggest opportunity
for like enterprise
you know adoption
right now right the
the there's this kind
of misconception with
a lot of enterprises
that you know that the
llm is going to magically
you know steal all
your information and
and somehow you know
i hear that almost every
day it's like oh we
we need we we need to
use on-prem because
the LLM is magically
stealing our information,
yet they have no
issue using, you know,
AWS or Google or
Microsoft, which
literally is their
Dropbox and OneBox and
whatever, right?
Absolutely, Reuben.
Yep.
Preaching,
preach, preach.
I mean, it's just,
it's what people are
worried about and what
they should be worried
about. Really, my
my position on it is
we absolutely have
got you organizations
have to deploy these
solutions as fast as
they can to get in
front of all of the
legacy problems that
they have. Like, you
know, don't do it,
you know, with intent.
Don't just throw it
into an environment
that you haven't
got identity
and data managed
in. That's like
throwing gasoline
on an old shack.
But, you know, our
adversaries are moving.
Like, I think we talked
about it a little
bit on the pre-call.
If I could explain, if
I could help people
understand how fast
things are going, if
I knew a good way. I
mean, people like us
who are passionate about
us, I actually posted
a triangle on this.
Like, if you step
out of our world,
because all I talk
about is AI and AI
security. But if
you step out of our
world, there are
very few people who
really understand
what's going on.
And the further
you move out of the
tech space, the
more lost they are.
And Ruben, I think you
talked a little bit
about this, the importance
of communication,
understanding the
business problem.
I mean, those are
skills. You know, I'm a
nerd, not nearly as
nerdy as everybody
else on this call,
but the being able to
communicate is probably
the top skill that
we all need to develop
and get better at.
So, Sandy,
how can I educate
my leadership to
persuade them
to invest in the
necessary security
to keep any customer
or publicly facing
agents safe?
Just set up a meeting
with me. i have some
really scary slides
can someone please
repaste sandy's link
or sandy if you could
please it's in the chat
i joined late that's
right okay also sandy
i want to i want to
thank you for putting
your hand up as far
as the uh the genetics
foundation's ai
safety and responsible
Deployment Committee.
Fabrizio Sealy and
a number of others
have also, excuse
me, sort of put their
hands up to help
build that resource.
And we're looking
forward to seeing
that come together.
So thank you.
You've been a
member for the whole
time, and it's
really wonderful to
have your expertise
on that as well.
Yeah, and I'm
working. And so we can
repurpose that. You
know, I spend a lot of
time talking about it.
So we can repurpose
a lot of the stuff
I've already done.
yeah it's it's uh yeah
it's it's certainly
a amazing time for
sort of the adoption of
this technology and and
and sometimes i don't
i don't know if it's
like my skewed perception
because i have to be
at the you know in
the midst of it all
like but it's become
all you know absolutely
insane over the last
few weeks like all of
a sudden the entire
world seems to seem
seems to want some kind
of mcp or an agent-based
infrastructure it's
just absolutely
astounding and i i wonder
if others are seeing
the same thing or is it
maybe it's just me i
was uh i was at a cio
event yesterday right
um and obviously they
were talking about
agents and ai but the
awareness even at the
top c level is very
minimal it's like this
thing is coming this is
what it can do etc but
the realization of i
i mean i i didn't
decipher this as much so
this was an you know
it was a formal event
organized by one of
the gartner competitors
actually so it's
a lot of awareness
required what i also
saw is opportunities of
looking at like there
were members that
from english heritage
these are these are non
-profits right our
national trust which
looks after sustainable
solution and others
i just feel that
they have so much of
need and i think
there's an opportunity
to create this
this volunteer base
that we have here
to shape some
projects and then
show potentially the
outer possibility
and, and other stuff.
So, yeah, you
know, that's what
came out. So one
thing is, I think
the real realization
even at C
-suite is a very,
very minimal about
the impact. Yeah. I
second that. I was at a
CIO meeting a couple
of weeks ago and we
presented there. And,
and one of the key
insights that I, that i
carried out of that was
the the strategy right
now for for a lot
of cios and a lot of
companies in general is
dabbling in ai it's
not really leveraging
it to um actually gain
competitive advantage
it's it's it's dabbling
we're experimenting
here we're doing
something there we've
we've implemented like
we had one from a from
a billion dollar plus
company that that said,
I don't trust any of
our data that has,
you know, pricing on
it for our competitors
in our Azure tenant.
And I saw something,
you know, somebody
wrote that in the chat
here. And I'm like, why
wouldn't you? Is it,
you got it emailed to
you. It's probably in
a OneDrive somewhere.
It's in the same tenant.
Like, why are you
concerned about this?
And it's AI literacy.
They just don't know.
And that's at
the CIO level,
right? So,
yeah, go ahead.
Now, your data point
actually just occurred
in your mind
because everyone is
hiding behind the fact
that we need perfect
data for AI, right?
Everyone is hiding,
like, data is, I
understand that, but
it's an old argument.
But the whole point
is, no, you don't
need perfect data.
You know, we've moved
beyond the stage.
So, I mean, it's
a very senior
individual, very
experienced individual,
but the industry
is keeping
on saying you
need perfect data.
Effectively, people are
trying to still sell
data management
solutions. that's what is
going on so that this
education thing um is
massive yeah yeah and
and but to the point that
you know everyone's
******* the tires 100
every every company
everywhere is *******
the tires on on these
agents and the almost my
daily conversation i
you know work work with
the variety of companies
that run the gamut
from the biggest
companies on the planet to
random aspiring
entrepreneurs. But the big
companies are, I
think there's a couple
assumptions that they're
looking at. We're moving
away from a purely
human-centric web. And
what does that actually
mean? And we're looking
at the broad drop in
usage of traditional
consumer websites across
the board. Everybody
is looking at right
now, if you look at
March, which is probably
the most recent you
know, month for actual
strong numbers between
a 20 and 40% drop in
traffic for pretty
much every consumer
orientated website. And
that's almost entirely
being driven by this idea
of zero click LLM
driven search engines,
chat GPT, Claude,
whatever. And so everyone's
scrambling to say,
okay, how do we measure
it with like the actual
impact of our brand?
How do we convince
people to go from the
support site to buy
the product in on the e
-commerce part of our site
and you know so there's
this sort of
reimagination of the web
itself and so part of
i think my job as an
energetic engineer is to
help navigate this kind
of reimagination of
the web and and and
websites and it feels as
like old time guy that's
been around since the
beginning of the web
it feels like 1994 it's
like everyone knows
they need to create
a website or this new
thing called the web
but no one's quite sure
exactly how to implement
it or or sort of you
know take advantage of
it which is a double
-edged sword it means
that the incumbents
are going to get their
*** kicked if they don't
do something quickly
and the ones that are
looking to to re to
establish themselves
startups or or you know
outsiders if you will
have the opportunity
to step into the void
that's potentially
being left by those who
don't quite get it rant
over all right um yeah
eugenics uh robot
text yes yeah hey one
thing we talked about
a few years ago a
couple years ago actually
do people like try
to influence the llm
by just putting up
a lot of content on
the web that favors
the company so it will
trickle down to the
models like when
they scrape and train
like Because like, for
example, if you ask
about like Facebook
or John Deere, right,
the LLMs would give you
like extensive answer.
If you ask about like
Uncle John's like
bicycle shed, they would
probably have no idea.
you know what i've
noticed um and this this
is you know anecdotal
at best but i i've
my traffic is soaring
and i think the reason
and this is not a i'm
not like an seo expert
by any stretch we'll
leave that to bron and
others who spend a
lot more time on that
sort of thing but here's
a perfect example this
is a post i did like
two weeks ago a cookie
cutter mcp you know
you know my posts are
basically in the top
couple spots. And I think
it's driven specifically
by things like my
subreddit. And what's
interesting is when I
do a post, especially
I post it to my
subreddit, which has
become really popular, I'm
instantly in Google and
Bing, right? Sometimes
within minutes I've
measured. And I think
there's like this
sort of fire hose of
information from
places like reddit
and x and others
that directly influence
where and how the
information is indexed
but on the on the on
the other problem with
that is you get like
a you know the zero
click uh component in
google where well this
is a bad it's not giving
me a zero click but
let's say uh your latest
uh top uh gamer mouse
or something you
know it it skips uh of
course it's not working
at the moment but
generally there's like a
there's a little summary
that gives you like
all the top results
without ever me having
to go to that website
of course i'm going to
show you it doesn't work
but you get the idea
would be interesting
if you try to ask
something like you
posted six months ago and
see if it shows up on
the llm and and i don't
know if people seo the
llms like because if
you whatever open ai
wherever they scrape the
data you just post a lot
of content everywhere
that kind of like
drives to your site or
something yeah i was
i anecdotally i was
using perplexity this
morning and my company
where i came up in the
search results as it
was looking for and
we've had a team doing
some seo um and ruv to
your point about um that
reddit channel because
there's so many
followers on that channel
i guarantee you that
the the page rank
authority associated with
that page is massive
because of the number of
followers because
reddit's one of the top
authorities on the
internet for content right
now interesting yeah
anybody knows like does
open ai or like entropic
do they consider
page rank in open ai
does have an agreement
with reddit they had
to yep also has an
agreement with reddit so
i wouldn't be surprised
if they aren't ingesting
the data in near
real time no but not
ingesting but they do they
consider page rank as
one of no they wouldn't
necessarily well it's
the other way around
because there are so
many followers of that
page right in the
context of the topic
right that would give
that page more authority
than let's say you know
me writing an article
on an mcp server
randomly on my personal
blog yeah and the i
think the the takeaway is
is it there's
consistency helps posting
frequently the there's
this other if we're in
the realm of uh you
know anecdotal i've been
i've been obviously
vibing for four years with
you know starting with
the early versions
of codex you know that
came out in 2000 uh
2020 21 i think it was
and then chat gbt and
and a lot of the work
that i do is in this
kind of gray area of
like the sort of what's
possible but not yet been
done like hallucinations
and i kind of let
the ai kind of guide
me a little bit and
like well what if i
combine this with that
and it's like well this
should exist basically
it's kind of the the
area that i'm trying
to play in and what's
interesting is what i've
noticed is i'm building
the things that i
think should be built
but it hasn't yet been
built and then in later
iterations when i
come back and i i look
at the things i built
two years ago it's like
it's re-indexed and
now i'm like the result
for the thing that
originally wasn't built
that i built based on
the input that it gave
me that i should build
and now i'm like the
top result for it it's
like this kind of self
-reinforcement feedback
loop or something
on this topic sandy can
i ask you a question
yeah yeah it's basically
what i said in the
chat like how do you
feel about this kind
of exposure in the
agentic world like versus
privacy concerns no
i i'm just as you're
speaking i'm actually
posting um an episode
of the cognitive revolution
in response uh to
your your question
Which is, this is an
episode with a former
person who worked at
OpenAI talking about,
you know, part of the
challenge of moving
forward will be what's
real, what's not real,
you know, who's, you
know, machine identity
versus human identity.
And in this episode,
you know, he
didn't specifically
call out, he talked
about Sam Altman's
eyeball thing,
you know, being
a verified human.
And, you know,
it is, I absolutely
have major concerns over
privacy. I mean, if
you watch, I mean, all
of our data is getting
****** up everywhere.
I, you know, when I
present, I talk about,
think about every place
you go. I went with
a friend to some
trampoline place to play
with as a family. And
as I walked in, I had
to be able to go in and
jump. I had to agree
to having being
recorded. I had to share
my information. I had
to share all of that.
Like privacy is
a problem, but
it's been a problem
for a while.
um and i you know i
don't have great answers
um because it it
definitely um all of this
data collection and i
mean we're definitely
in a world where we're
being you know it's
complicated um and so
you know like when i
look around on the
horizon and say okay you
know what what does
the future look like
um i could see a
splintering you know maybe
part of the problem
is we're all trying to
communicate on this big
dirty internet that's
full of horrible things
maybe we splinter
i you know if you think
about you know cell
phones when they first
came out i can remember
when texting you had
to hit a key like
four times to get the
letter that you wanted
i was like why would i
ever spend 10 minutes
trying to type hello
when i could just
call someone so it's
really hard this is so
huge i've heard it
compared to the wheel fire
electricity um i don't
think we know i think
that the future it's
going to be rough for
a little while and the
the future is going
to be really interesting
uh follow up on
that is do you see any
potential opportunities
in this privacy area
um here's i um i have
startups that talk to
me about governance
solutions and everything
here's the reality
we have never created
we do not have a
system that protects
people's privacy or security
today our our technology
world has never
caught up from the
physical world. So think
about your policing
system. Your policing
system was set up
because physical crime
happened at a city,
county, state, federal
level. That's how it's
funded. That's how it's
operated. Where 90%
of the huge crime that
happens to people is
actually from international
crime. And that's
handled, you know,
that group of people
here in the United States
is an incredibly
small group of people
that are trying to manage
and stay in front of
it. If you look at
the most recent FBI
internet crimes report,
the people who had, I
don't remember, I think
it was $15 billion.
The most impacted
group were people
over 60. They lost
a ton of money.
So now the audits and
SOC 2s and all of that,
I mean, the reality
is we haven't been in
front of this. We
have never had a great
system. It's been a
checkbox for a really long
time. Security is
really, really hard to do
well and it's been um
security theater is to
use Bruce Schneier's
term like um historically
as a CISO what you
knew you know we had
the you guys know the
joke about finding a
grizzly two joggers or
two hikers finding a
grizzly bear and one
guy stops put on his
tennis shoes all I had
to do was outrun the
next guy I just had to
have enough friction
that there was other
better targets for my
adversaries. That has
changed. I also posted a
video to a talk I went
to in San Francisco
that was absolutely
terrifying, where a gentleman
retrained Lama to
create his own version
of a system that could
become an AI worm.
So I think the future
is rough. I think
it's going to be
interesting. I think people
are doing a lot of
stuff really fast.
Security's always
taking a back seat you
know it took us 40 years
to get x-rays before
they wouldn't you
know kill people so
you know we're uh you
know like security
and and um people's
protections asbestos
i mean i can give up
you know like looms
i mean we've always
people had to die and
have harm before we
figured out a way i
think the complexity
here is we actually
have to rewrite the
entire rules to create
a safe world so um
that's a really complex
not good answer to
a difficult question
so uh on that
note let's let's
move on to our
presentations um
uh thanks i appreciate
all the great
feedback here um rob
are you still here
yep and we've got
a and we got alex
he's got some uh
some tools he wants
to share from his
workflow is AI stuff
you know the irony
behind everything today
is that docker has
completely broken on my
machine and it won't
spin up so we're gonna
look at vs code um
intros my desktop so
on the theme of data
and privacy and clean
data and um not clean
data so for those of
you who don't know me
i'm alex devold i'm
on my fourth startup
this one's called varai
um can you guys see
my screen i can't see
what's going on anymore
okay so i'm dealing
in the eyewear
industry um where one
billion pairs of frames
are made every single
year and like apparently
four billion people
already need glasses
and most of them
don't have it here's
the challenge the vast
majority of these
opticians including our
friend david crowe in
toronto whose wife is
an optician they're
using software from
probably 20 years ago
opticians are horribly
behind the existing
market so i have customers
in Kuwait, in Europe,
in North America.
And there's a couple
of key themes. One is
they don't know what
to do with their own
data. This one retailer
has 600 stores and
people are manually
entering SKUs. And they're
like, I want to be
able to support my
customers online. Like,
well, what do you have?
Half big data, like
literally half big
data from data entry.
So one of the first
things that I had to
do is actually build
something that I
called SKU Genie. That
was just find it
here. We talked about,
you know, scraping
and data cleaning.
So I built a system
that said, look, I'm not
going to be in the
business of actually
doing this every single
day. Like it's just,
it's not worth it. So
how can we apply AI in
such a, in a way that
it makes everybody's
life easier? And
hopefully you can see this
at this point. So the
intent was like, look,
man, we should actually
have an application
that is always on
almost like a cloud
function. Theoretically,
this could be an MCP
that's called as an
application that is
always continuously
cleaning people's data
because whether it's my
customer in europe or
the middle east even
though there's a fixed
number of manufacturers
nobody's doing data
entry properly why
is data so important
because you can't actually
build any ai models
for recommendations
so you know for gideon
that he's got a pair
of glasses in theory
his optician should
send him an email in a
year when his insurance
policy says hey you're
due for another pair
of glasses right the
ai should be able to
look back at the prior
frames that he bought
or Roof bought or
whoever's wearing glasses
and say, hey, this
person tends to like
these kinds of glasses.
Go fetch the SKUs, look
at the color, style,
pattern, shape, and
width of glasses that
this person's bought
in the past and send
them an email with
the new ones. None of
that is possible, right?
At all whatsoever.
The second,
so this is basically
done kind of sitting
in kind of my development
environment and
almost ready to go in
terms of the system the
second partner on
data and security as
sandy was talking about
it is that i actually
had to build a dual
deployment strategy so
where i was kind of
messaging the startup
channel what's up is
basically saying look
if i'm going to run
my staging environment
i actually have to
build a dual deployment
model so i might have
this core concept of
engines that
are running in
the background
for intelligent
recommendations
for frames.
But
because people in
Europe have specific
requirements, I have
to have a central
repository where
I'm building my
models, but then
I have to deploy
independent models
as they interact with
customers on behalf
of the retailers.
And it has to be HIPAA
FIHR compliant and
data cannot actually
transverse borders.
So the data consumed
by my customer in the
UK or in France has to
stay in that market.
So the models can be
trained separately.
So there's a whole
other layer of code here
that basically says,
we have a centralized
model. We're going
to deploy the model.
That model is going
to learn from data
in those markets.
That's anonymized.
There's a whole bunch
of legal and insurance
that I still have
to figure out around
this in terms of
operationalizing it.
And then secondly,
each individual
site has to be separate.
So retailer one can't
see what retailer two
sees. They can't see
what retailer three
says. But on an anonymized
level, if I'm the
manufacturer, I want to
be able to see how my
frames are doing. So
Veri actually stands
for a vertical AI stack
in the IRA industry.
so um yeah so i've
gotten to the point where
all the individual
components are built
the interesting
slash annoying
challenge is
that i've used my
experience in in
tech to basically
outpace my developers
like i think two million
lines of code have
been committed in the
last month and a half
following this new spark
framework so thank you
ruv um the challenge
though is that while
everything passes unit
tests locally and i'm
compiling my docker
file and pushing it to
live it starts breaking
it's like why are you
working locally and
i'll be able to execute
everything but the
second i start doing
this deployment model
with the with the
different environments it
starts breaking so it's
interesting times but
the lightning talk
is basically data is
important uh you have
to have clean data from
clean data i can make
recommendations from
recommendations, I can
start capturing all of
the user-related
information or transaction
-related information. But
there's a whole other
level, as Sandy was
saying, around data
security. There's three
major retailers that
I'm talking to right
now in Europe, and they
are scared witless
about what AI will do to
their stores. And how
do you link, how do you
anonymize personal
information from the
retail level so that Sandy
can get an email that
doesn't include
all of the personal
information so how
do you link ai
into this existing
legacy business and
i'm no word of a lie
i was talking to the
cmo of one of these
retailers and he's like
look this guy who's
our cto he said i
got in trouble i was
pushing for ai he's
ex-loreal i'm pushing
for ai pushing for
crm and it's like if
this guy quits nobody
knows how to run the
system so we have we
have like we have 650
employees. We have
a system that hasn't
been upgraded in five
years. I can get you
the data. I can
literally see the string.
He sent me the API
documentation on a
public URL. I can see
the URL. He goes, I
can't give it to you.
If this guy quits,
we don't know what
we're going to do.
So it kind of
touches on all of the
topics, right? So we've
got EU regulations,
we've got data
cleaning, you've got
data hygiene, and
you've got data
orchestration, and
you've got to make sure
that it sits
independently in these
locations or else
there's **** to pay.
It's interesting you
mentioned that because
that's like been my
reoccurring theme
the last week or so.
It's like I'm working
with some large
consumer companies and
they're all saying exactly
what you just said.
And they're struggling
with this idea of
the integration of
existing legacy data,
you know, the ability
to make it readily
available both internally
just to their own
people in a in a
uniform way but also
potentially externally
like you know what you
know what if i want my
supply chain to interact
with us programmatically
and as for all
the reasons you just
outlined so it's a
it's a huge opportunity
and to ocean's point
you know where are some
of the the opportunities
in the space well
there's obviously
opportunities to
secure that entire life
cycle in the ways that
sandy has mentioned But
there's also the
opportunity to instrument
all those things in
a way to streamline,
you know, it has
introspection to
understand where and
what's happening and
why it's happening
and or just be
kind of like, you
know, some of the
consultants in the
group, be the person
that facilitates
that transformation.
I thought the same
thing, Ruben, when he was
describing it. I
thought there's the
opportunity, build that
layer, because if you're
finding that problem
with agentic and trying
to implement it,
everybody else will have
it, you know, we'll
have that same issue.
But, you know, just
to make another point
around the regulation
and the future, I don't
think the way that we
have governance and
technology, HIPAA, I
mean, how many people
got HIPAA letters because
their personal health
data was impacted? I
think I got four of
them. Okay. So it's
not working. It's a law
that was put up in 1996,
you know, way before
we do what we do.
And, you know, so the
thing that drives HIPAA
and all of this, what
they're worried about
is legal. It's lawyers
is what they're
concerned about. They're
not concerned about
privacy or security,
really. They're worried
about getting sued.
So I anticipate, and
again, this is for the
big thinkers, which is
if you look over the
horizon, um there's
we've got to develop a
different way to solve
for for security and
privacy in the future
without driving it
through hipaa and regular
regulation laws because
they don't move at the
speed of technology
i don't know how
that's going to happen
but i'm telling you that
everyone who's telling
you about how their
ideas about around
ai governance um it's
it's lipstick on a pig
It's computationally
impossible to do it.
It was hard and
really wasn't working
well before. It's
computationally impossible
to do some of the
governance things
that people are talking
about around AI.
One of the first
things that I did
is we have a
cyber insurance
policy of $5 million,
even though I'm
not touching a
lot of data yet.
The number one
thing that I made
sure that my
startup did was get
policy around
cyber insurance.
Quite literally. and
there's an interesting
guy in calgary who i
follow on instagram
who uh who basically
says look like there's
two different kinds
of people there's the
people who do all of
these vibe coding videos
online saying hey just
get your clients to
use uh um oh my goodness
zapier and connect
with infrastructure
and this other guy's
like you're kidding if
you don't know python
like there's not a
single enterprise class
customer like ruv has
got multiple he's talked
about in the past. He's
got multiple lockdown
laptops given to
him by the customer.
It's a stack. I'm going
to see it right now.
Everyone in my enterprise
customers sends me
a laptop and it just
mostly gathers dust for
the one meeting I need
to do in Microsoft
Teams. They're all
teams that require that
stupid laptop with one
of five flavors of VPN.
Yeah. But the point is
that they will never
give you access to
their data directly to
connect through Zapier
or some other external
api call so there's
also a bifurcation
if people are thinking
about consulting of
like how do you sit
on the outside because
how do you sit on the
outside and support
because the tier one
the the the tier one
consultancies basically
are big enough to sue
if they get it wrong
right which is kind of
part of the battle of
always trying to find
customers right so i'm
taking the approach
that i'm going to
deliver a vertical
solution within the ir
industry I think it can
be applied to other
markets, but cover your
own butt. If you're
a consultant or want
to be a consultant
and you want to engage
with people, you should
probably consider
professional ability
insurance. I take a
different stance, just
FYI. So I'm more loosey
-goosey in my, and keep
in mind, I've got 60
customers and I'm one
guy. So the key to
me and the way I work
is one, I make it
frictionless to gain
access to my time. So you
go on my website, you
use my calendar, you
put in your credit
card, and you literally
earn my calendar if
you're willing to pay.
And generally that
involves an NDA, but at
which point it's
frictionless. That means,
you know, and I work
with the largest
tech companies as
well as everyone else.
And to get there, all
they're really doing
is basically sending
me an NDA and using
their expense card.
Now, is that official?
How many policies does
that break? Who the
**** knows? But it
certainly works right now.
So if you are a consultant
and you're looking
to gain access, it's
never been easier to
gain access to big
companies just by being
loud and doing this
sort of thing. yeah but
it's interesting you
notice the whole thing
because um that's what
my experience currently
is because we got in
a company the vibe
coding like to very um
like very sophisticated
so last time we did
vibe coding session with
the group we got the
working code within
like 40 minutes it's
actually took longer to
understand what we want
basically right the
coding was just the
client just did the whole
thing almost completely
but then it takes me
like four days almost
like full-time work
is to actually make
all the it people happy
legal happy to actually
get it deployed because
you get an app running
on the laptop or in
the whatever your
github environment and
then now you want to
actually talk to real like
data feeds you want
to talk to like give
it real controls and
that takes um i think
right now so it was
one hour versus like 36
hours like 35 hours of
actual work getting that
up to getting in there
so that's yeah yeah
how you doing rob
hey i've i've been uh
i've been a big part
of this this watching
part of the whatsapp
group where i've taken
so much information
and i i can't believe
you exist i just got
to give credit to
where credit is due and
it's it's a wonderful
wonderful community
and i've i've now
built two or three
applications and the
amount of information
is is incredible and i
just wanted to talk
on one point about
literacy because i'm
big into bias on ai a
perfect example a great
test everyone should
do is who am i just
go to your your chat
gpt and see how it
classifies who you are.
My sister was big
into EDI and DEI,
diversity inclusion.
And when it said who she
was, she thought she
was a black person.
So there's so much
bias that's placed into
AI that I think everyone
needs to be careful.
The other thing is
around literacy. I find
that literacy fails
on so many fronts.
When you talk about
financial literacy, you
talk about cyber literacy,
which is like even
even just cyber hygiene
uh ai literacy the
the the general idea
behind literacy is
people are lazy to know
understand the first
principles of things
when you think about
cyber most breaches like
95 happen because of
human error there's a
significant increase
in security if you just
did some some small
some some minor tweaks
to your your routines
and your habits to
have some form of
security hygiene so i
feel like the question is
how do you get the
grassroots adoption
around what what literacy
is needed for the
future of of our digital
world and that and i
don't know that's a
good question like to
me that's like how do
you how do you raise
the bar and is this a
cultural thing where
certain countries are
just doing it better
because they've invested
in more and and forced
people to adopt it
um is it is there you
know it's not i don't
i don't think it's
cultural i think i i'm
again i've got customers
in in more than two
dozen countries at
this point. And there
are two groups of people,
those who want to
learn and empower
themselves to be more
than what they are. And
that's human nature,
right? And then there are
the people who are lazy
and want a cognitive
offload of their
thinking process. And
they use AI as a way
to cut corners. There
are always going to be
lazy people who don't
want to learn or be
more than what they are
and they're content
in their complacency.
That's just the segment
of human population
regardless of society
and then there's the
other people which i
hope are on this call
that that that see ai
as as a the the ultimate
sort of you know
cognitive you know
prophylactic right that
gets that gives you the
ability to think
understand things that were
never possible it
acts as a as a common
interface to complex
things right that's the
portion of the
population that i want to
embrace lazy dumb people
are always going to
be lazy and dumb and
there's nothing much i
can do about that
that segment of the
population my opinion
i'm going to be a little
more forgiving um you
know i don't go i don't
have to become a brakes
expert to be able
to drive my truck and
not have a disaster
and i don't walk into
the grocery store and
say oh you know i'm
an expert on food and
you know i know how to
pick out safe food i
mean i think these are
solutions um you know
we we dumped the
internet we dumped these
tools on people and
and we haven't really
helped them given them
things you know and part
of it is we don't
expect them to pay for
it you know so maybe
there maybe there's an
opportunity to build
safer things that
there's a higher price
tag for where you don't
have to become educated
i think i think
there's a lot of
possibilities for the future.
I love, I love
your positivity and
maybe I'm too black
and white in, in my,
my perspective. And
so you, you give,
you give humanity
a lot more faith,
I guess. And I love
that by the way.
Well, I'm not an
expert. I, I trust my
doctor. Like I, you
know, like I can't be an
expert at everything.
And so you have to
trust and rely on other
people, you know, and
to build safe systems
that we can use. I,
I'm the opposite of
you. I don't, I don't
trust my doctor. i i
i need a second i need
a second deep research
on every everything
that shows up and i'm
always trying to hack
the the multiverse
if i can and maybe
that's just the way i
operate so whether it's
my brakes in my car do
i really need brakes
do i really need that
update and half the
time i realized i
didn't need it and i
just needed a new screw
or something and i'm
like i told you yeah
that's true and then
occasionally i'm wrong
and then i have to
hear from it from my
my wife from the kids.
They're like, why
don't you trust anyone?
But it's glass
half empty,
glass half full, I guess.
I got a job. It is so
fun. Can't wait to be
back. I not next week,
but I will come in.
I'll give you a threat
report. I'll talk
to you. You know, answer
that's been really
fun to be back in.
Obviously, I hope I
can contribute and
really help with some of
the research and places
that i play so thank
you thank you everyone
yeah thanks for
joining us great to
listen to you i i know
we lost uh one of our
roberts did we skip
anyone that wanted to
give a presentation or
show anything because
this is your chance
this this is the open
mic portion you can
uh you can show anything
you like otherwise
i can i've got lots
to show if you if you
want to jump in there's
some new features
in rue that rolled out
yesterday there's uh
some some the my agentic
robots text which
is all of a sudden
really popular um i have
a quick question okay
yeah mark go ahead
does uh does open ai's
uh acquisition i think
they just bought
cursor a week or so ago
does that signal
windsurf sorry um should
i dabble in that or
should i stick with root
code i mean i just
i don't want to like
dilute dilute my
attention but what what is
windsurf is what you're
really asking and
what is cursor and you
know so when you look
at these projects
both are basically
variants on a package
version of vs code right
vsx something or other
is basically a way
you can and i've
attempted to create my own
package similar to that
what those packages
essentially are are
a bundled version
of a vs code extension
with some modifications
to the ui so you know
when when you look
like you know i was
thinking about creating
basically a dedicated
version of VS Code
for Roo just because.
That's all it is,
right? So the reason
I like Roo Code, and
I've tried obviously
all of them, is I can go
and directly modify
the source code of the
extension. So I've
got versions that are
basically my own that do
all kinds of interesting
things because I can
basically vibe the
core of the extension
itself. I can see how
they built it. I can
create modifications.
I can't really do that
with windsurf so for
me i i like the openness
the community that
that's around klein
and rue in particular
and the ability to
modify it if i need to or
at least understand
how it's built but you
know i think that that
what we're seeing and
this is my opinion
in terms of you know
windsurf and cursor in
particular is we found
the killer application
for llms and ai in
code and what that
really means is it a lot
of developers are going
to have to dramatically
change how they build
and what the purpose
of a you know developer
even is for the
next you know over the
next probably few years
so yeah yeah on that
on that on that topic
ruven you're right
so there's an article
that just was posted i
don't know whether it
was on linkedin or
somewhere and they basically
said that there are
two the two two main
markets of the ai
industry have been
validated as absolutely
undeniably real and one
is rag and the other one
is um code assistance
that they've all vcs
now and everybody
or customers like
undeniably don't they they
believe that they are
the two most validated
and and recognized
markets of the industry
yes 100 yep so so yeah
so you're going to
see tons of stuff now
get funded and products
all in those industries
and those markets
vibe coding whatever
you want to call it in
a code and yeah the
the insertion and usage
of data within the
structured pipeline
like rag whatever you
want to call it yeah so
vibe coding will become
a thing a big thing
of the coding assistant
some people some
companies will not use
vibe coding internally
because i guess it'll
be too random to
unstructured whatever
right but other companies
will right so vibe
will be a big chunk
of that market rag is
is 51 of every agentic
pipeline you or or
app you see today now
has some version of
a of a rag component
they're the two most
validated markets and no
one questions them
anymore no yeah but i
think i have like two
points to the things so
first about the cursor
i found i use it for
sort of micromanaging
the code like because
i use both like line
and rule like for
doing like high level
stuff but sometimes you
just want to like
format your code or like
convert from like json
to yaml or something
that we just highlight
the code and do it
in cursor because rule
can do it but it will
like trigger
basically a huge like
conversation with all of
them and of course there's
much faster that and
actually right in
specs like all these
things and another thing
about cursor it's
actually annoying because
microsoft is trying
to because when you
try to build your own
visual studio you're
going with this open
source codium version
and like lots of things
that you kind of think
they always going to
work they don't for
example you cannot
connect to github code
space from like open
source visual studio i
mean you can but you
have to jump to a bunch
of hoops like and
recently microsoft made
the c plus plus plugin
it doesn't work for
the extension it
doesn't work with cursor
because they just
detect this as like open
sources just don't yeah
so that's like kind
of two takes on that
and actually and the
last one about wipe
coding people say doesn't
work i find it work if
you ground it enough
you need to sort of
like have a library of
your corporate kind of
things because you've
been making slack bots
and you just come up
with bunch of templates
how you talk to
internal like enterprise
systems and you just
give it to the lvm with
the azragoas templates
because that way it
doesn't try to reinvent
the wheel or make
something exactly there's
the secret the secret
to vibe coding if
you're going to take
anything away from
today's call is to start
with a template like in
python cookie cutter
in and node.js and npx
create dash something
what you don't want
to do is you don't
want to create the
scaffolding with the vibe
coding system like rue
or cursor or whatever
it is when you look at
lovable the reason
lovable works great at
the very beginning and
terrible at the very
end is the fact that
they've really figured
out how to create a
very standardized vjs
package that includes a
really nice ui component
and some other you
know some super base
integration and a
few other sort of key
packages that they bootstrap
when you first start
the project so if you
want to build absolutely
anything as a vibe
coder in first research
what the best scaffolding
for that would
be and search specifically
for python cookie
cutter template or
mpx create library and
that'll that'll that'll
save you 30 bucks
and but i also that's
what i started i find
it very helpful is
just build not this
scaffolding but also like
little modules like so
for example you need
enterprise sensor data
here is example we just
give it a like little
example project you
say don't invent like
your own like how you
talk to q server just
look at this template
and just do some like
exactly what's here
if you want to make
slack but like you say
like look at our like
current slack bots and
just implement one like
that so i i find it
helps a lot there is
a loop because last
time we did web coding
session it took maybe
like 20 minutes to make
it sort of usable like
after like the client
was running for like
40 minutes like doing
its own thing like
that yeah and that's
that's probably because
you spent 20 minutes
of planning and it's
sometimes you want to
get into the functional
example quickly so for
that you know what i do
is i skip i explicitly
say to skip the
planning phase into and
then i give it a bit
of guidance in the
initial prompt create
the scaffolding then give
me a ui or whatever
and and that usually
takes and actually i
got impressed with the
whole client because
the last web coding
session we did it was
like some rough edges at
sort of on the outer
level on the systems
i did not even look at
the internals what it
coded it just works
because i i just put
things on the queue and
it shows up in database
i have like zero
knowledge of like what
it's you know it's
it's funny because
because again i do a
lot of these hourly vibe
coding sessions people
literally hire me to
vibe with them for
an hour which who who
knew that was a job
but the but the the
takeaway on a an hour
-long vibe coding session
is i can't it's really
expensive to hire me
for an hour so i i
can't spend 40 minutes
you know creating
you know detailed um
directions so they want
to see something quick
right to feel like
you know the time is
worthwhile so i take a
top-down approach so i
start rather than
than creating detailed
planning docs which
you probably should i
start with detailed
mock ui components so i
make it look real but
it's not connected to
anything it's all mock
data it's all it's
faked until you and
once they're happy with
the way it looks and
sort of kind of works
then they can go and
build it out and i
can let it run for
several hours later
yeah but for me like
it's actually we can
code ui very quickly
with but it's very little
and it's typical in
enterprise lots of
our stuff it's all
industrial control software
or lab control there
is no ui just runs by
itself like so you yeah
so most of the code
you want to take
basically from one
instrument and basically
stick it to some like
analytics or lab
management software so it's
the ui is already
there like ui is on the
instrument or ui is on
the analytics package
actually i think that
the interesting part
behind this because
i've built four separate
projects in the span of
the last three months
all part of the the ir
industry like retail
uh project management
like i've built four
different platforms and
i think the interesting
thing here is basically
actually identifying
what your outcome is
so if your goal is
like an mvp this is
this is your approach at
using cursor or ru
right versus having to
build the full enterprise
platform like like
i've done so it's
kind of like if you
understand what the
output is like like we've
said like bypass all
of the the prompting
in the setup to say
i want a simple demo
therefore my my input
should be this i'm
expecting an output
of this with declines
up front to kind of
set those expectations
because there's a lot
of time and energy
that goes into
scaffolding an enterprise
application versus
hey i want a poc what
what does a poc look
like from a vibe
vibe coding session
And by the way, the
other thing that I
found super interesting,
like I've parted
ways with one of
the developers in
my company because
he kind of was
refusing to adopt
agentic development
approaches.
You know, in the last
two weeks, you have
both Anthropic and, you
know, Sam from OpenAI
saying 90% of our
code is written by AI.
So 100% of my code,
almost 100% of my code
at this point is written
by AI. and it's funny
when i get on these
calls there there are
two groups of of of
users and i hope none
of the people i'm about
to mention broadly are
on this call but
there's a group of users
that are really really
hate me and they tend
to be data scientists
and they i can you
know zoom is is a very
visual medium so i can
see that sort of scowl
on their face while
i'm describing how
i'm basically going to
replace their their what
they do and often when
i'm brought in to do
data science related
work, although their
boss isn't saying it,
they know it. I'm
completely automating what
a data scientist does.
And the bar for like,
when you look at
what a data scientist
does, it's a lot of trial
and error. It's like
trying to find the
coherence in the data.
We're getting to a
certain threshold for
positive versus negative,
getting the same result
more than X amount
of times. And to get
that, what a data
scientist generally does is
a lot of just trial and
error until they get
the result that they're
looking for which
is perfect for an agent
just does it and does
it and does it
concurrently until they get
the result and and
this what would take a
data scientist months
can happen in a matter
of hours and when that
so then the question
is what do i need the
data scientists for
when 90 of their job
is just trial and error
yeah but there was a joke
about data scientists
years ago that's um
there are these people
who don't really know
statistics and they
don't know like software
development they
just know back a little
bit about bot like
and that's the yeah
yeah and they and they
cost like three times the
the price of a regular
employee that's the
problem with the data
scientist industry
right is that it's why
cloudera and hadoop and
hortonworks like they
all merged because they
they they had their
customer base is only
the top of the triangle
where you could they
could have those
companies like uber and
lyft and you know meta
and google and all
those companies they're
only companies that can
afford a data sciences
team as part of their
product engineering
and product management
team like everybody
else couldn't afford
them well that's why r
exists the the coding
language literally
exists it's only a
small fraction of people
know how to program an
r and they happen to be
data data analysts and
you know the reality
is you know now i can
do r just by asking
it to convert my python
which is you know
works and i just convert
that to r i'm done that
took 10 minutes yeah
it's it's uh nothing
again i don't mean to
knock on data scientists
you know obviously
but it's definitely
the most disruptable
portion of the uh you
know segment right now how
about bioinformaticians
because they are
the same things they
kind of like not really
biologists and that
not really software
developers the kind of
people who know little
bit of both and then a
little bit of semantics
at that point no no
it's not semantics
and and that example i
was giving you of the
the person who was not
pleased to see me was
actually bioinformatics
it was it was specifically
for a pharmaceutical
company and uh you
know i get it i get
why i'm like you know
i'm what like a uh a
management consultant
would have been 25
years ago that was
deciding what to outsource
or offshore right i
can understand why i
wouldn't be the most
popular guy has anyone made
progress in agentic
sequel querying oh yeah
what do you mean
takes a sequel natural
language sequel i give
it a schema representing
in excess of hundreds
of tables and it
takes all of that lumpy
dumped data and turns
it into information
yeah it's mcp there's
tons of them the the best
i mean there's i used
to work for i used to
work for the last 18
months for a company
called minds db that
that actually was a
early adopter of of that
an early pioneer in
that space and text to
sequel uh is like pretty
much they had a um
that was unique like
four or five years ago
now it's like there's
thousands literally
just thousands of tools
that can do that yeah
it's pretty trivial
and the real trick is
that you want to it's
not so much the text to
sequence actually teaching
giving it information
about the schema
and the names of the
tables and that and the
sort of the structure
of what's in there
and then it really
performs well yeah there's
for me when i do that
i'm using mcp so the
there's a number of
mcps for like Postgres
or various data lakes.
And I just pointed at
that and I basically
optimize it,
convert it, do
whatever you need
to do to figure
it out, and I
go have dinner.
So Trino is a company,
Starburst,
they are all early
adopters, early
innovators in that space.
Yeah. Databricks,
actually, they always had
a model for years. I
actually talked to a
person, they said they
just did it so they
proved they can do
LLM, so it does exactly
that. i'm not sure it
goes against sql or the
spark but you can give
it natural language
query and it will like
here's here's what the
super base mcp looks
like you've got you've
got your organizations
you've got your
projects you've got your
costs then you've got
the ability to basically
list your tables
you can run the most
useful part of this to
be honest is the apply
migrations which allows
you to to apply
triggers i guess i'm not
logged in but whatever
um and uh and then
the execute sql and it
just does it right and
then you can and then
you use this mcp as
part of several other
mcps so i might have
another mcp that that
orchestrates my ews or
azure or whatever it
is and then or or then
i'll i'll create a
bespoke mcp just for a
particular customer's
data or api and then i
have them all
orchestrate each other is
there yeah no what's
difficult though is federated
sql across multiple
databases as one one
big sql statement
that's that's difficult
to do it's easy to do
it like mcp wise or
or in or dedicated for
a database like super
base doing your text to
sql for that particular
instance of that
database or that or
that schema or that table
space or that structure
but doing a sql
statement like like a
multi-table join across
different databases,
federated SQL
statements across
multiple databases
of different
structure, that's
hard to do.
Yeah.
And that's the only
reason why I'm still
employed, writing
SQL. Yeah, I mean,
a lot of
enterprises have...
Yeah, and then, you
know, you've got Oracle,
you've got SQL Server,
you know, you've
got Neo4j, you know,
you've got Mongo,
you know, and you're
trying to build an app
that's actually looking
at all of that data
in one app and then
trying to do some
fancy SQL multi-table
join, multi-table space,
multi-instance
join, that's very
difficult. Takes a SQL
on one instance, easy.
I'm sure we'd figure
out a way to do
it, but you're right,
it's tricky. You
probably might need
an intermediary sort
of layer of some
sort to normalize it.
Yep, yeah.
All right, we're
running low on time.
There's a new feature,
by the way, in Roo
that came out yesterday
for the Roo fans.
Obviously, I'm a Roo fan.
Let me show you
that for just quick.
Check this out.
And so when you go
into your prompts,
you now have the
ability to define
when to use.
Describe when the
mode should be used.
And if you've ever run
into the problem where
the orchestrator
sometimes, you know,
doesn't know when to
choose which one, this
solves that problem.
So you can go in there,
you can type in
test or whatever and
then, see now we've
got a, where'd it go?
Not saving it for some
reason, but anyway,
that provides a
mechanism to, oh
here it is, when to
use. So I'm gonna
update the Spark
protocol to include
that. I gotta
do some testing,
but.
You might wanna change.
It says MCP management
control panel in
the role definition.
Oh yeah, yeah.
Unless that's purposeful.
it still doesn't
know what mcp is
even yeah 3.7 still
says some some
other thing anything
but model content
yeah i'm constantly
changing that it's
it's i mean i've been
messing around with
this with this morning
that's why that's
why it's changed
but yeah it's kind
of a cool feature and
all right uh well
i guess we're we're
uh we're at near
the end here and any
guys uh anything
else you guys want
to discuss before
we call it a week?
Yeah, a quick one. I
managed to actually
use the reverse
pipe coding of
the platform that
you were showing
yesterday. We had
lots of errors, right?
So to try and
customize it
to meet a specific need.
Basically, was it agent?
Was it the auto agent?
What was it?
Oh, was that
the launching?
iver technology auto
analyst right oh
yeah yeah that that
that worked the the uh
lane chain one i
gave up on i never
looked at it again
okay anything you want
to show oh yeah i can
quickly show a couple
of things actually
i've been my vibe
coding so i've been
gaining my confidence
doing so uh let me
just share my screen
i'm just looking
for the share button
which has decided
to hide itself from
me wait a more
button i guess zoom
is generally in the
middle yeah there
it is it's also
there it is zoom and
it's staring at
me you're right so
hopefully you can
see my screen uh now
yeah yes so um i uh
managed to do two
things one is obviously
the one i was saying
you see there's been
some errors but a bit
of customization
around that so go back
it is working
it broke because
i changed some code but
effectively you know
basically got it to
start added some
customization features because
i'm trying to do an
automotive demo so
get started kind of
got it to store some
api keys the chat
feature is not entirely
working by the way so i
need to figure out why
so what do you see
You made the auto
-analyst automotive
analyst? The name works. So
it's an automotive
file effectively. So
I've got basically some,
the idea is to take
free API data and allow
some kind of front
-end visualization of
what the data is from
the industry. That's
what I was thinking.
But anyway,
this is working.
Are you using
something like
Lovable for your layout?
No, this is
basically these
guys. Like they
open source the
product, this
one, this product.
So basically... Oh,
auto-analyst. yeah i've
just used it i'm just
going to build on top
of it to see what they
are so changing some
features there so i did
that and then i mean
i guess you were
talking about the vibe
coding exercises right
so i've kind of tried
to create some kind of
legal document processing
system so similarly
i can just what i've
done here though i'm
not using ru i have
used your rules but i
have effectively used
cursor so i've find
found a way of operating
within cursor so
creating some specific
cursor rules using your
stuff and added ux and
i've got a cursor
version too i i don't
think i've published
it but yeah basically
exactly what you did yeah
and and and obviously
using that um this one
is effectively helping
uh overcome a manual
process of legal
processing and that
translated into kind of an
app where you can
upload a document for
example in fact i can go
down to the demo setting
and start the demo
probably we can do
that start a demo so
if you have a property
deed for example and
you want to upload the
property deed information
which is here and
then you just select
the property deed and
it's currently mocked up
but the upload feature
works so the whole
point about validating
those here processing
you know analyzing the
structure of it
extracting the entities um
and knowledge it doesn't
really have machine
learning models behind
yet but obviously
that can be integrated
so all i'm trying to
show is that i guess
you know what you have
been showcasing uh i
mean my role has been
as a program uh director
program manager right
so i'm not necessarily
coded but you know
i can see personally
in these job roles how
an idea in the definition
of jobs in terms
of making sure as an
individual contributor
your role is actually
to take a concept to
a stage and then you're
going to build it
it's really fast right
um so anyways that's
what i wanted to show
without taking you very
much but there are
some interesting things
that come about here
like knowledge graphs
so these have all got
auto created through
the process um and uh
i think what has really
helped as you said is
this research element
to kind of to have
this final uh report
with a plan and the
phases defined around it
that provides the
guardrails, I guess, for
the AI. It's not loading
up for some reason,
but I'll stop you. Great,
nice work.
Yeah, it looks
really good.
So, and the key, you
know, what I liked
about that, you know,
the auto analyst, it
was, you know, it's a
little bit half-baked,
but it's a good running
start, right? It
gives you a bunch of
stuff that you can
kind of run and modify
yourself, right? You
can add some additional
logic or some
agents, whatever. and
it'll get you moving
quickly. I think that
that's the takeaway
is make sure you
borrow or create from
someone that's already
started and put together
some other things.
Don't try to build
from the ground up.
It's just extra work
and then you spend
all this time building
and debugging things
that don't matter.
Modify what already
exists if you can.
All right. Well,
it's another week.
I'm excited to get
that codex thing
working. I don't
think I have access
yet. If anyone else
does, let me know.
It looks very
similar to the GitHub
Workspaces project,
to be honest.
It's basically,
I think, the
same general
idea as that.
But if it's
included in the
chat GPT license,
that's a plus.
Once I get access,
I'll give you
my two cents on
how that works. Uh,
we got, uh, Rachel,
do you have a, you
have a question working
with self-monitoring
agentic structures
inside chat GPT pro.
That sounds cool.
Yes. So this is a new,
new project, personal
project separate from
my, uh, professional,
uh, AI work. Um, so
just something that
I've been super vibed
about and haven't
necessarily been able
to find research to show
that people have, uh,
supported this before.
But OpenAI has
been throttling me
very, very consistently
and shutting
down my account
because I have
way too much
activity going on.
So I'm just curious
to see if anybody
else has kind of had
that self-automated
agentic structure
inside of ChatGPT.
There was a project
that I shared
a couple weeks
ago. it was
a browser extension
for Chrome
that allows you
to automate.
Super Assistant.
Yeah, Super
Assistant does that.
I packaged it for
Firefox as well,
if anyone uses Firefox.
Yeah, can you
share a link to
that? If you've
got a handy?
I haven't published it
to GitHub. I can though.
So far, I've just
been using it as a
personal thing. But
yeah, I will do that now.
Yeah, it's cool, right?
Yeah, so right now
I've been able to do
that just right inside
my ChatGPT account
with no external
integrations. So it's
just a continuously
self-monitoring loop
with self-prompting
and role assignments.
There was another approach
that I demoed last
year called Grease
Monkey, it was. and that
was all that's also
an extension for both
firefox and chrome that
allows you to create
these scripts that
automate sort of page
interactions but the
super assistance better
okay i'll check
it out yeah so uh
yeah there's it's
be careful you
you will get
throttled for sure
um that's a problem
we all that they i
think i think they
want you to use api for
more complex things
but if if you if you're
feeling so inclined
the um the agent
framework for open ai
is really good for that
sort of thing okay
definitely thanks for
the advice yeah and
i've got some uh i've
got a repo where i
create so much stuff
i can't remember where
the heck what it's
called but about a
month ago i created a
uh an example i
think it's in my edge
functions repo there's
a uh Let me find that.
Yeah, here.
I'll put that.
If you don't
mind, you know,
working in code.
But there's a OpenAI
agent that I created in
there. I think it's
in the scripts folder.
Spectacular. Thank you.
That'll do all kinds
of crazy stuff.
Yeah. All right.
So thanks, everyone,
who's tuned in for
almost an hour and a
half. This is always
the highlight of my
week. So I appreciate
everyone who sticks
it out to the end,
Alex and Rob and Max
and everyone that's
joined here. Thank
you. Thanks again.
Always happy to help.
If you have questions,
feel free to join our
– we've got a Discord,
which we're trying to
get off the ground,
and we've got our
WhatsApp channel, and
we've got the Reddit
and LinkedIn, whatever.
Feel free to reach
out. And I apologize.
I'm sometimes swamped
with meetings and
inbox stuff. i'm not i
do my best to respond
but i it's it's
overwhelming at times but
um anyway appreciate
it we're doing london
i think next week as
rob said earlier so
anyone uh in london
you know definitely
talk to bents who's
organizing events you're
still on the call
like i see your name
there how's that coming
along i'm here yeah
hi hi hi everyone so
yeah you you moved to
a different different
venue is that yeah
request the sorted
out the google um one
of the google venues
in st giles in central
london so 60 people
are coming and monday
is a co-organizer as
well some other people
as well vincent and
uh others so 760
organizers so we're
gonna have a super cool
agenda yeah if i if i
ever left my house i
i would definitely
join you in london i've
actually got a few
customers that i'm working
with in london i
just never leave
unfortunately yeah hopefully
next time it's it's
over subscribe so
there are waiting lists
now perfect oh well
congratulations that's
great and you've got a
you've got a structure
already like like
what like what format
are you going to use
yeah so we're gonna
give out some homework
for the next few days
and everybody should
have a ru uh installed
and vs code and npx
running properly because
we don't want to
spend time you know
setting up one-to-one
reports and then uh we're
gonna you know create
groups and create
an app from scratch
and gonna live stream
as well so it will be
very nice i made I made
this in Berlin and,
and it's, it's, it's
big, you know, it's
a lot of fun to see
people building something
for the first time.
Awesome. I'm excited.
I'm setting up a, I
think I'm going to
set up a restream
account. If you're
looking to stream live and
that'll integrate with
some of the various
portals and things,
just ping me on
WhatsApp and I can get
you access to that.
Yeah.
Thank you then.
All right. All right.
That's it. I'm, I'm
heading to the lake
for the, for a long
weekend here in
Canada. The weather is
beautiful. At least
today it is anyway. Um,
so happy weekend
and happy vibing
until next
week. Thank you.
Thank you.
My pleasure.