coming. My name is Zohar.
I'm with Kaltura. I'm a
Kaltura. I'm a Kaltura.
uh we're part of the
sponsoring partners
for the Agentics
Foundation and i'm happy
to have you all here
joining us this is the
very first meetup for
the Agentics Foundation
in new york with
chapters all over the
world now and this is
the first chapter um the
whole concept joe
will give some more
details about it uh in a
bit i just want to take
a thank you for louis
our friend here who
but yeah thank you
so much for coming I
hope you enjoyed this
I hope this is going
to be the kickoff
of a wonderful group
for H&X engineering
and people who are
Avid and curious
and interested
in the world
of a young age,
which is probably
one of these.
Thank you for coming.
Hello, everybody.
I'm Willy.
Very nice to meet you.
Willy Vansicle the III.
And I'd say about
six-ish months ago,
maybe even less
than that. Right,
I was just on
LinkedIn and scrolling
and it's AI
Hackerspace Fridays.
Someone's like my,
okay, so I put this,
okay?
And it's people
building things with AI,
right? And I'm
like, okay, this is
great. This is what
I've been doing, okay?
Not to make this
like all about me and
what I've done, But,
like, I didn't, like,
I'm not a developer,
right, because I
was a salesperson for
a lifetime of life.
And ChatGPT came
out, it was nice. I
started using it to
help automate some
of my, like, sales
activities, right?
And quickly wanted to
do more, right? I was
like, hey, I want to
do more of this, like,
I need to do internet,
I need to do more.
So here, there, and
then do this, right?
ChatGPT was like,
dude, you want to go,
no, right? What do
you mean? I don't know
anything about that,
anything about that.
You say that, right?
So I start copying
and pasting code
from ChatGPT to get
the VS code, right?
Running like Python
scripts, streamlit
things, and like
here we are now,
like a year and
three months later,
and like I've got
the key websites,
like I'm actively
contributing
to production
level code at like
enterprise
software company.
So it's really
incredible what
this stuff can
do in terms of
like turning your
career around.
People that are
looking for a pivot
more, looking to
like, I don't know,
just do something
different with
my education and
stuff, right? Just
dig in a little
bit, like roll this.
So anyways, what is
the Agentics Foundation?
So, this was founded
by Reuven Cohen,
about like,
technically like
eight years ago it was
officially founded,
right, it's a non
-profit organization,
and we're basically
dedicated to making
AI innovation
and education open
to everybody, okay,
by supporting the
development and
deployment of open
source agency and AI.
So, we're basically
a group of
people that are out
here building open
source software,
teaching people
how to use AI,
running workshops,
training people,
having these meetups,
there we are, right?
So what is agendics?
We're all familiar with
AI, ChatGPT, right?
It's coming up with
ChatGPT before, right?
But agendics, it's a
little bit different,
right? So we're
talking about a field
of study, okay,
focused on the design,
developing, deployment
of these intelligent,
autonomous systems,
okay, that are capable
of like receiving
where they're at,
what's going on,
reasoning, making some
decisions, and then
taking action, right,
with your software,
with them, whatever
you're finding, right.
Okay, so they're
proactive,
they're autonomous,
collaborative,
they're not targeted,
we create some issues
with these agents who
are not just chatting
and chatting to them.
Definitely not copy
and paste the code,
it's amazing, right.
So a little bit more
about the Agentics
Foundation here, we
believe the next
generation of builders
should not be limited to
these big multinational
corporations, with
Agentics, builders
can come from all
walks of life, right?
A year and a half
ago, I was making
cold calls and
sending emails, but
now I'm running
websites and building
rapid prototypes
and APIs, right?
So, the foundations
that have impact.
We have in-person
events, that's why
you're here, regional
chapters around
the world. Google
sponsored for London.
We've got Toronto
is big, Austin,
a lot of
different things.
Research and
development, we have
these calls every
week. Get out, we
brainstorm together,
we act together,
Reuven shows us the
latest thing that we
look the world
with. It's pretty
amazing, right? So
our community now, I
think these numbers
are a little outdated
because I think we're
actually at about
1,300, 1,400
registered members now.
We're on Reddit,
we're on LinkedIn,
WhatsApp, Discord,
all over the place
after this event.
We're going to
go ahead and share
some of those Discord
and links for
you guys to get
involved and start
connecting with us.
On every Friday, we
have the AI Afterspace,
that Zoom call
that I was telling
you about, where a
ton of people get on
there from all over
the world and demo,
we kind of do like
what we're gonna do
today, like we'll
show a little demo,
we'll talk a little
bit about HNC
AI and the latest
developments.
I will push to
the young logo
this week and
then we ship,
right, it's a
great community,
right.
And so I'm
gonna talk just
a little strange bit here
because some real
guys are gonna get
up afterwards and
show, right, but,
Who's heard of
bio-coding so
far? Maybe it's
your family.
Okay, we've all heard
of bio-coding, right?
They've got Andrew
Barclay's name,
famous, right?
And then we flew
up, and now it's
almost like,
oh, it's kind
of bio-coding,
right?
So there's two,
or not just two, there's
a lot of different
ways to code with
AI, but we're just
talking about two of
these like sort of
primary categories
you can put them into,
right? And one is,
is this my book,
right? It's, hey, AI,
make a to-do app for
me with a really cool
space background.
You know, I'll
make the buttons
red, this and that.
You're not really
worried about
infrastructure.
You're not really worried
about architecture.
You're not like
telling the AI, like,
hey, make sure that
this code is scalable
and it goes here and,
you know, use this
method for the same
thing. You just buy
it out, like trying
to get the AI to build
something that you
want to do, right?
It's flow, there's
a human, it's
always a feedback
loop in there,
right? You're
always, you know,
change this button,
hey, no, this, hey, I
need you to do that,
and the other, right?
Change that now to
agentic engineering,
okay?
And we move to
a more refined,
structured process,
okay? Where
our machine is now
in the process.
And instead of
me having to
go back every
single time,
my AI writes
a test for it,
right, and then tests
it, and then comes back
and fixes it, and then
comes back and tests
it again, and then comes
back, and you know,
we get this feedback
loop until the task
is done, and then we
can move on, right, once
a B and C has completed,
then we move into
this orchestration
layer, and this sort of,
I don't want to call
it an arc, but like we
put a lot of work into
context engineering,
like what exactly is
each LLM called getting,
how are we designing
all this open so there's
a lot more thought
process that goes into
it's a lot more
structured and and the
results aren't just you
know AI slot one of the
results are production
great software results
are you know these
open source libraries
that are now you know
16-1700 stars with uh
group's new uh cloud
flow implementation so
um pretty cool stuff
here that we're doing uh
agentic engineering
versus bi-coding there's
a big difference here
uh but bi-coding is
So cool guys.
Thank you for
listening to me.
I'm here to chat
a little bit.
Again, I'm really
fanciel of the
public ambassador
of this and the
Gensys Foundation
crew, but I'm a
person so yeah, no
big deal, right?
So we're going to
let Ocean get up here
and share a little bit
of what he's doing.
Thank you.
Don't forget you
share your screen.
Give
it up for Ocean.
Hello, my name's Nohishu,
I am one of the co
-founder of the HNX
Foundation. So about one
and a half, two years
ago, I started a,
right now we know it's
like agent stuff, but
back then nobody really
asked what AI agent
organization framework
was. So I was on that,
and then that was a
quick small line AGI.
Eventually,
so about last year,
around April, I met
with them, and then
I quickly got very
interested because
our passion are very
similar and he was
very enthusiastic about
like I was very
happy about that. So
basketball working
now and then we have
actually made the
Jetsons Foundation a real
nonprofit. I'm so
happy about that and
it's so great to see
all of you guys here.
So what we are hyping
about nowadays is
the all-you-can
-ease plan called and
Nordic Club both.
Whoop! The $200 plan,
it used to be meters,
and then everything
that I'm going to
show you today might
cost is hundreds
of dollars during
the demo, but no,
it's only good for me.
Anyway, so I ended
up quite wanting
to talk about today,
so I was chatting
with the client,
what should we talk
about? I want to
demonstrate you, right,
so tell me what
you want to demo.
and then it come up
with um now i have
so let's get started
with the cloud code
basically it is
a command line it
is a command line
interface uh that allows
you to programmatically
interact with
uh solid bottom so
what i'm going to
show you right now is
okay we're going to
How about warm-up joke,
which
is the last thing
we're going to
do, I'm talking
about warm-up joke.
All right, option
one, how many
AI patients
does it take to
change your life
more? Just one,
it needs to
correlate with some
research agents,
but let's talk about
an architect
agent to design
the blockchain
for a firm, and
a critic agent
to tune down.
As
you can see, I
have brainwashed my
cloud to refer me
as Ocean whenever.
It's really fun because
today you've got
to speak with very
casual, and this
whole system has been
completely personalized
to understand how
I work for them.
All right, this is Lyon.
I'm going to give
it an impossible
problem, and so we
can watch our song.
All right, this
is perfect.
Oh, perfect, yeah.
Great.
Nice.
Now I have to
improvise and go to
Devogar because
whatever I was
trying to show,
go my over here.
Yeah, all right,
let's try again, so
change plan and
let's get started,
so I'll explain
So I'm trying to change
the demo planer, I
don't realize this is
going to be, so I'll
use .
Atosication basically
is when Cloakville
wants to get something
done, it does not
do what it's, it has
the option to not
do itself. Instead,
it will basically
delegate that problem
to a task agent, which
is the sub-process
independent of the
main flow, and then
that task agent will
still get stuff done,
come back to the
orchestrator and then
we connect to it.
So what the lighting
orchestrator is,
is a… so in cloud
flow, actually,
we were talking
about the task agent.
One problem with
that is let's say we
have five agents
working in parallel
and that is kind of
the initial concept
of Squam. We have a
lot of agents working
on kind of the same
project but one
problem with having
them and agents working
together is the
coordination problem.
So what if two agents
or three agents are
editing the same file?
What if the agents are
editing file and then
another agent is doing
my testing then you
know as here change that
was a problem so every
agent will come back
to you and say I have
completed my test and
then when you put all
this stuff together
it's broken and that
is a major problem what
we are trying to
resolve with this small
coordination system um
so you can brute force
it as how I'm showing
you right now which is
a, let's actually take
a look at what the
plan looks like from
the illustration output.
So right now the task
agents are doing
their work.
The swarm system
basically allows each
of the task agents
to report their
current status to a
centralized place to,
yeah, kind of
database where we
well use neural
network to train
kind of a topology
in real time
according to whatever
they have done.
The interesting
thing is, even with
other neural net
training, the
topology feature
by itself already
dramatically in the
quality of language,
which is something
it's so traumatic that
all the sleep didn't
really expect it
before, that's why I
jumped into this form
that I'm helping out
with developing rust.
So anyway, so right
now it's like to
show us a consensus
theory framework.
Let's see what it is.
Let's
actually do this.
This looks cool.
Why are we showing the
regular concentration?
We are in New York.
Question is, is
the code based
task agent being
actually written?
Yes, so,
but what, as I can
see, I want to explain
the observability
following a bit. And then,
as you can see, like
all those tossing
and they're doing their
thing and you just
see that it did become
bigger and bigger.
So here it has already
made 45 changes.
I don't know what's
called where.
However,
how you can try to
understand what they're
doing live would be...
Now I can start this.
Okay, let's do
it like this.
So, you have all the
issues on GitHub.
And then, have your
task agents to provide
live feedback on GitHub
issues as comments.
So, you know, I'll
show you a brief one.
I was using
Swarm to develop
Swarm. And then
while the...
while they are remaining,
I have to be there.
The memory is
all beneficial.
The public itself
is just... The
public itself
is just direct
video icons to
the Sony platform.
Everything that you
want to have in the
public, like automation,
like locks on memory,
It's all additional,
that's part of which
it's an engineer,
otherwise it's just fine.
All right, so
it has posted on
the issue, so
let's take a look.
Yeah,
reach which report.
You're right, let's check
which report
actually, yeah.
Yeah, they do have
this, and you do
need to kind of watch
out, but I could
have had this
information earlier.
All right, so now
it's having a vision.
Yeah,
I was just curious.
Once you set this
up, do you ask about
how do you believe
that? How do you
basically evaluate
how effective it is?
Just, you know, you
tend to block them.
Yes, I'll give that
a bit. There's a
whole different
methodology behind it.
So what I'm
showing you right
now is the
depth portion of
how they are
coding them along.
So right now
we just saw the
agent opened three issues
regarding our
demo today. And
as they are
working along,
so they will post
comments here.
So they probably need
to sort of batch up
them, but they do
need to clean up the
UI, because otherwise
they want to . best.
So now let me show you
what the evaluation
framework might
be like. It's
actually more traditional
than my thought.
So LionGate is a
Rust framework for
capability-based
security really well,
that aims to provide
very fine-grained
control and access rights
for each individual
agent. So what you're
seeing right here,
every single task agent,
they actually have
the same access right
to everything as
for main log streamer,
which is not ideal.
And then in the... So
I had this idea about
back in February with
NCP, and then there
was that very... uh serious
security vulnerability
within the enterprise
itself especially
when everything is
configured once and then
you are doing with
the multi-agent system
so i thought how about
we start to you know
give every single uh
agent in a multiple
telecom a capability of
what they can access to
our system um so i get
that back in memory
and then took a few
minutes ago i thought is
it really good is it
really the climate state
of the art like you
know and i was claiming
so i So I said, how
about you do me a
formal mathematical proof
of the entire thing?
Everything needs to
be there based with
extensive research that
I know I'm interested.
So basically saying,
show me the map.
And what the slow system
was able to put my
work in two weeks for
that rust paper, and
then it was able to
prove this in a morning.
What's fun about all
of this is I actually
did not read too
much into it,
however I had a process
that keep on finding
logical defaults
from the previous
one, and then up to
a little iteration,
I guess I will start
to dig into it once
I want to make
architectural changes
because ASK was
validating the thing.
It's become to play
a lot of faults on my
previous architecture
decisions which I
actually need to go
in because it is a
kind of like a personal
text in 100 watts.
All right, so let's go
back and take a look. We
have to put some
comments in the topology
design for the
heterosubestification method.
Set the cyber phenomenon,
DLT, block the
data structure,
application,
pull.
And then here's
the training
system with
security analysis.
I'm not sure if I'd
be able to mute.
It might be
overfitting due to the
existing data I
already had in there.
That's why I keep
on mentioning
about Baceton-Bosmores.
All right,
yeah, this is, yeah, the
weird is that
testing. Yeah,
so that is
basically the entire
development
cycle of agentic
engineering at the
very PowerPoint.
There are so much more
tools to be explored.
I'm very unhappy
that I wasn't
able to share
this one today.
I just wrote
it last minute.
What is enabling is
something in automated
intelligence according
to your own wish
that... So, for example,
the entire foundation
of that was the fast
-growing network high
-found package, and
then Reuven took that,
put it into PLUSD,
and I stepped in, and
then I added the GPU
training functionality
to it. The crazy
thing is, I do not
know how to keep it
works other than I
have some very big
ideas about it, nor do
I know what a shader
is, or what a WGS
SL file works. But
I was able to get a
whole thing done in
a day, and it works.
Then you need to go back
to that mathematical
improvement
methodology to actually
prove that what is
working is actually
logically sound. So it
is really crazy to even
show all of this
web GPU stuff that I
literally could not
really think of. But now,
I actually have a pretty
decent understanding
of what is blood,
also with debug,
and yeah, so that's
about it. I'm super happy
to see all of you guys
here, and this fast
-moor network is
already functional. It
supports CPU and CPU
training, and we are going
to integrate this into
this blog such that
the neural net training
We have time to optimize
topology can actually
be very helpful.
And we're very excited
to see what that should
mean for the next
phase of each of these.
Thank you guys so much.
Thank you, thank
you. Give it
up one more
time for Ocean.
Right.
So next in line,
following the same
sort of financial
stock trading
thing, we have Anie.
She has a demo here for
something that she does.
If you want to see
the screen, then HDMI.
or she can share
the url with you
oh great yeah
we see we're
on it
go back oh
no worries that's fine
we'll just do it with you
Hey, well hello everyone.
My name is Kanye.
I am at VATS.ai
and today I want to
show you the AI
agent that I built.
So,
how many of you guys
have asked to do it?
So,
we built a
framework called
entity agents. Basically,
in the framework
that allows agents
So I'll tell you a
letter about how it
works first and then
I will walk you to
the... So basically
what it does is that
it helps my boyfriend
make better financial
decisions by
knowing 35 stops in
quick search, 35 stops,
multiple IDs, etc.
So it has
multiple agents.
And then, yeah,
so the first part
is data submission.
So it has two main
agents. The data,
it shows the
first agent for my
data, the second
agent is for that,
so the data is at a
perfect high
level of law,
and then you
have the analyst,
the analyst has a
financial analyst point
to view, so it analyzes
the data, and then
you have the data
to be recorded as
well. data and then
provide a really nice
work. And we're using
different, we're using
different workflows
based on a project,
so like the
orchestrator, like how
agents, how the
orchestrator have access to
agents and allow
agents to make calls
to communicate but
also have access to
So, in this
specific example,
the agents have
access to Facebook,
Google search tool,
and then 5%
provide the report.
So I went ahead and
wrote a Streamlit.
I'm going to
share it here.
Streamlit.
Okay.
Let's see.
Okay, so this is
the Streamlit.
So basically it's my
portfolio, I have the
following stocks and
then here I search
any other stocks, so
if you didn't want to
search no other
financial or like stock.
So now I'm with AAPL,
then you're on that.
So basically you're going
to start finding it.
Then I'm working for what
I'm starting with
it. I'm going
to do something
that I contribute
a lot, but it's
going to be a
slide of like how it's
going to do a call.
So it's accessing
different tools like
fetch and it's like
starting to look for data
about apple and like
beta is a financial
view of that apple it
is for its earnings
and quite so um and
you should be different
uh mcp server so so
these are the dots
basically
this is the main goal
So how it works is
that you have to,
it's very hollow and
it's very simple.
So basically we
have an agent.
So this agent
is going to be
based on the
founder agent.
And they have exactly
what they want the
agent to put a paper
together at this board.
And now the better
the content here
it is, the better
the engine is.
So that is that. And
then here you also
give it apples to
school. So here I give it
apples to the prior
person so that I can
actually stay through
reports in my files.
So the first phase
is the quality of the
whole component of it,
so it's like a gather
data and then check
to figure out the data
for the quality and
then we just now will
tie it to against reverse
reporting so that's
the value that I
corporate have been in
and the core of the
workforce and the next
thing about the agent
is the core framework.
So yeah, and if you can
give it about the data,
different agents
and then different
instructions So this
is the evaluator agent.
Again,
the evaluator agent
says what is good, what
is excellent, what is
fair for this form.
And then on that, the
agent tries to look
for it to stop and
then go to the end.
So yeah,
let's see if our
report is done yet.
So, for example, this is
one of the most recent
run the other ones
i ran it at 627.
so start price is
$16 so it's changed
it's not in fact because
How I can improve it
is that it has a big
gap for national data
from Apple Advantage.
The nice thing about
it is also that
should you hold
on to it or should
you accept? So if
you go to Apple one,
it tells you about
Apple, the Apple YouTube,
and gives you access
to the slides.
For example,
here, it tells
you if you
should buy more.
What is the accuracy
level for each stock
analysis on holding
or selling them?
So you should
never trust AI.
um but basically
this is not about the
video i was just
trying to show you the
possibilities of like
what you can build
uh with these like
frameworks that are
really composable
and you can work with
it's basically like
a block change change
depending together
and box you can
make it as accurate.
Again, you can add
APIs to it, you can
add an mcp server,
like a web server
that will be automated
and understand how
people are talking
about different
stocks or companies,
because a lot of
times, like, public
opinion about how a
company is really,
and that affects
the stocks. So
there's a lot of
different moments you
can access and maybe
a macro response.
Okay,
so that's where
the that you're
not planning to
really understand
if this is the quality
that you want it or
not, and you set the
quality. So if you
say what are the
mistakes, what are the
areas where you're going
on, or let the handle
run and then what
are the things to do
for and what are the
criteria for the data
so it keeps going
into a loop until
it gets to learn
about their kids now
I think we are
a good person.
We are a good person.
Every single person
can be a good person.
Yeah, I think I can. I
think I can
start up so far.
I think I can
I think I can do it.
Yeah, I think.
Me.
yeah so mcp agent
so mcp is for
It's like a new
one to make a
tool call. It's
kind of like an
API that gives
access to points.
We haven't served a day
rise for a couple days.
What we're doing is
that when Anthropy
came out, they
also came out with
a different work
frame, stuff like
how this new call
should be made.
And then what we did
is that we actually
took that. like this is
actually happening with
the way the age of
communication as well
so for example there's
different workflows
that the orchestrator
works well the activator
works well like you
have bunch of uh work
in parallel workflow
where you have a bunch
of agents with something
in parallel and
then you add them and
kind of have this all
so that's what we're
doing what we're doing
If you want to learn
more, you can do it here.
Tanya.
NCP agent, that
library is sick, hey?
I just built
something with
that NCP agent
in Slackbot.
We built that thing
on the conference,
it works better
than any grad.
right so great we
have one more demo for
you guys here I don't
know what this one is
about surprise But the
guy is really good.
Oh, right.
. Yeah, so you need to .
You only remember,
your CPH was
great because
it has a little NCT file.
It's inside your
Python script.
All right, so you put
that in the Python
script, and then you can
make anything in NCT.
Right, so any Python
script you write
can now be an NCT
file. You don't
have to only block
code for all of the
computers, for all
of the computers.
Right, everybody
give it up for...
Wait, wait y'all,
give it up there.
Wait,
okay, wait, now...
Give it up there!
I made
this app at a hackathon.
Me and Isaac are
actually very private.
I made it in like
one day. I just
had it done like
four months ago.
And so then you
put the, like,
buying code, like,
for the course of
the end of the
school. Let's go.
Woo!
And that's not localhost?
No, it's not
localhost. Shhh.
Okay, so welcome
everybody to
Lease Daddy.
We're rents. Yeah.
Alright, cool,
hashtag New York.
So when you rent an
apartment, you often
get a lease from a
landlord, and you
have a short amount
of time to figure out
whether it's good
or not, and a short
window where you can
do anything about it,
regardless of exactly
the same thing.
And so I'm just going
to quickly make a
lease. I didn't know
how it was going to demo
today, so I'm going
to just make a lease.
That's cool, just go over
my chat so you
can see it.
No, you can take
it, I'm taking
it, really,
you can go on.
We want to support
our business in New
York and maybe a new
conference at PDF.
And maybe we want
a couple of red
flags or like two
problematic expenses.
Yeah.
A couple of hidden
really unfair terms.
So we're going
to do that. We're
going to create a
PDF for ourselves.
When we doubled this
at the hackathon,
we had a friend who
was in Seattle, and
he wouldn't think
they had a terrible
lease that had like
this horrible security
deposit thing, and
he got *******.
So we actually
used a lease.
Okay, so we're
generating a PDF here.
This turns into a PDF,
but we can get it.
It's not worth
generating that. This
isn't the cool
part of the demo.
Let's
see if it worked.
Did it give you a PDF?
Oh, it did. I
see big lease.
Good job.
Big job AI. Checking
the user was a good job.
Yeah, like, yeah.
This is the hardest
part of the demo.
Okay. Okay. I'm just
going to analyze our
lease. So if you take
a second to profit,
what's happening is it's
an API called Anthropic,
and it's not super
eugentic, but there's
like a couple of
rounds of communication
that are happening
in order to make some
different outcomes that
will come up shortly.
So I think the first
thing that you kind
of need to know as a
renter are like, is
this good or bad, and
what the red flag,
what should I ask about
this? But the second
thing is like what
can you do about
it? So we kind of took
the approach to the
very healthy community
Like if you if
you've rented the board
multiple times You
kind of know that
like there's kind of
certain things that you
should and shouldn't
say and that you
should and shouldn't do
So I think that's
kind of the
focus is to help
enable users to
So I haven't even
looked at the lease yet.
So here we see
And when there is a
relatively variable,
it does say it's a
fairly... But here
there's a heavily
skewed at the landlord.
Okay.
One more time we'll
see what ChatGPT
did and see
whether Anthropik
could determine
what ChatGPT did.
So we have a crazy
event increase.
I'm kind of
curious to look
at the actual lease. um
um
i'm using this for sure
does anybody
see an actual
red flag so we
can check yeah
yeah
Yeah, yeah, so
here we have
our 14 days
notice right there
Yeah, so we found this
Issues and then the
next question is what
can you do about it?
So at some point you
have to go and tell
the landlord about this
So here we have the
draft email, and
so here we have a pre
-drafted email that
uses information from
this and provides
a draft that you
can send directly.
And then sometimes
you're arguing for
better terms, but
sometimes you don't have
to communicate in a
way so that you can
draft with ones that
are more about getting
a discount for
different terms. terms
this one's very like
strongly worded like
your lawyer friend
might might have the
gumption to provide
um you get action
acquired kind of thing
um we decided to just
kind of keep keep
going with it um get
very generative we
have one called rampage
No, but there's a, we
should have like an
MCP to go like extremely
on it, so if anybody
So the other thing
we built is there's
an AI coach where you
can actually use a
chat bot to go
practice simulated
conversations and this
is designed to be like
dismissive and
kind of not
really interested
in this as a
regular landlord
But it will actually
give in at some point
if you are being really
convincing. So if
you just go into
something like, you know
Generic, you might not
get a good result as
the landlord has a lot
they can do on what
he hates at it. So
we'll see how it goes.
Okay, so yeah.
Section 14
needs to be 10%
different. I
think we'll get a
little more
specific. I am out.
So we'll try to get a
little more
specific to see.
Were you able to
bring in the actual
context from WIse terms
into the supposition?
Yeah, they are
directly used in here.
So we have a, and
there's also a rank
-based implementation
where we can get
WIse terms from other
WIse, like, whole
corpus of WIse.
Other whole corpus.
So you hooked up
to like a WIse API.
Yeah.
So yeah, that's WeSteady.
There's also
a phone agent,
but it's not
running right now.
You can actually
call and do the
same thing on
phone call. Nice.
So yeah, that's WeSteady.
It's only so identical,
but I'm proud
of us being able to
go in really fast,
with a lot of
coding knowledge.
And if you're interested
in checking it
out, But this isn't
something more like
pursuing super deeply,
but it does work
and you can go try
it if you want to.
Yeah, that's
LeafDaddy. And
who are you?
What do you do?
Oh, so I'm Dan.
I'm building
a product for
energy investors. Please.
Ok,
well, it's p0-meet
-daddy-addy-daddy
-daddy-addy-addy
-addy-addy-addy-addy
-addy. I'll put it
in your classroom.
QR, I'm gonna take my YG.
Okay.
Guys, and then, we just
have one more person.
Thanks, give it up for
Dan, I get it back.
We have one more person,
wanted to share a
little bit about their
non-profit options.
Hi,
I'm Anatole,
and I'm nervous,
nice to see all of you.
Public speaking
voice is fun, right?
Wasn't prepared
to talk, so
I put some notes
on my phone.
But yeah, I'm Anatole,
technology manager
for Rewriting the
Code, just joined a few
months ago, a really
great organization uh we
support a community
of 36 000 women uh
specifically early career
and in college with uh
sorry still learning
uh access to mentorship
resources in-person
events virtual events
and currently
we're preparing our
ai curriculum uh
for me i've always
been fascinated with
with automation,
AI, I mean,
stuff's amazing.
So I've come from that
background and we're
figuring out what does
our community want?
What are people really
looking to learn to
be prepared for what's
coming in this year?
And at least from
my perspective, it's
created this really
interesting situation,
yeah, reading
through my notes,
where a lot
of what people
are learning in college
is dating,
right? Because so
much of this has
come out now.
So with a lot of
early careers, they're
either not
hiring or they're
looking for people
who already have
experience with a lot
of these AI tools.
So there's this
big gap that's
being realized now
and I think will
soon be realized
even greater.
And I'm sure we can
agree that the value of
a college education,
a college degree in
particular, is always
a little questionable.
It's really
been about what
you're doing with
it. What have
you done with
your experience?
So with this, how do you
prepare? How do
you get ready?
And I guess as it relates
to my organization,
how can we better
prepare our community
to be ready for
what's coming?
Online, I've spoken
with a lot of teachers,
a lot of teams, and
they've asked, how do we
teach our students to
use an AI, or they're
not just using AI to
answer the questions,
but to be a tool,
a co-pilot, something
that they know how
to work with, so that
they can go into the
job force ready to use
these tools you know
a tool is an asset
something to work with
it would be better
and not just not have
a job so I know about
one thing has said
many times he said
I'm not doing this to
replace people with work
sorry replace people
with AI I'm doing
this give one person
the power of 200 so that
they can do anything
themselves and be
empowered And I think
that's aligned with
that concept, really
empowering students
coming into the space
to do anything,
to really come
prepared for
what's coming.
So I know in my
opinion, I feel
a lot of that
curriculum should
really be focused
on exactly that.
Teaching people how to
use AI in their field.
There's so much
that you can learn
in AI. Honestly,
we'd love to hear
any of your opinions
on what people
need to be prepared
for the future.
And to close, I mean,
I'll just say again,
in the coming year or
two, I really think
it's going to be an
interesting period. I
mean, students have
been going to college
for four years, learning
all of this stuff
that technically
cannot be applicable
with a lot of the jobs
that are hiring, and
it'll take time for
that to get there, but
I think we'll really
start seeing that.
And that's the question
that I'm trying to
answer and figure
out, how do we best
prepare our community
for what's coming um
with the tools what do
they need to know and
uh yeah if you'd like
to talk about this
if you have any
suggestions we'd love to
guys that's all i
got for presenters
thank you all
for coming and
before i let you
guys go Okay,
this is the first
New York City
Agentics Foundation
to meet up, okay?
I don't know how
many people actually
know about the
Agentics Foundation
before you came
here, right?
So I'm going to, in
the blast that I send
you guys after this,
hook you up with
like a couple of
URLs where you can go
and get plugged in,
right? Where you can
get like in this
community be where we
are like pushing the
boundaries what people
are doing, they
act. All of these
naysayers that people
are like, oh, we can't
do this, oh, we're
being very careful.
Just go all in and
trust everybody
that's telling
you. Because like,
just .
Guys, that's really
it, like network
hangout, I think
we have to be
kicked out of here
like 7:15 or 7:30.
but a big shout
out to zohar