Hey,
buddy.
How's it going?
Good. Good,
good, good, bro.
I got way too much
light happening here.
Your screen's
really blurry,
too, for some reason.
Zota!
Hey?
What's up?
State of the art.
Oh, right. Yeah,
we love that term.
It's, let me see.
I'm gonna polish this up
here.
Yeah, request is a 2%.
Yeah, let's not bother
with affiliate programs.
Affiliate programs
are a bit of a scam.
Either pay a sponsorship
fee or don't bother.
There you go.
We've got Ocean
and Braun today.
okay yeah we've already
sent them thousands
of of customers
what more they need
undoubtedly right
sounds like david's
conversations with them
are going fairly well so
okay that's good
i integrated the deep
research into uh the
google uh drive this
morning so i could
automatically update the
uh my google sheets and
stuff as it did the uh
research was kind of
cool nice yeah
so i just asked a
specific project or is
it versatile just
anything i just yeah so
when i when i uh share
when i asked it to
do the research i
said just research and
put it into a google
sheet automatically
using the google sheet
mcp and it created
the and i said just
give me the best models
as an example and
it created a hundred
listing of a hundred
best models in order
fantastic and you did
those with two separate
mcps you didn't lump
them in together
i just got it to
orchestrate yeah i just
did it and just yeah
i one one did the
research the other
updated the uh updated
the yeah just just
to see if i could
so yeah pretty pretty
pretty cool deep
research on the
front end of
any system is
really potent
yeah it's it's
it's pretty cool
it's pretty cool it's
and it goes for a
long time like i did
a deep research last
night and i had it
running for like several
hours researching testing
it'd be pretty cool
for like like you
said you're so down
right do you create a
model state of the art
and then and then gather
information training
fine-tune all that
kind of stuff i think
it'd be like fine
-tuning flow would be a
really really interesting
one we could find
fine-tune a model
with it really easily
specifically for
the deep research
portion is that
what you mean or use
the deep research
in order to edge to
to fine-tune
the model yes
yeah that'd be cool
cool kind of use
case for it you
use that into into
the search gpc
interface or using API?
I use MCP.
I'm going to demo
it in a bit here.
Okay, good.
I created a
couple new modes
because, you
know, I could.
I did the,
and then I ran the
SCC to see how much
value it got according
to SCC, which
overestimates, I think
it was like $525,000
worth of code written
in. an hour but you
know whatever who
knows how realistic
that number is but
even a factor of 10 it's
still an interesting
number even yeah
even even even a
factor of 100 is an
interesting number that's
right 500 in an
hour in in value
generation five thousand
five thousand uh 50
right but put
me a 525 000.
it's a thousand
dollars i don't
know yeah i don't
know whatever it's
a lot yeah hey
guys brad hey brad
i can actually see why
people like watching
uh the the code go
through automatically
with the agents i ended
up um kind of before
bed just watching
code go through and it
kind of it was like a
meditative state just
going oh look at the
little little guys
making all these
changes and the red turn
into green it was
actually yeah oh the test
yeah there's like you
get a dopamine hit
when you when you watch
test driven development
it's like is it is
it am i gonna go from
like 150 tests failing
to 147. Oh, yeah.
It is awesome. I
think if we're redoing
a website, we
should add kind of
some form of live
Twitch type thing.
Whoever has automated
code writing
going, just
have that as a
splash page for
people to watch.
Yeah, seriously.
Maybe we just separate
the dashboard backend
from the front end and
that'll make it super
easy to move over.
There's a couple similar
sites to Learnstream
that I looked at
as well that might
be better. There was
something Apricot?
What the **** was that
site? I almost
went with it.
We'll have to ask
Deep Research.
But it was something
Apricot. and they've
had all the same general
because what you want
is you want the learning
stuff you want the
community features
you want like you know
you want certifications
all that kind of stuff
so it kind of has
to lean a little bit
towards learning yeah
well i was also thinking
i think i think all
of them have it but we
want someone like robert
or like um the london
chapter to be able
to have a place where
they can put their own
events or yeah exactly
i think it's called
wild wild apricot that
sounds like a either a
tech company or 1990s
alternative yeah why
yeah it's my it's my
it's my grunge band i
i i kind of i kind of
want to create a nirvana
cover band but you
know i don't know
who's got time for that
my son's that does it
does a mean cover of
come as you are so you
know that that was a
proud moment yeah wild
apricot check out wild
apricot i think that's
everything we want
it's you know it's it's
it combines yeah it
combines everything
it's it's organized for
non-profits it's got the
learning systems it's
got payments it's
got event management
mobile dashboard was
number one on their list
of things for dashboards
yeah exactly crm for
everyone yeah it's
it's it's almost got
everything we need now
the only thing it may
not have specifically
and the reason i didn't
choose it possibly was
because i it wasn't
it didn't have like it
did have it it didn't
have like a certification
or something
but well they're they're
they're pricing is
by contacts i don't
know what that means
because it gets pretty
pricey we also have
multi-chapter version
yeah so there's that
yeah so i i i ended
up going with learn
worlds but if if i if
i was going you know
if i was going to do
it now and not build
it myself which you're
right we probably
should we uh i would
probably have gone
with something like
wild apricot but we what
we could do is say
well what are the wild
apricot alternatives
yeah but it's not
that expensive to be
honest when you look
at the price we're
at around uh we're
somewhere between 500
and 2000 so 147 a month
that's basically the
same price as learnworlds
and even at 2000
so like 252 dollars
yeah it does donations
finances online
payments stores
management yeah well
the big thing is
it's not just a
normal site we can
add in our any kind
of courses with
certification which
will give some
motivation to make sure
that we have a
whole bunch of them
Yeah, I think
there's an API, so
if we want to add
stuff, I think
we hypothetically
come here.
I'm going to
add my bot here.
I'm going to, oh, shoot,
I forgot to start this.
I'm going to
start, I'm going to
live stream this
to LinkedIn,
because people
seem to like that.
The LinkedIn stream seems
to do pretty well, so,
well.
Yeah, if that works,
that makes total sense.
Yeah, it's a
long tail on it.
There's a few
hundred people that
tune in live,
but then there's
like 10,000 people
that view later.
All right, so
Rob, we've got
Ocean and
sorry, who else?
Braun Fieldwalker.
Mr. Braun.
I've got several
Braun's and I always mix
them up and I'm thinking
it's this Bron or
the other Bron and
they're like, what are you
talking about? Oh,
you're the other Bron.
I had a call
the other day
with some of my
customers and I had
a call with four
different Michaels.
It was like, which
Michael am I talking
to here? Wait,
you had one call
with four Michaels?
No, I had four
different customers
all named Michael.
And I was like, I'm
totally confused.
I was getting
all, I'm like, I'm
mentioning the
wrong Michael today.
I need, I need
to, I need to
somehow differentiate.
And they
all want to be
called Michael.
Those Michael
guys are pretty,
pretty particular
about that. Yeah.
Go live.
Fence.
They're probably
born in the
eighties, you
know, like Michael,
Nicholas, Ryan.
There was a lot of
variety. well yeah
we're we're going we're
we're live all right
so i'm gonna hit
we're broadcasting so
thanks everyone and
pause recording oh
i've been recording
the whole time anyway
we'll we'll get
all the for for the
recording that goes on
uh altura later we'll
have all our preamble
we didn't say anything
too silly uh uh here
we are may already
uh and rob congratulations
on the leafs
they made it past
the first round yes
so Rob was telling
me the other
day that his life
represents the
failure of the
Leafs hockey team
the last time
they won was
the year before
you were born
I'm not going to
say which year
that was you
can google that
I know this
gives you great
pleasure but I
was born I am the
oldest man or
a person can be
and never have
seen the Toronto
Maple Leafs win
a Stanley Cup.
Their last time
was in 1967.
I was born in 1968.
I have chased the
dream with Leaf
fans for the
entirety of my life.
I'm not holding
any grand hope out
this year because,
you know, after
50-some-odd years,
you get used to
it. But thank you.
Round one. Yes.
so what you're
saying is you're
the personification
of failure
and that's not
what i'm saying
okay but i have i have
enjoyed that i have
enjoyed that run with
that with alicia's
and well next time i
see you i'm going to
get you one of those
stanley cups with
the big sippy straw
at the top and that'll
make you feel a little
better there we go
so who do we got today
on the agenda uh so
today we've got uh we
got the heavy hitters
that we've got ocean
um hi ang lee ocean has
got uh some interesting
stuff that he's been
doing with uh with the
new uh rue boomerang
modes and the custom
modes so uh we've got
a demo from him and
then as well bron field
worker bron's been
working on some stuff in
the background and um
it's ready for demo
this week so all right
well that's that's
exciting the a lot of a
lot of what's going on
seems to still be
relating to the use of our
boomerang and our spark
modes and yesterday
in particular we did a
lot a live presentation
so it's showing sort
of what you could
do and i added a couple
new modes that sort
of integrates mcps
into the flow which has
been kind of cool. I've
been using this tool
from Composio, which
allows you to integrate
sort of third, what
do you call it? Remote
MCPs. So for those that
aren't familiar, up
until March, you were
only able to essentially
reuse local MCPs using
Studio. Now you can
use remote MCPs using
an HTTP transport,
which basically means
it doesn't sit on your
local machine and can
access the web without
a proxy. I think, if I
saw correctly, earlier
this week, the folks
at Claude, Anthropic
Claude, added remote
capabilities to the
desktop client for anyone
using that as well.
So a lot of what you're
seeing hypothetically
could be integrated
into your Claude
desktop if that's
what you like to use.
Obviously, I'm a nerd,
so I like VS Code,
but everything you're
seeing hypothetically
could run independently
of vs code as well um
so should we should we
jump in you do a little
uh a little demo
actually before we do
apparently this this week
was the week of llama
and it's amazing how
like almost no real
interesting news from
the the guys in meta
like there's no real
exciting model the most
exciting model released
this week was probably
the 5.4 reasoning
model from Microsoft,
which basically is a
tiny reasoning model that
will run on commercial,
or I guess consumer,
I should say, desktops.
So if you're looking
to run your own
reasoning model locally,
things, I guess, deep
seek-like, it's a nice
little model. I
played around with it
briefly, and I think I
was using Ollama to do
that, and it was a
nice model. So I think
a bunch of the clients
I'm working with are
saying that they're
really concerned about
the use of remote
models. I don't really
know where that
concern is coming, this
idea of data leakage
to a read-only
model, which leads me
to my next thought.
I've heard this several
times this week,
this idea that
somehow the language
model is going to
steal your information.
So we need to discuss
that just briefly,
just so we're all
on the same page.
LOMs are read-only,
right? When you
make a request, it
isn't being trained.
You can train a model
for sure. And training
a model, it does
involve the whole
process of, you know,
sending information,
usually in JSON-L
format, and that, you
know, is going to
use the GPU and do a
whole series of activities
to train it. But
when you, unless
there's a man in the
middle, which is possible,
then, and the data
as being sort of
siphoned off somehow,
the model isn't just
going to magically
learn from you, right?
So a lot of these
enterprises I'm talking
to have this idea
that these LLMs are
like some kind of like
brain intelligence
that is going to
learn as you interact
with it. Not unless
you're explicitly
saving that information
or, and if you're
using like a major
provider like Microsoft
or Google or Amazon,
you know, their
terms of service
are pretty clear. Now, if
you don't trust
that provider,
then why are you
using the cloud in the
first place? And
that data lake that's
feeding the LLM that
you have on AWS,
well, that's all your
data. It's already
there. So if you're
worried about data
leakage, well, you
should probably worry
about your data
lake more than you
should the request to
the LLM. All right,
that's my rant.
It's, and again,
several people
have mentioned
to me this week.
It's, you know,
it's not a thing.
At least it can
be, but it's likely
not. So Ruben, I
spent a bunch of time
on this. So is
it, you know, one
of the areas is
leakage across users.
Like if you dump a
bunch of data into a
model as part of a
conversation, and that
happens to have the CEO's
salary in there, and
you're the HR person,
that's good for you.
But then somebody else
uses that model, has
a conversation with it,
and maybe he somehow
gets the CEO's salary
back as part of
his answer. But he's
not allowed to have that
information. Is that
possible? in this
like sharing of yeah
that's that's leakage
that's data that's the
same that's the same
as any other data's
leakage right that's right
that's no every
hosting every hosting
service and every mcp
that you don't run and
you don't run all
can have a man in the
middle and that's you
know any service that
we're using We have
to, you know, go
through, like you said,
the licensing agreement,
but we have to
look, is that data
going anywhere else
where there's a potential
man in the middle
attack? And that's
really the thing from
an IP protection that
I think corporations
are worried about.
It is a potential
vulnerability for sure.
But the thing that
bothers me the most
is I'm hosting my data
in Amazon, and that's
fine. time, no problem
with some billion
rows of data in a
database on Amazon,
but somehow or other,
using bedrock on
Amazon is going to
siphon the data. Now when
it comes to access
rules and privileges,
that has nothing to
do with AI. That has
to do with when you
make a query, do you
have permission to
the data that you're
querying? No? Well,
then don't show it.
Don't allow access
to it. that is that's
just straight up old
school it you know
off right and has
zero to do with ai and
some and back to the
point of mcps and this
was another debate
that i heard earlier
this week around mcps
being kind of inherently
not enterprise
friendly no the the
updates to uh the off
rules that came out in
march solved all
those problems you can
explicitly quarantine
each of the MCP
requests using traditional
auth rules, and
that solves that problem.
Now, that all comes
right back to things
like Active Directory
and other forms of
authentication that
have existed for
decades at this point.
So it's almost like
the executives at
a lot of these large
organizations are
just kind of ignorant
to how IT works
in general, and then
assume that some
sort of sci-fi
version of Skynet is
how these things
work, and they don't.
anyway um that's my
that's my rant and i'm
going to show you some
cool stuff now how's
that sound all right
so um this this week so
this is yesterday if
i start with this so
yesterday i ran we we
did a little vibe coding
session we do vibe
on thursdays but an
hour hour and a half
something like that and
you know this is what
it output so i ran sec
when it was done i don't
know if these numbers
are right or not but
they're interesting
to see you know the
number the amount of
lines of code are
definitely right but the the
estimated value and
for up until the the
emergence of vibe
coding this was the gold
standard for sort of
valuing your your code
output this is using
something called scc so
if you're interested
in sort of valuing your
your your output, get
root install SCC. So
ask it to install SCC
using the go library.
Don't bother with
curl or the other
ones, go is the best.
And then when you
do run it, ask it
to exclude the node
modules. Remember
the node modules is
where all your
additional libraries and
modules are being
installed. If you're
using node, if
you're using Python,
ask it to exclude
things like the PyCache
and other sort of
compiled folders. that'll
skew the value
because you're getting
all the you know
modules and whatnot you
know obviously he's
gonna make them make it
look like more than
it is so make sure you
exclude that but
anyway an hour worth of
running the deep
research tool it created
12,000 lines of
markdown 5100 lines of
TypeScript and around 3
,500 lines of JavaScript
now the the value
is really the these
two areas here in the
code complexity. So
when you, when you
look at that, you're
seeing roughly around,
you know, 618, which
works out to $500,000
of perceived value.
Let me say something
about value
for a moment. When,
when one random
dude can crank
out, you know,
8,000 lines of code
or actually whatever
here that we have more
like around six, six,
six or 7,000 lines of
actual code in an hour
yeah the the real
value doesn't you know
doesn't really matter
right that the value
goes down so what i
think what we're what i'm
really saying here is
this isn't worth 512
25 000 it's worth some
order of magnitude
less than that but
regardless it's the effort
i i can you know i'm
cranking out in an
hour what this is saying
would normally take
10 months and a team
of four people to do
which is so this is your
your analysis on your
code base right that
i did yesterday just
just on on our live
coding session and this
is all coming from that
scc um that this is
all coming from that
scc thing yeah so what
we did this is scc
seeing i ran the scc
command you have to
install it so just you
know go in the room if
you're using my uh spark
mode going to the
devops option and just
ask it to install the
scc using go and then
tell it to do an analysis
of your folder and
exclude any libraries,
modules, et cetera,
et cetera. And this
is what will pop out.
All right. So it's
kind of, and to be
honest, when I end a
project, I generally
send my customer a
screenshot of this
and they're like,
holy ****, I can't
believe that created
so much. And this is,
you know, this is
just an hour, right?
Imagine what a week
or two looks like.
And usually this
is like, I just did
$62 million worth
of effort last week,
you know, and they're
blown away by it.
All right. So I
added a couple of
new modes, which
you guys might
like, and you'll
see here that I've
added a mode called
deep research.
And if you want to go
to my gist, you can
grab these as well.
Remember to when
you're adding new
modes, you can you can
either get Roo itself
to create the mode
or you can copy and
paste it, whatever
you prefer. Now, when
I create these modes,
I actually create
these modes to work
alongside my MCPs.
So in the mode
themselves, you'll see
that there's references
to the structure of
the MCP and so on.
And you can see that by
going to your prompts.
So here, if you go
here, we see here
that I'm going to
just jump which mode
I'm in, I'm in the
deep research mode.
We can see some of the
details. So in this
case, I'm, I've
created, I'm using
perplexity in this
particular scenario. I create
a folder structure
and then recursive
self-learning approach.
This is important.
The recursive self
-learning approach
means it doesn't
just analyze, it
reflects on the data
it's gotten multiple
times throughout
the process and
questions, and then
dig deeper into what
it's learned or
what it's gathered.
When you just do
a sort of blind,
get me the information
without the
recursion, it doesn't
really give you
that depth. So the
things like cross
-validation,
synthesis, and other
components really
works well for this.
Ultimately, what that
creates is a research
folder. You see here
that – and you can
customize this if you
want different approaches
to research. But
ultimately, what it's
doing is it's creating
a series of files
and then a final report.
So you can see here
that the final report
– and then I use that
to guide the final
development. So you
can see here that there's
an executive summary,
there's findings,
and so on. now what
i said quick question
the structure this
research folder of the
initial queries and
the the final is that
that's is that whole
structure going to
be used by by your
orchestrator or is it is
this going to sit there
and as it and you're
going to use it to
create your spec of
what you want to build a
little bit of both so
um so it depends on
what i'm doing so if if
i'm if i'm by coding,
I might just be like,
build me some crazy
thing that Kristen
will be impressed by.
And it'll go and create
it. And then, you
know, you'll research
it, then I'll create
it. Now I can take
that a step further now
and I can create a plan.
So what I did today
is I created a new
mode here called the
data collection mode.
And what data collection
mode does, it saves
that information to
a Google sheet. Now
I can save that to a
database or whatever,
but for the purposes
of this i thought
it'd be easier just to
show you what that looks
like so in this case
i said i told it
i'll run it here in a
moment but i said create
me a list of the best
ml models and organize
it from best to
worst based on you know
various criteria so
it generated this
this sheet i called it
data explorer oh it
called it data explorer
and it created a hundred
rows i could have
done i could have done
a million rows if i
let it run for a day
or two but in this
case i only let it run
for about 10 minutes.
And we're going to
do that again. So I'm
going to show you guys
how that works. So
we're going to go in
here and we're going to
select the deep
research mode. I've been
playing with Gemini 2
.5. It's not a bad model.
It has a much larger
context. So if you're
doing deep research,
there's a tendency
for Sonnet 3.7 thinking
to max out its context
window and i added
rules that really
make it work well for
gemini and you get this
if you use the create
spark but you'll see
here in the rules
folder that i i reminded
exactly how it needs
to operate so it makes
lesser models when it
comes to implementation
work better so
you can see how it
understands applying
dips and stuff like that
do those rules come
as a as a part of the
orchestration and like
the initial spec or
are you creating those
rules independently
If you use the MPX
create-spark, you get
all this. I didn't
include the deep
research components
because they're MCP
specific and I want
to keep this a little
bit more generic,
but you can just grab
that off my gist if
you want to copy and
paste that or you
can try it yourself.
All right. So I'm
going to go in
here. I'm going
to say create a...
I'm not going to use
deep research actually.
I'm going to go
in here first, I'm
going to go to data
collection, and I'm
going to say create
a project management
Google feed with
sample agile structure.
I'm just making
this up, right?
All right. In this
case, I'm going to
use Sonic 3.7
because I'm just
instructing it. I'm
not really doing much.
And I'm not collecting
any data yet.
We'll do that in a
future step. And I'm
going to say, don't
do anything else.
All right. So let's see.
Fingers crossed on
the demos. You know,
this worked 10 times
before I started
the call, but it'll
break now for sure.
But let's see. And this
is using an MCP, right?
Yeah, it's using MCP.
Yeah, you can see
here. We can go here
and see the MCPs. I
got data collection
MCP. You can see the
Google Sheet options.
right this is and I
and I created a mode
that tells it exactly
what the Google Sheet
options are don't
unless you tell it you
won't know and it'll
spend 10 minutes trying
to figure it out this
saves you a few bucks
all right so we see
here that it's good I
need to create a project
management Google
Sheet with agile
structure let me plan this
out it's going to
do a sprint planning
user stories tasks
team velocity tracking
burndown charts now
it's creating an agile
project management
template. That looks good.
It created that
successfully.
Now it's going and
it's going to create
multiple sheets
for that project.
And it's requesting
that I'm going to
turn that on. So let's
see if that works.
So it's good.
It's created the
first sheet. It's
called Sheet1.
Not the most creative
name, but it's
good enough for
me. Now it's going
to update the sheet
with the data for
the Agile. Now in
my other window,
while that's going, I'm
just going to refresh
my Google Drive and
I'm going to see
if I can see that
and I'll pull it over
briefly. So now it's
giving the response. It's
created, now it's
successfully created
that. In my other
window, which you guys
can't see, which I'll
bring over in a moment,
I'm going to show
you the Google sheet
and we're going to see
if the data resides
in there all right so
now we're going here
we're going to jump
back and forth for
a moment all right
so it's creating it's
it's building out
the structure of the
sheet now this is
particularly great
while you're doing
dev work right so now
that i've got an
agile structure i can
start getting when
i do the long term
implementation I can
use the Google Sheet
in this case as a memory
bank so I don't have
to have the memory and
all the MD files and
you know saved locally
I can just save it
to a Google Sheet now
I can do this just as
easily with a github repo
or project management
or JIRA whatever
but just to show how
the MCPs can interact
with third parties I
figured the sheet was
a good sort of example
of how it will look
now i i told it to just
make it up right i
didn't actually use any
real data i just told
it to kind of fake
it let's go back here
and i'll see where where
we're at this would be
great if it actually
used the github new
new projects uh feature
yeah it does i've
got i've got a github
project mcp which i
released a few weeks ago
it does exactly that
i love that that tool
man does yeah so you
can see it's it's
creating the sheets it's
continuing the update
You know we can see the
the various elements
it's adding for each
of the people now
Google sheets
Let's let's continue
Now I can take
this further
Now if I use the
deep research
I can save the
directly to a
Google sheet as well
So now it's
formatting the cells.
Let's jump back and
see what it looks
like. It's doing
some formatting
here we go it's adding
it's adding some
colors i guess it's
added some backlog it's
added some sprint
planning it's adding you
know task boards i can
take this further i
can ask it i can ask
it to do macros i can
organize a ui i can
make this the world's
most complicated
spreadsheet if i want to i
i didn't give it a whole
lot of guidance you
can see there's a
couple errors you know
we we can get it to
resolve those things but
this is literally
building it as we speak
and now what's cool is
again i can integrate
this directly with
the development flow
i didn't for this case
but it's still going
so you're vibe coding
a scrum master uh
it's exactly what i'm
doing uh yeah this is
crazy how many people
are you going to put
out of work with this
thing uh with you know
what what does what
did oppenheimer say
with with with great
power you know i have
big i have become the
destroyer of jobs yeah
yeah dude yeah i know
it's so so let's just
let's just go here for
a moment so each of
these i i can just
add random mcps and
then i can integrate
those mcps as part of my
flow so and that that's
what's what's crazy
in that like for
example the fire crawl
if you look at the fire
crawl MCP here I've
got the ability to to
not just crawl sites
that interact with sites
I can get the login
to a website I can
get the fill out forms
and then collect all
the information it
gets and put that
into a into my into my
Google sheet and then
build something I can
get this to like
literally go to a website
copy the website build
it you know whatever
I needed to do the the
perplexity one's cool
let's let's jump to
that for a i'm going
to stop this for a
minute so we're gonna
we're gonna i'm just
gonna let this you guys
get the point here it's
it's it'll go until
it's done let's
just quickly look at
whatever built all right
so it's formatting it
it's getting whatever
it's doing yeah so
it's it gives you a
way of of basically be
you know managing a
project and getting an
outline and and having
the the template to
manage your project
exactly so now i can take
it a step further and
i can say you know
So what should
we research?
Research, I'm
going to switch to
the mode. I'm going
to switch to a
mode here called
deep research mode.
And this does, you know,
where deep research
for Google or OpenAI
runs for maybe 20,
most I'd be able to
get it to run with 28
minutes. I don't know
if anyone's able to
get it run longer than
28 minutes, but that's
the longest I've ever
seen it run. I was
able to get this to
run for several hours
the other day, and it
just researched, it
collected. and i was
able to collect every
permit in in north
america for like if you
want to like build a
house or open a restaurant
or or open a store
and you got every
permit from every location
in north america and
just ran and then saved
that to a database
for me which is crazy
and wow dude that's
nuts yeah and that
information was hard to
get like it's all
spread out and did that
Research a
novel, let's say,
algo to cure,
you know where I'm
going with this, right?
all right okay and
um start start with
start with a the
perplexity ai mcp oh
you actually tell
it which mcp you
want it to use yes
i can use fire crawl
as well and you know
we're saving the
data data to the what
would we call that
one I don't remember
we'll we'll go back
down here we'll to the
data data collection
mode and well I gotta
remember all these
things and I think I
guess I call the data
collection data clone
mode slash mcp and
research a novel out
of the cure of cancer
all right let's you
know based let's say
based on the most uh
cutting edge research
available all right
we're deep i'm going to
use gemini uh so this
is interesting because
the most cutting
edge research will be
in private databases
not available on the
internet well that's
a whole yeah yeah we
because we are using
an llm we can infer the
unseen okay it did
the it so this is a
problem with with gemini
it doesn't necessarily
work quite as well
and now it's it's not
that i don't want this
initial stage i want
to actually you know
start with the uh
research but let's give
it one more shot and
i'll uh yeah it's doing
it's doing the research
which is not bad for
a running process
it's plan it's doing
a plan before it
implements which is based
on spur but i want to
show you guys to do
the research i'm just
going to cancel this
for a moment okay just
do i'm going to say
just uh do the data
collection using for
flexi also can you make
one more change okay
you started because
curing cancer it's
kind of not very well
defined problem because
there are different
types of cancers they
work very differently
like so you can also
actually have it here.
There is no like a
cancer back. So like if
you stick like a
specific cancer back, it
might actually do
a better job. Yeah,
you're right. And I'm
just showing you the
art of the possible.
I'm not curing cancer
here, guys. But all
right, so it chose the
wrong model, I can
tell. Let's see if it
figured out that it
used the right model.
All right.
Yep, it used the
right model the
second time. Google
is a little dumb,
like Sonnet is definitely
a better model,
but what I like about
Google is it has a better
context window for
large amounts of
information, so it did
a search, it found some
information relating to
it, now it's creating
a primary findings,
now back to your point,
the more narrow the
focus, the better, like
curing cancer is like,
yeah, right, you're
going to cure everything
for everyone. You
should do a specific
oncology, not a broad
one. But the point
is this is capable of
running and it'll run,
it'll run. And I can take
this a step further.
I could say implement
a machine learning
algorithm that they'll
test and find me the
coherence. Then I can
take it further and I
can say, create me an
MCP for a lab testing
service that can actually
go and validate and
so on and so forth.
And it'll do everything
required, right? So
it's continuing to
research. So now it's using
an iterative back and
forth loop. So it's
creating primary findings,
then it's revising
those primary findings,
then it's using
the citations from those
findings and digging
deeper into each part
of that. So iteratively
researching, figuring
out, and then I can
create the coding loop
as part of that or
testing loop or a
optimization loop, depending
on what it needs to
do. So it's basically
like, it's like the
Google deep research or
open AI research that
actually builds the thing
that you're researching,
where open AI
gives you, you know, 100
pages of stuff you have
to sort through, which
nobody reads. This
will actually execute,
build, test, deploy.
Also like a crazy
idea, because now there
is so many CROs, the
contract research
organizations.
organizations so you
can actually ask them
to do some kind of
lab tests and like
do like experiments
like this the same
way how you go for the
permits like it will
just contact the
the contractors and
they will just do like
physical things for
you but not for you but
for the LLM yeah well
anything capable of
interacting through
an MCP now we can
orchestrate as part of
a complex flow I'm doing
this as a single thread
which you're seeing
right now on the left
hand side. But what
I could do is I could
switch to the orchestrator
model and have
multiple threads that
do, as you point out,
multiple things. One
could be a project
manager, agile, and that
could just update the
Google Sheet as it
finishes different
processes. Another, I could
use, let's say, a Slack
channel, and maybe
it sends a note to
the folks in the team.
Oh, I guess I needed
to upgrade my gemini
model that's okay let's
switch let's switch
to it's not 3.7 but
i think you guys are
getting the idea all
right last thing i'm
going to do here quickly
one other example
create me a csv with
a list of the top um
agentic uh s this systems
and uh applications
and we'll switch to
the fire crawl I use 3
.7 as well why not and
let's see what give
me create me a csv cast
let's see what that
does so this is fire
crawl so fire crawl
basically is more of a
crawler elbow can search
as well but we'll see
if it if it figures
out how to do that
you know I'm running a
little longer guys I
apologize I'm gonna
try to wrap up here as
quick as I can so now
it's using the fire
crawl search it's
searching for top agent AI
systems and applications
with markdown and
let's see if it creates
the csv i'm just
messing around with it
yeah um while it's
running uh marco here um
i have a question
regarding the complexity
execution later on
because um i was last
time i mentioned it i
was using taskmaster
um to just figure
out how it would work
to let perplexity i
research tasks and
then basically let
Spark execute on those
subtasks and tasks.
And I figured out,
for me at least,
that the orchestrator
was not giving the
details needed for the
subsequent tasks.
So basically in the
end I had a bunch of
code which was not
working rather than
using Spark plainly.
Did you experience
the same thing with
the research modes
then later on to
execute basically what
was researched on?
You're likely not
doing the test-driven
development approach.
Did all your tests pass?
Or did it even
run any tests?
Yeah, actually, I
was even changing
the code mode a
little bit that
it actually writes
tests right away
after each subtask
or each task.
And I was not only
running the tasks, but I
was using Git as well
directly. so it was
basically creating a
branch merge that stuff
and then testing
everything so this was
basically working but
in the end still the
code was not really
usable yeah i'm not sure
i haven't had that
problem but hey yeah yeah
just one thing to add
because you mentioned
you were like asking
it to write tests
after that's not tdd the
test driven you write
the tests first and
then And so maybe you
should have different
modes for the code
to run the tests and
do the design and then
implement the code
that matches the tests.
Yeah, sorry, that
was my mistake.
I was creating first
a test and then
basically running
a redefine or
recoding based on
the test outputs.
Oh, you did. Okay,
yeah. Yeah, yeah.
I'm not sure.
Sometimes it has to
do with the structure
in which you
prompted originally.
you know this isn't
100% automated so if
you're striving for
100% you're never
going to get it I
would say this is more
like 80% automated
and once you sort of
find the flow it seems
to work pretty well
yeah actually maybe
you have an idea based
on that the actual
problem which I figured
out was that the
orchestrator was basically
executing the taskmaster
commands So basically,
it was telling the
coder what to basically
look on and which
next task the coder
should perform. And I
find that actually
the orchestrator was
not really giving the
right instructions to
the coder then. So it
was pointing to the
right task, but it
was missing a lot of
details the coder should
have been executing
on. How did you figure
that out, Marco?
The orchestrator
is writing a
subtask, right?
So it formulates
basically what the
coder should do.
So I've seen, I
compared that what the
orchestrator was actually
formalizing to the actual
MD file of the task.
And there were like
a lot of, maybe I was
designing it wrong.
Maybe I should have
just gave the coder the
plain MD file instead
of the orchestrator just
like doing and
handling the next task
execution. but yeah i've
seen like if it's more
complex if there's more
data the orchestrator
needs to deal with
it seemed that the
orchestrator is getting
like it it's just reducing
the information flow
to the to the other
sub um sub modes and
then crucial details
have been missing was
just my experience so
far and did you were
you able to uh improve
that through modification
of the custom
instructions um not
really so in the end i was
then getting back to
spark um plane mode
instead of taskmaster
itself yeah sure yeah i
i it depends i haven't
had any trouble but
but again i'm the guy
that created some some
things that i i take
sort of that might be
obvious for me might
not be as obvious for
others you know it's
how it's you know it's
one of those kind of
cognitive blind spot if
you will like you know
oh i forgot to explain
a step that i do
every time that i ever
thought to explain it
or something speaking as
a consumer of your
stuff reuben yes that is
a common thing i find
with your stuff man
yeah yeah i i i'm it's
it's it's hard to uh
it's it's hard to sort
of you know describe
the things that are in
my brain i don't know
but the you know
basically what what once
you get good at it and
it again the boat motor
sort of analogy once
you figure out how
to how to pull the boat
motor engine and get
it running and you know
the right questions
the right prompts and
the right structure i
have yet to find
anything i haven't been
able to build if you're
having trouble with it
building the wrong
things most likely it
has to do with the either
the planning or the
architecture phase that
isn't being defined
correctly once you've
got that then you've
got your sort of iterative
back and forth on
the tests, and it'll
build. And once the
tests are all 100%
passed, generally, there's
a bit of tweaking that
you need to do at the
end, but that's minor,
and it just works.
But yeah, it's not
like 100% hands-off.
but add if you add the
uh perplexity option
it it will solve
things like not knowing
the right api calls or
the the common like oh
i don't know how to
use the latest open ai
you know api right
because it wasn't trained
on it kind of kind
of issues so it'll
it'll definitely solve
that and you can also
use it as part of a
debugging mode so in in
the debugging mode you
can say you know if
the error happens more
than twice use perplexity
to go and research
these the solution
to the problem so you
don't get stuck in a
rabbit hole of trying
to solve the problem
that it takes 50 tries
to solve all right so
now you know here last
last thing I'll share
here's here's my list
of agentic you know
agents that it went
and found and it saved
it to a google sheet
which is kind of cool
so if you're if you're
looking for memory
use something like
google sheets it's cheap
easy and visible all
right we we've got
uh we got braun or
yeah ocean and braun uh
did i see Bron, do
we have Bron with us?
We'll go with Ocean.
Ocean's still
cleaning up all
of this stuff he's
trying to show. How
about Bron go first?
I can whip out
some stuff.
You need to talk
in third person.
Okay.
All right.
Let me share a
screen. Let me
see if I can get
that going here.
Okay, desktop
one, desktop two.
Let me drag
this window over
here. Make it
full screen.
I think this one,
let's see here, this
one, I don't tell
which one I want.
What are you
showing today, bro?
Let's see, am I
on this one here?
What do you guys
see? Yeah? Yeah.
Yes. Okay.
So yeah, like I
got this, I started
out making a run
-end for line it kind
of spiraled into
this app um so this
is like a sass app
like when you do um
brainstorming and
things like that
with um like you
know perplexity or
whatever you just
get text so i want
to make you know a
bunch of graphics
and front end for
that kind of stuff
um so this is a way
to use lm or agentic
backend to generate a
bunch of ideas a lot
of people struggle
like if you want ideas
you want them fast
you don't want to wait
for an hour all that
kind of stuff so you
start with the main
brainstorm front end uh
you can save you can
save your prompts you
got a prompt uh library
so you can use and
everything's got ai
enhancement so if you
make prompts you can
generate uh upgrades
with ai so you can do
i just did uh a hundred
ideas with gemini 2
.5 and the whole thing
uh only cost uh one
penny so when you're
doing you know
everything doesn't cost a
ton if you use lms they
can crank out a ton
of stuff for fractions
of a cent uh so you
know you can have
any idea i want uh i
don't know ideas oops
for my i don't know uh
garden store and
you can take the iii
enhancer it'll upgrade
this to more reasonable
uh approach for
brainstorming uh you can
do random ideas uh you
can do templates for
ideas you can pick
either the lion back end
or the open router
open router you can
pick from all the main
uh lms some of them
are better some of them
cost different amounts
but at a million
tokens they're really
cheap so I won't run
it right now but you
get the brainstorms so
once you've got these
these are saving into
super base back end
and you can for example
the lion one this
one will do more like
a light perplexity
kind of so you'll get
images the analysis.
I converted all
the references into
those sort of
super base icons.
And you get your
ideas. So this,
for every idea,
it'll generate
a graphic and
the content.
So this is
just six ideas.
And you can edit
all these. So if you
don't like these
ladies, so let's say, we
want to change that,
you can just edit it,
fire it into here,
upgrade it with AI,
and fire up an image,
so we got a new one.
So it's got backend
to generate images,
and once you get this
report, you can do
a slideshow or add
to favorites, export.
So I've got like,
what's a good
one? I probably
got the ice cream.
Let's see, ice
cream store i just
did a quick one
on this one so
slideshow will
show the full image
and then it'll fade
in the text so again
it's mostly visual based
like if you're trying
to come up with ideas
you don't want to
spend a ton of money
but you want to look
at more than just a
bunch of boring text
you can get sort of a
visual representation
um and then the reports
this will make a pdf
so if you're going to
uh like i can look at
i don't know a
consulting report so this
will generate text-based
sort of like pdf scroll
format for you so if
you want to give it
to someone you can do
this and then you can
pop it into print and
this will print out on
pdf it's another way
to sort of export with
graph everything's got
a graphic so uh then
once you do that um
you can this is just
image generator you can
generate images with
flux or unsplash is
like the search it's one
of the ways to keep
the cost down you can
just use real stock
images you only generate
with ai when you need
to um then i've got a
calendar so i kind
of try to just dump
ai into this wherever
i can so for this
i did uh google
calendar you'll get all
your events you can
delete them or add
them but you can do
a voice uh calendar
booking so i can say
it's like the 8th
i can say uh add a
booking for gentick
brainstorm meeting
on the 8th at 4 p.m
that's really neat
braun is there an area
tonight that i miss
it where you you can
upload uh reference
documents uh this is all
your initial prompt
so this is like right
now you can go to
deep research if you
want to get uh like
deep research but what
do you do before So
for example, I did a
hundred, I cranked out
a, this is just a one
shot, a hundred ideas,
right? So if I go,
uh, give me, uh,
innovative ways
generate income in
2025. I don't know
what I want. I just
want, I have no
clue what I'm doing.
Right. So this
will give you 100
ideas of how to
make money in 2025,
right? That's
with graphics.
So I can't do that
myself, but with AI,
like if you're going
to look at 100 ideas,
you want to look
at a wall of text
or you want to look
at it in a nice
graphical format,
right? It's a lot less
boring. um but you can
also do this like if
you want to feed
something into deep
research for example
uh what did i do market
opportunity i had
something for my
kid like a hockey
where is it i was like
uh oh there this was
a solana hackathon we
were gonna do right so
uh we were like what
are we gonna do for
the hackathon so nobody
knows so i did 20 ideas
for the hackathon uh
it also has a rankings
so like if you do a
brainstorm i don't know
let's find one here
um you know like this
ice cream i can rank it
so ranker will use ai
with prompts this one
is doing feasibility
impact innovation so
it'll go over your ideas
as like a first rough
round of okay what
did i make is it any
good should i bother
doing it it's to speed up
uh let's say sorting
and ranking all so
it'll go over score them
then it'll rank them
in order like one two
whatever this is three
so it's rank these
one two three and then
it'll give you all the
details of your rankings
so each ranking has
these criteria and
it'll show you exactly
why it ranked them out
of a hundred what score
it gave them so you
know if you do a hundred
you can get the ai
can be customized for
all that um and then
i'm like okay well how
am i gonna manage all
this so we can go to
the board so this is
like a clone of trello
pretty much trello charges
you for colors
backgrounds and all that
kind of stuff So I'm
like, okay, I don't need
to pay that. I can
just knock off Trello.
So you've got,
oops, I got my,
you can just change the
backgrounds to
anything you want.
Custom backgrounds.
It's got full colors,
any kind of gradient
color, solid colors.
And for these,
you know, you
can do drag and
drop. You can
move columns all
over the place.
You can mark them as
done. you can edit
them editing um
you can change the
background of each
card you can make tags
and priorities and
you can do comments uh
i like this one so we
can add these save it
you can change the format
so like if you want
to do text only you
can do cards show the
pictures or you can do
full cards so that'll
do the full content in
them different spacing
and you can have like
different boards you
want to have a regular
board you can you
can have any amount of
boards you want so and
if you want to call
them so you can enter
like a new basic
column or all of those
brainstorms you made you
can drag those in so if
i want to drag in the ice
cream store ad that'll
pull in that brainstorm
for those ice
creams and i'm just going
to add so this is all
like a full let's call
it ai trello board
you can generate
columns content graphics
everything with ai and
are you going to set it
up braun on the as a
individual user or the
agency levels yeah i
mean i have to add the
multi-user so um right
now uh it's just single
but then i gotta to
add the this all set
up for multi-user i
just haven't added it
yet so you can have
because most like if you
want to show ideas to
your buddies or you want
to have a couple
different people you got
to have the multi-user
makes it more complicated
of course but that
all the all the
security and privacy and
you know that's all done
on the back end i just
have to do the front
end um very nice i
have a question for you
bron um you know it's
very elaborate it's
awesome beautiful stuff
so there's obviously
the amount of time
taken to code it is one
thing but i'm actually
the the front end of it
right it's like how
much time did you spend
on the actual conceiving
the design of this
and then documenting
the design i mean i
doubt whether you just
sat down and just started
vibe coding right
you've spent a bunch of
time thinking about
this thing i pretty much
sat down and i mean like
i've been in software
and dev for 30 years
so um i again i just
started when i started
it i just was doing
this uh where am i
here i was just doing
this right so i wanted
to like uh lions got a
react back end like
ocean had the back end
but it's hard for people
to use it right because
it just it's all it's
like a platform but
it's not being used
so I'm like well what
how do I make a something
a lay person can
access it right so that's
where I started with
this but then once I
got the text it's just
again it's boring so
like okay you know add
pictures that I'm like
make cards so it just
sort of spiraled then
I'm like go let's get
reports uh let's let's
make a slideshow you
know ideally i'd like
to push this into
more like a gamma i don't
know if you know that
one like yeah i know
i know gamma pretty
well yeah yeah so that
like but this is more
like um how do you
take uh ai and you know
you it's it's all the
same like you get into
a database first of
all and then from there
it just shows you know
like sky's the limit
for what do you do with
your data you want to
make a slideshow you
want to make a trello
board you want to make
it a pdf report and
you know i even did
audio here somewhere like
if you got a brainstorm
where is here save
a bit of time for ocean
too brown if that's
okay yeah you ready to
go ocean there just a
quick note um i just
want a second brown like
i usually find myself
like don't even think
about ui i just may
ask a lamb to come up
with ui i just give it
a very general guidance
oh really yeah it's
very lms i think they
much better at front
end than that's like
like other things but
the front end is almost
zero like approaches
i mean i yeah some you
just give it a static
guidance or you kind
of give very general
because this one i would
call it like a dashboard
like admin dashboard
or like yeah so like
you didn't go into
lovable and map it map
out the ux and then
come back and then weave
it i would just Because
sometimes it comes
with wrong UX, I would
just say, this *****
when I redesigned it.
We'll have a coffee
and have a new year.
You guys are
awesome, man.
Nice work, Brian. Thanks,
Brian. This
looks beautiful.
Looks amazing.
And what coding
language did you use?
Like, what's the
platform? It's all front
-end, it's all TSX,
React, and the back-end,
because it was the
original line, it was
Python, so it's fast
API back-end. And
it's pretty much like
I got to thank Ruv
and all the other
guys, Brad, even you,
Rob. Like, I got my
first sort of AI gig
with these guys. So
because I was all I
used to be Lampstack,
WordPress, all that.
So it's kind of it's
all just spiraled.
Like the whole group
and Agendix.org has been
awesome because, you
know, I met Ocean
and all these guys.
everyone sort of like
contributed to pushing
me out of let's say
old school into 20th
century. Right. So.
Yes. Amazing.
You did. Yeah. I
think we're all
very proud to see
your, your abilities
blossom here.
This is, this is
really great work.
Nice.
We need to sign up. We
need to sign
up info, bro.
All right.
Awesome.
All right,
I'll share my screen.
Yeah,
hey, Ocean.
Yeah, Brian, can you
stop sharing? Yeah.
All right, so let
us get going here.
So I was just
fixing my rule modes
and the other
stuff, because I
was setting up
some tools as well.
So a little bit
background here.
so i was just
checking uh i was just
checking out my
repository organization so
basically this is
similar to roof spark
uh what i've been
doing it's a github
focused uh auto auto
development workflow
and i have been uh
using this and it's
super fun so what i've
been doing earlier
Let me terminate
this subtask,
cancel.
So what I'd ask the
orchestrator to do is,
given our entire
codebase, what to do next?
And then the orchestrator
in this, it will
start with coming up
with a bunch of issues.
So it just generated
the past five
issues. And so how
the situation works is
start to work on those
issues one by one,
plan them into
PRs, and then over
every single PR, there
will be automatic
quality assurance,
review, and eventually
a quality gate for
that specific PR.
what it come up with
you ended up having
every single PR very
well commented because
every single handoff
among different modes
there are templated
reports that they have
to give so for example
the reports are so
for example this is
one of the reports this
is a QA summary of one
of the research that
was done on the factory
store service so
for example and then
here's a bunch of other
ones so let's take a
look at how things are
spinning so i said
all of that and i say
and
we will be able to
see issues and things
pop up it's a lot more
fun if you leave it
overnight because then
you will start to see
it close like 12 issues,
20 issues overnight,
and they have a very
well-polished PR.
So that's basically
what I wanted
to show. And then
to augment it,
one problem that I find
all this integration
to have is it's
difficult for agents
to use. That is why
I kind of made a
command line interface
for them to interact
with various tools
and integrations.
So for example, I've
been using a command
line called kive
search, which I did.
So it allows you to
search things like
perplexity, AXA,
without using the MCP.
So the upside
of that, let's
see if it's functional.
Okay, that is not.
Is it using API
directly to perplexity
or is it scraping
perplexity?
It's just API directly
to perplexity underneath.
So the thing is,
the backend of it is
stateful. So you can
technically have like a
branch going on that
talks back and forth
with you, whoever is
asking that services.
So, for example,
there is this
perplexity search.
Like, I don't know
why I haven't set
up the environment
here yet. So there's
a search. You can
ask perplexity.
There's ask, where
you can just chat with
another LM. You can
choose which LM.
I mean, agent can choose
which LM they
want to talk to.
An agent can choose
to which branch
they talk to, to
continue talking with.
So that is what I'm
doing. And then to
integrate more features
down the road from
ask, that will be
to use memory tool.
It's just unfortunate
I didn't quite
finish to show the
whole thing today.
So you're using the
CLI instead of an MCP?
Basically, I
find MCP, if you
go look at a
system prompt,
like we have the,
so right now I have
the GitHub MCP open.
let's go take a look
at a system problem
it's so it's crazy
yeah well why not
just streamline so
stream no we're using
the sub subfolder
or using like where
does that come from
no i'm just telling you
right now like using
the mcp just with the
github and then you
get of you probably
get like 10 000 tokens
of instruction from
the github mcp alone
but for the different
detail modes for those
things I have a system
here I mean just
yeah you can you can
reset exactly you can
set your own modes
which will streamline
that yeah I said the
whole thing and then oh
the coolest idea about
all of this is not
the individual thing
that showed you showed
you it's about how
I orchestrate every
single most to work I
basically go to chapter
03 and i come up with
a golden path workflow
so every single path
each in each mode
is at that path so
um things are pretty
established it has to
go from implementer to
uh architect
researcher etc it
depends on the task
so ever so the most
important thing
here it really
is the whole
orchestration flow of.
Yes, this is, I
think this is the key
here, which is you
go from a golden path
and their rows. What
does each one do?
And then once they
finish doing that
thing, what to do
next and what is done.
So once you define
that, the whole
thing can get
autonomous very quickly.
It's just very
expensive to run.
Unfortunately, I
didn't quite finish the
whole thing to show
when it's running.
I was refactoring it.
It's probably a bad idea.
I'm not going to lie.
It is expensive to
run. And that's when
everyone likes to
complain. Like, you
know, the Spark is
super verbose and
takes forever and is,
you know. But the
reason it's expensive
is because it's extremely
detailed, right?
So it depends
what you're doing,
right? Yeah, you
can get the Honda.
But why not drive
the Ferrari?
It just depends on what
you're trying
to accomplish.
And if you don't
want it to be quite
so complex, don't
create as many plans,
right?
Exactly.
And then one thing
that I've been kind of
struggling is the amount
of paperwork that was
involved in between
all of the steps and
processes, which is
getting things to be
somewhat inefficient.
because there are too much
review, too much research,
too much planning,
and they ended up not
having enough concrete
of a plan and go
back and forth a bit
too much. So that is
another thing I'm trying
to find out about
to see how can I get
basically the process
to be more efficient. I
mean, I have a question
for you, Ocean, right?
That summary folder
that you had there with
all those 20 summaries,
but is the system
going to access and read
all of those summaries
as it as it processes
through its rules
and everything yes uh
so that is kind of like
an issue issue based
and pr based and then
so some of the deep
research come from other
sources like chat gpt
one thing i do is i
dump it there and i
just say uh look into it
read this five research
and then tell me
what really needs to be
done here and then you
do it and so it is
not reading those 50
research uh deep research
from open eye that
is way too long but it
is only looking at that
five and then it
generated the issues and
then the and then it
stopped looking at it
and then the next next
mode they only look at
the issue if they need
to refer back to the
research i mean the
information is there if
it feels like it needs
to it will go and
read it but it but from
the perspective of an
implementer it just
needs to know the plan
right if you really
want to go back you can
yeah keep in mind in
terms of cost like i
said the other day i
let mine run for roughly
12 hours and the
overall cost after 12
hours was 68 for 30 32
000 lines of code and
another 60 000 lines
of tests and markdown
so that was about 70
us um so you know it
it's it depends on
what you're doing and
whether or not you can
justify spending 70 to
buy code obviously
and letting it run for
12 hours but after 12
hours i built the entire
application the the
estimated value when
i ran scc against it
was something like 30
or 40 million dollars
in effort and several
years against like a
team of 20. If you're
on charging that 68
bucks to your customers
as a consultant,
that's totally doable.
Yeah. So I'm not
bragging that that was a
$25,000 project. And it
took me 12 hours. I'm
not charging based on
the amount of time it
takes me. I'm charging
based on the value
which you get from
leveraging what I'm doing.
So I'm straight up
telling them, look, I
built this last night.
And you're like, well,
I thought this was
going to take you three
months. Well, no, it
took me 12 hours and
this is how I did it.
And here's a video of
it doing it. So the
way you charge as a
consultant is shifting
from like an hourly sort
of, well, how much time
did it take you? But
the flip side of that
is obviously the value
proposition changes
dramatically. Now, if
they were to hire some
big consulting firm
to build what I built
for them, it would
have likely been million
bucks right easily so
you know the 25k they
spent for me is still
substantially less
than what it was going
to cost them otherwise
so everybody's happy
right sure yeah yeah
so that's um uh ocean
how how does the
context etc pass between
different orchestration
mode and MCP servers
I'm glad you asked
that is github so
every PR and every
issue there are detailed
comments and then all
of those reports the
purposes of them is to
serve as contacts for
task passing in so
like there were certain
issues orchestrator
research implementer
and there the quality
they say all of this
are trash go back and
do it again so the
next time around they
will have to read
through all those comments
changes before they
rework the second
thing so like uh and
then i i specify to say
if you want to uh you
basically just tell
them which issue to
look at uh here's the
file you need to read
here the stuff you
need to do it's just
like how i would tell
a human to do things
if they do not know
anything about anything
and then how to
reset the context
you just create
a new thread id
uh no that that is
the orchestrator that
that's the boom ramp
uh task because every
single boom ramp task
the subtask it is a
new context okay i see
okay that's so yeah
you just like from
the orchestrator it
just say you go read
this 10 issues in the
comments and then it
will put So it will
save it as part of
the input to the
implementer, and the
implementer can just use NCP
or Git and then grab
those information.
But you don't
control Boomerang
directly, right? It's
just part of Roo.
Oh, yeah, it is
part of Roo, but I
did decide on those
policies and rules
and then how the
orchestrator is
passing on all of
those instructions.
And then that is the
important thing is
Once you have
a system like
this, which part
is doing what and
how they're
working together.
And as the human, that's
all you need
to think about.
Once you sort that
out, you can ask
ChatGP to give
you the specific
rules to guide the
different modes.
And all that
orchestration or
orchestrator so
-called programming
is all through prompting?
Basically.
Okay. And do you refer
to, say, this is an
input as a set of file
as a set of folders
or that well this is
just the daru folder
this is just the
daru folder you can
have all the policies
you want underneath
when the boomerang
task is uh you know
you're moving from one
task to another you say
oh i've created this
context either in
the md files or this
10 summary files or
this research file
then you take the file
names or just give it
a folder say hey here
is a context read all
the md file and then
do your do your next
part that you are
supposed to do so
let's take a look at an
example so this is a
uh uh uh sorry so yeah
if people have time
can show an example uh
i'm yeah well i'm
i'm not sure if i
quite understand
the question you're
asking like You're
talking about
how do you orchestrate
subtasks or
how do you keep
the tasks on point?
What I'm trying
to ask is every
LLM call, what
context is passed?
For the orchestrator,
when it's
in orchestrator
mode, when it goes
to one of the
boom rank tasks,
and is it done through
the context, like
input output, like MCP
server? Or when it's
done through file, do
you give the file name?
Do you give the
folder name? because
everything is generated
dynamically i'm just
trying to get my head
around how the context
is there we go i haven't
communicated yeah
so this is a example
of what the implementer
or the orchestrator
ask the researcher to
do please research
and then here is the
context here's the
issue here is the readme
and here's the components
that you need to
read about and then
and then this and the
researcher probably did
uh yeah it did i think
i think jd what what
ocean and reuven are
saying is that
basically the system is
talking to itself you
don't tell it what to do
it tells itself what
you know you sort of
kind of tell it what
to do and the uh but
the or the orchestrator
is acting as a well
exactly as an orchestrator
and then it passes
the most important
parts of each step of
the subtask back so
when when the subtask
finish it gives you a
summary that summary
is then passed back
the orchestrator and
the orchestrator okay
here's all the important
parts of what happened
in the origin in
the sort of subtask so
it doesn't so if the
subtask doesn't need
all the context it
only needs what was
important from that then
it says okay now based
on my orchestration
i gotta go move on to
the next step test or
create new content
or whatever. And then
it passes that, the
orchestrator passes the
information to a subtask,
which then implements
that. And that
creates a more clean
context structure and
saves you money because
you're not using a
massive context window
and stuffing every
request with 200K or a
million tokens. It's
only using the parts
that are needed. And
that's more efficient.
And the orchestrator
will also not have
the whole context,
right? Because one of the
tasks that is done
that context was
established and done
and only the output of
that thing will be uh
moved back to orchestrator
for the next task
right yes so that's
why you kind of need
to like tell each
most specifically what
to give back to the
orchestrator i do i
do the opposite i did
that approach
generally get
brings you into
sort of the rabbit
hole problem
It does work sometimes,
but what I like to
do is a more sort of
declarative approach
to the development.
I'm giving it general
guidelines in terms
of the planning, the
structure, which is what
I refer to as my SPARC
approach. And what I'm
not doing is explicitly
saying how to solve
the problem. I'm
saying here's generally
how to think about a
problem, and here's a
methodology that you
want to sort of guide
you through the problem
solving, like test
-driven development,
the London school,
whatever. and and don't
and continue until
you're done but what i'm
not saying is explicitly
you know the the
steps to solve it right
i'm basically saying
here here's the input
my prompt create me
a cure to cancer go
find figure out the the
optimal way to the
cure cancer and then
create an algorithm that
that that proves that
it's possible with
100 coherence and then
when once you've got
the coherence, you
know, you're done. And
that process could take
hours or days or
whatever. But in between
A and Z, it's figuring
it all out itself.
Is the scope, I mean,
I feel like, you
know, in months
prior, the scope size
mattered. It was much
more about like having
smaller pieces. Has
that now changed with
this latest kind of
version of Spark?
Or like, do you feel
like now it really can
be as broad as you
want to could you build
a you know a you know
300 000 line platform
and oh yeah just so
if i do without issue
what what you're what
you're not going to do
what you're not going
to do is all 300 000
lines at once you
you'll you what you're
doing is you break in
the phases and you say
build me phase one
build and then when once
phase one all tests
pass you're good you
review it then you move
on to phase two now
phase one could take
you 12 hours. But what
you're not going to
do is say, build me
phases one through 50
all at once and let me
know in a week when
you're done. That's just
silly and it's not
going to work that way.
So you're doing
narrow phases
that break into
multiple parts.
Let me interrupt just
a sec. So we were just
looking at the researchers
doing its thing.
And then all of
those contacts that
research just did right
now after the task is
done are lost. but
all the thing that the
researcher is giving
back to the orchestrator
is the text completion
message and then
that that's all this
yeah that's all it sees
but did it create any
md files and md any
summary docs yeah yeah
it did all it's it
did its very thing and
then say i'm done here
is what i did all
right yeah that's cool
yeah nice nice work ocean
it's looking looking
amazing i love
watching how others are
sort of modifying the
concept. This is really
exciting. I think the
takeaway from what
I've watched you and
Bron and others do
today is maybe we need
like a light version,
like a more streamlined
version that's not
so in depth, right?
And a lot of what
I'm doing is like super
optimized for like
just deep, you know,
analysis and completions.
And what you guys
are showing me is
like maybe we need
like a middle ground or
a lighter version
that skips a lot of
that sort of upfront
heavy analysis and just
gets to the point and
implements whatever
it needs to do without
having you know
12 000 lines of or yeah
12 000 lines of mds
when and only 3 000
lines of code or
something i agree like
current approach i
have is a little bit
too heavy-handed in
terms of the process,
process of paperwork.
I do agree that there
needs to be some
kind of more autonomy
that we should give
to agents in a way.
Like all those record
keeping is how we're
trying to keep track
and how we observe
into the process
and system. But what
if this observability
is actually hindering
the effectiveness
of the system? So I
think that is a trade
-off that we're still
actively exploring
yeah no that makes
makes a lot of sense
all right we're almost
out of time anyone
anything anyone's to
discuss show tell promote
whatever i got a quick
question about your
spock mode binary that
you did that like is
it it does a configuration
creates all the
configuration files
and all that yeah it's
an mpx um mpx are pretty
cool by the way it's
all open source you
can go to ruve uh dash
dev if you want to see
how it built it is it
just is it just do
the kind of config is
that all it does it
creates the rumors and the
profiles and is that
all it does it well
it's also not to belittle
it not to belittle
it i just know there's
there's there's you
can belittle all you
want it's uh it's it's a
cli so and there's a and
i've included several
easter eggs for those
who are who want to
discover because i
created it on easter um
and so it can help
configure mcps there's a
wizard there's all
kinds of little things
in there as well but
basically yeah this is
the the thing i run when
i start a new so i've
got a dev container
every time i start a
new project it auto
installs that and that's
my running start now
i've got i've got a
private version i use
with all my with all my
envs and whatnot included
but basically i'm
just giving giving you
guys the same general
approach that i start
with um and then when
i'm done a project for
a client i customize
there you see there's
a tutorial option i
change that and i update
the tutorial mode to
be specific to the
repo and whatever the
heck i built for my
client and then you know
whenever developers are
using it all they need
to do is pop in the
tutorial mode and say
what the heck did
root build right okay
got it yeah yeah i
just wasn't sure yeah
the mpx is a really
useful. Like if you're
doing, if you're
going to do any MCPs,
you know, set
them up as, as, as
MPXs and you're,
and you're, you're
out quick and
off to the races.
The, the other thing
I would suggest, you
know, if you're looking
at, uh, you know, if
you don't want MCPs and
MCPs can be a bit of
a pain, if anyone's
played with them, you
can, there's a command
option in Rue that
allows you to do almost
all the same things you
do with MCPs from the
terminal. And I think
Ocean might show you
some of that as well
and that's way simpler
anything that exists
as a cli is now capable
of running so it's
it's easy it's quick
and doesn't require any
mcp right that's quite
neat there's a couple
couple elements through
for announcements
for next week um i got
uh my internet dropped
me there for a moment
i was just going to
throw it on the table
that maybe if there
was a standing project
like just a project
suggestion and anybody
who wanted to try their
specific configuration
could duplicate that
one project and then
share the metrics we
sort of track what
that optimal you know
combination of files
modes custom instructions
et cetera setup actually
is you know what's
the most efficient
with the nicest front
end et cetera et
cetera i want to do a
weekly bake-off we
could do a weekly bake
-off man and see who
hits the leaderboard
as we had a leaderboard
discussion today
on uh who has the best
implementation right
and a genetics benchmark
for food for thought
food for thought is
where i hear i hear
the term soda you know
flying around a lot
so uh guys i just
want to share with you
the Toronto GenX meetup
next Tuesday, May 6th.
So that's, we're all
getting together with
Reuben downtown. It's
225 Wellington Street
West. It'll be the
first in-person
gathering, so it should
be a lot of fun. We're
going to go through
all this kind of stuff.
We've got, I
think there is
so far 28 folks
registered.
Yeah, 225 Wellington
Street West, 6.30 p.m.
through until 8 p
.m., so we'll take
90 minutes there
It's a nice location.
It's our friends
at Tribal Cafe.
Right, Brad, who
are hosting us?
Yeah, shout out
to Tribal Scale
for setting
everything up.
I'll be there early
if anyone wants
to come early.
It starts at 6
.30. I'll be there
most of the day.
And that is, I'm
just going to share
the link to the
event in the chat.
There it is.
That's the first of
many, many, many.
all around the
world Bansi,
Mondweep are getting
things ready in
London we've got
Columbus, Ohio
Denver, all over the
place Singapore, a
bunch of those so really
exciting so I hope
everybody that's in the
GTR or Southern Ontario
or traveling through
can come out next
to Zubin great to meet
you all face to face
yep yeah well
thanks everyone and
thanks for everyone
who presented
Ocean, Braun
Robert, Brad.
It looks really good.
Really good work
you guys are doing.
I'm impressed.
It's cool, cool stuff.
Ruf, can you hear
me? My microphone may
be playing up today.
But, you know, this idea
about the
lighter version,
I think if we can convert
it to some kind of
spark foundations,
right? So anyone coming
in new goes through
that example to get the
initial kind of commonalities
well understood.
so so they create
something meaningful
from their own ideation
right so where i like
which is kind of i
guess if we can think
through something like
that that would make it
the learning journey for
many kind of smoother
and then it could be
what you are doing
really super advanced
or at that level right
so probably there are
steps in between this
adoption journey that's
just my thought here
something we because
when we when we organize
this event like i
think what would be
ideal i was thinking
like when everyone comes
they comes with a
laptop and they say hey
you need to get these
subscriptions of these
uh the open ai etc and
then let's get started
three hours we go
through the process and
after the three hours
they have created
something from their idea
through that process.
So that's like
a, okay, you're
Spark Foundation
certified now.
That's awesome.
I like it. I don't
know how to do
that, but I think
it's a great idea.
And this is something
that was brought up a
lot and we need possibly
to make a simple
entry point so you
don't start where I am
after several years of
learning and iterating
through the process.
We need like some kind
of like okay i want to
get going but i don't
want i'm not necessarily
like an expert
and not everyone should
be an expert right
at least you can't start
where you finish or
whatever the analogy
is so what you're
suggesting if i understand
is like a beginner
mode like i just spent
an hour i can get the
thing running i can i
can vibe code without
getting spaghetti and
now i'm ready for step
two exactly and the
journey from there on
which will which will
evolve as we go along
but that's the
starting point yes that
might be a good project
for for chris chris
you're kind of going
through that process right
yeah i kind of figured
it out right and
your modes like you
don't need to change
anything right you just
need to explain better
how to use it um so
just basically starting
with like a structure
or a framework just
vibing out the base
code and like tell tell
basically tell it to
do just that right and
maybe you don't really
need to do like a
whole lot of testing
just get the structure
get the framework built
and then once that's
set up then throw
all your files into a
single document and then
feed it to like gemini
or something the entire
context of everything
you just created and
then i had it build
me a plan of just
tests right with phases
and tasks and all it
was was tests and then
with the entire context
of everything it
built i told it to
make it so that once it
passes all the tests
then the plan would be
fully operational and
i put that into play
turned it on went to
sleep woke up everything
worked perfectly so
that that was the
strategy i went through
was just create the
structure create the
framework essentially just
vibe out what you
want and then have an
entire plan strictly
dedicated to only testing
and then getting it
all working and what
what you guys recommend
for that initial
scaffolding um like for
a beginner versus an
advanced or are you
using stuff like to get
things going or you're
starting from um like
some kind of told it
to build an interface
it it made the
decision for me yeah
so i i tell you my
experience i actually
leverage i was trying
to do you know implement
all of reuven stuff
i found it a little
complicated and and
difficult to follow So
then I connected with
Chris, and Chris helped
me out. So I leveraged
both of those two
guys to figure out and
actually get up and
running. So the
experience from nothing
was a little tough.
I mean, I'm a product
guy, a product manager.
I run product management
teams, but I can
code relatively well.
And even still, it was
difficult to get up
and running from
nothing with this whole
Spark, Sapo stuff. it's
like really i found
it quite a little
quite difficult but
between both chris and
reuven i managed to
figure it out but it
took me about four
weeks to really get
it clicking in my mind
yesterday i just had
my took my co-founder
through setting him up
uh on his cursor system
and it it was really
educational for me
to help somebody else
do it um and it was way
smoother and i knew
all the tricks and i
could help him do it
really quickly uh instead
of taking like three
four weeks it only
took me like four hours
um but still it's pretty
tough your journey
right we need if you
could document that
journey that's a great
personality i have a lot
of documents what did
you go through right
and that i think is
foundations that's
exactly what is spark
foundation so if you
have and i have been that
some of that journey
myself but if some of
us who are at that
spectrum could probably
collaborate to document
that to say right this
is how we went about
and then let's replay
it on a few others to
validate whether that
works cool all right
i'll see if i can i'll
see if i can document it
all right i appreciate
i appreciate all you
guys this is this
is a great idea i get
i get a jump i get
another call i get a prep
for um thank you until
next week yeah and
and if anyone's in
toronto and they want to
come out you know feel
free to join us downtown
uh next week and
if you want to do this
in some other location
let us know we're we're
excited to to make
this happen you know
and yeah aloha from
hawaii las vegas san
francisco uh you know
wherever we we've got
people how many i don't
know how many countries
i don't even know if
the number is a lot
so it's it's this is
this is great i love
doing this obviously every
every weekend is is
is a is ending the
week with this is just
amazing it's a good it's
a good vibe and rob
as always thank you
for helping organize
this you you keep this
thing moving forward so
thanks for for making
that happen and uh and
and uh till next time
thanks everybody bye
bye good weekend bye