And then we have
Dami as well.
And Dami's put
together really a quite
remarkable front-end
design tool. So it should
be fun to see. And
the neat thing about
that is that we met
Dami at the first
ever in-person Toronto
meetups on Tuesday.
Yeah, that was great fun.
Yeah, that was great.
So a little irony in
that whole thing, right?
We did it at a large
software development
company. I don't know
if they knew what
they were signing up
for when they invited
us to use their space.
But thank you to
Tribal Scale for
letting us use their
space in Toronto.
They're right
downtown near the
Blue Jays, you know,
where they play.
So, yeah, it was
a nice turnout.
It wasn't huge, but
to be honest, I'd
rather have a
smaller, more targeted
crew than some crazy
big thing, which
I think we're
planning for next
month. That's something
bigger, right?
Yeah, that's right. So
first Tuesday of every
month, we'll do the
meetups and, you know,
everybody's welcome and
not overly structured.
But then we do have
an event that's lining
up for Toronto Tech
Week towards the end
of June as well. So
very excited about that.
And then I should
mention, Brad wanted
to take a few
moments before we get
started just to bring
us up to speed on
everything with the
Eugenics Foundation.
if that's okay roof
brad are you there
well yeah just just as
well while we figure
while we figure out
where brad is um you
know we've been getting
a ton of interest
in these meetups and
we've got one happening
in about a week two
weeks week i don't
know in london um and
events is is helping
organize that lots lots
of excitement around
that uh some folks
reached out to yesterday
about dubai and i
think we might that
looks like that probably
will happen here in
the next few weeks as
well we've got tokyo
a whole variety of
locations all over the
world coming together
so um that that's we we
had our sort of kickoff
for our ambassadors
last night at uh what
was that eight o'clock
eastern and and
appreciate everyone who
dialed in i think the
folks in sweden where
was it three o'clock in
the morning or something
three o'clock in the
morning from sweden
that's right robert
and then And we had, I
think it was Mark from
New Zealand as well.
Yeah.
There's a suite of
meetups, live events
that are going to be
taking place through
the Kill Network
with Alex Gross
right across the Midwest
as well. So, yeah,
there's a lot of
activity happening.
Yeah, for sure. And
it's exciting to see all
the interest. And
we're also, and I don't
want to be unsolicited
for sponsorship, but
there's a number of
different organizations
and companies that are
interested in helping
sponsor our efforts.
And I'm going to say
this. I think I
would prefer if our
organization was sponsored
by a bunch of big
companies rather than
having to sort of depend
on smaller membership
fees. But for now,
we're membership
orientated because that's
easy. And I really
appreciate everyone who's
signed up on the Egentix
.org site, even with
the hiccups when it
comes to how it works.
You're keeping
the lights on and
helping us sort
of get this thing
moving forward. So
thanks for that.
Did we find
Brad or are we
going to push
that in later?
Brad's here.
I'm here.
Sorry, I was a couple
of minutes late.
Hey, Brad.
Hey, did you have a
question for me or do I
get it? just uh have
you had a few updates
that you mentioned that
you wanted to cover
oh yeah yeah just uh
i just uh wanted to
thank everyone um uh
coming out um i don't
have the exact numbers
in front of me but uh
yeah membership has
been been growing uh
we've been um talking
with the committee so
we we are now getting
a plan and we're moving
forward on the
financial aspect so so
thank you very much
to everyone we've just
mentioned for keeping
the lights on now we're
actually using this
for for best practices
uh i won't keep much
but uh our membership
is is still growing we
have we're approaching
the thousand people
that are registered
on the agentix.org and
there there will be
some work done on the
agentix.org website
forthcoming and i'll
i'll update that later
and uh last thing just
wanted to thank people
we did a slow code
session yesterday and
it looks like there
was some really good
interest to to help bring
education for people
that um a little bit
more step by step
so we did a pair
programming uh with a lot
of people here in that
are in this room helped
out yesterday to to
participate and the
advisors while i typed
on the screen so it
looks like we'll be
continuing something like
that and i'll give
more details later on
and there's a video
for that somewhere i
hear where can people
see that i just got the
i just got the video
downloaded and i'll
be uploading it to
youtube and i'll i'll talk
to so here so here um
if he's on the call
for for putting on
cultira but also on the
agentics uh youtube
site so the the video
is forthcoming i'll
put in the chat the we
ended up creating a
starter pack that includes
um root code and uh
spark by by Reuven.
So we actually
created a starter pack
that people are
available to use. It has
all the tools in
there. There's an
instruction guide,
step-by-step guide in
PowerPoint format.
There's a starter pack
for some of your
first prompts and
the link to the
video will also be in
there. So I'll put
that in the chat here.
Nice.
It's pretty rewarding
to see all the adoption
around sort of the
approach that we've
taken to orchestration
and the adoption
of Roo has kind of
gone through the roof.
You know, over the
last couple of weeks,
I don't have the
exact numbers, but I'm
well over several thousand
daily installations
of create.dashspark,
which is only
essentially used within
Roo. So if that's
any indication of
the adoption of their
platform, it would
appear to be substantial.
And I think the only
way you even discover
that is if you go,
well, you know,
you're one of us, or you
go to their community
page in their
documentation. So, you
know, indirectly,
it would appear that
they're doing well.
And if you look at Open
Router, I think
they're the number one
project now on Open
Router. So I think
we, you know, we now
have a couple of claims
to fame. I'm going to
brag. We discovered
Lovable. I think
we were the first.
GPT engineer, that's
right. Yeah,
GPT engineer.
So, you know, I
think when it was
just, you know,
two guys in Sweden.
So I think what
we should do now
that I'm thinking
of it, we should
probably start like
a venture fund and
put some money in
these companies.
Yeah, each one.
Yeah, I'm pretty
sure Requesti is
going to be the next
big company and,
you know, Rue and
so on. So anyway.
Osplix as well.
Osplix, yeah, they raised
$7 million, I hear.
So for securities,
that's pretty exciting
too for them. yeah
like there's and that's
actually an idea that
I was pondering the
other day and this is
something Nick and a
few others we've been
talking about it's
like you know a lot
of these startups that
you're seeing and I'm
a bit of a **** it's
like I can like recreate
half these Y Combinator
startups in like 20
minutes but it makes
you think you don't
necessarily have to
be like you don't hit
a home run anymore you
really just need to
be a bit faster a bit
more agile than the
competitor or literally
just recreate someone
else's successful SaaS
company and make it
cheaper, faster, and
better slightly, right?
So lots of opportunities
in the space, for
sure. If you know
what you're doing and
you can move quickly.
That was one of
the topics I guess
we had on Tuesday
night was the
idea of a zero
-person startup,
right? The idea
that you could build
these companies
with no people.
So anyway,
interesting times.
I'm going to go quickly.
few days but i want to
show you a couple new
features that i found
really interesting
um and and we'll we'll
take it from there
so one of the most
interesting things i've
discovered this this came
out i think yesterday
oh is that a question
no okay so um if
in chat gpt there's a
new feature that allows
you to go here and uh
if you go here deep
research and you'll
see here that there's
now an option that
allows you to connect
your GitHub repos as part
of the deep research.
So the default option
was web, right? So
you use deep research,
you would go and
search the web. Now you
can go and add a repo.
So if I type in, I
don't know, what's A2A,
I think it was my,
what was it? A2A MCP?
Oh, of course.
This is like literally
like, this is like a
perfect example. If
I'm going to do a demo,
there's going to be
a giant doesn't work.
Let's, this isn't
mine. I didn't build
chat GPT, but
let's, let's, let's
try one more time.
And I kind of
thought it was going
to break. So I went
and went Betty
Crocker beforehand.
Let's see here.
Let's try one more time.
This was searching,
searching, A2A.
Okay. So as you guys
know, I've got a ton
of repos and a lot of
my repos that, you
know, I build and forget
about, but this
one's an interesting
one. So let's go here
and I'm going to say,
oh, I got two repos
selected. I didn't
know I could do that.
All right. I'm going
to disable this one
and I'm going to go
here and And I'm going
to say, give me a
Python implementation
of the A2A platform.
So A2AMCP was a
platform I built that
basically integrated
both A2AMCP.
It basically allows
you to create agents
that combine the
two specifications.
So in this case,
I'm just going to
basically go and tell
it to go research
that. So it's using
deep research. This
will take a while.
so we're probably
gonna have to come
back to it later but
um let's just say
i'm going to use uv
and i don't know
if it searches
the web so i'm
going to go here
and i'm going to
suggest that use
a v fast enable web
search as well uh don't
you think i'm able to
enable them both no
is it both enable i
can't tell yeah so yeah
nicholas nicholas uh
how do you say his
last name chelaine just
demoed this for his
ask sage platform as
if it was the first to
ever do it but uh
yeah you can enable on
rag um deep research and
web as well yeah yeah
yeah so we've been
sourced and client and
you could technically
i'm curious how this
is different than
what we do already in
client and rue though
so if we're connected
it's it's it's cheaper
so the well i guess
i'm spending 200 bucks
a month so it's cheaper
in some weird other
way but basically
it's included it's
included in the credits
you get for using so if
you're paying the $20
a month plan then
you're not using the API
plan like you can use
it through this now
is what you're saying
I follow now so we're
accessible to more
people I guess exactly
give me the full
implementation
as a phase
series of steps i don't
know yeah be complete
yeah it's very
similar to what we do
right with rue or
incline yeah exactly it's
it's it's very deep
research but i found it
i found it interesting
all right so i'm
gonna let that bake for
a while the other one
i had here where is
where did i do it um
i think i did last
night oh here we go i i
went and you know did
this last night just
to see so in this
case what I did is I
pointed it at my my
version of windsurf which
is my sort of integrated
vs code clone and
then I pointed it at
that repo and then
and basically as I said
optimize and fix my
windows build which
has been giving me some
trouble and then it
went ahead and told
me all the things I
need to do to fix it now
at this point all I
really need to do to
fix my build hopefully
is copy and paste
this and tell Roo to
go implement it so So
it's, you know, it's
an interesting feature.
There's also another
feature that I
want to show you
guys, which was
kind of cool that
came out yesterday.
And if anyone's actually,
I've been struggling
to get it to work.
I don't know if, I
don't, and I've,
everyone I've talked to,
no one can get it to
work, but hypothetically,
it's a really cool,
interesting idea.
So I created
an MCP for it.
All right. So first
and foremost, I like
creating MCPs for stuff,
as you, as you guys,
you know. So here's
some of my MCPs, I get
my Firecrawl, my Man,
my Superbase. And then
I created an MCP
template. I've been using
Fast MCP. It's great.
It's quick. It's easy.
You can basically use
any Python library.
If you want to use
something like LineAGI
or whatever, you can
basically just slap
a Fast MCP include
on it. And it takes
any Python application
and makes it MCP.
So based on that
concept, I'm like, all
right. why don't I
use the brand new fine
-tuning capability that
just came out from
the folks at OpenAI,
I think, yesterday. So
they just released a
new feature. Let me
find that in my other
window. Yeah, that's
really cool, the fine
-tuning feature. Yeah,
and this fine-tuning,
let me fine-tuning.
It's called reinforcement
fine-tuning,
and I'm going to
drag this over.
The reinforcement
fine-tuning
uses a self-reflection.
Oh, where the heck
did my screen go?
Sorry, guys.
Fine tuning.
Enforcement fine tuning.
Sorry, I've got
too many screens
open, and it
just disappeared
when I tried to
drag it over.
All right, second time's
the charm, I think.
All right, so let me
try to explain this
best I can. This is
failing at the moment,
and I wasn't sure why
it's failing, but I'll
figure it out eventually.
But basically,
if you go in, I'm
going to show you the
Playground first. And
basically, I created an
MCP version because
I was struggling with
it. But basically, you've
got a couple different
options now. But
you've got supervised,
you've got direct
preference optimization,
and reinforcement
fine-tuning. The
reinforcement fine-tuning
uses the O4 Mini model.
And as far as I can
tell, at least according
to OpenAI, if you use
this, you can fine
-tune it on specific
tasks. Like, let's say
you're creating a
legal analyzer or a
security analyzer or a
pharmaceutical system
or something. You can
go in here and then
you can upload training
data. The training
data is in JSONL format,
you know, and then
you can choose, you
know, existing files.
You can browse the
files you already have.
I've uploaded some files.
Then you can define
the schemas. schemas
like and to be honest
i wasn't exactly
sure what to put in
this or what the correct
uh you know reasoning
efforts are and
and what the different
batch sizes are
because they didn't
do a particularly good
job of actually you
know giving you guidance
if you look at
their documentation
it's basically their
documentation it is is
it's likely not
going to work is what
they say which is, I
don't often see that.
Yeah, here it is.
It's basically
saying that there's
a good chance that
this isn't going
to work for you,
which is a weird
thing to put in
your documentation.
Where does it say that?
Where is it? Yeah,
it is. Reinforcing is
a complex process with
many moving parts.
This is the polite way
of saying it's hard
to use, which it is.
So if anyone figures
out exactly how to get
the work i i let me
know but group challenge
yeah and but here's
the craziest part it
was easier to create the
mcp for it which is
what you see here than
it was to actually
implement on their website
so that's why i went
these are cake now
yeah so so what it is
i created an mcp so
the first thing i did
here is i created the
generic mcp so this
is an mcp for npm this
is my fine tuning MCP.
And then I created a
sort of, you know, sample
MCP. So this sample
MCP is what I was
showing you a moment ago.
And that so it's
kind of a three step
process. So once once I
had my sort of fat, you
know, my example,
hello world template
working and goodbye,
then I took that and
basically duplicated and
then I got and then I
created the the actual
implementation of the
fine tuning and we can
go in here and i can
do i can choose uh run
the fine tuning mcp
something like that
but again it's pretty
cool it's it i for
for complicated things
craig and mcp
abstraction is like
basically the best
possible way so what i was
thinking of doing next
is i might i might
go back to some my
old projects like
that quantum computing
thing i built a
couple months ago in
the genomic system. And
maybe I'll slap an
MCP on top and just
let the thing kind of
iterate on it for a
while and see what
it can come up with.
So you can see
it's listing
the fine tuning models.
So these are my
different models.
And then it'll
go, once it sees
the models, it
goes further.
It's going to
list the jobs.
You're going to
see a bunch of
failed jobs because
I've been struggling
to get that last
one to work.
So the kind of irony
is it was again easier
to build the mcp than
it was to actually
get the **** thing working
here's the training
data so now it's
creating its own so
what's cool about the
training data is i can
use my other mcps like
perplexity and fire
crawl and other things
and then scrape the
internet and and have
it auto train now the
the the most important
thing and i'm jumping
around a little bit
here what is is when
looking at this
reinforcement system the
reinforcement fine
-tuning basically means
that it creates an
iterative sort of reasoning
based approach to the
creation evaluation
optimization of a
language model so if i
want to like hyper
optimize the language
model specifically for
coding or or within ru
or klein i'm going
to show you the last
thing you can you can
create that model then
in your settings in
right here you can you
can choose different
you know you can create
different profiles.
So in this case, what
I did is I created a
OpenAI custom model.
So in the OpenAI
custom models,
give it a sec to,
well, is that,
let's, is it OpenAI?
Not loading, there we
go. Okay. So you've
got the option for
an API provider.
You can choose the
API provider, then you
can choose your base
URL, which is api.openai
.comv1, put in your key,
then you put in the
name of your actual
model that you've trained
so in this case i i'm
what i'm trying to
do is essentially
rather than having this
folder full of rules
that you see here i think
i can make a model that
basically is trained
on all these rules
and then i can get rid
of all those rules oh
right and then it'll
know exactly how to
handle the inserts and the
file operations And
now the benefit of that
is I can use the O4
mini model, which is
way cheaper and has a
million context window.
And so that gives
me, you know, I think
it's like half the
price of Sonnet.
And it's got five
times the context.
That's my plan. I'm done.
Why don't limit
yourself to open AI
models when you could
potentially use a
DeepSeek model or a
Quen model and fine
tune? Well, DeepSeq
is loaded with
malware, which I
don't like for coding.
Well, yeah, I
figured out how
to get rid of
it, you know, but
it still has
issues for coding.
And it's not
particularly well
suited for, you know,
it's a reasoning
model. So it's
not particularly
well suited for
the implementation.
It was easy. It's new.
I just was curious.
And to be honest,
my customers are
all large enterprises,
right? They're
not going to use
some Chinese thing.
Not a chance.
They sound like a source
for enterprise
sponsorship.
DeepSeek is that
feature specific to
OpenAI, though. So
it's not something that
you can actually
apply DeepSeek to yet.
You can. Remember that
strawberry pie project?
Maybe you don't
remember it, but last
summer I created a reasoning
and training system
for the PHY model
that basically allows
you to create reasoning
models on any small
language model like PHY.
Yeah, that's a thing.
Yeah. But what I'm
saying is what was
released recently, what
you just demonstrated,
that's an open AI
specific platform feature.
In Azure. Yeah, both.
So basically
any Fortune 500
company is
using Microsoft.
So for me, I show up and
it's some giant
corporation.
If I suggest Mistral
or DeepSeek, they're
going to say.
Right, but what he's
asking is why can't,
I think what he's
asking, right,
and what I'm, if I
understand you correctly,
correct me if I'm
wrong, is he's
asking, why don't you
use DeepSeq instead
of GPT-4 or Mini?
And the reason
is because that's
the only model
that OpenAI
will allow you
to fine-tune.
You can't put DeepSeq,
unless you use an
alternative solution,
which is what Rube
has described,
it's because your
restraint is the OpenAI
platform. They're only
allowing you to fine
-tune that model.
I believe they may
allow you to fine-tune
O3 models. oh you can
you can you can you
can you can fine tune
a whole bunch of models
now uh you can only
use one model for the
reinforcement here let
me start guys that's
what i mean to say
is the reinforcement
feature you just demonstrated
is only available
on a single model
it's four mini or yeah
and they're they're
currently the only
ones that yeah they're
currently the only ones
allow you to do it
this easily yeah your
base model cannot be
different like you the
next drop down right
there base model let's
see what they give
you there those ones
so i can i can Your
basic model is only
available from OpenAI.
It can't be DeepSeek, and
it's only that
particular model until
OpenAI chooses to give
us more models, right?
Yes. So here's the
trick, as far as I can
tell. So the
reinforcement fine-tuning,
which is cool, but
ridiculously complicated,
you can do your own
reinforcement, but this
is basically automated
reinforcement.
It means they're using
basically the same
techniques that they
do for like deep
research or whatever to
do the reinforcement.
The supervised,
yeah, that came out
yesterday. The
supervised, I think
also made it came
out yesterday.
Yeah, well, they
made an update on it
yesterday. But this
allows you to choose other
models. But because
you can integrate it as
an MCP, you can do
the same reinforcement
using the MCP flow
in root code and get
basically the same
result. And it's cheaper.
So you can do these.
Now, if you really want
to do it with your
own, like a DeepSeq or
Mistral or something,
there's a bunch of
different ways you can
train your own models.
It's just more costly.
You get to GPUs.
So if you fine-tune
that model, does
that then get associated
with your OpenAI
account and only you
access it, right?
Correct. So you see,
you see these names
like when, so these
are the different
models that I, I know
if I want that, if
I want to use one
of these models, I
basically use that
model name in what I
showed you in that
last screen right here.
Yeah, right, right
here. And I'm putting
that model name in.
So this, this would be
a GPT-40 model I trained
a while back, that
kind of thing. Unless
I'm mistaken, though,
I think there's some
idea that they're
going to allow us to
share these, these fine
-tuned models with the
rest of the community
as well. yeah that's
kind of where i
was going here is like
for now it's just you
and your your open ai
account i can't use
it i can't see it i'm
only you right but
that's okay and they're
hosting it for you
in their virtual
environment and your virtual
account environment
and and it's not
cheap so uh to train i
trained a agentic model
the other day and it
was like 500 bucks
oh man that's that is
painful but no it's
not painful the same i
i that that same model
that cost me 500 was
50 000 last summer and
i was bragging about
it being 50 000 and
the summer before that
it was 5 million or
probably 50 million yeah
i know i know the the
numbers man i yeah so
we've 500 is good but
i don't want to be
dropping 500 we we've so
in two years we've
gone from probably
somewhere between 50
million to 500 for the same
exact job yeah what's
that three orders of
magnitude for yes so
so it all depends on
what you're trying to
do like like 500 if
you're like some giant
company is nothing right
that's like less than
an hour of my time
it's it all it's all
relative i guess but you
can do some really cool
stuff with it could
you uh throw the
strawberry fi into an mcp
yeah that's what this
is so anything can be
anything can be an
mcp guys anything like
yeah i know but i'm
specifically just my my
point is more about
the strawberry fi that
is exactly so i didn't
call it strawberry
fi because i didn't
brand it but that is
exactly what this is
yes it's preparing the
training data you can
it automatically uploads
the data it fine
tunes, it handles the
job, it gets the tuning
metrics, and then it
recursively improve
it over time. So I can
just let this run
overnight. It can fix,
optimize, and then
eventually over several
hours. And then I
benchmark it. And then I
can look at the state
of the art for the
given thing I'm trying
to solve. And then I
can meet that criteria.
And it just does it.
I can set it and forget
it which is the the
best part of it magic
no no no gpus to worry
about just it just
kind of magically works
well not the reinforcement
one which i'm
still trying to get
working but the other two
worked it only came
out yesterday though
right so i mean well it
bugs me that i couldn't
get it to work but so
if anyone else figures
out how to get the
reinforcement working
send me a message
because it's i i've got
right to the end but i
i think i think my my
issue has to do with
like my training data.
I was trying to repurpose
the existing training
data. I think they
changed the structure
for like some kind of
reasoning structure.
Regardless, I've
struggled with that part.
And I'll publish
the MCP for anyone
that wants it here
later this afternoon.
So, Roo, what about,
I'm just thinking
here, like SageMaker
AI, for example, AWS,
you could generally
access O1 Mini and others,
I'm presuming from
AWS as well. You could
feed in your sample
fast. I was seeing a
demo the other day
where you could actually
fine-tune the model
based on your data. So
the approach that you
are suggesting in chat
GPT, could it not
theoretically be replicated
on? So then you can
do it on any model,
like you're not limited
to open AI ecosystem.
Well, the key is the
automated reinforcement
using reasoning.
So supervised and
reinforcement learning
has been around forever,
but the ability to
sort of easily plug in
a kind of reasoning
component to it has been
is relatively new
right you could do it
manually if you knew
what you're doing that's
the strawberry by example
but it was complicated
it was even more
complicated than what
i just showed you so
the the mcp in your
example if you want to
use bedrock or whatever
or and you want to
train retrain let's say
a mistral on oh three
and create a pipeline
it's literally just
asking mcp to uh you
know take the data
from one language model
train in the next
language model and then do
it until there's
coherence on both, meaning
they're both working
the same capability.
Now, that
breaks the terms
of service, I'm
pretty sure.
Then I think the
first rule of any of
these proprietary
models is you can't
train other models
on it. But let's
be honest, every
single, everybody
does. And if you look
at like DeepSeek,
you can tell it
was trained on
Sonnet. Like it literally
thinks of Sonnet
half the time.
Right? Right. So
that's a problem
I'll let you guys worry
about, but it just
makes it easy.
Very good.
1230, shall we bring up
the lightning talks, Ruf?
Yeah, let's do
it. Who do we
get today?
Wonderful. Ocean,
are you with us, sir?
Hi.
So I was actually
thinking I could push off
today's, but since
we're talking already.
So hi. Today, I want
to show a little bit
about how to use PyAdaptor
to build NCP servers,
and especially you
can use it for your
memory. So as Ruth was
showing that it is super
easy to create a NCP
server with FastNCP.
So why don't we kind
of like make some?
So one thing you can
do with PyAdaptor
is PyAdaptor is a
PyDentic model-based
adapter. It allows
you to adapt your data
from and to anywhere.
So you can literally
get a output from
your NCP, for example,
and then you add a
adapt to database
layer, for example,
and then that will be
saved into a that
will be saved into a.
Sorry, can you explain
Pydantic? I don't
think most people
know what that means.
Pydentic is a Python
data validation
framework. So let's
take a look at a
very simple example.
Basically, Pydentic
allows you to not
worry about things.
Like, worry
about what sorts
of things?
Data structure?
so yeah pidentic
model basically
allows you to
not worry about
like the uh
the type of the
the type of the model
so the type of the
data you put in so
basically if you put uh
so let's say we create
a user uh base class
and then id we let
it to be a string and
then name let it to be
a string And then if
we create a user, let's
say user equals to
user ID equals to one,
name equals to one,
PyDentic will make
this into a validation
error. What this is
useful is when you're
putting a validation
layer in your NCP usages,
all the input from
the agents, they will
get pre kind of
cleansed biologic first.
So for the ID, for
the name, you can add
validation rule to it.
What PyDapture is great
is it allows you to
save this kind of data
into any kind of
situation you like. So,
for example, here we
have a user, and then
let's say this is a
config instead of a user,
and then we have a
bunch of items here.
So if you want to turn
this configuration
into a Tomo, let's
say, you can just do...
And Ocean, this is an
MCP you're showing?
This is what I'm
showing is kind of like
a lower level building
block for MCP.
So let's take a
look at how you can
use this in a MCP
setting. uh let's say
you get fast ncp
and then you do a
tools and then you
dab your tool here
so let's say you
you call an open ai
service response equals
to open ai result
let's say what
you can do in this
case is directly uh
give a response to
adapt to neo4j let's
say and then this
thing will be saved
into Neo4j. All you
need to do is to
make this response.
Sorry, it should
be like this.
Basically,
what this enables is
seamless data
integration,
and then this
can go from Neo4j
to, let's say,
children of a
vector database
or even just SQL.
So yeah, I should
make it into the NCP.
So why not just
abstract the database
directly? What's
the advantage of
creating a secondary
abstraction?
This is more of a lower
level utility package.
It is for building
NCP that you have your
consistent data
infrastructure around it.
That is kind of the
whole point. So in
currently you use all
the NCP and then they
come from everywhere.
You literally just
find a link online
and then put it there.
And so what this
system is aiming
to achieve is a
consistent treatment
of all of those
NCP services.
Okay.
So let me see if I can
explain this. And I'm
the guy explaining it
in a simple way. But
I think what you're
describing is a common
interface for data
that is typed, So which
means that, you know,
you're not going to
have breakage depending
on like random data
being thrown at your
application, which
if you've ever, you
know, you know, create an
app, often users
will throw in random
characters or lines and
dots and whatever, which
breaks your app, you're,
you're normalizing
it through your
Pydantic structure. And
then, then you're
creating a, a uniform way
to interact with a
secondary data system.
Mm hmm.
Okay.
Yeah, so let's just
do a very simple
one, a very
simple NCP server
with this, and
then I'll be done.
So let's say you do
a perplexity search
NCP server, and what
you can do is we
need to get the
perplexity pidentic
model first, so which
is the request model
that you want the
agent to produce.
you
should you should
create a cookie cutter
template for this it
would be a lot easier
yeah so like this is
i found it to be super
simple to use this
actually it would be
easier just show you
the notebook uh this is
a super simple framework
to call any uh to
call any endpoint as
well so here uh exit
query and then do it
like that and here is
open router uh you
just need to send a
request object and then
it gives you a response
as well and here is
exactly the same for
perplexity chat endpoint
so the kind of idea
is a very central
interface for agent to
for this whole system
is developed for agent
to use it's not really
developed for human
users to be honest
okay uh cool so yeah i
really need to clean
this up and have it
more polished i'm sorry
just dumping around uh
a lot of running ideas
that's okay uh so
one of the things a
couple things to note
when with the mcps is
you know when i'm doing
these mcps that i the
in in what you saw
with well ocean one of
the quickest ways to
sort of bootstrap this
is to use if you're
using Python, ask Roo
and other systems to use
a cookie cutter. What
that does is skips
the first 20 steps. It
creates a scaffolding.
It creates the code.
What you don't want
the Roo and other
systems to do is have to
build all the muck
underneath because it
costs money. It burns
through a lot of cycles
that aren't needed. The
reason I was suggesting
to Ocean to create
a cookie cutter is
once you've got that
cookie cutter sort of
hello world in place,
that gives you the that
gives you a running
start and a lot of
people are are like
spending a lot of time on
the stuff the scaffolding
the sort of first
several steps don't
worry about that stuff
um if you don't have
to like if you're
building an enterprise
app maybe but otherwise
it's it's it's expensive
and just not worth
the money the other
thing i'm gonna i would
point out i've seen a
bunch of people show
up this week and say
you know i'm building
a llm interface as an
mcp that is crazy don't
ever use an llm as
part of your mcp that's
the entire purpose of
the mcp is to interact
with the llm so if
you're if your llm is
abstracting another
llm you're just burning
money for no reason
the whole purpose of
the of the mcp is to
have the llm interact
with something other
than an llm so just just
throwing it out there
i know i've seen
like four people show
me their their LLM, MCP,
and I'm like, well,
isn't that redundant?
So just,
you know, this is
a perfect example.
This would not be
something you'd
want to do as an
MCP because your LLM
already is
orchestrating it. So why
do I need to call
an LLM for that?
Random rant here.
I suppose, but
there are definitely
more ways to
interact with it.
For example, you
can have your
surface be a LN
-dominated surface.
So instead of being a
simple tool usage, you
actually get an
intelligent agent on the
other side. So if you
want to use your memory
services, that can
be tuned better. But
there are a lot of ways
of playing with this.
Yeah, if you want to
do what Ocean just
said, my suggestion is
to use A2A protocol.
It's better served
for that sort of use
case. um you know
and that's a that's a
discussion i think that
a lot of people sort
of get confused by
it's like they they try
to use an mcp for for
things that probably
isn't best suited
for or just expensive
for if you're looking
at orchestration the
a2a or the adp protocol
allows for sort of
inner agent communication
right where um
where the mcp is a
unidirectional it means
i'm making requests
to a secondary system
and then getting a
response and that generally
is a response
from some kind of
application but it doesn't
involve any kind of
orchestration or you
know multi-step logic
uh yes so just one
thing i want to show
before i get off is
the um coming up with
this so the the crazy
thing about pydapture
is i do not code a
single line the whole
thing was automatically
be coded by the
system that I created
that also utilizes rule
so it has a bunch of
rules and then the
the whole idea behind
this is a github based
orchestration system
and at every single
step we use clearly
templated documents
to record whichever
one thing each mode
has done so I will
clean this probably that
you can do like a
kind of init just like
Spark init as well.
Then you can have all
of these rules and
templates being copied
to your repo. So I
actually set up the rule
folder first before
I do anything else.
All right.
Who's up next?
All righty. So next.
Thank you, Ocean.
Always very neat,
man. Nice work.
so we have next up
we have dami and dami
we just met and uh
welcome to the aai
hackerspace uh friday
friday afternoons uh dami
we just met dami
tuesday night at the
toronto meetup so it's
uh it was great to
see some new folks
out there lots of new
folks that were out
there actually i'm gonna
i have to drop off
a little early brad
has a message uh for
the foundation at the
cap end but i want I
want to welcome you,
Dami, and he's got
some pretty slick front
-end design software,
to say the least.
Hey, Hackspace,
Friday afternoons,
Dami. We just met Dami.
We're getting some
feedback there.
It's from a user
called rtriad. You can
mute him. I'm not
sure. but uh there
we go sorry sorry
sorry sorry about
that that's my uh
username for my company
and i didn't um put
my personal name
in there oh no
that's fine it's fine
i i i it was
either that or some
like asian gang
or something
Well, thanks
for having me.
Nice to meet
you. All right.
Nice to meet everyone.
Yeah, so my name is Dami.
I'm the founder
of UI Design AI.
And at UI Design
AI, we built
the first Text
to Figma plugin
where you can type
in a prompt and get
a Figma design. That
was two years ago.
More recently, we've
been exploring the
Shopify space. So if
you check out the site,
you can click on
the Shopify product,
which is what I'm
demoing. And the premise
here is Shopify is one
of the biggest website
CMSs online, but they
don't really have
any AI tools for their
platform. This is
actually one of two
tools that launched on
the same day that's
serving the market,
but this one's faster
and better, I think.
But yeah, the whole
premise behind it
is you have sort
of a lovable, bold
experience, but
rather than watching
code animate, you
can actually just
get your visual
response right away.
So yeah, so you
basically have code.
No worries. Yeah,
I can probably ask
answer questions after,
but I'll quickly go
through the demo,
but yeah, definitely.
But yeah, basically
you have the visual
output here with
design and code.
So one cool thing
that's really useful
here is you can
edit the code here
and then also see
the output in the
visual editor as
well in one place.
So the idea is you
able to like look at
designing code. This
is also powered by an
engine that works
with Shopify's liquid
language. So as a user,
you can go in here
and modify some of
these tags as well.
So it uses the data.
I think one of the
data fields might not
be defined. But yeah,
you can basically
sort of toggle these
fields. So I think here
I could potentially
add description and
call it description.
that part doesn't
matter. And then maybe
modify here to use
description, but it
might not actually
update it here. Oh,
yeah, it might still.
Yeah, so description
and I think title
launcher are different.
But yeah, you can
basically use different
liquid tags in here.
And you also have
an IDE experience
where in the IDE
experience, you can
also look at the code
and modify these fields
here as well. So,
yeah, I think this is
actually what's missing,
the title. Or
heading was the
actual different
field. I can
modify this to
say description.
And then this
will be heading.
I believe I'll
copy it into
this file too,
just in case.
And I believe back
in the canvas, when
I go to the code
view, I should be
able to modify this
to use description.
But this part's a
bit glitchy, so I
shouldn't have
demoed that part. But
essentially, you
have design and code
together, and then
you have a visual
editor as well to
toggle the styles.
And the idea is to
add drag and drop,
maybe after the fact,
but allowing people
to create these
interfaces more visually.
You can also go in
here and also modify
the base theme and the
website that you're
using for. So if I
say bundle for shoes,
So in this canvas, I
now have another art
board that's generated
with a different design
that's a bit more
interactive. And then I
can also come in here
and see this output.
One other cool
thing as it loads
the next generation
is just loading.
One thing I kind
of added into here
was this idea of
light mode, dark mode.
So a lot of websites
don't support light
mode and dark mode
off the bat, which is
actually pretty
funny. But in here, if
I go into appearance
and then modify my
screen to be light
mode, in this layout,
you'll see that
reflected, it takes a
second, but yeah, like,
almost immediately.
And to me, like, this
is just like basic
CSS, but these are
things that should be
built into modern
websites without having
to, like, have a
bunch of dependencies.
It's just as simple
as using CSS, right?
So, yeah, so that's
part of the demo. The
other thing we're
launching is a theme store.
So currently
Shopify has a theme
store where you
can buy custom
websites for quite
a lot of money.
But we think
that with AI, you
can do the same
thing without
having to pay
all that money.
So basically here
you have these things
that look a little bit
better, but this is
just for this is on
staging. but essentially
you have this concept
where you can have
different your website
contents essentially
laid out in different
layouts so you can
quickly see what your
theme information
could look like across
different places in
Shopify currently you
can't do that you have
to buy a theme first
or trial it and then
manually change the
setting so this is like
a much a step forward
I think and then the
best part is after
you do that you can
come into the editor
again and keep prompting
and also modify the
different layouts
rather than using
Figma or using multiple
tools for those outputs
you can use this editor
and division here
is to go beyond just
Shopify websites I
think Shopify is a
underserved market that
has a data structure
where it doesn't require
a database as much.
So we can do most of
the front-end stuff.
And then later on, I
think, moving this to
general websites and
then eventually web
applications, I think,
is the next focus.
So,
yeah, the product
is live for Shopify
stores. If you
know anyone that
has a Shopify store,
e-commerce store
that needs help
with their website,
happy to trade
feedback for website.
And, yeah, like, I could
type my email
in here maybe.
How do you sign up? I
went to the OpenStyle
AI and it doesn't
look like that's
the site. Where do
you sign up for this?
Interesting. Yeah, if
you go to figma.ai or
uidesign.ai and click
the Shopify button,
you should be able to
sign up. Okay, good.
Yeah, your OpenStyle
AI is just dropping
JSON. okay so uh yeah
we have a bunch of
subdomains but yeah we
should we should update
the brand name too
but yeah for now it's
still ui design ai and
then uh it redirects
to the subdomain um
but yeah definitely and
and you're so you're
like basically trying
to be like a lovable
for for spigma and
shopify sites i mean
the funny thing is i i
built artifacts and
lovable before everyone
else did i just never
thought it was fast
enough uh but yeah like
answer your question
yes but like we built
this two years ago
right like we built
this like text app using
stack blitz in like
web containers the
same thing as both um
i literally was like
this typing animation
is just too slow and
figment launched their
thing the other day
with their typing
animation and i was like
honestly like why is
this typing animation
still a thing i'm
not sure if i have
it open here but
like um i was just
surprised like they
added their own lovable
clone and i i
think that the step
forward is having a
visual output first.
I saw like this
video go viral on
LinkedIn the other
day about someone
that basically
added a, they were
able to add a
visual output to,
I forget where it
is, to, I probably
don't have it open
here, this one.
They had a visual
output in Cursor. And
I think people are
kind of wanting
this sort of experience
where they're
not just watching
code being typed.
So this is like the
first endeavor into that.
I think lovable and
they're all great but
i saw someone today
post that they prompted
5 000 times and i
that also confuses me
i think it was it was
this one like like this
person prompted 5
000 times to build a
website i i think
that's a bit crazy in my
opinion 5 000 is low
like it like i i think
but if you look at the
amount of tokens i used
over last week it's
it's uh north of 200
million tokens which
would probably be you
know hundreds of
thousands of prompts now i
didn't do any of those
but i 5 000 if you're
manually doing it
is is totally with a
reasonable reasonable
for i mean i'm the kind
of person where as of
recently i mean bash
commands are pretty
popular now but like if
i'm promoting something
i'll make a bash
command and have
everything done in one shot
uh including like
multiple files so like
that's that's where my
vibe's at but i think
it's interesting how
these companies are
making money from tokens
and like from my point
of view i think it's
it is sort of like
a slot machine for most
people i think you're
more of an expert
but i think the next
paradigm is allowing
people to still prompt so
like here i can come
in here and say okay
make the colors red for
example um it doesn't
know specifically
what i mean by colors
it's using to use but
you can still prompt
rather than updating css
um and it should update
the colors to be red
but i think i think
there's there's a middle
layer where like you
don't need to do everything
through prompting
or you can do certain
things through
prompting or select certain
elements i just think
that like this paradigm
is needed that's
all yeah yeah looks
great nice work on this
hey i got a question
for you like it's very
fast and very responsive
so what is there
something that you guys
do to make it that fast
or is it just the the
stack that you chose
it's yeah like very
fast thank you thank you
a lot of people noted
that like i think like
as a designer like
Like, being in flow
state, you need the
output to, like, be quick.
I think there's
obviously technical
difficulties
to everything.
So, yeah, we're just
aware of the technical
limitations of the
browsers. And there's
even more ways to
make it faster or
whatnot and, like, to
support more things.
And I think, yeah,
like, it's just, like,
we care. Like, I
care a lot about this
stuff. And early on,
I told my team member,
I was like, yeah,
like, we need to, even
for the last two
years, like, the coding
animation for sure.
But, like, with this
output, I think speed
is important and it
matters. and you
want to make it even
faster. Was it the stack
that you chose that
made it fast or was
it the code that you
actually wrote? Like
what makes it fast?
My team member
probably can answer
better, but I think
it's a mixture of like
experimentation
with browsers and
then also like his
understanding. And
then like we also
like when we did a lot
of team retreats,
we had bad Wi-Fi.
I think just like pain.
I think a lot of people
don't have bad Wi-Fi
and they don't end up
testing the stuff on
bad Wi-Fi. So it's just
like, I don't know.
they don't have experience
nice looks looks
great and you're
you're live how do you
charge for this thing
right now it's just 20
a month so i think
it's like uh if you if
you feel if you want
to try it out or have
those one of the shopify
stores cheap for now
we're talking to users
and getting feedback
and helping them with
their stores outside
of the platform so
right now just the focus
is just talking to
customers and finding out
the use cases that
matter and then also
fundraising so just uh
getting users in order
to to show investors
that there's interest
and and and you're how
you guys funded like
do you guys start
uh yeah i've been
building this for the
last two years self
-funded um so my last
job was at a no code
company and they were
not focused enough on
ai and they had like
20 million and like a
stack team and i learned
that that doesn't
matter uh so yeah
just like for the last
two years i've been
building these experiments
in the figma plugin
plus this um with
my own money and
then um i think going
to market with this
product and the focus
about kind of rethinking
code um i think
it's time to fundraise
unfortunately but
yeah i think it's it's
just the nature of
things are you familiar
with at all with b0
oh yeah yeah like
we were like i
was probably like
the first user
like this is a
competitive map from
like uh two years ago
they weren't live when
i had when i had it
open i actually update
this but uh yeah yeah
like like ran into
the v0 ceo um versus
ceo at salesforce
tower last august when
they were having their
team planning or july
and then i was also
having my team planning
one person i think
they had a lot more
people but um i know
people in toronto that
work for them i think
the interesting thing
about v0 is it works
but it doesn't work
all the time and i've
tried lovable too it's
just like i've been
designing for 15 years
and i think these
tools are great for
some people who get
output but once someone
wants a little bit more
customization these
tools just don't don't
cut it but that was
going to be yeah that
was my next question
is where what so your
component library
you're pulling from
right now it's for react
components and such
yeah like we have a
library that we've created
similar to the figma
plugin as well but
But one thing that's
interesting is like doing
this intro, I can't
pronounce this word,
interpability with
thing where like,
if someone uploads
their theme, we can
use the components
from their theme
and train AI to
understand that theme.
I think at the end of
the day, like e-commerce
is like, they're all
the same, like in a
sense, like they literally
are, like Shopify
has a structure where
like, you have to
have a homepage and
then the homepage has to
have like certain things
and like you have a
product page and the
cart, like literally.
I'm thinking, I'm
talking more technically
speaking. I understand
that. But so
it sounds a lot like
B0 where they're
relying on, well, B0,
you should say, and AI
generates it with
some extra tailwind.
It looks similar
to that, but
you guys went
with a more of
a Figma like
user experience.
Yeah. And like, I think
the other learning
from the Figma has way
too many products. That
is so confusing. But
the other interesting
thing about the launch,
like the first text,
the Figma plugin. and
the interesting thing
about this is like
if i do spotify ios
mobile um what's happening
here is like we've
taken this project that
ai can now edit and
update i'll put like
about uh cities for now
it's still it's still
gonna draw the other
one but um essentially
we have this like light
mode dark mode i think
i glitched it up i
have an accident but
uh it's gonna draw the
new one now but uh
basically like this is we
don't update this anymore
but we this is like
figma's world and
we're able to like draw
um it's not a city but
we're able to maybe
it's a city but anyways
we're able to draw um
these elements and then
also like from there
derive like what the
styles are and everything
else and i think for
for shopify one of
the more interesting
things that we're kind
of working towards
that's almost done is let
me just pull it up
here is uh this idea of
like uh sinking so like
basically being able
to do this like we're
almost done this
right and it's like to
me this is you're working
on this part right
now this is what I was
interested in yeah
for sure for sure for
sure like we've been
working on this for two
years and like it's
weird how this is so
simple now in a sense
but like it's getting
there isn't it yeah
yeah to me this is the
exciting part yeah yes
it is it feels like
you're you're you've
got a great so I spend a
lot of time in shopify
and and standing up
you know lots of brands
and skews it it feels
like you're you
you're in between like
if i think of all the
shopify plus agencies
that i've talked to
over the years and my
friends who run shopify
related agencies like
there's there's a customer
that you're honing
in on that is kind
of like um if you're
trying to go for
adoption like i'm on my
fourth startup so it
sounds like you've got a
good core product you
still need to be kind
of technical it's not
going to be the lovable
person typing in a
prompt saying give me
a website but if you've
got these core if
you look at like the
list of the top 100
shopify plus agencies
and you talk to those
shopify plus agencies and
they're the developers
and this is going
to help them get the
profitability and like
really iterate fast
for their clients it
seems like there's a
really good usp for
the product that you're
building for us usp
unique sales proposition
okay so it's kind of
like honing on it because
it's not going to
be lovable it's not
going to be somebody
over here that's kind of
like doing lovable um
then you've got like
i know two european
retailers iro retailers
who are just porting
to shopify now and it's
like some of these
people don't even know
how to do basic data
management like forget
about even getting stuff
like oh my goodness
i've got 17 15,000
rows. Roo's talked
about like fire crawl
and it's like, these guys
don't even know how
to do basic data
management, but hey, we
can do a Shopify store,
right?
Every file is named new,
newer, newest,
the new ones.
Yes, there's
500 brands that
have the word new
plus brand name
that have to
be cleaned up.
So there's the basic
data cleaning, but
it feels to me, and
I'll even introduce
you to some of the
people that I know.
Mark Lewis is
awesome. you can look
him up on LinkedIn.
But it feels to me
like you've got a
really cool product
that could be used
by a lot of people.
My two cents is I
don't think it's $20 a
month. I think it's
finding the guys who
are actively building
on a regular basis
lots of sites, helping
them iterate faster
with your tool because
they would get it.
How'd you come up
with the pricing for
20 a month um so
the thing is like i
didn't update the
stripe thing for i was
busy to be honest but
uh like i think like
i really do want to
undercut the shopify
pricing i think
it's overpriced but
there's truth to like
the fact that agencies
are willing to pay
a higher price point
so i think it's just a
matter of figuring that
out and for go-to
-market we need to have
this open somewhere else
we need to basically
figure out um the
acquisition onboarding
and also like defining
the pricing which is
somewhere down here i
think uh i'm not sure
where that is but yeah
like basically like
figuring out um what
the right pricing is
for these people but
that's something that
another team member is
prioritizing and then
i was going to bring
up something else
yeah like basically here
um it costs like 250
for a template right
now i think that cost
can definitely be a lot
cheaper this is this
is an old slide too
but i think it's just
yeah i think just
bringing down the cost
and democratizing it
but i think there there
is like a middle ground
to figuring out um
incentivizing people
based on themes
and also number
of stores and also
maybe size of store
similar to how
Shopify prices. But
I think the cost
of websites should
be a lot cheaper.
It's not just the
website though. If you
think about like, this
is an abstract snapshot
in time of like the
unit cost of building
one website, but total
cost of ownership,
like we talk about
building apps and building
them, right? But
maintaining them is
equally painful, right?
like maintaining code
like i inherited code
from a guy two years
ago in this startup
that they hadn't touched
the repo in two years
like forget upgrading
angular that's that's
exactly where i am
right now i got exactly
that problem i got
this huge app yeah
yeah so so dami i would
say like the the value
proposition isn't
twenty dollars a month
the value proposition
is how do you help
these guys have more
profitable agencies
accelerating the design
process because you're
right a picture's
worth a thousand words
people get excited over
what you've built in
terms of how quickly
it builds right so
you're gonna you're gonna
increase the
profitability in theory if
this works you know
you're gonna increase
the profitability per
project for a customer
so there are a ****
ton of agencies
out there pardon
my language who
basically make money
off coding and if
you're gonna like
roo does the code
example of i just made
five million dollars
for the software
in three hours.
So like, it's
not the $20 a
month. The value
proposition is
fast, profitable.
And by the way, as
part of the life
cycle, like how do
you build campaigns
into your widget,
right? Because there's
Boxing Day, Black
Friday, like whatever
those things are.
So I don't know. I
think as an editor,
I think this is
great. I think it has
legs. It's just a
matter of figuring out.
I don't think it's
the individual person.
I think you should be
talking to agencies
and larger groups
who would deploy it
more aggressively
and actually give you
feedback from a
development perspective.
And by the way, guys,
if anyone wants to
trade their LinkedIn
stuff, you know, feel
free to put your LinkedIn
in the chat area.
Alex and Dami, you
guys are both in
Toronto, so you guys
should know each other.
Oh, Toronto.
Wow. Okay. Wow.
Yeah. So, you know,
I've known Alex for
decades at this point.
so uh you know he knows
everyone that you
probably need to know
yeah and to be honest
that's that's the uh
that's the value
proposition i think more
than anything else
for our crew is we
collectively are like one
degree away from pretty
much anyone we need
to be connected to
right that's amazing
some degrees degrees
from kevin bacon yeah
another another another
value proposition
good also because we
are all so geographically
spread out, right?
So ideas like this,
right, if you're in
a different part of
the world, I mean, you
could do proxy pitches
in some of the events
and, you know, and
other stuff as well.
Just a thought.
Yeah, that's a great
idea. Like, we could,
like, tune into the
Dubai or Stockholm or
London meetups and stuff
and, you know, be a
talking head for five
minutes or something.
Sorry, guys, I'm going
to wrap up quickly.
So So Ruben can close
off or whoever else
needs to talk. But
if anyone wants to
connect with me, I added
my LinkedIn in here.
Alex, I appreciate
everything you said.
Totally on point. I'm
going to reach
out as well.
And happy to
connect in person.
And if anyone wants to
connect with me, this
is my email address.
And then this is the
website for the app.
And I put my LinkedIn.
Appreciate all the
thoughts and feedback.
If you know anyone
in the Shopify space,
yeah, feel free to
intro or reach out.
And yeah, thank you
all. And thank you for
the opportunity, Ruben
and everyone else.
and you guys are
great and when are you
gonna have an mcp
first soon i don't know
enough about mcp so
it's funny how like
i'm learning from you
guys i already wrote
this down i need to
like just just like
it's like on my to-do
list actually and i
need to just read
about it it's just so
convoluted but i i do feel
like i'm understanding
it more basically
you guys are saying
but there's a few people
in i think there's
a few people tuned
in right now that
could probably help
you in like 10 minutes.
We got a few minutes.
Anything you
want to discuss?
I have a topic to
just bounce off.
It's not a demo.
It was just an
idea that came
to me yesterday
morning and I tried
to validate it.
Obviously, the mini
version and the
roof code, I was
thinking, We've been
talking about
mature individuals,
professional. What about
everyone is talking
about China has
introduced AI in schools.
This country has
introduced in schools
and other things.
So what I was
thinking, I fell into
Google Gemini, kind
of a thought to
do a bit of deep
research about what
we are doing here.
Potentially could,
how could that
relate to primary
school students?
Right. So the idea was,
if you see my screen,
so my son goes to
this primary school at
Cobham, right? So
the idea was that how
do you encourage
and learn by doing
philosophy to say the
different national
curriculums that are
out there and the
various bits around
their ethos and goals is
how do you introduce
children to this
new way of engaging
AI? So, for example,
taking the UN
Sustainable Development
Goals and then effectively
introducing kind
of elements of coding,
joint projects,
kind of unplugged events,
et cetera, et cetera.
So, long story short,
this is what kind of,
like, I'm happy to
share this or some
feedback. But the idea
was, if I go down slowly
a little bit here,
things like this, right?
Introduce projects.
So I kind of, as I
was doing, I created
a quick kind of a
bit here to show that
kind of interactive
demo. So where people,
what they can do
is they can engage
with the tools that
we are using here,
but probably create
something out of it.
I mean, I need to
develop this, but
just happy to kind of
get some feedback
on what people think
about it. So there's
a bit of stuff here.
My wife's a teacher
for sixth grade this
year. She's previously
taught second or
third grade, I believe
it is. And I trained
her how to use agents
to grade papers
using, you know,
giving it a rubric and
things like that. And
I actually was able to
catch some of the
students submitting
papers that they had
used ChatGPT to write
their papers already
in the sixth grade.
All right.
So they're probably
already ahead of this,
some of them, depending
on the age group.
yeah right i already
have yeah you know i have
middle school um
children and um a lot of
the classmates themselves
they use ai tools
without understanding
like they don't know
what the model is they
don't know like things
but they just go and
yes so responsibility
right um yeah some
people get in trouble
something yes they find
useless some people
like doing great but it
seems like it's a wild
west with the middle
especially with middle
schoolers yeah that
the ai **** is a is a
really big concern
obviously um you know so
it used to be called
cyber bullying and it's
evolved into uh you
know all different
branches now and the
the ai is uh certainly
helping with the make
that a big problem um yeah
yeah so i mean this
is like not aimed at
secondary this lane
broke more like you know
just before people leave
primary school let's
say you know years
five and i mean what
probably they can little
be is four and five
here's five and six
that's how it is but um
things about teaching
them about ethics
things about bias you
know how do you you know
all of that stuff and
getting people more
hands-on that's the
thinking about it so i i
think the i think the
challenge my and my
daughter's in the sixth
grade as well so same
same age group um the
the uh the challenge
i think i see with her
and her friends and
and she's she's done
pretty well with ai you
know she had six
million users of her app
before she turned 10
so that says something
but the the what i've
seen over the last couple
years is like a
cognitive offload it's
like i know she's you
know she's in the other
room but she's she's
super smart and super
capable but there's
a tendency to have ai
kind of do the you know
kind of the hard work
for you so you don't
have to and the hard
work is what you where
you learn right so the
the when you're young
you have to learn the
way of to do stuff
so you get to our age
being older so you know i
i'm literally offloading
all this stuff
because i already know
how to do it and i know
the right questions
to ask but if i offloaded
all that stuff when
i when i was younger
when i when i learned
all this what would
i know now right and
that's i don't know i
don't know how to solve
if you can solve that
problem the cognitive
offload issue we're
facing where half the
population are going
to be like that wall-e
movie sitting in a in
a chair you know in
blobs with no with no
you know common thought
that's the that's the
worry i mean yeah the
parallel the parallel
will be learning to
drive right manual
driving is not really a
thing anymore so i'm
wondering what of today's
skills or maybe
yesterday's skills are no
longer necessary
tomorrow yeah no but this
is going to the heart
of what we do right
thinking reasoning etc
if everything is kind of
offloaded you you won't
develop that critical
thinking capability
at all yeah well the
driving example is
also right because the
great because like in in
10 years like my daughter
she's in sixth grade
she's probably never
going to drive a car
she'll never sit behind
the steering wheel
so she won't i can
i learned to drive a
manual transmission
car man and and so you
know but now my my
daughter's not gonna even
learn to drive yeah
guys i there's a funny
story there's a
movie with sylvester
stallone and sandra
bullock judge dread where
sandra where all of
the cars are self
-driving and then it
says you have to drive
it's like i remember
that demolition man my
if i can interrupt
really quick i have a
story from um my time
in the service i was
in the navy for very
many years and i
was trained by a
marine called gunnery
sergeant and i'm old
enough to remember when
as an engineer back
then we had to do
things with a slide
rule so i lived uh the
crossover time from
working with a slide
rule to when we had
our first electronic
calculators And I
distinctly remember him,
you know, throwing the
calculator up against
the wall and breaking
it and saying
that, you know, these
things, you know, you
lose batteries,
they're not dependable.
So the end of the
story is that just
like he was
resistant to the
calculators, which
were simply a tool,
some of us are resistant
to AI, which is
simply a tool. You know,
I don't need to know
how a car operates.
I don't need to
understand a combustion
engine to drive a car.
And, you know, I've
seen in the Navy,
I remember that we
had guys that, you
know, used to be
you didn't throw the
captain overboard
because he was the only
one that could
navigate by the stars.
So, yeah, I do
agree with some of
these older
technologies, some of
these older things,
we do need to
teach our children
that. But also,
you know, we have to
have a balance where we
become open to the new
technologies and the
new ways of doing
things. Because those
are the people we're
going to compete against.
They're doing it and
we need to catch up.
Yeah.
Dennis, I was just
about to mention the
slide rule. Exactly.
But one thing is,
and the calculator,
so that was the
argument back in, I
don't know, 30 years
ago or something. But
one thing is people
who know how to use
slide rules, they
also understand how
the numbers works
and how algorithms
work, right? Yeah.
and also like sometimes
when people rely
too much on calculators
like sometimes
they mess up and
calculators give them
a ******** answer
and then they don't
know and they just
take it for granted
which is a great thing
for us to remember
and i'm so happy with
by the way i i actually
teach ai and i have
my own group that
i lead i found this on
linkedin uh and i am
really appreciative
of you guys allow me
allow me to be here
um this is just i i'm
gonna come back every
week i'm you guys get
tired i'm gonna have
more ai guys in here
and you can stand but
um we love we love
having you for sure
yeah this is uh this is
wonderful um just again
you know thank you
guys for allowing me
in here and um i'm
gonna try and step
into the background and
do something i don't
normally do which is
keep quiet are you
really a fox uh well
thank you for that so
uh in my bad old days
I was the uh instructor
for CompTIA so when
you paid an inordinate
amount of money to
obtain a CompTIA
certification been there
I I was the online
instructor for most of
those so I I had most
of the, I used to be
the product manager
for Cisco for, I'm sure
you've heard of the
CCNA certification.
I was a product
manager for
CCNA. I was with Red Hat.
I was with Red Hat
when we started. I
wrote a book for IBM
on Linux clusters
and I was invited
to the white house
by the then former
now again, president,
no, no political
connections is
just, I did work
that he appreciated.
And I got to go up
there and meet him.
Yeah. It was, you know
without the political
affiliation one way
or the other he's
an amazing human
being to talk to and
to be in his presence
I can understand
why he's in the
position he's in
because he makes
you feel like you're
the only person
in the room yeah
did you share your
LinkedIn in the chat
I surely did I've got
about 10,000 followers
so as I said I can
bring bring some traffic
to here and no i am
not a fox that this
comes from when i used
to teach the online
classes uh okay one of
the things i found is
that the video the pure
video uh for people
that didn't have great
bandwidth it was a problem
and the characters
weren't that hard yep
as live video is harder
and more bandwidth
box is cool man yeah
thank you sir yeah it
was unexpected um chris
you you have something
you want to say your
show here let's show
off this new uh system
i developed so what
this is able to do i've
set up a remote system
here now that will
take the like a prd
document and completely
build the entire thing
out from start to finish
fully autonomously
without any human in
the loop requirement
whatsoever it consists
of you know 26 different
modes nine orchestrators
17 workers they're
all controlled by a
pheromone trail system
based which gives them
swarm intelligence
and a pheromone scribe
then controls the this
is essentially the memory
system and the sorry
sorry i'm gonna pause
pheromones like like
like sense of smell
between like ants like
what yes where yes where
where does the smell
come from so the the
ais leave signals
like pheromone trails
pheromone signals okay
and these signals then
based off of what they
do have different
multipliers of evaporation
right and so the
scribe is in control of
controlling the memory
right and so and it's
a documentation first
so first when you start
a project it's going
to do the the research
right you're going to
have all of the research
documents and it's
going to it's going
to do the deep research
like like what your
deep research does right
and then it's going
to take that and then
the spec writer is going
to write out its
documentation architect
is going to write out
its documentation it's
going to then code
out you know like a
framework and then there's
also a a spec writer
for tests that's actually
what's active right
now is the spec to
test planner and what
this does is then it
writes out all the specs
for all the tests that
are required and then
the coder goes to work
writing code to pass
the test and then
that's basically how it
just automatically builds
itself out from end
to end and then the the
the pheromone system
is allows it to keep
track of you know what
documents are where
so like this time this
spec planner got told
it needed to read these
documents and these
were the path lotations
and then with the
information in these
documents it has everything
needed to then be
able to write out the
specs for this particular
test right and this
is all managed through
the swarm intelligence
system because every
mode has access to the
pheromone file which
is just a dot pheromone
file here and uh
can you can really could
just a quick question
because i've spent a
lot of time with swarm
systems i i haven't
been able to create a
true swarm system with
rue because it's it's
uh sequential so is it
a swarm or is it just
a mimic because a
swarm that's sequential
isn't a swarm it's
just a series of steps
well it it goes into uh
into a loop because i'm
using gemini the new
gemini so um i have
to be worried about the
context window but i
you can actually have
the ai models task
complete at certain
context limits so when mine
hit 350k context tokens
they task complete
or they task complete
if the task completes
before that's that's
what ruben was getting
at chris was is it
single threaded or multi
-threaded do the agents
work one at a time or
are multiple agents
operating on different
files concurrently so
it's not swarm a swarm
it needs to be
decentralized or concurrent.
And there's some
implementations that
you can see, but
if it's sequential,
then it's something
other than a swarm.
So the nature of a
swarm, think of it
like an ant
colony. Each ant is
independently operating,
but is being orchestrated
by a central
queen or whatever.
But the problem with
Rue is there's no
capability for that
kind of independent
organization.
right well i called it
swarm because when i
looked it up online
it was called swarm
intelligence but yeah
it might not technically
be the swarm as you're
referring to but i mean
actually it's interesting
you mentioned the
ants there was research
done in san diego
like about the whole
swarms and specifically
about ants ants are not
controlled by queens
they're actually
controlled by this collect
they have this collective
intelligence that
uh yeah it's exactly
pheromone and one ant
basically just gonna
die it cannot find food
like you need at least
three ants to do like
anything useful like
that's yeah so but i
think i think what i'm
getting at is the fact
that each ant somewhat
operates autonomously
through some some you
know interconnected
communication something
yeah but i'm not
i'm not each ant cannot
even survive they're
super dumb but like
three ants can actually
find some food or
do and it's actually
grows exponentially
the more ants you die,
I do like the, but
there's nothing
special about one
ant, you just, it
just comes from
numbers. Oh, yeah.
That is actually
interesting
information. Thank
you for that.
So is it just the
pheromal files at JSON?
Yep, yep. And it gets,
it gets manipulated
by the LLM, by the
agent, goes through and
manually calculates
this stuff based off of
the configs above and
then just just one
quick quick note for
what you created could
totally be a swarm
relatively easily all you
need to do is is move
away from static md
files to a shared
state you know kind of
event bus once you've
got the event bus then
then suddenly you can
have multiple vs code
instances and each of
those and you can look
my vs code uh you know
implementation the
way i did that and
what you built would
instantly be a decentralized
swarm okay so yeah
i was just trying to
get it to autonomously
build an entire
program with nobody
stepping in right or
having to give any context
like having to all
figure it all out itself
and so that's cool
but do you really need
vs code at that point
maybe like bunch of
aiders would be even
better exactly well that
that was my implementation
last year and
you look at my swarms
from last year and i
used i abstracted ader
to do that that's if
you look at a spark
spark one that's exactly
what i was doing um
and and the problem
with swarm i've i've
struggled to get swarm
to be like to build
things concurrently i
find that a lot of good
software just needs
to be built in a
sequential form because the
nature of software you
know one thing affects
another pretty you
know pretty clearly
unless you're uh using
like a microservices
architecture where there's
like a communication
channel in between
each of the operating
components but if
you're if you're working
in like a monolithic
structure like a lot
of what we we're looking
at here i haven't
been able to get any
level of concurrency
it's both though like
even in microservices
you still need that
foundation in place if
i don't have the
message queue in place
then the developer
that comes in to start
working and expects it
to be in place isn't
going to see any success
like to your point
like you're absolutely
right you You still,
whether it's monolithic
or microservices,
software is developed
in stages, whether
we like it or not.
Until later on, then you
might be able to bring
a bunch of people or
you definitely want
to bring a bunch of
people in and work on
different branches. But
in the early stages,
it's weird because
I see a lot of people
trying to do all this
stuff in the very early
beginning. And it's
like trying to throw
a thousand person
party in a house that
hasn't been built yet.
Yes, that's a good
analogy. but it's trying
to do this on an
eventually consistent basis
so instead of having
the different modules
be synchronous
they're all developed
independently and then
when ready to run the
assumption is that the pre
-agreed interoperability
means that they just
work yeah they come
together at some point
right when they can
agree that they're
mature enough if i
understand what you're
saying but i think one
thing back to the
microservice part sorry go
ahead flat i don't
know sorry i was just
going to add like what
truth said there's yeah
so software is developed
sequentially but
sometimes the research
kind of activities
that you don't know
which approach is going
to be better so at
that point you probably
it's better off like
to fork into like two
different like swarms
and then like because
we had conversation
this morning is like
what's better for data
storage a white column
so the narrow like
columnar structure right
so if you have the
agents like one group
they just can fork
themselves and one group
tries one way another
group tries another way
and then they get the
performance numbers
and then the supervisor
will pick which one
Chris you want
to continue
or do you have something
Chris
I love Chris he's
always creating
the most interesting
things and thanks
Chris for sharing
that by the way
you're pushing the
boundaries for sure
you know what would
be interesting for,
you know, the swarm,
and this is something
that I played with
a bit, is, you
know, quantum based
applications, right,
where you're looking
at every eventuality
and possibility, and
then you can sort
of attempt to figure
out which is the
optimal solution
across multiple paths.
Those are the types of
apps that
probably do best.
And I think Guy
mentioned about A2A.
It's exactly the problem
I was having with
A2A. It's like A2A
scales to a point.
And the one way that
I was getting around
that for A2A was
using the message bus
and the real-time
capabilities of
Supabase and to create
a kind of, yeah,
Kafka, that's another
good one, streaming.
So there's, whoever
cracks the idea of
real-time, you know,
distributed streaming,
web development or
application development
is going to change
everything. I
just, we're just missing
something to make
that feasible i'm
not sure what that
is exactly but it's
not quite there it's
the same communication
patterns over
and over again it's
it's not an unsolved
issue yeah it could
be solved better
and and when you get
deep research on google
or open ai to try to
tell you to solve it
it doesn't it's just
regurgitating you know
whatever and that's
because cscd is a difficult
problem for a lot of
people and the good
solutions aren't really
well documented, I
don't think, you know,
but it's a CICD issue.
You know, for example,
when you run into
issues, if you don't,
if you're not generating
issues literally within
GitHub, nobody can
follow behind you and
pick up where you left
off, whether it's an
agent or a real human.
Those steps are
missing in our
current workflows.
The best example
we have, and this
is already 15 year
old tech, are
fast flux botnets.
And when you look at
how these fast flux
botnets work under the
covers, they're taking
advantage of a whole
globally distributed
series of unprotected
computers and orchestrating
them in a kind of
graph-like structure.
that is probably the
closest thing we have
right now to potentially
you know solving or
orchestrating like
true swarms and what do
you do with those you
take nothing good you
know ddos and you know
yeah yeah but uh but
if you look at how those
are architected you
know because they're
architected one to to
avoid uh discovery on
the command and control
because you know the
bad guys don't want to
be found. And the
resources are constantly
changing, right? That
computer turns on, it's
exploited, it goes away,
that kind of thing.
So it's interesting
how it's architected
just as a design pattern.
You've essentially
solved that part of
it though with the VS
Code MCP server, but
it's still, okay, now
I've got this capability
to deploy all of these
VS Code agents or
bots, whatever you want
to call them. How do
I best utilize this in
a GitHub branching
strategy? is really I
think where the struggle
is that like okay one
agent starts writing
code what is the other
agent actually going
to do like that's where
I ran in trouble with
this trying to do
multiple VS code instances
it's it's like until
you get your project
to a certain point you
really just can't
take advantage of more
than one agent working
at a time it's writing
the same problem or
the same feature in a
different branch using
a different method and
then the second the
feature that's tested
that's very it's the
same problem with scaling
development with a
lot of developers you
have interfaces and modules
that are independent
and interfaced together
through well-known
interfaces and someone
could code code the
module and someone could
code another module
that uses that right
and yes if you don't
decompose your problem
like that then yeah
you're stopping on the
same code yep yeah all
right guys i i gotta
jump uh a great time
as always Thanks,
everyone who participated.
This is the highlight
of my week every week.
And yeah, we got lost.
What was the code
valuation tool that
you shared yesterday?
Oh, SCC.
Simon Charlie Charlie?
Yes, Simon Charlie
Charlie. And
if you're installing
it, ask Rude
to install the Go
version of SCC.
Smart.
It's easier to install.
um and the other
thing i know i always
end every one of my
consulting projects even
though the sec value
is kind of bs um i
show them like oh look
i created you know
whatever millions of
lines of code and
it's worth a billion
dollars and their minds
are blown but just
just just remember like
the easier something
is to create the less
value generally it
has so measuring the
value of code based
on lines and effort
and person years in a
world where i could
crank out a hundred
thousand lines in an
evening obviously makes
the code less valuable
that's just is what
it is right and i'm
not pretending that
it's worth a billion
dollars it's not it's
worth 89 dollars in
tokens so but regardless
the the lesser uh
those who believe in
the old school way of
valuing code it's a
number at the very least
you can grab a couple
zeros off that and
it's still valuable
gotta go alright
thanks everyone
appreciate it talk
to you next week
have a good weekend
guys thank you everybody