All right, so I
thought today I'd
fool around. I don't
know if you guys
have anything in
particular. I was
going to fool around
with the Codex
system and see what
that's all about.
I was playing with
it earlier, and it
solved some interesting
problems I was
having with my A2A
MCP server, which I
still haven't got
around to publishing,
but I'm almost there.
So that was exciting.
So let's take
a look here.
One sec, I'm
just going to...
All right, I'll
just walk you guys
through the process,
I'm going to share.
If there's anything
you guys want to
cover, just ping me.
I'm, you know, always
open to whatever we
want to build. I've
got no real plan
today other than take
a look at this and
see what it can do.
So the OpenAI
Codex looks
like it's the version.
Oh, what?
Oh, it went black for a
sec, but I'm back. Okay.
All right, so I just,
I forked the repo,
but so there's two
things we can do here. We
can install it, and
so we're in the repo,
but I'm gonna actually,
I'm gonna modify,
I'm gonna see if I can
modify their system.
So to see if I
maybe make an MCP or
something out of it, I
don't know, let's see
if I can get the
system to build itself.
I'm gonna install it
globally, and then I'm
gonna modify it
locally, which might be
interesting for testing,
but we'll see how that
works. uh so just
install it here mpm i
dash g so i just clone
the repo you guys want
to follow along feel
free to do that and
then then there's various
options here so we
we've got different
i'm thinking about it
we may need to get an
extra one like a knob
all right this is this
is the this is the
one where people aren't
automatically muted.
There's always some
form of a reminder.
Yes. Third days
are the ones
where I have to
mute everybody.
Yeah. Note to self.
Okay.
Anyway.
All right. Guys,
mute yourselves.
I'd rather focus
on this than
clicking the mute button.
All right. So
where was I?
Okay. Okay, I installed
it. Looks good.
So we can test it by
just explaining this
code base to me, I
guess. Let's start with
that. Oh, auto approve
mode, full auto.
Okay.
I like the
sounds of that.
I don't know.
I'm going to
start with the other one.
Auto seems like
a bad first step.
All right. I'm going
to use this one.
All right. So it's
kind of like similar
to that Claude codering
system they came
out with about a
month ago, which I
used once and never
used again. But so far,
this thing seems to
work pretty good.
The UI is a little
weird. Like, it's
got all this sort
of code output
for, like, so it's
running commands
and then it's
getting the list. It
just, I think it
needs to, like,
organize it better.
Like, I don't, do I
need to see all this
stuff? Or, I kind of
think it needs to be
hidden. I don't know.
So, it's thinking.
Alright, here we go.
Here's a high-level
tour of the repo,
which is the open
source, open AI,
Scylla. Okay.
Now, I don't think
it knows about the,
this is one of those
problems that we
face a little bit
with these types of
apps. I don't think
it knows what a model
context protocol is
because it's probably
been trained before it
was invented. So what
I'm probably going to
need to do just to help
it along a little
bit, I'm just going to
assume it doesn't know
what it is. And to be
honest, MCP actually
has different meanings.
So I'm going to just
tell Give me a basic
hello world model context
protocol using the
MPM SDK. official. I
want the official SDK.
Let's use studio
for this seems
like a better
approach since
we'll worry about
the SSE later.
Using studio and basic.
Yeah, I think
that's pretty good.
All right. So
I'm just going to
give it a little
bit of guidance.
Just to give help it
help it build what I
want to build so basically
what I'm thinking
just I'm just messing
around here but what
I was thinking is what
if we could make this
uh open AI codec system
an MCP that I can
evoke within uh other
tools right so then I
can have like a I could
have a Klein or root
code invoke this as
an MCP and code things
independently and one
of the things that this
does is it runs in
a kind of segregated
terminals component
that doesn't apparently
touch anything else.
So it could be good for
sort of a parallel
sort of implementation.
So that's what I
was thinking would
be cool to do.
And I don't think
anyone's done it
yet. So let it be us.
All right. So I'm
creating a hello
world. I'm going
to start with that.
All right.
So I'm going to copy
this and I'm going
to go back here. And
I'm not going to start
with a thing I want
to build. I'm going
to build a simple
first step to see that
if the thing can
actually build the sorts
of things I want to
build. Then once,
assuming that it
actually works, then
we'll go and try to
work the other thing.
So I'm going to
call this mcphello.
And then in there,
I'll create a readme.
And then I'll paste
this in here. We'll
lose the citations.
We don't need that.
All right.
Now I'm going to clear
this and then I'm
going to, this time
I'm going to try to use
maybe I'm going to
try the auto, maybe.
Okay, I'm going
to use auto
-approved. This
is that. So let's
see what happens
with this.
Actually, I'm
just going to
type it here
because why not.
Create a basic MCP
hello world using
the readme .md. I'm
still getting up
to speed on exactly
how this codec system
works. So that's
in the MCP hello.
Hello.
Okay, let's see
what it can do.
So I gave it a
really, really
basic plan, just
a hello world, I
didn't review
it, but whatever.
We'll put it in here, I'm
just going to clear this,
clear this,
and we'll see,
we'll see what happens.
I exported, so it looks
good using the O4 mini,
auto-approve,
let's see what it, let's
I can read the file,
good, okay.
So it's, we're in
full auto mode.
We'll see what it's
gonna do. So the
readme is pretty
straightforward.
It basically is exactly
what I took from,
let's take a look here.
I'll let that think
whatever it's thinking.
So this is a basic
model context example
using the official
NPM in studio.
Pretty simple. Not
a lot of code here.
Again, I'm using a guide
because it was invented
after the thing
was trained, so I
doubt it would know
anything about it.
So I had to go tell
it a little bit.
Let's see here.
It's thinking. All
right. Wow. Thanks.
Any comments?
Anything exciting
you guys have
seen this week?
Anything new?
That's probably an
understatement of
the century but uh
the image thinking
is very interesting
like adding the
sorry go ahead yeah
yeah it can create logos
you know you can upload
wireframes and it
creates the final ui
production level the
0304 image image thinking
and so many other
use cases like millions
it's it's impressive
i was i i was impressed
because i always do
that maze thing every
time and it never
works and this is the
first one it worked so
are we are we at like
some kind of like
inflection point uh in in
language models i don't
know what the maze
tells us it's as smart
as a rat maybe interesting
was that 03 you
did that with ruth i
did 03 I didn't even try
a four on that. I just,
I grabbed in May's
image, I uploaded it
and it was, it took
five minutes and
someone else is like, I
figured that out in
like 30 seconds, but you
know, but the key here
is it actually worked.
Rather, I guess
if the benchmark
is like four minutes
and 30 seconds,
what will an X
model be? Two
minutes, one minute,
I don't know.
All right, so it looks
like it built something.
CD, okay, let's
give this a
spin and see
what happens.
It was quick, built
it in the time of
tick took me to make
some small talk.
All right, MCP, MPMI.
Now the real test here,
if there's any
errors on the
first go. No,
no build errors.
That's a check box.
All right,
let's start it.
Ooh, an error.
Okay. A minor error,
but an error. It
wasn't one shot,
at least.
All right. So we'll
pop it in here.
A little wonky
interface for a sec.
Maybe I didn't copy it.
Let's go back and see.
Go back.
I guess it took a
second copy. All
right. Let's see
if it fixes that.
I don't know.
Maybe I'm used to using
better interfaces.
Even the Spark CLI I
created last October
seemed more intuitive
than this thing.
This is like cyberpunk
or something.
Hacker style.
I don't know.
It doesn't do it for me.
Let's see if it's
figuring it out.
So what I'm going to
do now, I'm going to
do the sort of layered
approach where I get
the initial MCP working.
Then I will, I'll
then say basically
create me a version of
the codex as an MCP or
something like that.
But before I do, I need
to get the thing working.
the other thing i
noticed by the way the
uh this is pretty cheap
i i did a comparison
uh the same question
basically a hello
world using sonnet
3.7 and and uh oh
four i think it was oh
four mini and it was
half the price less
than half the price
for the exact same
output so whatever
they're doing they're
using less tokens to
do it which is which
is i guess important
looking to save
some money anyway
yeah rob did you get
the the latest model
working in uh on
requesty you said
yeah that's right uh
well um certainly the
04s the minis but
03 had to go back
over and verify the
organization and open
ai and i didn't
bother last night oh
three oh lock that
down to tier four five
again they did that
oh oh three they said
you can't get it unless
you're a tier four
five which is kind of
nuts but even if you
are four or five then
you've got to show id
and and validate
your organization and
identity and send your
kid over there send your
first five-year-old
baby i didn't yeah
click on the approved
biometrics okay i mean
i mean no one even you
who even uses straight
api anymore nobody
well occasionally i
pull out the you know
just when it doesn't
work basically i mean
you're not gonna go
hey no more requests
to you straight to the
bandits themselves yeah
let's see let's see
if i can i mean you
know what now i'm now
Are you still tiered,
though? Like, you
were at, like, five,
but then you also
got banned for
being naughty a lot.
I don't know.
Was it Playground at
OpenAI? Is that
the address?
Because, yeah, why
bother putting out
benchmarks and then
no one can use it?
It's like... Well,
it's OpenAI, right?
It's half the
time it doesn't...
It's unprovable.
hey we we just
got uh you know
agi but no one
else can verify
it other than us
so let's see can i
use it here and try
if you're go you
should really go to api
and then you can go
to the limits right
just go three go to
you can use it in
the chat okay in the
standard interface
I get that this is
for API that's why
I'm just curious this
is the way I quickly
test if the API
works so this is 03
tell me how about
create me the
ultimate
brawn UI in Node.js
let's see what that is
it's
i wonder because it
can it access other
people's uh you know
like shared knowledge
to say like it does
know who i am and like
my where where i don't
know i can upload
my my action figure is
this star trek agentic
engineer dude i might
be having the same
problem you guys are
having here it looks
like it's not
responding unless it's
thinking really hard
about what a brawn ui is
i can't tell but uh
i'm gonna let this run
for a minute but i'm
gonna switch to uh i
think they must have
just all just marketing
bs like sonnet was
dominating they're like
we'll throw some some
kinks in their armor
and and confuse everyone
but yeah you know
like throughput put
is 80 90 yeah you who
gives a **** if you
got the number one ai
that works for five
seconds a day and costs
80 no one it's you
know like that's the
thing if you can't like
if you look at open
router it's what is
it billions a day is
what you need well it's
prohibitively expensive
at this point i just
mean if you look
at 43.5 billion tokens
uh today for for clot
so like if you can't
push out that kind of
token go away that's
what i mean like you
can't you can't have
a sort of poc demo
available only only
person only people i know
that do that not bad
is google they'll go
okay have it for free
for like 10 rpm it's
it's reasonable you
can still use it a bit
minor minor problem
here it looks like
it's the client the
uh client or the
server doesn't stay
running it exits so
the mcp server seems
to exit make it
Yeah.
Even if I go to open
router to pay
the $10, $40,
you can't use it.
No, let's, let's go
back here. I love
multitasking. Let's
see. Did this ever,
oh, it did. Okay.
It looks like, it
looks like I, O3 does,
does work from the API,
at least for me but
again guys i i i as
you guys know i tier
five by sure luck um
i did not spend enough
to to get into your
tier five access but
they seem to have given
it to me so thanks
for that you earned
it though you earned
it uh yeah ey earned it
by spending an obscene
amount of money with
them thank you ey
uh all right so uh yeah
looks looks uh looks
like that that works
let's i don't know
what the heck it built
can i switch the um
can i switch this to
use oh three uh my
my other one i wonder
all right still thinking
doing a lot of thinking
but that's okay
i wonder I wonder if
this will work in my
sort of go-to-bad
scenario where I let run
the, what is it, Rue
code run overnight.
This might, if I can
set this up to run on
a dedicated instance,
maybe as like a
serverless, as a
serverless function, maybe,
as a serverless
function might not work,
maybe like a Vercel
image or some hosted
cloud image somewhere,
and then I could just
let this run overnight
on crazy stuff. You
can probably use
Cloudflare Worker because
you're only charged
for compute cycles now.
Yeah, Cloudflare
Worker would
be a good
option for sure.
So I just spin
up Wrangler.
It'd be cool to be
able to like, because
I don't want to
leave my computer on.
Not that I really
care, but you know, I
prefer to leave it on
a server somewhere.
All right, so let's
take a look here. My
next question is, can
I switch the model?
I don't like the look of
that, let's render that.
I hope this is
interesting, I'm
just curious how
this thing works.
So we got it working,
it built an MCP
server, it doesn't
look like it doesn't
stay running, which
is a minor issue,
so hopefully it will
fix that in a sec.
So we've got
suggest, auto edit,
and full auto. I think
we're running full auto.
Linux, IP table. So this
literally run to
set up a sandbox.
Okay.
So there's a file called
run.sh. Where's that?
Let's take a look.
So this looks like it's
setting up, it looks
like it just runs in
a terminal instance.
Okay. Okay. I
could totally just
do the same
thing for running
that on a
serverless function.
It looks pretty
straightforward.
Just needs network
access, it would seem.
Here's a, this
is probably
a Docker image, I guess.
Something like
that, maybe.
All right. Is it
still thinking here?
It does seem to run.
Has anyone else played
with the codecs at all?
it's interesting that
they chose codex too
i don't know for anyone
that's been around
the open ai ecosystem
long enough their
first model pre gpt3
was actually gpt codex
which was the
predecessor to the gpt3
model so it's interesting
that they've chosen
to use codex and
codex for those that
aren't familiar was
all was the first
implementation of the
github co-pilot back in like
2021 which is what
powered that so they
re they went back to
their sort of roots
and used the same name
again now you have
to be like a a super
nerd i guess to even
know that maybe but uh
here we are let's see
i wouldn't be surprised
if members of the
original Codex team
that work at OpenAI?
Yeah, well, everyone
that's there, everyone
I know that was there,
so I met the team
when I was at Microsoft
and that was in 2019.
And the entire team
that I knew from
the deal that we
did with Microsoft
and them are gone,
totally gone.
And what's interesting
is then everyone
was, you know,
back then it was,
at least at Microsoft,
It was really
difficult to get
that deal through.
One, my boss's boss
basically said that
this was a stupid idea
and it was basically,
what was Clippy 2
.0 is what he said.
And that was Microsoft.
And now, like
everyone is involved
in, you know,
not involved in
the project. It's
like, oh, yeah,
this was part of
our master plan.
And I digress.
There's no master
plan. It was like
pulling teeth.
Alright, so it looks
like it's still
building, but the
interesting thing here,
I'm watching it build,
and then I ran the
server, but the
server is now running.
So, it looks like it
built an MCP server,
so that's good.
So, what I'm going
to do is, I'm going
to let this finish,
because I'm not sure
exactly what it's
doing, and I'm not
actually sure how
to stop it in the
middle of thinking.
I can exit, it looks
like, and I can
clear, but I don't
know if I can, like,
interrupt.
So, what exactly is
it thinking about?
It looks like it's
running tests.
You know, the other
interesting thing about
this, by the way, I
noticed earlier, and
I've only really been
playing with this for
like this morning, it
seems to be able to
run tests directly as
well. So, if you're
familiar with that sort
of test-driven development
approach we've been
building over the
last year or so, you
can actually use it
directly within this
structure. So basically,
as part of your
guidance, like you saw
where I pointed it at
that readme file, just
include, you know,
additional specifications.
So you could get this
to build the spec.
Then once the spec's
built, basically
you say execute it.
So it does seem to
build really well
kind of on autopilot.
So they've done a
great job of that.
I'm still waiting for
it to stop thinking.
It looks like,
okay, so what we're
seeing right now is
running the command.
so that might and it's
so this might block
it from stopping
though i don't know
i'm going to can i
type here no can i exit
okay okay i just
figured it out i
hit escape twice
now that uh it
so they're the
they're putting in
like common CLI
style interaction.
So if you're old enough
or geeky enough to
know that hitting escape
twice will get you
back to a prompt similar
to what was that?
Vi, I think did
that that way.
That's what
they're doing.
So I guess these guys are
team Vi, not team Emacs.
All right. Let's continue
this and say, I'm
going to give it a
little helping hand. So
what I'm going to do
is I'm going to take
this, hello, and I'm
going to duplicate it.
And now what I'm
going to do is
I'm going to call
this codex MCP.
And I'm going to
tell this to update
the, can I do an at
sign? No, codex MCP.
MCP to implement
the, I've been
using root to
incline too much,
I keep trying
to add signs,
codec CLI. So codec
CLI has a studio
style MCP server,
I don't know if
style is the wrong
word, it's It's just
the studio MCP
server with, well,
what do I want?
With discovery and
various tools for
automated code
development, I
guess. I don't know.
Something like that.
Let's see if you can
figure it out. So, you
see, so just for you
to be aware, I created
a simple hello
world. well, I always
start with something
that works, right? It's
easier to start and
use a template. Once I
know that it generally
worked, I didn't
really test it beyond
the fact that it runs,
but good enough to see
that it actually runs.
So, and we see the
available tools,
so we know that
that works and the
Echo result. So
everything works.
So Echo is the most
basic test that I
generally do. And the
fact that it knew,
how it knew that
I do Echo all the
time, Maybe I am AI
or something, but
it worked, and it
gave me the test
that I needed to
know. I never even
told it that, but
that's kind of cool.
So now I'm going
to use that, and
now I'm giving it
a really simple.
We're going to see if
we can build ourselves
the Codex MCP. Once
we have a Codex MCP,
then I can start
integrating that into Roo
and Pline and Cloud
Desktop and other tools,
and I can access it
that way. and I can
take it a step further,
I could probably start
adding the Spark
protocol to it and maybe
I can do what I did
with those guys at the
boomerang tasks and
do that for the codex.
And we'll call it
Spark Codex until
they sue us for
copyright infringement.
All right. Oh, you
guys hear about the
Lovable and the Figma
thing yesterday?
Yeah, the dev mode.
Like, I look back
to my stuff, I've
taught five different
projects dev mode
over the last,
like, several years.
Figma is ridiculous.
How can you sue
for dev mode? And
who knew that Figma
owned dev mode?
Oh, it's a commonly
known thing?
What?
Yeah, it makes no
sense. Figma. I think it
was a Figma in their
imagination. okay that's
that's hilarious man
i'll have to ask my
buddy who uh who is
who works at uh adobe
oh don't we
never bought them
though did they
that that fell apart
oh i thought they did
no no the their their
founding team is
was all i don't know
something happened
adobe wanted to
buy figma but then
regulators blocked
the the acquisition
oh okay that's that's
not what i heard i
think i think they i
think somewhere someone
pushed someone got cold
feet at adobe because
they heard about
the wild ways of the
founders and a bunch
of other stuff and they
finangled to get out
of the deal that's what
i heard and if you if
you know the uh the
figma founders they
love to party they they
should have they should
have created a crypto
company to be honest
it's right up their
alley but uh technically
the u.s regulators
shut it down i think
is the story that that
people are being told
and i think maybe a
billion dollars on on
not getting the deal
oh awesome hey uh reuben
is it this is a is
this to get this codex
thing running did
you have to install a
um an extension into
vs code uh yeah so so
so in no extension so
i'll show you i'm just
waiting for this it's
banking um so let's
go here to the readme
all right so i
i went to the
open ai slash
code uh codex
repo, and then I just
installed it. So open
AI, so MPMI, G installs
it globally. So it's
a global install, so
you can execute the
codex command, and
that's it. Now, what I
did here is I cloned
the repo with the source
code for the actual
CLI. So in this case,
I went and got it. You
don't need to do that.
You can just do the
MPMI command. But the
reason I am doing it
is I want to actually
not this one, but
this one, I want to
actually steal their,
borrow their CLI and make
it into an MCP. So
that's why I took it.
So,
but you don't need to
do it this way. You
can just literally run
this command so now
it looks like it's
it's creating some code
ruf could you share
your screen please i
you guys can't see my
screen no i can see
it i see it i see it man
thinking yes honestly
if i've been going
if i want a half an
hour you guys without
you guys seeing my
screen then i i'm like
i'm a lunatic um i can
i can stop sharing
if that if is it only
one person that can't
see it or or can
anybody else not see it
it is displaying it's
visible it's visible
yeah no problem yeah
yeah i can see
your face on me
uh i don't know
well maybe you
have to change
the view mode
yeah nothing against
my face but yeah
you don't want me
looking at that
So yeah, I think I'm
staring at a bunch
of like command line
stuff currently.
Not the most exciting
thing to watch.
Let's see what
it's building.
Looks like it's
updating the servers.
I didn't really give it
much guidance though.
Like I didn't tell
it if I wanted to
copy the files. I didn't
I didn't tell it what
file or folder
structure I needed or
wanted so it looks
pretty basic let's take a
look at the code that
it's building just to
see what the one that
was codex which was
on the top of your
screen and the one at
the bottom was a
difference between the two
uh okay the top is
the is the readme
so in this case this
is this views the
source or in this
case, the markdown.
And so in this case,
I just wanted to
read, like the readme
for the GitHub,
right? So this is
telling me everything I
need to know about it.
And then down below,
I'm running the actual
command, right? So
if you want to run
it, like I can run
multiple versions, which
is comfortable too.
So if I want to go in
here and run codecs,
I just, oh, I
exported it in the
other one, I
guess, whatever.
So you're going to
have to export it.
I guess I'm
running it here.
Oh, there we go. It
looks like it's done.
Let's, okay, so let's
quickly see what it says.
Update it, read me,
survey the
show. Let's see,
list off file. Okay,
let's see what let's see
what it does this is
run start I don't can't
tell what it's actually
doing well here
we go I got a different
air this looks pretty
good actually okay so
it built an executable
not really sure what
that does but that's
okay read file it's
kind of a nice feature
write file straight
up codex an echo oh it
looks like there's a type
error relatively minor
error issues now
isn't that ironic the
issues is creating an
issue but okay okay so
that this isn't really
this is a really simple
error luckily so what
we have here is a
echo looks like an echo
error it's not actually
issues it's the echo
meaning it doesn't
return the echo correctly
which is relatively
easy fix I'm just gonna
pop that in there so
this is a perfect example
of why you want to
use test room development
if this had ran
a test it would have
found that error and
automatically fixed it
but I never asked for
any tests so the only
way I could determine
that there was a problem
was by running it
right so what we can do
next is we could what
let's fix this problem
first and let's see
how far we can push the
boundaries of this but
i'm it's it's 12 35
eastern here in toronto
and we've built two
things in 35 minutes
we've we've built the uh
an mcp the hello world
and we built the first
possibly the first
codex mcp mostly other
than this one error
and that took about
five minutes after we
created the first so
so far i'm impressed
these these aren't
necessarily easy code if
anyone's built an mcp
they can be tricky
right especially studio
style ones and this
isn't fully running
yet so i i need to run
it more but it looks
generally correct uh
how would you be able
to tell it to rock to
run a test before it
actually ran it like
spark you could do
that but does this have
the ability for
orchestrated like that it
does uh that was the
first thing i did this
morning i did i was
working on a different
project um i was working
on my um my a2a mcp
server and and it
turns out that a2a mcp
server was actually
relatively comp more
complicated than
anticipated and I ran into a
problem with remote
style SSE. Anyway this
morning I ran it and
you know before our
call and it fixed the
problem in 30 seconds
and I was struggling
to fix it previously.
I would have been able
to fix it I just didn't
have time to look at
it too closely but
the fact that it fixed
it in 30 seconds was
pretty was a pretty
good you know tells me
it's it's pretty good
for sure uh let's see
here with this setup
reuben hypothetically
uh you could have um
the custom room modes uh
invoke the codex mcp
or several instances
of it and be building
out little micro tools
for a project uh yes
that's exactly exactly
so what i'm actually
thinking to start, but
yes, you articulated
it almost perfectly.
Use it to create
multiple instances that I
can invoke using the
MCP server that work as
concurrent or parallel
coding agents that
then report back to the
orchestrator. So right
now, when I'm using
the room modes or the
boomerang stat
tasks approach,
I'm essentially
creating sequential
tasks that run, you know,
sequentially.
So what I was
thinking is what if I
could create rather
than the sequential
tasks of the root
code system what
if I could invoke
codecs but concurrently
in multiple
terminal sessions
to do different
parts of the project.
If that makes sense.
So that's what I'm
yeah so you seem
to know me pretty
well because
that's exactly what
I was thinking.
All right so the
Zod error is gone
let's just go back
and check i'm going
to go back so the
client run client
okay now it's executing
the hello world
result hello looks
like it worked
okay this is great
we built the whole
thing and it works
now this is the part
that i i find more
exciting okay Okay,
let's, you know, create
a unit test frame,
let's create a
series of unit tests
for the codex
MCP and run them.
Okay. So the reason
I want that is I want
to add some crazy new
capabilities to it,
right? So now that I've
been able to get the
codex system to
actually build a kind of
abstraction itself,
which I have to verify,
to be honest, but I'm
not actually overly
concerned about the
core functionality just
yet. i'm more concerned
about the abstract
of the mcp itself then
i need a test framework
confirm that all the
actual capabilities
of the mcp server
actually work so when
i look here i can see
that we've got the
actual structure right
and was that right no
okay yeah so i can see
the structure i see
the tools i see the
readmes i see the writes
i see the the codex
and the echo and then
we test the echo and
the echo returns. So
we know, generally
speaking, that at least
the echo works. Now,
what we don't know is
whether these other
ones work. Now, I could
evoke that going
into Roo, but to be
honest, I don't want
to show you guys my
environmental variables
and all the other things
that go along with
it. So what I'm going
to do instead is I'm
going to just create a
unit test framework
and then get the unit
tests to verify that
all these things work
correctly. Once I have
that, then we're going
to say, let's create
some crazy stuff
with it. Let's create
a concurrent parallel,
blah, blah, blah,
you know, that
hacks the quantum
realm or something.
All right, so
let's create a
test. So now let's
go here and take
a look where
it's doing that.
I'm not sure where it's
creating those tests.
I guess I should probably
just look where
I can see it.
It looks like it might be
creating the
test in line.
Yeah, it's creating the
test directly
in the server.
Or no, what's it doing?
It's still thinking.
It hasn't created
anything yet.
And which model are
you using here, Aru?
Well, I'm using the
one that's default.
I haven't figured
out how to
change the model yet.
So it's using the
open, the 03, oh,
sorry, 04 mini.
so what i don't know
to be honest and maybe
someone else can tell
me if they figured
it out i don't know
how to switch this to
03 i think the problem
is most people don't
have access to 03
via the api so they
probably didn't bother
making it easy to do but
unlike most people
i have access so i'm
curious and the 03
model is actually most
is supposedly better
for this so we'll see
all right looks like
it's still thinking
when it turns you know
when it turns green it
means it made it
made a real it made a
change but i'm not sure
what exactly changed
so what the biggest
difference i think that
i see with this is
it doesn't it doesn't
need to do any Any of
that sort of scanning
stuff you see in
RueCode or Klein or
other sort of IDE style
like cursor, it does
it all in these kind
of containerized
code components that
you see in the bottom.
So that's interesting.
You know what we
could do probably is
we could create a VS
Code extension similar
to how root code.
And then we can expose
this directly in the
same style as root
code. It's already
using JavaScript and
TypeScript. So as anyone's
built a VS code
extension knows, it's
all JavaScript and
TypeScript anyway. So
we could probably fairly
easily modify this
to be, you know, a
codex IDE extension.
And we could probably get
this thing to build it.
so after i create
the mcp i'll
get it i'll see
if i can get it
to create a vs
code extension
for that's why i was
asking that's why i was
asking earlier right
is is this is this
an extension or or is
it something that's
running that's piping
code in here piping out
it's a cli it's not
an extension so it's a
terminal session
right it's a terminal
session yeah but it could
be so that your comment
inversely got me
thinking it could be a
extension in the same
way that ru is an
extension right so rather
than having this silly
sort of interface down
here what we could
do maybe is just when
i just copy the same
basic interface as
ru maybe what i could
and and rather than
executing the coding
sessions in the ide
sort of that thing that
spins along in up in
here in the top right,
we could have it run
these things, but do it
and pipe it into the
UI over on the left.
I might be rambling. I
hope that makes sense.
It's a good ramble
is kind of what I was
thinking. I was like,
yeah, maybe just, but
I'm trying to figure
out what the benefits,
the real benefit
is. I mean, it seems
pretty nice to watch
this terminal output.
Well, we can output
the same terminal
output. but we can
put it directly in
the same sort of
UI style as this,
which is a little
more elegant, right?
Yeah, natively within
the VS Code app.
Yeah.
Yeah, and then I guess
you could do other
stuff, right, within
the app. You could
kind of extend the
capability of Codex.
Yeah,
exactly. So I think I
inversely sort of came
up with your idea that
you suggested that
just came out from the
opposite direction.
Check this out.
It's running the
tests, coding, and
running tests. So
now it's concurrently,
it's using a
diff structure,
which is interesting.
Okay, so it created,
it updated the file.
then what it did you
can see the code this is
the see so for those
that are familiar the
diff before after
basically and and then down
here it then said it
it successfully patched
it then what it did
is it checked this
server then it's making
sure that it works then
it's running the
test you can see it's
running test at hh which
is weird like why is
it running a test us
at sh i would run it as
just so it needs it
it the codex seems a
little bit like an
untrained baby it needs a
little bit more guidance
but that's no problem
we could probably use
a guide or create a
guide for it possibly
but anyway it it did the
test did did run and
it gave us a we've got
a memory leak which
is a great result
actually it's now it's
trying to fix the memory
So those diffs,
the diff output,
unlike Spark, right,
where you're saving
the diffs to a vector
database for leverage
along later on,
historical leverage,
it was just doing
the diff for its own
use in that moment?
Yes, it's
exactly. So in the
Spark, I'm doing
the same thing.
The only
difference is, pun
intended, is
I'm saving that
information for
later reference.
So if it does something
similar, it'll
find the previously
implemented code and
use that rather than
going and asking the
LLM, which is cheaper
and faster and easier.
but I think given
that they've open
sourced their entire
CLI I think I can
relatively easily port
all the Spark stuff I
did remember the
guys that have been
around long enough,
Bron and Rob and others
remember the Spark
CLI created back
in October, we
could do basically
that style CLI
directly in this codex
and it would give us all
the same capabilities
all right so
let's continue i
think that saving
the diffs is a
good it's a great
idea actually
you know even if you
know you don't you
do it personally right
for your own coding
style as your personal
sort of coding
coding ai reference
that's great if you have
a global have a global
diff of everybody's
like you know diffs
that that's even
that might actually be
better yeah well that's
that that's a that's
a massive data
leak but yes it at least
it is right yes yeah
it'd be it'd be
useful in the same way
that like me asking
random questions to
to uh chat gpt knows
knows about me let's
let's do that while
we're uh waiting for
that to finish Let's
go back and chat to
you for a second. We'll
choose over three.
Give me an existential...
Why is existential such
a... I massacred that.
Existential
overview of me.
Let's see what
it comes up with.
uh it's is it too early
today for existentialism
which i apparently
can't spell it is
here in san francisco
that's for sure it's
never too early yeah i
know it's never really
too early in san francisco
for anything yeah
that that was that was
my monday morning i
had a like an existential
crisis and posted
some crazy **** all
right i wake up each
morning bewildered by
how quickly intelligence
is becoming abundant
okay come on yeah me i
think i think i wrote
that earlier today but
anyway uh yet meaning
still feels scarce oh
my god this this thing
kind of scares me a
little bit especially
when it does this it's
it literally is the
kind of **** that i like
to talk about logic
neural intuition non uh
run non-stop like a
stream of consciousness
this could literally
be a post I do later.
So as you're
on this topic,
you asked anything
new earlier.
I'm curious. I don't
see a lot of people
talk about data
privacy. And I see here,
Brini, Sam, Finn. So
I was working on a
Jeeves agent this week.
And I was trying to
decide if I was going
to say my height,
my weight, my mom's
name, my kid's name.
I was just trying to
figure out if how deep
i wanted to go what is
your take on the day
that you put yeah yeah
i well i i've also
created an astronomical
amount of code i
created i created an
ai specifically that
targets my own dna on
the maternal side so in
like 100 years my great
great grandchildren
will get a message and
some crypto tokens so
i i might not be the
the best uh for you
know if i'm comfortable
like legitimately you
know hiding a you know
an ai that unlocks
with my dna like some
sort of treasure hunt
then you know what
else you need to know
about me yeah why not
right okay yeah oh well
it knows it knows
everything about my kids
yeah so if you think you
have any privacy
you don't um
it keeps something
human he crowds
his ideas for everywhere
chemistry sets
gaming mods how
does it know that
funny thing is
whether you tell
it or not it's
going to know it
there's just so much data
out there in
the world today
yeah i don't know
about sam but he seems
to have gotten finn
and isla pretty well
Creepy.
A little creepy.
And I just shared it
with all you guys,
which is probably adds
to the creepy factor.
All right.
Where are we at
here? Let's give this
another run and see
how bad it's broken.
I'm just curious what
kind of test
it's running.
Where did it
put those tests?
Yeah, the O3 is
a great model.
No question.
I thought I
said it created
a test.sh somewhere.
Oh, it's creating it
in MCP Hello World.
Interesting.
I don't think
I asked it to do that.
Like Spark, where
you have these master
specs, right, that
it can go through.
You don't have that
for this, right?
So that's why we
don't know why and why
it created this
Hello World. So it's
just you gave it a
tiny little prompt
to say do this, and
it it's done all
this **** yeah it's
it's also the tests
like are weird like
it's installing it
it's not exiting it
all right i'm just
gonna it looks like it
got confused with
the original guidance
which is interesting
So, yeah, to your point,
it's like anything
else, I'm vibe coding
it. We're vibe coding,
right? I'm not giving
it really any guidance.
I just gave it
some really rudimentary,
I want to create
an MCP. But other
than that, I didn't
tell it anything about
structure, testing,
file formats,
nothing, right? And
this is a perfect
example of why vibe
coding doesn't work,
right? I didn't give
it enough guidance.
so rather than you
know continuing like
you you're creating and
using the MCP folder
which I told to use
it went and decided
to go and do all the
tests in the hello
world folder all right
so I'm gonna stop
this for a sec and
I'm gonna I'm gonna
go back here and I'm
going to you know I'm
gonna try something
totally different.
I'm going to go here.
And I'm going to
create a new folder.
And we're going
to call it
Codex, VS Code extension.
And then what we're
going to do is I'm going
to type it in here
because it's easier.
Where is that?
Looks like there's
other CLI references.
I'm going to grab
this right here.
In this case, what
we're going to do is
create a basic VS Code
extension that uses
We're going to use the
source code directly.
And I'm going to go
in and I'm going to
yeah, I'm going to
use this codex CLI and
creates It's a basic
UI to manage the CLI,
the web extension.
Yeah, that sounds good.
Let's do that.
Reuben, if you want...
Hello?
Yeah, sure.
If you want to use O3,
you can just pass it in.
Oh, I can? How
do we do that?
I've pasted it in
the chat so it's
just it's just
dash dash model
oh dash dash model
yeah dash dash model
repaste it okay let me
find it looks like this
okay let's let's
let's let's do
it let's do it with
let's do it with
oh three and see
what happens.
So, so I had that at the
big, at the
end, you think?
Oops,
I don't know. It's
not specific. I mean,
the command is codex
minus M and then you
specify the model
number. Generally, if
you want to do it
from the cursor, the
terminal directly as
well, you can do that.
Sorry, so I'm
putting that at the
beginning here
as a full mode.
It's not clear where
I should put it.
Probably here.
Yeah, I mean,
yeah, I'd say at
the beginning.
And you said it's
GPT-03, not just 03?
That's what I
got. That's what I
but you can also
use dash dash M
GPT-03. I think
both pass through.
Okay, well, let's see
what happens with that.
All right.
Nope, that didn't work.
The model doesn't
appear list. Okay, so
it's not that, I think
it's actually 03.
03.
Okay.
All right.
because they
dropped this because
the other O3s
were O3 mini, so
I assume it's
the same general.
Let's see here.
Okay, it worked.
O3.
All right, now we're
cooking with gas.
That might be
Canadian expression.
All right, so
let's see what it
does here. So now
we're going to create
a VS Code extension
for Codex.
apparently 03 is better
if you believe the stats
it's i guess 03 03
is the new 01 pro
which makes it which
is better than the
04 mini their their
naming conventions
make no sense
how so 04 mini is
somehow an 04 mini
high are worse than 03
It's the most
confusing part
about trying to
decide what to use
where and when
every other day.
You have to
switch your models
to figure out
what the setup is.
Yeah.
All right.
Doing stuff.
Let's take a look
at the folder.
Yeah, it's
creating the SRC.
Now, if I was doing
this, just to be honest,
what I would have
done is use the Yeoman
package to create the
scaffolding and then
updated the scaffolding.
It appears to be
building everything from
scratch and installing
it. We'll see if it gets,
if it's smart enough
to use the scaffolding
here in a second.
Oh, yeah, it is.
It just did it.
Okay. It's not stupid.
All right. So we
can see here that
it's, I think it's
what it installs.
No, I'm not sure
what it's installing.
No, it's built.
It looks like
it's building
from scratch.
Yeah, it's, that's
not the best
way to build a VS
Code extension.
It's kind of a
silly way to do it.
This would greatly
increase the cost.
Okay. Open the
VS code, start
debugging, launch
the extension host.
Start.
Okay. In the
command palette.
F5.
You'll have, I
don't want that.
And you're not
clear exactly
in the, I think
it's at one, not at five.
It's not clear what
view codecs open
manager three
performance. It's not
clear how I actually
get it to run.
i think this needs
to run the cli
um use you know
creates the vs code
template integrate
the uh so
moral of the
story still needs
definitely needs
guidance and
needs plans and
needs tests.
So all the problems
we're running into
right now are purely
a lack of guidance.
You do it.
Here we go.
Now it's installing that.
So I think the VSCO
VSCE is the tool
that builds the
scaffolding, which
basically creates
all the files.
So it did create
something.
Let's just go see
if we can run it.
Oh, yeah, it did create
a bunch of stuff.
Okay, try, okay,
so now you can,
yeah, okay.
Now it's installed
VS locally.
Okay, that's
what we'll do.
Me do it, but
that's okay.
Extension,
where did I put it?
Yeah, I'm just
fooling around. I'm
trying to, it says
it created that
somewhere. I think
it's in this file.
but there's a vsix
file in there yeah
yeah i think it
created as a binary
uh okay how do i run it
now okay
it's
simply installed
it's installed now
try it in any
vs code instance
extensions yeah
So, which one is it,
back and ask it,
these, it doesn't,
yeah, it is, VS Code, VS
Code, GitHub,
no, is that,
yeah, I think this is it,
it just was a weird name,
exciting times,
Are we feeling secure
yet? All right.
I think I'm in.
It's something.
A very, very basic
VS Code extension,
and it took a
couple minutes.
Now it doesn't do
anything, mind you, but
I don't think it'd
be long before I can
start adding UI.
So, okay, so we just
go back here and say
update the VS code.
Yes.
Code.
Codex.
Extension.
You include the UI.
I'm
not really sure what
the heck it built. This
is basically just,
it's just the default.
But you can log in
with your GitHub,
which is kind
of interesting.
I think the icon was
already there before.
So it must be
something else.
Maybe.
Are you saying
this is like
some sort of
project extension?
one quick clarifying
question so obviously
when you change the
model like two or three
um with codex obviously
your data and code
is still local but in
terms of the interactions
with the language
model it obviously
doesn't get to see the
code it doesn't get
the token there right
how where does the link
happen in terms of
it's sending the
information back to 03
or 04 mini you know it's
it's basically just
you know same as most
other uh llm based
apps it has to send the
data as payload to the
model otherwise the
model can't tokenize
it it's got nothing to
exactly and it's
using it as you can
tell here it's using
a diff structure so
it's it's using a
patch so in this case
you can see that
it's adding or
subtracting in this
case various information
so it's adding this
it's looking for
something and then
patching it this is a
good way to do it by
the way so it's not
attempting to write
the entire file it's
only it's only doing
diffs and Basically,
it's using the
same approach that
the guys in Ader
popularized a year ago.
Ader was
definitely ahead of
the curve on
using diffs. So
they're using the
same structure.
And if you look
at the clod CLI,
they end up doing
the same thing.
Run once.
Compile. VS code package.
Debug.
Command line.
Okay. Okay, let's just
do it one more time.
I think you're
right. I think that
thing on the side
wasn't even it.
All right, so,
oh, missing.
That's because I
probably skipped that.
Okay, well, why
don't we test it?
Codex OpenManager.
Okay.
OpenManager Explorer.
Oh,
this is what we
actually wanted to see.
running start codex
start CLI okay
okay CLI
okay so I see
what I basically
yeah I'm not gonna
do the I'm not gonna
do my um I'm not
gonna do my key here
for obvious reasons
but it has a very
rudimentary integration
with VS code
it worked and I
didn't really I didn't
really see any
bugs, which is cool.
So now I can
directly integrate
the codecs into VS Code
specifically. So if
I want to modify or
have commands, I can
do that. Now, I would
say the easiest way to
integrate codecs into
root code or client
for those who are
using it would be to
use the command option.
I'm going to show you
that quick. I've got
a few minutes where
I have to jump. so in
in root code you've
got the option here
under I think it's
prompts and we can go to
here and we'll go to
edit through modes oops
there we go we have
custom modes I'm gonna
go to I'm gonna go
grab mine quick so
we're gonna go to my
gist and grab the roof
and I'll show you There's
a nice little trick
that I've been
playing with for doing
code-based approaches or
command, sorry, command
-based approaches, I
think it's called.
So we go in here.
All right, so I'm
just going to grab
that raw version
of my orchestrator.
And, you know, I'm
probably going to
use this orchestrator
for codecs, too.
I just haven't
gotten around to it.
That's the next stage.
I'm not going to use
room modes for this.
I'm going to actually
use the global modes.
I'm going to use global.
Mix it in. Give it a sec.
you can see it show up.
All right. So here's
an interesting thing
you can do with this.
So in this case, you see
how we have different
groups, right? And
we have read, I think
I might have a command
in here somewhere.
Yeah, command, that's
it. So we can do command
modes. So I'm going
to grab the command
and we're going to grab
down right to here.
And go to the bottom.
And I'm going to
add this here.
All right. Did I break
it? It looks broken.
You missed the open.
Oh, is that what I did?
Yep.
Okay.
All right.
Perfect. Good eye.
And I'll get rid of
you with closing.
So now we're
going to call this
one, we're going
to call this codex.
In this case,
we're going to
get rid of all
other commands.
And in this case, we're
going to, you know,
I'm going to keep this
as an orchestrator.
Why not? And I'm going
to say using only
the terminal command
and codex with the,
what is it, with the,
what do we got here?
I'm still getting
an error, I'm
still getting
a, looks like a
JavaScript error
too for some reason.
What am I missing here?
Anyway,
it's not showing
up for some reason.
probably because
I broke it.
Let's modify an
existing one.
Let's just modify DevOps
and we'll call that.
That one worked.
Okay. Let's just
use that instead.
I'm too lazy to
figure out why it
is. I'm going to
use the command.
It
doesn't seem to
like that structure.
No, I think it's okay.
All right.
This
is generally
easier than having
to worry about
an NCP server.
All right. Is it
going to run? I need
to probably give it
current mode codex.
That's a lot of text
for something I just
wanted it to run,
but we'll see what it
does. I'd probably
give it better guides.
Let's
just run it.
So now if I want that to
I want that to
auto run, I've
got that turned
on, all I need
to do is go grab
this, go here,
scroll down until I
find this, add to my
list of auto run
commands, add, save, done,
auto runs, I didn't
click anything,
so it auto runs,
we know that works,
and I don't have the
key in, but boom, now
I've essentially, I'm
going to cancel that,
but now I've created a
terminal style command
option that will only
run that command.
Now I can add, you
know, all the other
information here as
well. So what I can do
is I'm going to go
to my code one and
here, and I'm going to
just add this because
this generally works
the way I like the
code includes the
details of completion
and some other details.
So we're going to
go back to the bottom,
wherever that was,
and we're going to
paste that in here.
All right.
I'm going to go
back here and
grab the overall
guidance.
And I'm going to use code
one for that as well.
This is basically telling
it how I like the code.
And then the last part we
need to do is
after that, and
then I'm going to go
here for a moment.
So, we've got
that. But what we
don't have is we don't
have the commands
it needs to use.
So, what I'm
going to do is this
is custom modes.
Okay.
Update the
following instructions
And then I'm going to
switch to my ask mode,
and then we're going
to just grab that.
So what I'm doing again,
rather than having
to worry about an
MCP server, let's be
honest, A CLI is
basically an MCP server.
I'm just creating
a unique role that
includes all the
requirements that I need.
So that looks good.
I'm going to
just grab this,
copy that, and then
I'm going to go here,
put that in here.
Perfect.
Go back here.
Oh, invalid.
Oh, that's because
I forgot this.
I think that
should fix it.
I don't know.
Sometimes you need
to play around with
it to get the exact
guidance and prompt
right. What I'm
trying to see here is
if it will actually
execute correctly.
It's still struggling
in the first job. It
did an analysis, which
is probably the right
thing to do. I
want to see if it
actually executes
on the command line.
Ask a follow-up
question. It didn't work.
Still isn't executing. So
I'm going to add that
to the guidance as well.
Still not executing.
It has the
ability to do it.
Yeah, it worked
that time.
Oh, no, it ran
the wrong one.
Dummy. So
it's a little bit
of back and forth.
I'm sure I'll get
this working five
seconds after this
call is over. But
basically, it doesn't
know that codex is
a command it can
run. So now I've
figured it out. So
what I need to do, I'm
going to put it into
codex. So codex,
I got to add the right
JavaScript around
it, this command,
the terminal, I
basically need to
tell it like how
it needs to run.
Single quotes will
work in there.
Otherwise, you
can backslash it.
Command the terminal.
Never ask.
Just run the command
in the ‑‑ I'm being a
little redundant here
but uh let's just try
one more time again
i don't have the api
keys set up correctly
but i don't even care
i just want to see that
you know create a uh
ruben you've extended
the mcp tool list
right to have a codex
command and uh you're
you're trying to get
it to run that command
I bypassed MCP
altogether.
I'm just basically
creating a
command-based
system here called
Codex, which
you see here.
And I want it
to automatically
execute as subtasks.
So in this case,
never ask, just
run the command
in the terminal or
use subtasks, new
underscore task.
It
probably just needs
more details and
it's confused.
It doesn't really
fully understand what
codex is supposed
to do. So it's
just bad guidance.
I'm not fiddling
around with this
and eventually you
get it to work.
All right, I got
another call in five
minutes. I probably
need to prep for, but
hopefully this was
helpful for everyone.
Yeah, okay. Anyway,
it's asking me,
yes, why don't
you believe me?
Basically, I just need
to give it a little
better, like, don't,
like, all the things
it's asking for, I
just need to tell it.
Here we go.
Bam.
I did it.
I'm going to give
you guys this.
All right.
So now we have,
who needs an MCP?
All we need is
this, and I'm
gonna give it
to you guys.
This is just
an extension of
the Rue code
extension, right?
Yeah, but the
Rue extension.
A Rue code extension,
a Rue code mode,
I guess is what
they call it, that's
specifically for
codecs. So you can
get Rue code to
orchestrate the codecs,
which is cool, right?
In the orchestrator mode.
And the benefit of
that is that we get to,
so you have an...
It has all these
other modes that
it can work within.
Documents and
DevOps and security.
So as I build out
the new version of
Codex, I'm going
to eventually not
want to use Roo at
all, but I'm going
to use Roo to modify
Codex to a point
where I can bypass
Rue altogether.
And could you,
the one question
I haven't asked
before is, each of
those modes, could
you assign a different
language model
like for the document
specification?
Yes.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
That's exactly what
I do. Each mode
has a different
language model.
So I'll call
this codexmode.
All right. that
you're good
a chance to try
that plug-in the guy
suggested a couple
meetings back
that hides the
environment variables
in VS Code it's a
VS Code plug-in and
it hides environment
variables and
keys and he
suggested it to us
while you were
to you and just
I don't even
remember what that
was at this
point. Me either.
There's only so much.
Yeah, there's too
much. I can't even
keep all this stuff
in my brain. I'll see
if I find it and
I'll send it to you.
I shared the
link, though, for
you guys to
the codex mode.
If you want it, go to
the link in the text
and you can just copy
and paste it. You saw
what I just did. So
just copy and paste it
into your Rue modes
file and you've got the
basis of a new codex.
style mode um we
built some stuff totally
vibe coding today
though this was this
was like 100 just random
stuff takeaway plan
you know watch out for
your environmental
variables you know and
you can build stuff it
all it all basically
works so nothing there's
no better feeling
than when it actually
works front to back
90 minutes yeah um
tomorrow i think we're
gonna do a ai hackerspace
because why not it's
a holiday for some
maybe we'll get some
more new people who
don't have to work uh if
you're if you've got
anything you want to
show tell discuss
we've got openings talk
to robert here he'll
uh he'll hook you up
and actually uh reuben
we've got uh uh hans
from roo code tomorrow
for a lending uh
canadian apparently from
edmonton alberta yeah
Yeah, so we'll
have the Ruko guys
here. So that
should be great.
Yeah, by the way, that
Spark thing went crazy.
Like the post did 125
,000 views on my Reddit.
And as you can
see, I can't
see the exact numbers,
but I've got 135
stars in that
repo, which is a
gist. I've never had
a gist to have
135 stars before.
So apparently
that Spark thing
was the right
Spark. All right.
I'm done I'll see
you guys next week
thanks thank you
love you guys bye