Okay.
Hopefully this
is helpful.
Everyone's like, how
do you build so much
stuff so quickly? So
I thought I'd just
quickly give you
the breakdown. And I
was, I was attempting
to build something.
I started this, I
started about 10 minutes
ago. So for those
who are interested,
all right. If you
can mute yourselves
again, this is the
call for whatever
reason, it doesn't
seem to mute.
And good to see you,
Chris and everyone.
All right. So I'm in VS
Code. I've
started a project.
You can see I'm
running, I created an ad
generator because I
was curious. Everyone's
asking about this new
ad, sorry, the new
image API from OpenAI
that came out, I
think earlier this week,
maybe last week, and
how to use it. So a
couple things to note,
you're going have to
validate your account
in open ai so that
requires let me just
show you quickly what
that requires for
anyone that's interested
so you have to go
here and there's a
validate organization
under general value
organization once you
click that that
basically pops up this
little screen and you
basically have to scan
a picture of your
your driver's license
and a left and right
image of your face
god knows what they're
going to do with
that but nothing good
i'm sure but anyway
once once you have that
then that activates
a lot of their newest
models including
the i think oh three
main model and the uh
and the image model
which is what i actually
wanted so once i
add that i went into
rue so this is a brand
new repo so actually
so let's just go
and i'll show you
exactly the flow so you
know how that works.
So in GitHub,
what I did is I
created a new repo.
If I can find my GitHub.
Too many open GitHub.
And I called
it image agent.
So basically
all I did is I
created a new repo.
There's nothing
in the repo at
all. Literally
just a repo with a
readme and a gitignore.
So when I created the
repo, I essentially
created a node.js repo
so when you go I'll just
go show you exactly
what that looks like so
you go into new repo
and then a couple things
to note when you are
creating a new repo
you know to choose your
owner I've got multiple
accounts obviously
so I'm giving it a
name public or private
in this case I made my
public I don't care
it's important you click
on the readme to make
sure that and the readme
is important because it
basically initializes
the repo otherwise
you have to do an
initial commit, which
is why bother? That
basically does the initial
commit. In this case,
I chose the git ignore.
I just typed node.
And then I license. I
generally choose MIT
because I give away
all my stuff. But it's
up to you. You don't
necessarily have to do
this at all. I just like
to do that. And then
once you have that,
you can go back and it
creates this. Now,
once you have this in
place, you can go here
and create a using code
spaces. you can create
a new code space
and you can see here
i've already got one
running called turbo
enigma which i basically
started here and i
like to invoke my code
spaces from the ui just
it sets everything up
and then a few minutes
later i jump into vs
code so then once i
got my vs code running
i went in here and
i'm not going to
show you exactly
what my my env is but
my env essentially
includes my OpenAI
API key, which I'm
not going to show
you. And then what
I did is I went into
Roo and I set up
my Roo MCP server.
So the MCP server
essentially sets up all
the MCP related
information. Now, the other
thing that I did in
Roo before I started is
I went and I copied my
my root code room modes
I guess they call it
so I did that right
here so I went here and
I chose I think it's
edit global modes
which is basically what
guides it so this is
these are my modes that
you see here the
specifications the DevOps
this is tutorial this
is what makes it all
kind of work and it
works pretty well so
then what I so now that
I have this this this
is based I just copy
-pasted from my other
projects if you need
this you can grab it from
my I just, the guys
at RuCode have asked
me to commit my Spark
approach to the repo.
Maybe I should do that
today, but they
essentially,
they wanna integrate
that directly into
RuCode now. So maybe
that's a project
we'll do while we're
doing that today.
But basically this is
what makes it all work.
Okay, so now, so,
you know, again, just
if you wanna find
that, for those who
don't know where that
is, you can go to my
gist and I'll just
pop that in the chat
for you and here we
go it's in the chat
and under just
you'll see that
if you scroll
down you'll find
somewhere in my
pile of stuff the
where is it here's the
client rules this is
what you need this is
the room modes i've
made modifications to
it since but this will
get this will get you
going so just just
go to room modes and
just copy and paste
that doing the raw or
whatever and select all
kind of thing and
you're good to go all
right so you so now we
have that now what i'm
going to do is i'm
going to use the browser
mode so i'm going to
hit f1 and i'm going
to do simple browser
show now the reason
i want the simple
browser show is i'm and
today i'm too lazy to
how to jump between so
i'm just going to use
that so i'm going to
choose browser show
and i'm going to find
the url quickly wherever
that is So I'm just
going to load that,
start this up again.
I'm going to npm run dev.
All right. So
this is the URL.
So then we're going
to go here, and
then I'm going to
hit F1 yet again.
And I'm going
to, all right.
And simple browser
show, pop this in here.
now this what what's
nice about this and is
i i don't have to
leave the interface to
see what's going on so
i can kind of have a
it it kind of it
basically works the same
as lovable in this
scenario you can kind of
work and edit in real
time was what was what
we want to do so i'm
going to i'm going
to close this and just
start at the beginning
of where i started
so in this case i'm
going to just give this
a bit more room. I'm
going to cancel. I'm
going to cancel this.
It's like it's,
okay. So I'm going
to go right, I'm
going to go all the
way to the very
top and show you
where, where I,
what I started with.
All right. So
my initial task
was actually
pretty simple.
So just to recap, I
created, I created a
new GitHub repo and
I went and created,
you know, So a, you
know, initial API key
for OpenAI, which I
went and got approved.
And then I copy and
pasted that into my
environmental variables,
which I'm not going
to attempt not to
show you. But then I
said, test the curl.
So I grabbed the
example curl, which
I actually tested
previously and in a
different browser just to
make sure that everything
actually worked.
And what that did is
essentially gave me
the ability to know
that the actual API
worked, which is when
I realized that I
needed to go and
approve my organization.
So anyway,
that, why is that?
All right.
So then I created a
really simple task.
Test the curl,
single responsive
modern UI
using the curl
text, sticky. I
said, create a
sticky header,
fundable startup.
I don't know.
This is an important
one. this is something
I've been doing a lot
lately is the idea
of using scaffolding
and it turns out and
I'm probably going to
write a post on it here
in the next day or
so but it turns out
writing scaffolding or
using scaffolding for
auto-generated code
is kind of like a
performance enhancer
for the code because it
rather than having to
write all the code your
yourself the scaffolding
will actually go
and generate all the
a lot of the pieces
that you need and if
you look at things like
lovable or vo or mpx
or a lot of the these
tools that are coming
up they're all using
sort of pre pre-built
templates to uh to
do a lot of the sort
of initial work rather
than writing all the
code which costs you
money for the tokens
and whatnot this speeds
up the process so
one of the one of the
more interesting i'm
using the mpx approach
right now but there's
also a cookie cutter
library I think it's
called let's let's
find that quick let's
go here I think Python
and Python cookie cutter
has the most amount
of options cookie
cutter I think that's
what I think it's
what it's called yeah
this is awesome so Python
cookie cutter allows
you it doesn't just
just doesn't just
build scaffolding for
Python, it builds it
for almost every language.
And there's 1000s
and 1000s of different
options for Python
cookie cutters. So
if you're looking at
using, you know,
quickly building
something rather than
letting the AI sort
of build everything
from scratch, you
might do this. So
let's just give you
an example. Let's
go to perplexity.
And I'm going to,
let's say I have
an idea, you know,
what are some
good Python cookie
cutter templates
Let's say I want to use
using supabase
npm node.js,
good enough, let's
see what that says.
I'm going to do
search. I still
like perplexing
better than the search
in ChatGPT. I
don't know, it just
gives me better
results, I find.
But you could
easily do this in
the ChatGPT web
search as well.
All right, so now this is
telling me some
good options.
Cookie cutter
templates with
your node page,
generate Python,
how to apply the
CRM template.
So this is giving
me some ideas on
some of the different
cookie cutter
packages for Python
on and cookie
cutter MPMs and how
to customize it.
There are no
other bucks for
CRMs in SuitBase.
That's fine.
Give me some broader
examples using
cookie cutter
to achieve the same
results using multiple,
I wonder if there's
something that you
could get the architect
mode to figure
out, like, on the
template first.
Yeah, that's what I did.
So you see here, I
actually, I didn't
use cookie cutter,
I used MPX create.
So for those
that are familiar
with the create
concept for
MPX, it's doing
the same thing.
I said, keep it simple,
focus on the
MVP to start.
And then we can see
here, it created, you
know, the orchestrator
was initialized,
and then it created a
subtask. I'm not going
to show you the
subtask because I'm in
the orchestrator
mode currently, but
basically it came up
with the initial spec
that was completed. Then
it came up with this
advertisement generator
specification.
You can see it's
quite a bit of stuff.
And that, so one of
the things you could,
what's interesting
actually about the Spark
approach is the initial
specification. And
what it's doing is
it's taking the spec,
but it's not actually
writing the specification
to the actual MD.
It's actually creating
the spec and putting
it into the memory.
So the context rather
than, and then passing
that context as an
orchestration and then
building it iteratively
from that point of
view. I kind of like
it. It's a bit faster,
but it's another way
to do it. So then it
passes it to the
architect mode that goes
ahead and creates an
initial sort of, you know,
spec document, which
we can see here. I'm
going to pause the dog
barker, sorry guys.
All right, so then that
pet gets passed and
we see here that it
created basically a
really simple architecture
that we see here.
And I was looking for
simple here. This is
literally something I
built in five minutes.
Now we don't see this
particularly well
here because these
are diagrams that
aren't being rendered.
I don't think actually
that makes me
wondered is is I think
there is a diagram
option let's let's
install it yeah if
you enable mermaid it
works on the on the
same window yeah so
2.6 million
downloads that sounds
like a good
chart is better
actually the
official oh it is
the one below is
better mermaid
chart the one
the one keep
yeah that one
that one is better
okay it's interesting
that the 3.5 million
is uh sorry guys i'm
just if you again if
you guys are talking
please mute yourself um
all right so uh yeah
i solved that so let's
let's go back take a
look at what that what
that looks like uh all
right hey reuben you
know when the when
When Spark Orchestrator
created that scaffold,
you didn't code that,
right, when I put it
into memory and the
context. It just decided
to do that itself.
Yeah, it decided
to do it itself.
All right.
I only gave it like
three lines, right?
I basically said,
build me something for
the image generation
system from OpenAI.
And that's really all
I told it. I'm vibe
coding this pretty
much, but I'm vibe
coding it with a
structure. So this is the
structure, right? So
in this case, it's
using the, you know,
it contains the
download functions and
API keys, the backend
proxies, and then
we have a data flow.
Now, is this for me
or is this for the
AI? It's for the
AI, right? I don't
really care. It's
useful to know what it
built, I guess. So
now I can see that.
Now it's giving some
implementation
instructions.
It's giving some
more API integration.
And ultimately, this
is what it built. So
now we can go back to
the simple browser.
We can see here.
Now, I don't think
it's fully built yet.
So let's say create
me a Toronto agentix
meetup image. image.
All right, generate
advertisement. Now, the
issue that we have
with the preview, to be
honest, is I don't
see the actual result
particularly well. And
I don't think this was
working earlier. And
I don't see the error.
So the drawback again
is the fact that these
images take a while
to generate, so it's
hard to tell if
it's failing or not.
So what I probably
need to do next is
figure out why I'm
not getting the image
by doing some kind
of console or browser
or browser console
based test. So in
this case, I'm just
going to quickly
look and see if I can
see anything here.
Ruv, whilst you do
that, you know the
curl.text that you
used as a prompt
to Ruv, is that something
that you defined
something in that
curl.text file?
I did. I went
to, I basically
went and tested
it as a curl.
I'm not showing it to
you because I've got
my key in there.
Basically, what I want
to do is make sure
that the thing worked.
So now I'm actually,
I'm not seeing the
image output, and I'm
not sure if there's
an error. So there's
two ways to actually
test this. The easiest
way is I'm going
to go back to the
browser for a moment.
And I got a
lot of browsers
open, but let's
go back here.
And then we'll
go here. And
I'm going to go inspect.
It looks like it's
just not parsing.
My guess is it's not
parsing the actual
image. So create
a sample meetup
image and then
generate advertisement.
Now, again, it's saying
it's complete, but
it's not showing.
That's because probably,
again, I need to figure
out where that is. So
what I'm going to do
now, I'm going to let
this hopefully fail or
be done. Then I'm going
to add a output of
the result directly to
my actual terminal or
browser console, and
then I'll get it to
parse the JSON correctly.
What I could
have done also is
basically gave
it the response
format that it
was expecting.
That's the other
option I have here.
Unfortunately,
it takes 30
seconds or so
for this to work.
While it's doing
that, Reuben, I got a
question for you. when
you were setting up your
room modes at the very
beginning there that
was awesome and i've
just gone through this
myself actually with
with chris royce he
was helping me um you the
uh custom instructions
you didn't show the
custom instructions
you didn't dump that
in did you need to
dump that in the custom
instructions for room
mode i did yeah it's
yeah so under prompts
you go here you go to
you can do edit global
modes or project i
don't really know
what the differences
i think the difference
is room mode shows
up in your repo where
this is like in a global
settings like outside
of the user space
i'm not really sure
what the difference is
i i noticed that the
global mode shows up
more quickly without
having to refresh so
i use that and then
that so then i just
copy and paste that in
and as soon as it
initializes you'll see
a listing of those
and i i've made a few
minor changes this
since i published it on
gist but i but generally
it's the same yeah
but down more in the
on the on the down
the list this is this is
the custom instructions
right for for global
which is where
you put these are the
individual remote um
instructions yeah
but down more is
that big bulk section
yeah that's it
customer that one
yeah yeah that's
you didn't that's
that's right here
that that's these
that's this line
oh okay that's okay
i thought yeah so
yeah so i thought
it was a global one
if we go let's let's
just go to super
admin super base admin
for a sec and that
is the super base
admin isn't in my uh in
my gist that i use
this for my to sort
of automate my data
science related
activities but just to
prove that this this
works uh you are super
you are the super
base admin scroll
down a little further
I'll just add one two
three and you will
see one two three
shows up here so it's
basically just another
interface for it
you do have one more
global file which yeah
talks about you and
your coding styles in
general what to do
right yeah yeah their
client I root root I
think it's this one
here this is your rules
that md now the rules
i i use that for more
complex projects for
sure and it's in my
and i think i called
it climb rules originally
uh i don't know
do i have just yeah
that's the confusing
thing and your guess
man some of your stuff
well they keep they
keep changing they keep
changing the names
they a day after i
published it they
changed the names and the
locations but yeah
I'm you know this is a
moment in time so basically
this document here
we go here we copy
this pop this in here
and now this defines
the the rules as well
and so so now we
go back now I'm now
I get a little
debugging to do so I'm
just gonna so I'm
in the orchestrator.
I'm going to go back
to the orchestrator
mode for a moment
because we're in
the orchestrator.
I'm not seeing any
image output from
the open AI request.
Now, here's the thing
that's interesting.
We're vibe coding
right now, right?
I'm just kind of
fooling around to see
what I can do and
what it can do. I
don't have a purpose
other than I want to
create something
for today's call. So
it's like, oh, the
ultimate, this is vibe
coding without
really any direction.
but I still want to
give it direction.
So I know generally
what the problem is
because I'm successfully
making the request.
I'm just not seeing
the image. So I
can assume that it's
likely not parsing
the response JSON
correctly. So, you know,
I'm going to tell
it. The likely issue
is the response JSON
on from the open
AI request isn't being
parsed correctly.
To help debug,
show the raw response
in the browser console.
Now, I could do the
same thing in the
terminal, to be honest
with you guys, but I'm
just going to do it
this way because it's
generally a better
way, I find it to debug
client-side things is
to debug in the client.
A quick question.
Does it need to start
from orchestrator?
Or are you going to
just go into a coder or
somebody and say,
hey, please go and fix
this or add some more
debugging instruction?
I'm using the orchestrator.
Right now, you
see how it switches
the sub instructions?
And you'll
notice here that
it switched to
the R coder.
This allows me to segment
the context window,
right? Because I
don't want to max it
out. And I want each
part to be remembered
by the primary
orchestrator, but I don't
need all the **** that
it did in each of the
subparts. All I need
is the result, whether
it was good, bad,
or whatever it did.
And when we go back
to the orchestrator,
we'll see that once this
thing adds the initial
browser debugging,
it'll then go back to
the original orchestrator.
So this allows
me to sort of
boomerang back between
subtasks and orchestrator.
And the orchestrator
uses the thinking,
in this case, the 3.7
thinking model, which
is substantially more
capable than the 3
.7 implementer model
for sort of abstract
thought, right? Right.
So how is the context
maintained? Is it
per task for when it
goes to the sub one
and all of them is
sharing all the context?
Correct.
It's sharing. It's, well,
sort of.
It's sharing. In a
minute here, it'll finish
and I'll show you
what's shared and what
isn't. It's not sharing
all the context.
It's segmenting the
context. So that means
that the primary
orchestrator has a 200k
context and it's getting
kind of the results
and the in the
in the history of
orchestration but it's
not getting everything
that was done in those
subtasks just what's
being passed back
after the subtask was
successfully created
or potentially what was
allocated originally
to that subtask so
and would you know if
subtasks are also
stateful or stateless?
Means every time
they are invoked,
they will forget
what was before or?
No, this is
stateful within the
structure of the
orchestrator itself.
We'll see that
here in a moment.
So see how this
task which is
finished, subtask
complete, pops back.
Now you will see, now
we get the results.
So it didn't give all
the things it did,
it just gave a summary
of the things it
did back to the original
orchestrator, which
uses a lot less
context and it's all
that's really needed
for the orchestrator.
Then the system will
be like, okay, thanks.
Now I'm going to
cancel that quickly
because I don't want
it to do anything more.
Now I'm going to go
back to and just make
sure that this works.
So I'm going to go and
it's running. This
looks good. I'm going to
go back here and I'm
going to go to the UI.
And I'm going to
just to be on the
safe side, I'm
going to refresh it.
I probably don't
need to refresh it.
And I'm going
to say create
a Gentix meetup logo.
all right and i'm
just going to generate
that now you'll notice
here on the side we've
got debugging information
this debugging
information is telling
me is is confirming
a couple things to
me one it's telling
me which model it's
using it's using the
gpt image one model
the size is correct the
prompt crate and agentics
meetup logo that's
correct so now and
and n1 means how many
versions of the image
do I want? In this
case, I'm asking for
one result. Now I
could ask for two or 10
or a million results.
It's just going to
take a lot more time.
One is faster.
So,
okay, perfect. So
now what we got,
we can see that I'm
getting a response,
the raw response
from the OpenAI,
and it's giving it
to me in base 64.
So this is a
really important
distinction because
what I think, one, it
wasn't rendering
because it didn't
know what the
response format was.
So now I know it
needs to be converted
from base64 to
probably a PNG.
I'm going to
go down here,
and I'm just going
to copy this so
everything is actually
working correctly.
Copy.
Back here. Now I'm
back in orchestrator
mode. I'm saying we need
to display the final
response from the
OpenAI API in the UI.
You know, here is
the raw response or
something like that.
I'll paste this in.
so this is so this
is giving a context
to what it needs to do
okay now it's so now
i understand the issue
it opens returning
base 64 encoded image
instead of a url it's
so it's it's confirming
what i already sort
of knew now i if i
was doing if i wasn't
vibe coding it what i
like likely would
have done is created a
detailed specification
that basically told it
what the appropriate
response looked like
and so rather than me
having to go and tell
it you know well you
have to go and display
base64 i would have
created a spec that
says it's going to
return base64 make sure
you display it
appropriately but part of
what i'm doing right
now is just discovering
i i don't know i i
just started playing
with the api you know
literally a half an hour
ago so i'm i'm
learning as much as the
system is so we're kind
of learning together
all right based on
this i need to update
the image service to
handle base64 coding
returned by open ai
let's make unnecessary
changes all right
so it's updating
my image service json
to to hand so if i
think it thought it
was going to get a
image uh url rather
than the base64 code
So now, so you
see how valuable
this sort of
debugging output is.
It gives us a second
to finish off.
Again, we're in
a subtask again.
All right. Now, what
I didn't do either is
I didn't create a unit
test. But again, I'm
kind of just winging
it here a little bit.
So, Ruv, I've seen
someone actually
doing something similar
using NA10 today.
they had converted
the base64 to binary
and then it displayed.
I mean, I think
maybe that's what you
are doing as well.
No, I'm not
converting to binary.
There's no reason to
convert a base64 to
binary unless you
want to download it.
And right now I'm
not at a point to
download it. I just
want to display it.
When I get to the point
of actually wanting
to download it, then
I'll need to convert
it to a binary like
PNG or something.
All right, let's...
So would you like
to make any additional
changes? No. So,
if all is well, it
should boomerang
back into, see, once
it turns green, it'll
boomerang back into
the initial view.
So, now we're back.
Gives a summary.
Application now.
And I'm going to
just wait a sec
and then cancel it.
It sometimes has
a tendency to go
down a kind of
rabbit hole. I don't
want the rabbit
hole at the moment.
So, I'm going to go here.
I'm going to
copy this again,
refresh the entire page.
pop that in here.
All right, now
we see it again.
Generating your
advertisement.
Takes, again, about 30
seconds or something.
Now, the draw, if I
want to do a binary,
now I'd have to
store the binary.
And I'm right now, I'm
just, I don't really
care about storing
the binary that means
I'd have to you know
enable some kind of storage
mechanism where right
now I'm just storing
that in directly in
the image itself all
right now we got an
image agentics meetup
all right this is this
is like the critical
part oh it looks like
an even generated image
download option let's
see what happens for
that uh looks like
it yeah it looks like
it's storing as a png
perfect all right it
went ahead and did that
automatically as you
can see i can see my
debugging information
on the right now this
is the part that get
now that we can generate
images now we can
start getting creative
right so i've got the
most basic part of my
image system working
what do we what
do we want to do
well let's create
a let's um update
the the ui to
to include more
options like a step
-by-step ad wizard
that guides a user
through the various,
I don't know,
various style, fonts,
colors,
types,
and other, you
know, advertising,
I don't know,
related options, I'm
just making
this up, related
options that will
be used and passed
I'm also going
to, you know,
also include a logo
generator option like
that, right? So, I'm
back in Orchestrator.
We know it works. I'm
going to go ahead and
I'm going to commit
this right now because
we're at a point
where it's functional.
Again, I'm just going
to let that work for
a sec. Let's see what
else we've got here.
We've got Crayad,
we've got, I don't
think any of the
other sections work.
No, no, the
other sections
aren't functioning yet.
All right,
let's see the color,
light, dark mode.
Let's just check if the
mobile components work.
Yeah, it looks like
it's mobile. Not the
greatest looking
thing in the world,
but whatever, not
bad for half an hour.
All right, so I'm
going to go back.
Now, now that I
know it's working, i
can go back to my
simple browser and view
it here so i'm
going to commit this
oh uh first oh
i you know i did
cancel that
classic move i
included it's
it's including the
variables i'll worry
about that later so
what what i i'll just
fix that quick i'm gonna
go here go to git
ignore and I'm going to
because I did it quick
I actually hard coded
in the curl file you'll
see that there's a
curl.txt
there I'll make
sure it doesn't do
that do you put
the ignore for the
Rue modes and
stuff in here too?
yeah well sometimes I
would do Rue
modes for that
um now i i think i i
think i've actually
went ahead and committed
and now i gotta undo
the commit whatever
i'll worry about that
later um i'm gonna go
back here so i now i
because i'm in the
orchestrator i'm gonna do
a sub i'm gonna do
a sub one i'm gonna
start this off let's
go back to the simple
browser and this will
this will go ahead and
create a hopefully
update the ui to be more
geared towards creating
the ad let's see
let's see what it does
we can also see how
think the thinking mode
so here we go subtask
go all right so now
it's so you can see you
create a subtask create
a multi-step wizard
add a toggle between
advertising and logo
generator expand design
include font selection
color scheme selection
ad layout you know
again i'm just i'm just
fooling around with
to see what i can do
with this library like
one of the things i
don't like about the uh
current image generator
in chat gpt is that
you have to give it really
explicit uh prompting
to get anything decent
out of it and and
everything's freaking
yellow so i what i want
to do is is give it
much cleaner guidance
and it looks like what
what the open ai image
generator api does is
allows you to bypass
some of their sort of
uh limitations that
they put in chat gpt
so i can get a lot more
creative with how i
use it and that so what
i'm really trying to
do is figure out what i
can get away with and
how much i can customize
it all right so now
it's creating the
wizard now keep in mind
because i've given it
the root codes and the
client or i guess they
call it whether it's
not called client rules
it's just called rules
that md it now has
a clear idea of how i
like to code structure
file length and all
that sort of stuff so
that's guiding my vibe
coding session right
now mostly so i don't
have to worry about
telling it exactly what
i want it kind of knows
what i want based on
those files now the
other thing i could do
because i'm not going
to show you this again
but because i've got a
well actually while it
goes you can see here
i've got the supabase
mcp installed this
supabase mcp is just
crazy i can let this like
last night i let this
run overnight and it
created the most complex
real-time uh chat
notification logistic
system for one of my
clients it was you know
just the most complex
you know postgres style
database with triggers
and and functions all
kinds of stuff and
it just used the mcp
to create all of it so
it's it's good at an
early stage in the
project when you're looking
to set up a database
it's really really
dangerous later in the
project when you have
real content and data
running because it
could break things badly
but when you're
looking to just sort of
create a you know a
detailed architecture
initially it's a really
easy way to create the
the permissions and the
triggers and all things
that are important
right so these errors
are going to be expected
we're watching it
build in real time so
it's this so basically
what we're seeing
right now is kind of
similar to sort of the
setup you'd see in lovable
right where you kind
of see the preview
as as it's being
generated now the other
thing that i'll probably
do here in a minute
because i'm too lazy to
actually set up a real
database structure,
what I would do is save
the data to the user
storage. And one of
the benefits to some of
the most recent updates
to HTML5 is you can
actually save, you
can use your end user
and their storage on
their hard drive to
sort of mimic, you know,
sort of SQL or NoSQL
style database.
So we'll do that
here in a minute.
Now, this is, again,
Again, this isn't
a real problem, it
just hasn't included
it yet. Did it
include? Perfect.
The other thing
to note under,
you can see here that
I've got different
settings. Oh, they
removed it, it looks like.
Root code keeps changing
things. I can
never figure out.
This worked yesterday,
now they did an
update this morning and
now I can't find it.
Well, here are my
auto settings. This
is what makes it
run automatically.
All kinds of
stuff in here.
I got, you know, the
codex is the OpenAI
agent. You can see I've
got different paths
and things for some
projects I'm working on.
Include, this is new.
Ru, one quick question.
One of the challenges
I have faced is when
I have used Spark and
test-driven approach,
it seems to get into
a loop during the
testing cycle.
and it kind of, I
left something and
ran the whole night
and it was still
unable to fix the same
issue, goes in
a loop. Is that
something that you
may have encountered?
Yeah, it is. It's a
problem. And you have to,
the issue is
the way you've
implemented your phases.
So your phases aren't
specific enough
and your prompts
aren't explicit enough.
So what happens
is the tests to
drive the recursion
in whether what it's
achieving is functional
and complete.
One sec.
Where is the modal?
So this is interesting.
It updated.
Now, I'm going to
let it keep running
because it created
the wizard, but I
don't see a wizard
in the UI for it.
so hopefully let's
let's see if it figures
it out so yeah so back
back to your question
what what you're doing
when you when you
define your phases
your phases need to be
clear and in terms of
what the key deliverable
at the end of each
phase is so the
deliverable each each
phase essentially is all
the test paths right
and but you have to
be specific in what
those what those phases
are supposed to do
like it's the ui it's
the data layer it's
a particular feature
it's the wizard it's
whatever it needs to be
so when you get when
you get stuck in loops
and generally means
your phases and the
instructions for those
phases are too broad
right and and hopefully
the tests themselves
should should stop
the loop so if
if if you're if
you're if you're doing
test-driven development
and you're getting
the loops it's
ambiguity in in the
guidance that you're
giving it does that
make sense yeah um
all right some kind of
to frame our
minds on like like
some like how
you would have
started on some
sample projects
yeah um and this
this actually could
be a good example as
well um so again it
depends on if doing
something for a
purpose or just
because of vibing it.
In this case, just
quickly, I don't see
where the wizard
button is. I don't
see a button to
display the add wizard.
Update the UI
to include it.
So you notice it was
starting to go into
documentation
mode. I stopped it,
canceled it, went back
to the orchestrator,
and then told it
basically I don't
see what the button
is. Maybe it's
somewhere. It's not
obvious wherever it is.
So now it's
creating a subtask.
Ruben, I'm seeing you
doing a flow where
you're opening the
browser and checking
for things, as well
as looking at the
console and checking
the error messages.
Is there a way for
Roo to just open the
browser for you to
monitor the console
and do it so you
can skip that step?
Yes, there is,
actually. That's a
really good question.
And where the heck
did I – I tried
that the other day.
There is an option
– where the heck
did they put –
they keep changing
the UI on me, so
I – here it is.
Use remote browser
connection.
So, connect to
a Chrome browser
running remote debugging,
you know, enter
the DevTools
protocol hosted
to, and I think we
can do that by
just doing this.
Connect to the
Chrome browser using
the remote debugging
enabled port.
Enter the host headers.
You might have to turn on
debugging on
the left there.
Yeah, I'm not
actually, I tried
this the other
day, I was able to
get it working.
I was not sure,
get your browser
running mode.
Let's, let's,
while this goes and
figures itself out,
I'm going to go
back to perplexity
for a moment.
I'm going to
let this code
here in the background.
And this is a cool
feature, actually, and a
really powerful feature.
So it's everything
you see here on the
right here, this would
all automatically be
fed to Rue code, right?
So right now I had to
go copy and paste it,
which is not that big
a deal. But if you're
going to overnight
dev mode, you're not
going to be in a position
to copy and paste.
So what I'm going
to do quickly, I'm
going to go back
to Perplexity and
ask it how to
actually enable that.
Well, isn't this ironic?
All right, come
on here. Ruv,
while you're
pulling that up,
do you have any
kind of, like,
caution or anything like
that for using
Rue in Cursor?
Yeah, I use Rue in
Cursor. It works fine.
It's just a VS
Code extension, so
I didn't have any
issue with it.
How do I enable
debugging?
Oops. Hit the
wrong button.
Oh, come on.
That's a ******
interface.
How do we get back?
That's annoying.
By the way, if
you don't use
power tools on
Windows, if you
guys can see my
clipboard here,
this is the most useful
thing ever invented,
in my opinion. I
can save all my
previous history of copy
and paste. I can pop
in my emojis and all
that kind of stuff.
It's power toys for
Windows.
All right. So let's
go back here. This
time I'm not going to
hit the wrong button.
How do I enable a
remote debugging port?
Let's see what's
going on here.
I'm going to
I'm going to disable
this for a moment.
All right, it
updated the UI.
It's not exactly
the best-looking
UI in the world,
but whatever.
And it's not done yet
because I'm still...
It's not doing anything.
Let's cancel that
for a moment.
This is another example
of why you need to
have console access.
So I'm going to
refresh this, and let's
see what error, it's
not even running, maybe
that's the reason.
We're getting
an error, let me
just start it,
refresh that,
yeah, let's
see, yeah, this
is, it didn't include it,
okay, it's not
hard to fix,
I'm not going
to fix it, but
I'm going to
let it fix it.
it basically just didn't
import the
wizard correctly.
While it does that,
I'm multitasking here.
Let's go back to
perplexity and see what it
says about enabling
the remote debugging.
To connect a Chrome
browser for remote
debugging such as a
tool from a browser,
you need to launch
Chrome with the remote
flag. This opens a
specific port commonly,
922 allows dev4 protocol.
Here's what you can do in
different
operating systems.
Oh, so we need
to actually
run it explicitly
with that.
There's a good
chance, Ruben, that if
you click on the
sidebar, there's the
debug mode with the
triangle, and then that
will open a debug
session automatically
for you and give
you a port for you.
Okay, let's do that.
So where do you
think we find that?
Go back to your
IDE, I think it was
the cursor you
were using. Yeah.
Okay, and then on
the left, there's
a picture of a bug
with a triangle,
play button
triangle, just above.
You got your root
icon and then three
above it. Yeah,
that guy. And
then run and debug,
and then hopefully
it won't be hard
to configure it.
It usually has
an auto create.
Yeah, it's coding, so I
probably need to
let it finish.
We'll do that next.
Oh, it just
switched ports, too.
why did it decide
to switch to
port 3000 who
knows let's just
double check
what does that
um that was
another question i
was going to ask
you like it it
does that a lot
when i'm when i'm
regardless do you
not stop that yeah we
got so to be honest the
fact that it was port
51 whatever was kind
of weird to start
with that was that
was me probably it
automatically for some
reason rule automatically
goes to that if
you're using the fight
yeah maybe that's maybe
that's like a
like a simple
oh look there's two
different interfaces
now okay so let's
let's let's go with
product advertisement
brand awareness uh a
toronto agentics meetup
meetup
Alright, looks
good, next,
let's go with
something orange,
playful display,
it better not be Comic
Sans, I hate Comic Sans,
balance, yeah whatever,
enter your advertising
amazing main headline.
An amazing event.
April 29th,
6.30.
Now, I don't know if
it'll handle the text.
This is me just
seeing what'll happen.
We're about to find out.
All right. Give Give it a
little summary, generate.
Apparently it
does because,
yeah, generate.
Okay, so that
generated in an error.
So before I go, I'm just
gonna copy that quickly.
But before we do,
I just wanna see
if the original
problem still exists.
Toronto, you need a logo.
Yeah, so standard
mediums were not,
So, it broke it,
like this was
working, this
is a regression,
so let's go back
here for a sec.
I'm going to cancel
that, cancel this, and
then I'm going to go
back to the original
orchestrator,
and I'm going to
tell it that the,
oops, cancel this. the
uh updates to the uh
wizard broke the um
open ai requests use
at and this is a common
common issue right
like do what i told
you to you use curl.pxt
request format and
make sure to now
I could just roll back
I guess and that's
one of the reasons why
I made the commit but
to be honest I'm not
building for any particular
purpose here so I'm
just gonna I'm just
gonna roll with whatever
it's big the issue
is essentially it's
making the wrong request
it doesn't know how
to make the request
even though I told it
exactly how to do it it
It hopefully
should just resolve
it pretty quick.
I'm okay with the
UI. I just need
to make it work.
Give it a go here.
So you were
saying that if I
use the debugging
mode here, this
will actually
enable the...
I thought it would.
I'm testing it right now.
And it's not jumping
straight into it.
So I'll keep looking
into that and see
if I can get it
before the call goes.
I think it's this
launch thing.
Although I think
what I probably
should do is do a
script, maybe a Bash
script or PowerShell
script that
launches Chrome with
that specific flag.
And that would
probably be...
I did get it
working the other
day. I think
that's what I did.
Basically, it saves
me from having to go
back and forth. it's
a nice little feature
all right so what's
it doing it's up to
the wizard to pass only
valid parameters to
the image generation
functions yeah so
what it did is it created
a bunch of new new
parameters that i
that i didn't need it
doesn't look a major
issue mind you now
what one of the
drawbacks to the view
the simple browser
view here is there's
no obvious way to
see the console.
So there's no expect
option. I think
there's some
extensions that allow
that. I still don't
have it running.
Now let's handle
the base 64.
This was working
earlier. It went and
decided to change
what was working.
All right. So let's
go support 3000.
I'm going to
actually, because I'm
curious on the
console, I'm going to
just let this
finish for a moment,
I don't want it to keep
doing whatever it's
going to do, so I'm
going to cancel that.
I'm going to go
back to my browser
and I'm going
to open that up.
All right, inspect
console and
create a Toronto
Identix Meetup logo.
usually when it takes
more than a few seconds
it it is indicator
that works last time
when it broke it broke
immediately so i'm
starting with the simple
one this is just this
is just basically to
see that it actually can
generate an image and
display it then i'll
switch to the the the
wizard and see if it
can do more complex ads
or logos or whatever
this would be an
interesting tool for like
let's say you had a
like a brand guide
and you wanted it
to use you know the
appropriate toronto
agentics meetup or let's
say let's say someone
else wants to do a
meetup in some other
city and you want to
define like an agentics
meetup style and
you give it like sort
of the core brand and
then you can generate
ads and promotional
materials for it all
right so this looks
like it works so
let's switch to the
wizard and this time
we're going to do brand
We're just going to do
trial agentics meetup.
I mostly just
want to see the
difference in what
gets produced.
So I'm going to do next.
Do an image.
I don't care. I'm just
going to do whatever.
Drawing meetup,
learn about the
genetic area or
something like that.
It's September,
it's April
29, 6, 3, 4, all right,
next,
looks good. Now,
we're going to keep
an eye on the side
here, Generate.
Now, the fact
that it generated
the initial should
be an indication
that it should
generate the next.
So what I'm really
looking at is, is it going
to generate something
that's dramatically
different than the
default? The default
basically has no prompt.
This has a whole lot
of different prompts.
It's got design elements,
it's got summary, and
we can see it right
here. right so
basically what I'm doing
is I'm just inserting
a kind of prompt
engineering which I could
hypothetically just type
into that other box
but most people don't
know how to prompt
engineer so I'm just making
it easy for them all
right so a couple
issues it it looks like
it did the the colors
correctly it looks like
it needed to better
does a layout but it
looks like it works.
So we can go back.
And I'm going to go
back one step further.
And I'm going to choose
a different color.
And I'm going to choose a
different layout.
I want to see
this. Oh, what's
going on there?
That's a weird.
I don't know what's
going on there.
I'm going to do vintage.
And I'm going to choose
different fonts, playful.
And I'm going
different as
well portrait
copy we're gonna I
don't know what's going
on the bag I probably
fix that all right oh
it looks like it
looks like it didn't
clear the previous
request all right
the first so now
the first worked and
the second didn't
so what i'm going
to do is i'm going
to include the the
debugging for both
because it's it'll
give an indication
that most likely
oh it's the wrong this
image size doesn't exist
okay so now there's a
couple things i could
do to figure that
out i don't know what
the I'm going to
actually go to open AI.
What is that
called? Image?
The image options.
This one.
Image generation.
No, we'll use
perplexity for that,
what are the OpenAI
image size options for?
Some of this is,
I'm going to do,
there's no way that
the root code would
have any idea
of what a model
released a few days
ago it has for options,
so I'm going to
go and tell it.
Here we go.
I was right.
So, these are the,
you know, this is
Dalek 3, I don't
want Dalek 3, I want,
alright, that
didn't give me
the correct
answer either.
OpenAI, image, API,
is this useful for
you guys, I don't
know, I'm just
mucking around here.
Their UI is so
slow, it's crazy.
I think they're
vibe coding
their API reference site,
it crashes my
browser temporarily.
There we go.
Okay.
So I'm just
trying to figure
out what the
right sizes are.
Model background prompt.
oh here we go sizes oh
it looks like
there's other options
you know i'm going
to do i'm going
to give it all
the options i'm
going to remind it
what the issue is now i
obviously could fix
this myself but why
bother all right so now
i'm going to give it
the error and then i'm
going to say fix the
image issue and refer
to plans image gen md
and i'm an orchestra good
does it allow you to
refer to a url using
the act yeah well you
could but then it then
it kicks open the browser
and that's a whole
thing i don't want
to go through that it
was quicker to i the
the other option is
you could use an mcp
that uses something like
um uh wget or some
other you know curl but
to be honest it's
quicker just to uh why is
it not seeing that
um doesn't exist the
file doesn't it that's
that's weird plans of
this file shows the
yeah yeah okay yeah
that's that's the
that's the result
so uh
so um yeah this
this is basically uh
need a little bit
extra guidance there
but the the issue is
a simple one and now i
i end-to-end testing
would have found this
be to be honest if i
created a unit testing
framework to test in
each one of the options
the 10 by the 10 24
by 10 24 you know was
fine and actually now
that i look at it it
actually told me the
answer i guess i could
have just blindly pasted
it in there now that
i see it but you see
here this is actually
the api is actually
saying what the issue
is and how to how to
fix it oh well i now now
i know that's the
difference between uh by
coding and engineering
is that you actually
know what you're doing,
I guess. And looking
at the site told me
the answer, I guess.
I just needed to read.
It's actually
said it twice.
.jsx, updated the ads,
it's fixing the images.
Yeah, basically those
are the two issues to
validate.
I don't know if I need
validation, but okay.
Okay, so that looks
good. Let's go back here.
Actually, I'm
gonna let it finish
and then I'm
gonna cancel it.
Now, I could
stop the subtasks
by clicking
this up and then
choosing not to
execute subtasks.
But it doesn't matter.
Cancel that.
Right.
Let's generate it again.
Looks like it worked
that time. Now, remember
when you're using
client-side apps,
you don't necessarily
have to refresh the
page. if the secondary
files are being rendered
independently of
the primary UI. So
you notice I didn't
bother to refresh the
page here, and it
actually made the request
correctly. But it
looks like it defaulted
to 1024 probably
because the UI changed.
Yeah, so I'm going
to have to go back.
This means that it's
going to do a square
image, even though
I think I selected
a non-square image.
That probably has
to do with the UI
not being available.
yeah that's exactly
what it was so I'm
gonna choose that
and then go back
and I'm gonna do it
again another color
and we're next now
the image the the style
is kind of not great
because I'm if you
look at the prompt it's
giving it really
rudimentary prompting now
what I could do to
make this really look
like a professional
image is I could give it
way more descriptive
text as part of the
auto-generated prompt
look like a a magazine
style, photographic,
blah, blah, blah, ad.
And let's just see
what happens here. If
this works, it should
be a bigger image.
I chose, what
did I choose?
Portrait, so it
should be rectangular.
Here we go.
Not bad.
Learn about genetic
engineering.
The text is correct.
no typos no
hallucinations
we just built a
again a year and a half
ago this would have
been a a well-funded
startup now it's a
random app we built on
a thursday afternoon
was this was this
helpful for you guys
yeah it was good man
it's a little random
though dude we're
jumping all over the
place but it's okay
yeah that's that's
that's how that's how
i roll i know i know
i know you style
yeah let's just
see this yeah yeah
that's that's
how i built stuff
right we created an ad
system a fundable
startup up.
Yeah.
Thank you.
It was really helpful,
so I appreciate it.
Absolutely. Thanks, Ruth.
Any, I've got, I've
got a couple more
minutes if you guys
have any questions.
And, yeah, the other,
the only thing I was
curious about, I think
the, we go back here.
I'm definitely
going to play
with that browser option.
Enable text-to
-speech, remote.
Connect your browser
running remote debugging.
I stuck out on my
research. The best I got
is you could add port
to your launch JSON,
and then you can
connect to it here.
But I think in the
comments, we're
talking about
maybe it's just
easier just to
launch your browser
with that command
on the end of it.
This is a code space,
so this isn't going
to work with my
local browser anyway.
So what I need to do is
this.
Right, and then
I'm going to,
it's probably
extension I could
probably use,
I don't know.
Launch a browser using,
and I'm not going to use
the orchestrator
for that.
I'm going to use the
DevOps mode for that.
And I'm going
to see if it
can figure that
itself out.
You can install, I think
you saw Chrome and, yeah,
I don't think
this is installed,
so that's not
going to work.
We'll see.
We'll see what
figures it out.
Issue with the browser
use is that it only
works with Cloud by
default in Rue and
VS Code, but i was
able to get browser use
enabled for for any
model using uh an mcp
server i just put it
in the chat uh and
that basically does
the same thing opens
up a chromium and um
pulls the information
from the browser and
and gives browser
access to any llm that
you're using within
i know i don't i don't
want browser access
actually that's
easy we already have
browser access that's
built right into Roo,
what I want is console
debugging access,
right? I can do that.
I think you need to
have browser access,
then you can
access the console
which is running
within the browser.
So that is what you
need to do, I think.
That exists already with
the browser computer
use within Roo, right?
but the problem is
it requires you to
actually open up the
session and surf the
website i don't need any
of that i don't i don't
want any of that i
actually just want
just the output which i
which is um slightly
different so yeah you we
could use the mcp approach
that you mentioned
or we could also
use the the browser
capability that exists
within rue or client in
others but yeah but
again but the problem is
with that is it'll start
surfing the website
and trying to click
and it's a whole It's a
whole thing that I
don't necessarily want.
I really only just want
this information, right?
Not the stuff
on the left.
Now, why did my remote
connection to Codespace
die? I guess that was
a hint that our Vibe
session is over when
I crash the browser.
VS Code's done.
Hey, Ruben, one final
question. um like in
your room modes the
thing i was interested in
is the custom instructions
for all modes i
that's the file i'm
having the most difficult
with it's sort of
down the bottom three
quarters way down the
bottom of the page for
room modes the custom
instructions for all
modes yeah that's that
that's that's the file
i'm showing though i
think it was previously
called root modes they
don't call it that
anymore it's called
uh custom modes that
json i think or something
like that um because
the each mode has its
own instructions but
did you have nothing
in that in that box for
custom instructions
for all modes uh no i'm
using i'm using this
route this this custom
modes file this this
one you mean i can't
see your screen okay
uh if you go to to ru
and config right and
prompts and then my my
uh my code space is
dead for some reason i i
put it in the i put
it in the the chat but
it was it was one of
the files you have in
your guest it's one of
the uh ru code files
you told us this last
time yeah so where's
this file this this is
the room this used to
be called room modes
until the day after i
published it and they
changed it and then and
And this used to be
called Klein Rules until
the day after, and
now it's called Rules.
But they're the same,
they do the same things.
So this defines my
agentic development
process, so this keeps
it on, this keeps it from
going off the rails,
which it will do if
you don't use it,
right? So this tells us
the philosophy, the
workflow, how to resolve
issues. Now, this was
originally built for
Klein Rules, which
doesn't exist anymore.
This defines things
like a memory bank.
To be honest, I'm not
a big fan of memory
banks. I don't see
the value. I think
they cause more problems
than they solve.
So what I've been
working on, rather than
using memory banks,
I've been using a kind
of test-driven
development bank, if you
will, and the tests
indicate where you are
in the process rather
than some random MD
that doesn't get referred
to half the time.
um then we got the
general guidelines for
programming languages
now i made this generic
because i switch around
but basically keep
it simple use best
practices make those and i
keep the best practices
based on whatever
it's doing then i define
things like where the
documents and what the
structure should be
subfolders naming
conventions architecture
is there a link to that
file somewhere on your
gist yeah it's it's
the client rules file
okay yeah just copy
paste that in here roof
can you open the file
i put in the chat
because you told us it
was this one uh last week
so i'm a bit confused
yeah it's not that
one man i got that one
open it's not that one
oh let's see here so
what you were saying
effectively is the rules
.md file is the same
as what you could put
within custom instructions
for all modes it
does the same this is
also the same thing
this is an alternative
so i use this as well
which one man dude i
can't see inside your
brain man i gotta pick
one i use this i i use
this as well unfortunately
so this is a more
this is a more in
-depth version of what
i was showing just a
moment ago so what this
this takes it a step
further and says things
like don't create files
that are x longer
and and but basically
they're doing they're
doing similar things
the the difference is
tool i've got explicit
tool use which guides
the tool for things
like mcps which helps it
really you really only
need what you're seeing
here you only need
if you're using mcps
because it struggles
to understand the nuance
of the ncp so one of
the other things you
can do here with the
mcp if you're doing
mcp based development
which is a whole other
can of worms i might
add um is do i have
that open i might have
another window open
that i can show you that
quickly well if the
eugenics website had a
best practices where the
daily changing versions
of these things were
it is it's well we
could do a get well i
guess we could do an
actual github repo um
let me show one of these
files i just think
when you're locked with
all this information
trained in there just
ask it in the chat inside
the foundation yeah
check this out so so
this is how i handle
mcp-based development
so in this case I've
got a file called
mcpinstructions.txt. Now,
this mcpinstructions
.txt, I then
ported into my
settings in,
where the heck
did I put that?
You can see it
more clearly
here, but basically
in prompts,
yeah, we have a
Supabase admin.
So the Supabase admin
basically takes all
these instructions
that you see and i put
it into the into
whatever it's called
the room modes or
whatever the rules mode
file so basically
takes all this and puts
it in a single line
down here so this
single line is really
long but you so what
this what that does
if i go back to my
other uh file for a
moment i don't think i've
publicly i've shared
this publicly yet
But where the heck do
they go? MCP
instructions.
This is easier to read.
So what this does,
this tells it exactly
how to use the MCP.
Without this, it's
basically lost. It doesn't
understand how to
use the MCP, what the
structure is, how to
list all the parameters.
This keeps it on check.
So if you're going
to use it. That would
be awesome. Share that,
man. That would be
awesome. Yeah, if
you're going to do MCP
-based development,
which basically takes
everything I just
showed you and kicks it
up to a whole other
level, because then
you can have multiple
MCPs executing for
various parts of the
project. So, for example,
I can spin up separate
code instances,
dev boxes, APIs,
whatever, as part of my
flow. So I then use
that as part of that
other file I was just
showing a moment ago,
part of this.
And each part of the
modes has MCP-based
implementations that I
can define. So when we
go back to this for
a moment, you can see
here that I said that
this particular MCP has
the ability to read,
edit, and do MCPs.
Now, for certain MCPs,
I might actually remove
the edit feature, and
then it has only the
ability to read local
files, and then when
it comes to like
executing stuff, it'll
default to using the MCP
for the execution. So,
I'm telling it how to
execute those MCPs.
And you see like
certain things that
like, here's an
example. I only
have read access
for the tutorial.
For the DevOps,
I've got the
ability for it
not only to do
the MCP, but
I've got command,
edit, and read. The
DevOps is really
useful for MCPs. I
use the AWS and Azure
MCPs to basically
orchestrate all
the setup, securing,
and deployment on
the Azure or AWS
clouds, which, to be
honest, can be a
real pain. So I just
let it go do its
thing based on stuff.
My request to you,
Reuben, would be could
you please share and
post that MCP config
and the global instructions,
the two versions
of different alternate
versions of the
global instructions.
i've just gone through
my whole room mode
spark config and that
was the file that i
stopped that that i
couldn't find was that
global instructions
and that's the
intelligence man i think it
would be helpful ruby
if we have like a
repo because we have
files kind of all over
the place but we don't
have like a dedicated
roof or yeah i've
got a i did this a
while back what i
probably need to do is re
i've got a repo i did
last year um what the
heck did i call it i
built up i think it's
called yeah rude code
is that i should i
should call it dev oh
rude dev here it is
i need to update
rube dev with all my
latest stuff this is
uh how old is this
it's just said last year
it's probably
a year old then
god that's ancient
yeah yeah man that's 30
years that's three
decades i don't i don't
have delusions of
grandeur my ai does in ai
years yeah that's 40
years old yeah all right
so what what i need
to do is i need to
update rube dev maybe
i'll call it dev mode
just to **** off figma
and uh that's awesome
you're gonna cease and
desist i know i know
i'm doing it right
when i get a cease and
desist then i'll get
my legal bot to respond
to the cease and desist
with a whole collection
of of you know uh
you know responses
yeah so that file those
files are important
like i just went through
my entire config and
that was the one i
couldn't find anywhere
i'm like but i gotta
have this this is the
this is the intelligence
man all right well
I'm not going to
commit to that
just yet. What
I'm going to do
quickly is I'm
going to add it to
my gist for you guys.
And this is for the
Supabase, just
to be clear.
And I'm just going
to remove some
replace. Maybe
Vincent's not on
the call, but
maybe Vincent can
put on the
conversational video
interface on
top of your repo
to give that kind
of experience.
All right, I'm gonna call
this MCP instructions.
By the way, Rube,
did the beta on
that the quantum
space UI work,
the one that
you were updating
last week?
The quantum space
you're calling for?
Yeah, I got it
working like 10
minutes after
the call ended.
I haven't
published it yet.
It's moving, things
are moving so quickly.
I saw like 50 people
do the same thing.
uh all right so while
you're doing that
slight tangent you said
that uh rude the guys
at rue want to actually
include your uh
spark ontology uh in in
their system the product
yeah i gotta do a
poll on it i just
haven't got around to it
i should have probably
did that today all
right i just i just
shared i just shared
you guys the link thank
you so just change
that up depending on
that with the mcp you're
using obviously the
one i did for that
is using the it's the
super base mcp uh actually
let me include the
super base uh
configuration i'm i get a
call here in four
minutes but let's see if
i can get this in
before the call and this
will allow you to use
the super base mcp uh
let's find that quick
i'm not sharing because
i don't want to show
you guys my keys.
Ruv, while you're
doing that, I found
that cloak extension
that'll hide the
secrets. So it's in
chat for you. You
have to test it. I've
got to install, but
does it actually
work? I've never had
the courage to test
it. Yeah, you have
to test it. I haven't
tested it yet.
So you're OK.
I'm just adding
the supermcp.json.
Let me share my screen
quick for you guys.
All right,
share.
All right, so
there's, this is
the, if you copy
this into your MCP,
this will run
the Supabase MCP.
Replace your key
with your key,
okay?
And that,
this'll give you,
this is basically,
this'll work for, just
replace this part here
with whatever MCP you're
using, whether it's
AWS or whatever random
MCP you're using. And
this is meant for a
local environment,
but it gives you the
general idea. And this
is the guidance. Whenever
you're using an MCP,
you need both. You
need the guidance and
you need the MCP setup.
Without this part down
here, the MCP won't
basically work. It'll
just do random stuff
and garbage the
guidance uh logic file
does that go in the
custom instructions for
all or the mode specific
instructions mode
specific okay uh all
right i okay let me
grab that for you
one second i got two
minutes all right you
you guys i'm like i
don't know i like i
don't know why people
have this new uh schedule
their calls right
after but anyway i've
got packed One sec,
let me, I'm going
to grab the roo, I'm
going to use, I'm going
to give you guys the
global mode, I'm only
going to give you
Supabase because that's
all you need here.
So there we go,
I'm going to
add that to the
gist as well.
All right, so edit, I'm
going to add
one more file.
This is basically,
what the heck do
they call this
thing? This is a
custom modes JSON,
I'll call it that.
Okay, what else do
I need help with
that? I got 60
seconds of your time.
All right, I've
updated that.
All right, so let me
share my screen quick.
All right, so now
I'm not giving
you any instructions.
You guys
will have to figure
it out based on
this call, but
this is the mode.
this is what enables
the system to have the
Supabase admin this is
what creates the MCP
this is what guides
the MCP but but you
don't you don't need
this because basically I
stuffed it all into
one line right here and
then I just refer
I'm giving I actually
because the thing's stupid
I actually duplicate
this I create a file
called Supabase MCP
instructions and then
I tell it again to
review the instructions
you know you can't
be too redundant when
it comes to these ai
but basically it's
the same instructions
so just add that
to the room modes
file right as
another mode the top
part exactly and
then and then enable
your your super base
uh mcp with this
remember to
change your key
and this gives full
access to your super
base so be careful
especially if you're running
in a production
environment it could
screw things up really
really really badly
which i've done many
times do you have the
edge function um
customization or guide no it
doesn't include edge
functions edge functions
is actually relatively
easy to do anyway
it's just super
base space functions
deploy edge function
you could create a mode
call it edge edge
function and just tell it
to and have it only
run the command mode
um let me just show
you quickly what that
looks like you do that
a lot right yeah so
right here i gotta jump
i'm late for my next
call but right here
you see how it says
groups just put in one
group call it command
and then tell it to
run whatever terminal
style commands to
be honest 90 percent
of things don't even
need an mcp as long
as there's a cli cool
but just just think
of like just type
command right there in
that place and it'll
run it as a command
thanks all right i'm
i'm going i'm late
I'll talk to you guys
tomorrow thanks dude bye