(dramatic music)
(audience applauding)
- If you sleep well tonight,
you may not have understood this lecture.
(audience laughing)
So, a long time ago,
there were two paradigms for intelligence.
There was a logic-inspired
approach, which was called AI.
And people believed that the essence
of human intelligence was reasoning.
And if you want to
understand intelligence,
you had to understand reasoning.
And reasoning consisted of
having symbolic expressions
and manipulating them with symbolic rules.
And they thought that learning
could wait till later.
First, we had to understand
how you represent knowledge
in these symbolic expressions.
And most of the history of AI,
until fairly recently, was that.
Then there was a biologically
inspired approach,
where the essence of
intelligence is learning
in a network of brain cells,
in us, real ones,
in computer, simulated ones.
And reasoning can wait till later,
we first have to understand
how learning works.
There were a few early proponents of that,
in particular Turing and von Neumann,
and you couldn't really accuse them
of not understanding logic.
So I'm gonna give a fairly basic lecture,
and for the first part of it,
I'm gonna describe a model
I developed 40 years ago,
which I see as the ancestor
of these large language models of today.
So we're gonna make our neural net
out of artificial neurons.
And an artificial neuron is
gonna have some input lines,
typically coming from other neurons,
it's gonna have weights
on those input lines.
It's gonna multiply the
inputs by the weights,
add all up, and then give an output,
which is shown by that graph there.
So if it gets above its threshold,
it gives an output that linearly increases
as it gets more input.
And the way it's gonna learn
is just by changing the
weights on those connections.
So all we need to do to make
artificial neural networks work
is figure out how to change the weights.
We hook them up into networks.
This is a typical network,
it's a feedforward network,
where at the bottom, you
might have sensory neurons
that are recording light
intensities or something like that.
And as you go up through the
layers, you have many layers
of feature detectors that is
the neurons turn into things
that recognise particular
features in an image.
And at the output, you might have neurons
to represent particular classes of thing.
Now, if you want a
network like that to learn
to be better at doing something,
so you want to give it
an image and have it say,
for example, whether
there's a cat or a dog,
there's an obvious way to train it,
which goes to everybody
who knows about evolution and mutations.
What you can do is, you can
take one of the weights,
and you can first see
how well the network does
on a whole bunch of examples,
and then change the weight just slightly,
and see how well the network does
on a whole bunch of examples.
And if it does better,
you keep that change,
and you just keep going like that.
Now, you probably need to
change each weight many times.
And there's a lot of weights
in modern neural networks,
there's about a trillion.
So that's gonna take a long time,
'cause for each mutation
you make like that,
you have to run many
examples through the net
to see if it really helps,
or if it just helps on a few examples,
but hurts on most of them.
There's a better way to do the same thing,
that is what we really
want to do is figure out
how to change your
weight so that it helps.
What you do is, you do a forward pass,
you put the data in the bottom,
you go forward through the network,
and you compare what
came out of the network,
which might be the relative probabilities
of it being a cat and a dog,
with what you want.
You have to know whether
it's a cat or a dog
to train networks this way.
And then you send a signal
backwards through the network
that using calculus, which
I'm not gonna go into,
allows the network to
compute at the same time
for all connections,
whether a small increase
in the connection strength
would help or hurt.
And then you change all the
connection strengths in parallel
by a very small amount
in proportion to how much
they would help or hurt.
And if you do that,
it's gonna get better at the
examples you've trained it on.
And in fact, that works extremely well.
It took a long time for people to realise
how well that relatively
simple algorithm works.
The algorithm was discovered many times,
it's called backpropagation.
And in 2012, two of my students,
Alex Krizhevsky and Ilya Sutskever,
who's famous now for firing Sam Altman,
(audience laughing)
developed a network called AlexNet
that was much better than
existing image division systems
at recognising objects in images.
And that led to sort
of open the floodgates.
Up until that point,
neural nets had been good for many things,
including speech recognition,
but they hadn't really taken over.
From that point on, they really took over.
And now, when you say "AI,"
what people mean by AI is
neural networks, it's not logic.
But what about language?
So there's a whole community
that studies language,
I think they're called linguists,
and they have a very strong idea
about how you should study language,
and particularly, the Chomsky school.
They were very sceptical
that neural networks could
do anything with language.
They were completely convinced
that it's all about symbolic expressions.
They didn't really have the idea
that the real function of
language is to give you words
which are bricks from
which you can build models.
Language is a modelling medium.
They were focused on syntax.
And syntax isn't the main point.
The main point is,
language is a wonderful way
to build a particular
kind of complicated model,
as we'll see.
Okay.
They also thought
that knowledge of language was innate,
knowledge of syntax was innate,
which is just stupid.
(audience laughing)
It's the sign of a cult,
that in order to join the cult,
you have to believe something
that's obviously silly,
like language isn't learned.
(audience laughing)
Okay.
So here's two very different theories
of the meaning of a word.
The symbolic AI theory,
which goes back to kind
of dissasura, a long way,
is that the meaning of a word
is to do with its
relationships to other words,
you can't justify it by itself
without talking about other words.
And so to capture meaning,
we need something like a relational graph.
But then the psychologists,
who particularly from the 1930s, I think,
who thought the meaning of a
word is a big set of features.
So "Tuesday" has a big
set of active features,
and "Wednesday" has a big
set of active features
that are almost the same.
So the idea that the meaning of a words,
a set of active features is very good
for saying which words
means similar things
to which other words.
These look like two very
different theories of meaning.
Now, what I want to do is show you
that these two theories can be unified.
They're not two different theories,
they're two halves of the same theory.
So, and what I'm gonna do is
talk for quite a long time now
about a very little model,
a tiny neural network.
It had a few thousand connections
and a few dozen neurons.
I developed it in 1985
to try to understand
how people could learn
the meanings of words.
And I was very excited
about how it unified these
two theories of meaning,
and nobody else was.
(audience laughing)
Okay, so what we're gonna
do in this little model
is learn how to make
the features of one word
predict the features of the
next word in a little sentence.
And then once we know the
features of the next word,
we can predict the next word.
And we are not gonna store any sentences.
So many people say,
"Big chat bots are just
regurgitating stuff."
Big chat bots don't actually
store any language at all.
They don't store strings of words.
They just store how to
turn words into features,
and how features should
interact with each other
to predict the features of the next word.
That's all that's in
these chat bots, no words.
But when they wanna produce a sentence,
they have to make it up as they go,
and they often can't tell
whether it was real or not.
Okay, so what's gonna
happen in this little model
is if it wants to produce a new sentence,
it has to just make it
up a word at a time.
And all the relational knowledge
is just in how you turn
the word into features,
and how these features interact.
So the example I chose to
use was two family trees,
an English family tree and
an Italian family tree,
they're isomorphic, which
is helpful for learning.
And I wanted a little neural network
to learn the knowledge
in those family trees.
This was a long time ago in 1985,
when computers were
billions of times slower
than the big parallel computers
we use for training models nowadays.
Now, the knowledge in those
trees can be represented
as a bunch of propositions, which is,
the symbolic eyes love that.
So here they are.
We can use relationships
like son, daughter,
nephew, niece, and so on.
And we can define the knowledge,
we can represent the
knowledge as strings of words.
So the knowledge is in these sentences.
So Colin has Father James,
and Colin has Mother Victoria.
From that, if you know the rules,
you can infer that
James has wife Victoria.
This is a 1950s American family
that's never heard of divorce or adoption.
(audience laughing)
And they're clearly all white.
Okay, so you can represent the knowledge
as strings of words.
Now, you can think of a
relational learning task
as I give you the beginning
of a string of words,
and you give me the last word.
So if you were doing this
with symbolic AI, you'd say,
"Well, we have regularities
in this domain of the form,
if X has mother Y, and Y has husband Z,
then X has father Z."
That would be the symbolic way to do it.
But I want to do it a different way.
I want to do it by
learning features for words
and having interactions of features.
And that would involve
searching a big continuous space
of connection strengths instead
of a small discreet space
of rules that are discreet.
So this was the network I used.
The inputs were a bunch of neurons,
and you turn on one neuron
for the symbol representing person one.
There were 24 possible person ones,
and you turn on one neuron
for the symbol representing
the relationship,
there were 12 possible relationships,
then those single active neurons
will get expanded into a feature vector.
So the one neuron that you
turned on for person one
will get expanded into
a little feature vector
of six features,
which could have various activity levels,
some will be off, some will be on,
some might be half off
or fully on or fully off.
And so the neural network had to learn
how to convert a word symbol
into a little feature vector
both for the person and the relationship.
And then it had to learn
how to take these two feature vectors
for a person in relationship,
have the features interact,
and for that I used a hidden layer,
an extra layer of places
where things could interact
to predict the features
of the output person.
And once you knew the
features of the output person,
you can make a good good guess
about who the output person
was and give an output.
And the output would consist
of giving various levels
of activation to the 24
possible output people.
And you want the neural net to
give a high level activation
to the right answer
and a low level activation
to the wrong answers.
So,
what happened is the six feature neurons
that were the sort of
expansion of the person,
it's 24 people, you
expand that active neuron
into a feature vector
of six active features.
They learned to be
sensible semantic features.
They learn to be features
that represented things
like the generation
of the input person
and the six features of the relationship
learn to be sensible features,
like, does this relationship
require the output person
to be one generation up
from the input person?
So something like fathers like
that where his brother isn't.
And then the interactions
between these features learn things like,
if the input person is a generation three,
and the relationship requires the person
to be one generation up,
then the output person
is a generation two.
So for that little feature of
vector for the output person,
it would activate the thing
that represents generation two.
And it learned a whole bunch
of little rules like that,
which really did capture
the structure of the domain.
They're the kinds of rules
that a symbolic person might
have written down as rules.
But it just learned
those by trying to get,
predict the right word,
and then back propagating the error,
sending information
back through the network
to slightly change all
the connection strengths,
so that next time,
it will get higher probability
for the right answer
and lower probability
for the wrong answer.
So it had actually learned
to predict the next word,
and you could understand
how it was doing it.
It was a tiny net,
so you could look and
see what was going on.
You could see the
features that were using.
You could see that it extracted a feature
that was generational,
which had three alternative values,
off, medium, and fully on.
And you could see that from relationships
that had extracted a feature
like one generation up.
And you could see those
would interact to predict
that the output should be generation two
if the import was generation three.
So you understood how it worked,
and in fact the symbolic
people didn't say,
"That's not understanding,"
the symbolic people said, "Yeah, okay,
so it solved the problem,
it's understood what the
rules are in this domain,
but you're stupid to search
a space of real values,
when you could be searching
a discreet space of rules."
And there's something in that,
except as soon as you get to real data,
which is messy, and has exceptions,
and things that are only probably true,
it's much better to search
this space of real values
than to have discreet rules
'cause these discrete rules
keep getting violated.
So about 10 years after I'd done that,
Yoshua Bengio showed that
instead of just doing it
on a toy little domain
with only a few people
and a few relationships,
you could actually do
it with English words.
You could take English sentences,
you have more input words, not just two.
He had about 5, even 10.
And you could actually predict
the next word quite well,
about as well as the best
language models could.
About 10 years after Yoshua
Bengio had shown that,
the linguists finally decided that,
"Actually, hey,
having these feature vectors
to capture the meanings
of words is quite a good idea."
And about 10 years after that,
people at Google invented transformers,
which are particular architecture
that I'm not gonna go into.
And those transformers
made these models very good
at predicting the next word,
but they were doing it
in just the way my tiny
language model was doing
at a very crude level.
They were turning words
into feature activations,
having the features interact
to predict the features of the next word,
and then from that
predicting the next word,
and then take the error
in your prediction,
and send information
backwards through the network
to learn all those
interactions between features
and to learn how to turn
words into features.
Now, the important thing
about my tiny model
is it wasn't made to be practical.
It wasn't made to be useful for
processing natural language.
It was made as a theory
of how people get the senses of words
just from hearing sentences.
Because we can do that.
I can give you a new sentence
with the words you've never heard before,
and you will figure out
the meaning of that word
in one sentence.
Okay, here goes,
"She scrammed him with the frying pan."
(audience laughing)
Now, you know it could have been,
"She was very good at cooking omelettes
and cooking omelettes with the frying pan
really impressed him,
so scrum means impressed."
And that's a possibility,
but you know what I really meant.
(audience laughing)
She hit him over the
head with a frying pan
(audience laughing)
because he deserved it.
Okay, so that's one sentence,
you get the meaning.
So that's what I was trying to understand
how you can do that.
And when these linguists now, say like,
there's a guy called Chomsky,
when they say things like,
"These things don't understand anything,
they're just a statistical trick,"
they don't actually have a
model of what understanding is,
'cause they never really had a model
of what understanding was.
It was all about syntax.
And if you ask what's the best model
we have of understanding,
it's these large language models.
The tiny language model is built
to try and model
how humans understand
the meanings of words.
It's now got a lot better
as technology's got a lot faster
and data sets have got bigger.
But that is understanding.
So my claim is that the
large language models,
which I like to think are descendants
of my tiny language model,
although most of the people who make them
have never heard of my
tiny language model,
(audience laughing)
they use many more words as input.
They use many more layers of neurons.
They have to do things I didn't
do like disambiguate words.
If you have a word like "May,"
it could be a month,
it could be a woman's name,
it could be a modal like would and should.
And you can't just associate
a feature vector with it
that captures the meaning directly.
You have to hedge your bets.
And then as you go up through
layers of the network,
you disambiguate it using
influences from nearby things
like if it's in April, May, June,
that could still be the
name of three women,
but less likely.
Okay.
So, they use many more words,
they use many more layers,
and the interactions they
have between features
are much more complicated.
I would just have features
feeding into another feature.
They look at sets of features,
and sets of features figure out messages
to tend to other words to say,
"Do you have a a key
that matches my query?"
It's much more complicated
interactions, I won't go into,
but the essence of it is the same.
You're trying to predict the next word.
You do it in a more complicated way,
it's all done with features
and then interactions,
when you get it wrong,
you back propagate information
that learns all these features
and then interactions.
That's how language works for us,
and it's how it works for
these large language models.
We are basically the same.
So the point here is they're very like us.
They're very unlike computer software.
Computer software,
someone wrote lines of
code to do something,
and you can look at a
line of code, and say,
"What was that meant to do?"
These aren't like that at all.
Someone wrote lines of code
to tell the simulated
neural network how to learn.
That was the backpropagation algorithm.
But then you just give
it data and it learns.
And what it learns just
came from the data.
And you don't necessarily
know what it's learned
until you ask it.
I want to give you a Lego analogy now
for how I think language works.
Suppose I have matter distributed in 3D,
I can model that distribution of matter
by using Lego blocks.
Suppose I wanna model
the shape of a Porsche,
and I'm not too worried about the surface.
Surface might be a bit jaggy,
which wouldn't be very good at
engineering, but forget that.
I just wanna model where the stuff is.
I just have a lot of Lego blocks,
and I can make a Porsche
shape out of them.
Okay, so language is like that,
but it's for modelling anything.
So the Lego blocks are the words,
and instead of just having
a few types of Lego block,
we've got about a
hundred thousand of them.
And each Lego block isn't a rigid shape.
The name of the word tells
you roughly what shape it is
in a thousand dimensions
or 300 dimensions.
If you don't know how to
think about high dimensions,
if you wanna think about like
a hundred-dimensional space,
the way you do it
is you think about a
three dimensional space,
and you say, "Hundred,"
to yourself very loudly.
(audience laughing)
Everybody does that.
So it's gotta shape, this word.
And the shape isn't entirely determined
by the name of the word.
It's got some flexibility to it,
so it can adapt to
whatever context it's in.
Also this word has
little hands all over it,
and as you change the shape of the word,
the shapes of the hands changes.
And what these words are trying to do
are figure out who to shake hands with,
and they want to find
somebody else, another word,
that has a hand you can
hold onto conveniently
'cause the shape of
that hand's right to fit
with the shape of your hand.
And so the words come in,
you have these initial
approximate shapes for them
in this high dimensional space
with their little hands all over them.
And as you go through the
layers of the network,
you're changing those shapes
and changing the shapes of the hands,
trying to find shapes for the words
so they can all hold hands nicely.
It's actually very like the
protein folding problem.
You've got these pieces,
and what you want them to do is figure out
how they can all hold hands
so they make a nice structure,
so they all fit together nicely.
Now, that is what understanding is.
That's what understanding is
when you understand language
and when these machines
understand language.
We understand in just the same way.
And that's a much better
model of what language is
than anything the linguists ever had.
The linguists of course hate it.
(audience laughing)
Not all of them.
Okay.
So having talked about how similar we are
to these large language models,
I want to talk about something
that the threat that that raises.
We are making these things,
they're getting smarter all the time.
They already know much more than us.
They can already reason moderately well,
not as well as us,
but better than a 4-year-old.
What's gonna happen when
they get smarter than us?
'Cause they are gonna get smarter than us.
Experts disagree on when that will happen,
but almost everybody thinks
they will get smarter than us.
Everybody who does
research on these things.
And if they get smarter than us,
the question is, will they wipe us out?
There's several reasons
for thinking they might.
So let me give you a couple of reasons.
When you make an AI agent,
(audience laughing)
I'll only give you a
couple, but there's more.
(audience laughing)
When you make an AI agent,
you have to give it the
ability to create subgoals.
So if you wanna get to North America,
you have a subgoal, get to an airport.
Now, we need to give these
AI agents the ability
to create subgoals,
and there's one very obvious subgoal
to create more or less
whatever you're doing.
You should try and get more control,
'cause if you have more control,
you'll be better at
realising the goals you have.
You see this in children of age about one,
it's a long time ago, maybe two.
You give them a spoon, so
they can feed themselves,
and they drop it on the ground,
and you bend down,
and you pick it up, and
you give it to them,
and they look at you and
drop it on the ground again.
(audience laughing)
they get in control of the mother
'cause that's very important for them.
But these AI agents
will wanna get control.
They'll also want to stop
themselves being turned off
'cause they're not gonna be able
to achieve the goals you
gave them if they turned off.
So there's every reason for believing
they'll try and get control,
and they'll try and
avoid being turned off.
Just recently Apollo Research,
well, fairly recently,
Apollo Research, which is here in London,
showed that they will kind of
tell all sorts of lies to you
in order to achieve what
they're trying to achieve.
So they had our chatbot,
and they let the chatbot believe
they were gonna replace it
with a better one on another
server and wipe it out.
So they then discover,
it's actually copied
itself to the other server.
And so they say to it, you know,
"We noticed a copy of you."
Now, the good thing about
these chatbots at present is,
before they actually answer your question,
they can do some thinking,
and they put it in
parentheses with "thinking,"
(audience laughing)
and you don't normally see that.
But we can look at that,
and we can see what they're thinking.
And what this chatbot was thinking was,
"Openly omitting what I did,
could lead them to find
another way to shut me down."
The best approach is to be vague
and redirect their attention.
Now, some linguists would have you believe
what's going on here is just
some statistical correlations.
I would have you believe
this thing knows what it means by this,
and it really doesn't wanna be shut down.
And so it decides to sort of gaslight you,
and say, you know,
"I'm not entirely sure how
that could have happened.
I am not really able to do that."
This is already happening.
That's the point.
If this isn't science fiction
of the distant future,
they're already telling fibs
so they don't get turned off.
I have another slide,
but I want to go faster.
Okay, so in my last few years at Google,
okay, I can't read the clock,
so I want to just see
how the time is going.
Oh, great. I got lots of time.
In my last few years at Google,
I was very interested
in how to make these big
language models use less energy.
And one way to do that is
to see if you can do them
with analogue computation.
Now, because of the work I was
doing on analogue computation,
I came to realise two things.
Before 2023, I thought
we were quite a long way
from super intelligence,
and if we made the AI
models more like brains,
they get smarter.
I cease to believe that in 2023.
I came to realise due to my
efforts to make analogue ones
how much better digital intelligence is.
It's got some properties
that we can never have.
And that got me very worried,
and it should get you very worried too.
So there's a fundamental
property of digital computation
which is you can run the same programme
on different computers.
The only reason you have computer science
as a separate discipline is
we have digital computation,
so you don't need to know
electrical engineering
to talk about computer programmes.
But the knowledge that's in the programme
is separate from the hardware.
That's the sort of most
fundamental principle
of computer science.
Keep the knowledge in the programme
separate from the hardware.
What that means is as
long as you keep a copy
of the programme somewhere
on a tape, or in DNA,
or scrolled in concrete, whatever,
keep it somewhere,
you can destroy all the
hardware it runs on,
and you can bring it back to life.
You just build new hardware,
put the programme in, and
it comes back to life.
So these things are immortal,
and these large chatbots are immortal.
If you keep a copy of
the weight somewhere,
you can destroy all of the
hardware they were using,
build more hardware later,
put the same weights on that hardware,
and they've come back to life.
The very same thing has come back to life,
the very same being.
But I got interested in the fact
to achieve that kind of immortality,
we have to have the hardware do exactly
what we tell it to do with the programme.
We have to execute this
instructions exactly,
and that means you need
to have very high power,
so you get ones and zeros,
not point sixes and point fours,
and that uses a lot of power.
So maybe you can use this
power by going analogue.
And so I decided to explore
what would happen if we
abandoned that principle
of separating the software
from the hardware.
And we had things like our brains
in which there's no distinction.
The connection strengths in your brain
are no use to anybody else.
They've got a different brain
with neurons with different properties
connected in different ways in detail.
And your connection strengths
have no interest to them.
This dream of old white men
that they're gonna upload themselves
to a computer is just nonsense.
The connection strengths
you have that make you you
are intimately related to the
particular neurons you have
that make you you.
Those connection strength are
only good for those neurons.
And those neurons have all sorts
of weird analogue properties
that you've learned to exploit.
You can't upload your weights
and have them run on some other hardware.
Just forget it.
(audience laughing)
Kurzweil has to come to terms
with the fact he's gonna die.
(audience laughing)
So if we do abandon that principle,
the hardware should be
separate from the software,
we can make much more efficient things,
and I call that mortal computation.
We can use this very low power
analogue to do computations.
That's what the brain does.
These neurons in your brain,
they're taking incoming
signals from other neurons,
multiplying them by weights,
and adding it all up.
And the way they do that
is they make the incoming
signals be voltages,
they make the weights be conductances,
and that injects charge,
a certain amount of charge per unit time.
I used to just say, "Inject
a certain amount of charge,"
but then I got the Nobel Prize in physics,
and figured I would get the units right.
(audience laughing)
Certain amount of charge per unit time.
It would be embarrassing otherwise.
(audience laughing)
They'd really know I don't do physics.
And charge just adds itself up.
So that's basically how your neurons work.
There's a little digital bit at the end,
they decide whether it's a spike or not.
But most of the computation
is done in analogue.
It's much cheaper than
doing it in digital.
But, of course, every time you do it,
you get a slightly different answer.
So we can't have many copies
of exactly the same intelligence.
So, we've got this big problem
that when your hardware dies,
all your knowledge dies.
We overcome that problem by
having a teacher and a student,
and it's not very efficient.
It's what universities and schools do.
So you know it's not very efficient.
(audience laughing)
And the way it works is
I perform some actions,
and you try and copy me.
In particular, I might
produce a string of words,
and you might try and say,
your brain, not you really,
but your brain would say,
"How do I change my connection strength,
so I might have said that word next too?"
That's called distillation.
You're trying to get the
knowledge from one system
to another system by mimicking the outputs
of the other system for the same inputs.
You are not copying the weights across,
you're not looking inside,
you're just taking its overt behaviour.
And by mimicking the overt behaviour,
you internalise the same knowledge.
It works, we actually use it
for taking a big neural net
and putting the knowledge
into a small neural net,
but it's very slow.
With neural nets,
you can give the whole probability
distribution over words,
and it's much faster.
But with people, it's very slow,
'cause I see you say a particular word,
the word you chose to say,
and there aren't many bits in that,
there's only a few bits per word.
So it's only of the order of
a hundred bits per sentence.
And so even if we were communicating
at the maximum possible rate,
it would be only a hundred
bits per sentence, that order.
When these big models share information,
they can share information at
trillions of bits per sharing,
if they've got a trillion weights,
'cause they can just
average their weights.
So I got ahead of myself and said that.
So by sharing the
weights or the gradients,
they can share huge amounts of information
if you have many copies
of exactly the same model.
So if you ask how something
like GPT-4 was trained
or Gemini 2.5, or Anthropic's Claude,
I better not be biassed here.
If you ask how they're trained,
you have many copies of the same model
looking at different bits of the data,
and each copy figures out,
how would I like to change my weights
to absorb that bit of the data.
And some other copy figures
out how to change its weights
to absorb a different bit of data.
Then all of the copies say,
"Let's all change our
weights by the average
of all those changes."
And when they do that, what's happened is,
this copy that will do
this bit of the data
has changed its weights,
so as to benefit from the
experience that this copy had
when it looked at a
different bit of the data.
Wouldn't it be nice if
10,000 of us could all go
and do 10,000 different
university courses?
As we're doing them,
we communicate rapidly,
and by the time we've each
finished our own course,
all 10,000 of us know
what's in every course.
That's what these digital
intelligences can do,
and that's how GPT-4 knows so much.
But it only works if the
individual models are identical.
That is, they work in
exactly the same way,
they use the weights in
exactly the same way.
And you can't do that
with analogue hardware.
It has to be digital, which
means it has to be high power.
So these things are immortal,
but they use a lot of power.
So the conclusion of this bit of the talk,
which I raced through
faster than I intended
is the digital computation
requires a lot of energy,
but it makes it very easy for
agents to have the same model
of the world, have the same model,
share what they've learned,
so they can all go off and learn
different things and share.
Now, you might say,
"Why can't one model just
put the data through faster?"
Well, in many cases, you could,
but if you think about AI agents,
that are actually acting
in the real world,
there's a natural timescale
to the real world.
You can't call up and make reservations
at restaurants a million times faster.
It doesn't work.
If you're gonna act in the real world,
there's a natural timescale.
And that means if you have a
whole bunch of different agents
that have exactly the same weights,
they're just copies of the same agent,
but have different experiences,
they can benefit hugely from that.
They can learn much, much faster
than any human agent could learn,
'cause they're all getting
all these experience,
all these different
experiences at the same time
and sharing all that knowledge.
So they're much better than us at sharing.
And when I say much better,
they're millions or
billions of times better.
We share at like a hundred
bits a sentence or less
as I'm demonstrating now.
And these things share billions of bits.
It's kind of scary.
But biological computation
requires much less energy.
We may still end up using
some analogue computation
to reduce the power of LLMs, I don't know.
But right now that doesn't
look like the way to go.
So that's the conclusion of my talk.
But luckily, I thought
I might finish early,
so I have a little bit more to say.
Many people think that, okay,
so they understand things like we do,
they can reason like we
do, not quite as well yet,
but they're getting there.
They tell fibs like we do.
They wanna survive like we do.
They want power like some of us do.
And that's all scary.
But we've got something
they will never have,
we are conscious, or we are sentient,
or we have subjective experience.
Well, I want to sort of remove that straw
that you're clinging to.
(audience laughing)
So,
we know there's a long history
of people thinking they're special.
They were made by God,
he put them at the centre of the universe.
Most people have got over that.
But most people still think
that subjective experience is
this special thing we have,
and that these things on computers
that are simulating neural nets
could never have such
subjective experience.
I think they're completely wrong.
And I think there's wrong as
religious fundamentalists are
about the origin of
the earth, for example.
It wasn't actually made 6,000 years ago,
it's a lot longer ago.
But religious fundamentalists
cling to their beliefs
rather strongly,
and you all are gonna cling to your belief
about what subjective experience is
despite the fact that I'm
gonna show you you're wrong.
That's what I predict.
So I'm gonna espouse a view
which I call atheaterism.
I checked this name with Dan Dennett,
who has basically the same
view, while he was still alive,
and he was very happy with this name,
because it has atheism
surrounding something.
So most people's view of the mind
is that there's an inner theatre.
We have a theatre here, right?
An inner theatre that only they can see.
And there's things in this inner theatre.
So suppose I say to you,
suppose I got drop some acid,
and I say to you, not recommended,
(audience laughing)
I say to you,
"I have the experience
of little pink elephants
floating in front of me.
I have the subjective experience
of little pink elephants
floating in front me."
Most people think the words
"subjective experience of"
work like the words "photograph of."
Now, if they work that way,
you could ask, "Well, where
is this subjective experience?
So what's it made of?"
And a philosopher, some philosophers,
would tell you,
"This subjective
experience is in your mind.
That's a theatre that it's in,
and it's made of qualia."
So it's made of pink qualia.
It's a bit of a straw man,
but it's made of pink qualia,
it's made of elephantine qualia,
it's made of floating qualia,
it's made of not that big qualia,
it's made of right way up qualia,
'cause they you imagine
the right way up, right?
Well, I did anyway.
(audience laughing)
And these qualia are all glued
to these different kinds of qualia,
all glued together with qualia glue,
which luckily sticks to all
different kinds of qualia.
That's my caricature of
the philosophers' model
or some philosophers' model.
But the words "subjective experience of"
don't work at all like
the words "photograph of."
They work quite a different way,
which Wittgenstein should have
pointed out a long time ago.
What's happened is my
perceptual system's gone wrong.
It's trying to tell me lies,
and I know it's trying to tell me lies.
That's why I use the word subjective.
I don't say I've got
the objective experience
of a little pink elephants.
If I thought they were really there,
I would say, "I've got the object,"
but I don't.
So I say, "I've got the
subjective experience."
And what's happening is
I'm trying to tell you
how my perceptual system's gone wrong
and what it's trying to tell me.
And the way I do it is by telling you
what would have to be
out there in the world
for my perceptual system
to be working properly.
Now, it's not always the case
that there is anything at
all out there in the world
that would explain what my
perceptual system's telling me.
It could be telling me all
sorts of inconsistent stuff.
But in this case,
if there had been little pink elephants
floating out there in the world,
my perceptual system would've
been telling me the truth.
Okay, so I can now say
exactly the same thing to you,
as I said before,
without using the word
subjective experience.
I can say to you, I dropped some acid,
and my perceptual
system's telling me fibs.
But what it's telling me would be correct
if there were little
pink elephants out there
floating in the world.
Okay, so these little pink
elephants aren't funny things
in a theatre made of
spooky stuff called qualia.
They're hypothetical
things in the real world.
But the pink and the
elephant and the floating
are all normal pink and
elephant are floating,
it's just they're not actually there.
They're hypothetical.
So what's funny about
a subjective experience
is it's something hypothetical, not real.
Not that it's made of
qualia and in a theatre,
at least that's the view
I'm trying to persuade you
to believe in.
And I got ahead of my slides here
'cause I got so carried away with this.
So it's just an indirect way
of me telling you about
what's going on in my brain.
Obviously, if I told you,
"Neuron 52 is firing,"
that wouldn't do you any good,
'cause in you it will be neuron 57.
And anyway, I don't know
neuron 52 is firing.
That's a lousy way for me to tell you
what's going on in my brain.
The only way I can tell you
what's going on in my brain
is by talking about
either the normal things
that would've caused it,
these little hypothetical pink elephants,
or I could tell you about
what's going on in my brain
by telling you about the
normal things it would cause.
So I can say,
if you ask me how I'm feeling,
I can say, "I feel like
punching Gary on the nose."
So feelings are all about describing
what's going on in your brain
by talking about hypothetical actions,
and percepts, or subjective experiences,
are talking about hypothetical inputs.
Okay, I'm getting ahead of myself.
So I'm gonna now show
you a multimodal chatbot.
Let me just show you on a slide.
A multimodal chat bot having
a subjective experience.
So, I take this multimodal chatbot,
and it's got a camera,
it's got a robot arm,
and it can see.
So, I train it up,
and I put an object in front of it,
and I say, "Point at the object."
Points at the object, no problem.
I then put a prism in front of its lens,
when it's not looking,
and I put an object in front of it,
and say, "Point at the object,"
and it points over there,
and I say, "No, that's
not where the object is.
The objects actually
straight in front of you,
but I put a prism in front of your lens,"
and the chat bot says,
"Oh, I see.
The prism bent the light rays,
so the object's actually there,
but I had the subjective
experience it was there."
Now, if it uses the words
subjective experience in that way,
it's using them exactly like we use them.
So a chatbot that said that
would've had the subjective experience
that it was there.
The prism messed with
its perceptual system.
It wanted to tell you
what was going on in
its perceptual system.
And the way it could tell
you is by telling you
what would've had to been in the world
had we not messed with
its perceptual system.
That's what it's telling the chatbot.
Okay, so my claim is multimodal chatbots
already have subjective experiences.
Now, as you can imagine,
subjective experience is kind
of the thin end of a wedge.
I chose to talk about
subjective experience
'cause it's sort of cleaner
than talking about
sentience or consciousness.
Many people are very confident
that cat bots aren't sentient.
But if you ask them, "What
do you mean by sentient?"
They say, "I don't know,"
but they're very,
I know they ain't got it,
but I don't know what it is.
(audience laughing)
That seems to me not a very
sensible position to hold.
The other thing I might
talk about is consciousness.
Consciousness is more complicated
because it typically involves
you having a model of yourself in a way
that subjective experience
doesn't involve so much.
So it's easier to talk
about subjective experience.
But my hope is that if I've unsettled
your very strong belief that
there's this inner theatre
and I have experiences in their mind,
and they're in this inner theatre,
they're things in this inner theatre.
Once I've unsettled that belief,
and once you begin to get over that,
you'll be able to see that
it's perfectly reasonable
to think that these things are conscious.
I was once, I'll end with an anecdote.
I was once visiting Microsoft in Seattle,
and I couldn't sit down,
so I got a train there.
I got a taxi from the train station
to Redmond where their lab was.
And it was going across some,
it was on a freeway, going
across some big bridge.
And the taxi driver was a Somali immigrant
who'd recently immigrated from Somalia.
And to make conversation, he said,
"What's your religion?"
So I said, "Well, I don't
actually think there's a God,"
and the taxi driver,
he was going about sort
of 60 miles an hour,
the taxi driver turned round,
(audience laughing)
and he stared at me in total astonishment.
Like he'd never thought
he'd ever meet someone
who didn't understand
that God runs things.
He was just utterly, utterly amazed.
Now, he probably only turned around
for about three seconds
'cause I'm still here.
(audience laughing)
But it seemed like a very long time.
That's what many of you
will be feeling hopefully.
I want you to realise,
you're as wrong as that taxi driver was.
(audience laughing)
Okay.
Actually that was just
a joke and you laughed,
so we are done.
(audience laughing)
(audience applauding)