We're live. Here we
are, July 10th. The
time just keeps
flying by and we got
a nice cast of
characters here. Thanks
everyone for showing
up, by the way.
First,
I've got to point out
that I'm in the midst
of getting a new
studio set up and you
can't see it, but I've
got what looks like a
lightsaber behind me
that's glowing sort of
turquoise and some
other lights behind me.
They're doing a great
job of making me
look a little bit better.
Not the best canvas
to work with but
this this camera this
you know i guess
it's a canon eos r6
looks much better
than this previous uh
aliexpress uh camera
i was using before but
uh this was my old
camera you can like all
of like 30 bucks on
aliexpress i think
this new one's gonna
be a lot better so
thanks to kelsey and
angelo for coming in
all the way from north
bay ontario to uh
help the setup I
really appreciate that.
I'm going to mute
everyone here. If you
do want to pipe in,
feel free to unmute
yourself. But I
think this particular
Zoom doesn't have
the auto mute setup.
My apologies. So
we don't want to
hear your lunch order
if we can help it.
So before I
start, though,
we got a special guest.
So we got John
Willis, who's the
godfather. I'm going
to say grandfather.
Godfather of DevOps.
and uh you you've got
a new book coming out
i hear yeah yeah yeah
um so um thanks Reuven
and just to give a
quick quick you know i i
met Reuven on a plane
ride and he introduced
amazon cloud to me so
that we go back he's
like have you heard
this cloud thing no yeah
but anyway yeah no
so i've done a number
i've considered one of
founders of devops and
written a couple books
but i'm pretty proud
of my last book it was
it's the history of ai
it's called rebels of
reason it's sort of
a michael lewisian
style version of all the
things that had to
happen to get to where we
are literally on this
call right now um and
and going back like 100
years but going through
touring and and
anyway i i think it's
pretty entertaining it's
technical it it sort
of gives uh i think
it's fun book and so uh
you know again it's
out there on amazon i
posted the link and thank
you so much for giving
me the opportunity and
i'm looking forward
to hear the question
i've been asking is
where do i get started
so this was my today is
my my jam to hear to
hear you walk this us
through this so thank
you yeah and again john
and i met what 20
something years ago on a
random flight from
austin to toronto and he
was my seatmate you
know and were we hacking
on something on my
laptop and you're like
what what are you doing
yeah yeah we just like
what are you doing what
are you doing and i
told him a little about
what i was doing and
he's like well have
you heard about this
thing i call cloud i'm
like no what is it and
he's like oh man you
gotta look at it i
literally like like as
soon as i got off the
flight i literally dug
in and like became one
of the original cloudoratis
by accident so yeah
no it was uh it was
definitely a ride and
cloud that camp cloud
camp me and you and
dave and anyway we got
a cool history so yeah
we so for for those
who don't know this is
like cloud 2.0 for for
people like john and i
and you know this
there's a template and i
i definitely seem to
be following it back in
the cloud days it was
like hey let's let's
create uh these these
cloud events to introduce
this concept of cloud
computing and that
grew like just crazy
until i don't know how
many cities were in dozens
and dozens of cities
around the globe within
a matter of weeks
and we launched that
in 2008 so yeah it's
been a that's almost
yeah almost 20 years ago
so that's crazy yeah
wow yeah it is a little
crazy so the so this
week and will actually
last couple weeks have
been absolutely crazy
as well with with
the sort of work that
we've been doing with
the swarm development and
some of you might have
tuned in last week
to see see sort of
early iterations of that
and we've been making
huge amounts of progress
um we've got jed on
the line here as well
who's been helping
debug jed how's it going
it's going always fun
trying to figure out
the next uh frontier
and being at least part
of the team building
it yeah well it's it's
it's really nice to
have uh real people to
interact with in the
development process
because i'm often just
interacting with my ai
so you know it's different
when someone says
well this doesn't work
as expected so really
really appreciate all
the efforts that you
and ocean braun and jeff
and rob and everyone's
been doing the get
get this off the
ground so let's get to
the exciting part actually
one before we do
there we have a new uh
video portal that the
kaltura guys have put
together so let me show
we've lost the cover
here today um so there's
a site video.agentix
.org and there's a
new flash card option
i don't know if we have
zohar on the call or
not but let's see if
i can figure it out
there's some nice
features on this so we're
gonna go in here and see
what so there there's
a there's a meetup in
in new york tonight
i think possibly that's
right yep meet up
new york city tonight
i think they've uh i'm
not sure exactly how
much the space how much
space they've got but
they're booked solid
we are already at
capacity um so the first
basically the first 75
people to arrive will
get in and you can name
drop jed if you need
to right i i i'm i'm
with the band or or
whatever they say so
there's a uh let's see
what we got here i'm
i'm there's a all our
previous videos are auto
sort of being included
here there's some other
options um i'm not
sure i'm not sure how
how this works well
i'm my mouse disappears
that's weird there
we go strange but
anyway i don't i think
there's a problem with
zoom at the moment trying
to show it but essentially
you can go here
you can take a look you
can browse the videos
i'm not sure why my
mouse disappears but
that's that's probably
a byproduct of sharing
my screen and zoom oh
took a second to load
you when we've got
highlights and then I
think what you know
various flashcards anyway
take a look look it
sounds pretty cool I'll
do a deeper dive later
but that's that's
probably not the most
exciting part we're
gonna do today so what
we want to look at is
the new latest updates
to cloud flow so for
those who aren't familiar
club flow is this
idea of running swarms.
So swarms is a concept
that's been around
for a while, actually.
It's sort of autonomous
agents that can
collaborate with each
other. And the biggest
issue we've had with these
types of environments
is they were
prohibitively expensive.
So now with the rise of
Claude Max, where you
can get the sort of
unlimited use, it's
not unlimited, but for
all intents and purposes
it is unlimited i
i do max out when i
start going into like
crazy land of you know
spawning hundreds of
agents at a time but to
be honest most of the
swarms you're going
to do aren't going
to be in the hundreds
anyway they're going to
be probably somewhere
between five and maybe
20 agents that work
concurrently we've
added a whole variety of
different new features
we i'll show you here
in a moment things
like the hive mind this
is a system that allows
this the the agents
to use a queen
orchestrator which is also
pretty crazy the other
day the orchestrator
named herself seraphina
which was uh i
guess a biblical god uh
like the top angel in
heaven i didn't even
know that was a thing
and apparently that's
funny because i have
a very good friend
called seraphina by the
way it's a real name
really it's yeah and so
she's the a six-wing
god or six wing wing
angel he is an angel
by the way okay there
you go right it's it's
i i i'm not up to speed
on my uh on my
biblical history so but
there you go but if of
all the names to give
itself herself it was
an interesting choice
um and i'll dig in that
a little bit we get
the neural networks
so the system can now
you know attempt to fine
-tune itself uh we've
got a variety of MCP
tools, right, I'd
say 87 at this point.
And this is underpinned
by a lot of the tools
that I've been building
over the last month
or so, including most
of the Rust tools,
the QDAG system for
distributed kind of
darknet. We've got the DAA,
which is a sort of
abstraction of that
that allows for a kind
of decentralized agent
process. These are
all built in Rust and
compiled to a WASM.
And then we've got the
neural network
components and the neural
forecasting components.
I took all that stuff,
we put it together
to create this and we
packaged it as an MPX or
MPM that you can install
and run using TypeScript.
So really, really
fast, really light
and really powerful.
So what I'm going to
show you today is how
to get all this stuff
working. So we're going
to go through the
process step-by-step.
Hopefully if you have
any problems and if
you want to follow
along literally all you
need to do is start at
the vibe casting because
that's where I'm
gonna do it so we're
gonna go here and I'm
gonna I'm gonna walk
you through it slowly
and if I'm going too
fast pipe in and tell
me but this is this is
gonna be the step-by
-step all right so we're
going here we're on
the RubeNet Vibcast
I'll pop that in the
chat here for you guys
and here we go it's
in there you can go
here so I'm gonna create
a new code space on
main depending what
you're doing if you're
looking to do something
that involves like
and and more heavy
sort of analysis then
you might want to not
use the default code
space I don't really
care I'm just going
I just want to show
you guys how this works
so I'm gonna go and
I'm just gonna do the
default on main so
at this point I'm I'm
using the web-based
version now there's
differences between the
web-based version of
claw of sort of code
spaces and the VS code
version, the biggest
difference you're
going to see here is a
moment when I actually
attempt to activate
Claude code. It takes
two tries for, I don't
know why, and it has
nothing to do with
me. It has to do with
some kind of way
that they link the
authentication. When you
use it through VS code
directly, this problem
doesn't happen, but
I'm going to show you
how to get around that
problem anyway. So
we're going to go back
here I'm gonna go and
I'm gonna copy and paste
the first code so
this is gonna install
the anthropic cloud
code and again a couple
assumptions here you're
paying for a pro account
at the very minimum
if you use a swarm
the pro account will
essentially last you
about 20 minutes and
then you'll be you'll be
quoted for several hours
if you're using the
hundred dollar you
can probably get away
with the five agent swarm
for several hours if
you're using the two
hundred dollar you can
go all day now if you're
like me and you're
running concurrent
swarms you know then
you're gonna max it out
after a while but I I
I'm comfortably doing
a few hundred thousand
lines of code an hour
using the two hundred
dollar plan it's it's
crazy all right so
while while I was blabbing
here this was this
was setting up so
now I've got a really
generic I'm gonna create
a new branch let's call
it July 10th and I'll
create that then what
I'm going to do is
I'm just going to copy
this in. I'm going to
select allow. I'm going
to allow this forever.
Why? I don't care.
All right. So now
we post it in.
Then I'm going
to install this.
So I'm doing a
global installation.
Now you could do this
also as an MPX and
I think as well as
not a global, but
for this using a
global, the DASG
basically allows you
to run it as Claude.
And And you'll notice
that when we get to
the next stage where
I'm actually installing
the Claude flow, I'm
going to install that
as a remote instantiation,
not as a global
instantiation, which
means that you can
always get the most
recent version, which
works well when you're
working in a kind of
fast iterative alpha
type of release that
what I'm doing right now,
I'm me, us collectively,
we're updating this
several times a
day. All right. So in
this case where I'm
going to go here and
now that I've got, I'm
going to jump back
because I'm lazy into my
type, I'm going to
activate it. So this is
important. If you don't
activate it, you're
not going to be able
to use the dangerously
skipped permission.
And for those folks
who are saying, well,
the dangerously skipped
permission is a
security vulnerability.
Yes,
a hundred percent
it is. You're having
an autonomous AI swarm,
you know, operating
with very little
oversight. And so this
is why I'm using
a code space. It's
important. Don't run
this locally. If you
do, it's just a bad
idea. You're on Mac,
high likelihood it
breaks your Mac badly
and you get a kernel
panic and you're
going to have to
reinstall the entire Mac.
Windows, you use
the Linux subsystem.
You're a little
bit more protected
because the Linux
subsystem is
sort of a
containerized approach.
That said, do you
really want to swarm
around your local
environment? Probably not.
So that's why I'm
using this code space
approach here. So I'm
going to pop this in
here and this is
going to activate. The
first thing it's going
to do is going to
prompt me to actually
log in to cloud code.
You can choose the
color mode. I like
dark, so I'm going to
go with dark and I'm
going to choose the
cloud. You can use
an API. Now, interesting
to note here, if
you want to use
the swarm for like
actions on GitHub or
doing random security
checks, things like
that, then you can
switch to an API based
And you can instantiate
that through a
command line tool that
basically gives you
an argument that
you can pass the API
to or use the .env.
I'm cheap, so I'm
using the $200
a month plan, which
is, when I say
cheap, it's way
cheaper than the
thousands I was
spending before.
All right, so now I'm
going to click here.
I'm going to go
with the Claude. And
now this part, if you're
in the code space,
we're going to have
to do it twice.
I don't know. yeah if
anyone from Anthropics
watching you got to
fix it I don't know
what your deal is but
this this only really
affects the code space
so I'm gonna click
authorize it's gonna
go to a local host
I'm gonna have to go
back and then I'm gonna
click it again and
we'll see yeah this is
what you'll see now
we're gonna go back
and I'm gonna control
click or command click
if you're on a Mac
and that's gonna open
it again the second
time's a charm don't
know why it's a it's
it's a bug not in my
system but in cloud
code so now we go here
this time I'm good
it's gonna I'm gonna
authorize I guess I
probably should be showing
you this this authorized
code but whatever
it's just this is
just for this purpose
so I'm gonna paste that
in here oops that's
not what I want it
didn't you didn't copy
okay let's try out one
more time copy code
when it says copy it
usually means it copied
but in this case it
didn't let's try it one
more time all right
I'm logged in now I'm
gonna hit enter and
yes use recommended
settings I'm giving you
all the settings here
in a moment so you don't
worry about this too
much yes accept all
right so this is the
danger this is essentially
setting it up so
now once I'm done I'm
just gonna close this
for a moment I'm gonna
hit ctrl C a couple
times now what I would
normally do is at this
point as I probably
switch to my VS code
but I'm lazy so I'm
not gonna bother doing
that right now then I'm
gonna jump back to here
close this tab and
take a look at my next
so what this does is
initializes it so I'm
gonna copy this and
there's a couple different
settings here as
well so if I go here
and just copy like this
this is gonna force
so this is gonna overwrite
if you already have
cloud code installed
and use the force use
the force in anyway
it's it's going to
overwrite your your claw
.md file so if you want
it and you can instantiate
this in a subfolder
and then copying
the bits and pieces
that you might want to
keep but in this case
this is a pretty clean
repo so i don't care
so i'm going to go
ahead and actually run
that for a moment now
i'm gonna gotta i've got
a nice little script
it's gonna ask me to
so i included the dash
dash why give it a
sec to do its thing
bunch of stuff install
i'm i'm gonna try to
make it lighter but it's
it's kind of heavy so
it takes a second to
install i'm i'm i'm
giving you the the wasms
and a bunch of stuff
here and we'll watch
it do its thing the
dash dash y basically
just makes it so it
doesn't ask you questions
that's why i included
that um the alpha
gives you my alpha branch
and as i do updates
you're always going to
get the most recent.
There's a double
-edged sword to that,
though. The fact I'm
giving you my alpha
means that if I do
a bad update, which
can happen, you're
going to get the bad
update. You can
also add the version
number to that if you
find a version you
like. But for me,
I'm just using alpha.
And at some point, I'll
probably move to a beta.
And it'll probably
stay at beta forever.
Now, the benefit
to calling
this alpha is when
people complain,
I can say it's an alpha.
It's amazing
how much people
complain on
free software.
But while that's
happening,
if it's done, okay.
So what we see here,
it's creating the
files. It's the V2. It's
creating the cloud
folder. It's creating my
settings. And this
was, I think, Jed, you
suggested, I think the
settings, maybe someone
suggested it. This is a
local settings option,
creating my my hooks
I'm initializing my
memory system swarm
dot I added this last
night by the way this
is a really cool feature
I'll get into in a
minute but basically
I added memp a SQL light
memory for the swarm
as well as the hive
mind so there's two
different memory systems
and we've got some
other sort of commands
here we and we're
installed no now that
it's installed we can go
ahead and start trying
the thing out so in
this case what I'm gonna
do is I'm just going
to use the MPX. Again,
you can install this
global if you want.
And the benefit to
installing globally is
you don't need the MPX.
So hypothetically, if
you want it to install
globally, you do
something like install,
I think it was install-g,
but I've already
installed it.
And I don't bother
with that. You
probably don't
need it either.
Now I'm gonna do that
and we'll do help.
This is just gonna, I'm
looking for a couple
of things here. I'm
looking to make sure
I have the right
version. So we got the
alpha 43. So this is
the version I did last
night and I probably
should get more sleep.
I did this at two o
'clock in the morning.
So hopefully all is
well for this demo.
So we've got lots of
different features.
You can see here
that we've got the
hive mind wizard.
We've got the swarm.
Now what I'm going
to show you is a few
things. I'm going to
start with the hive
mind wizard because
it's kind of crazy.
So I'm just going
to grab that. And
so I'm just going
to grab this part
here because I don't
want to type it.
So we're going to go
back here and I'm just
going to pop that
in here. and this if
all goes well should
instantiate the wizard.
Now what the wizard
does is allows you
to create the sort
of running server for
the swarm itself. You
don't need to run this
just to be clear.
If you don't run it
the system just figures
itself out. It'll go
and instantiate this
stuff for you. This
just gives you a
little bit more control
over what it's going
to do and how it needs
to work and we'll
see that in a second.
A new swarm and
the objective of
the swarm needs
to be something
like a really
compelling demo.
And the Swarm name, we'll
call it, I don't know,
Seraphina.
All right. And then
we have different
options for the
queen coordinator.
I know it's straight
up sci-fi. So it's a
hive mind structure. So
you can, and I'm going
to add more sort of
structures later but
these were the ones
that seemed obvious to
me so i went with
strategic high level
planning now you're going
to notice that there's
two different approaches
there's the hive
mind approach and
then there's a swarm
approach and the key
differences i'm still trying
to figure out exactly
you know what and
how this all this stuff
works to be honest
this is a lot going on
here but from what i
can tell the hive mind
approach is really
good at kind of open
-ended, go figure it out,
do the best possible
solution to a problem,
but I'm not sure what
that solution is.
So it leans a little
more towards vibe
coding and a little
less towards I've got a
particular architecture
and system that
I want to implement.
Now you could guide
it obviously towards
those sort of details,
but in this case,
you know, I'm not
particularly concerned
about that. So I might
choose tactical
for detailed task
management. And so I
might point it at my my
GitHub to create an
issue or something like
that. I've got
adaptive, it just learns
and adapts. I have a
tendency to use that.
I don't know what
I need to know, but
I need to know it
needs to update itself.
So I'm gonna
choose adaptive.
And maximum number of
workers, and I might,
I'll choose five
here today, why not?
And then I can
choose different
types of researchers
I can include.
So I'll choose
reviewer, optimizer,
document, I'll
include all
of them, and
I'll hit enter.
Now, there's a
consensus system built
into this. The consensus
system essentially
allows the system
to determine how
it can collectively
come to a decision.
So depending on the
consensus you want to
use, it'll make different
determinations based
on the queen and the
subordinate agents.
So a majority means the
majority rules, right?
Everyone has to agree.
You know, if I got
five agents, then three
of the five agents
essentially have to
agree. a weighted
approach means that there's
more waiting towards
the queen basically
is kind of the the ceo
if you will and the
byzantine that's that's
a little more difficult
to explain the
easiest way to explain
it is it kind of works
like a consensus
algorithm on a blockchain
similar to how the
ethereum blockchain would
likely work where you
have sort of a proof
proof of work proof of
stake kind of approach
i'm still trying to
figure out exactly
how that one works so
I'm not going to use
that today I'm going to
go with majority rules
all right so now we
get that now you'll
see here that we've
got you know an auto
scaling this will means
it can add new instances
on the on the fly
sure hey quickly Ruben
on your on your consensus
algorithm thing do
you know uh what the
advantages are of the
different modes I'm
still trying to figure
that out okay it's fine
yeah I built I built
it three days ago right
and so I'm learning
I'm learning as much
as you guys are i i
know that there's
differences i can see them
when i try different
things but it's too
early to even tell you
exactly what those are
and maybe you guys
can play with it and
tell me i i don't know
you want to say something
jade the best
suggestion i have for
everyone who's experimenting
with this is to get
to a cloud code
interface and use that to
ask questions of the
source code that's the
only way i've been able
to ramp up to maybe
20 of the speed that
Reuven been getting.
Yeah,
that's a really
good suggestion.
And to be honest,
I do that too.
So now that we have
this instantiated, you
don't necessarily even
have to use the Claude
flow system because
I've given you all the
commands. So as soon as
you instantiate Claude
code by going here
into a new tab and just
typing in something
like Claude will help.
and I'm just going to
grab the dangerously
skipped permissions
because I don't, and
so I don't have to
necessarily instantiate
it the way I was
showing a moment ago.
And the benefit to doing
it the way Jed just
said it is I get all
these slash commands
and these, all these
slash commands are
basically the commands
you see here for
like GitHub. So if I
was to choose GitHub,
I can get all those
commands and you can
customize these. So
what I'm seeing a lot of
folks do is they, once
this is instantiated,
they're just going
into cloud code and
they're instantiating
this inside an existing
repo and then they're
saying go customize
the command customize
the cloud md file to
meet the specifics of
this particular repo
so what i'm giving you
is a kind of generic
template to create
these either hive style
or or more traditional
if you will swarms
but you you can
instantiate any way you
like so in this case
you i i did it that way
now this is running
here so now it's
suggesting here that
i've got uh and i wasn't
fast enough so it's
decreasing it's so it's
auto tuning itself
so in this case it's
decided to reduce the
concurrency of agents to
nine so i'm going to
go ahead and just grab
this and we're going
to create yet another
instance and then then
we're going to get
the swarm to go do
something so this again
this is the hive this
is the hive mind so
create
research oh what
are we gonna
research any ideas
what what you guys
want to create
research and create
the most amazing
breakthrough
of all time
and
build it.
Maybe we'll
choose a genre.
I don't know. Is
there any genre?
How about animations?
It'd be cool to see some
visual stuff
come out of this.
Like a front end
kind of experience.
Quantum entanglement.
Yeah, keep in mind.
Yeah,
front ends are probably
the least if you want
to do a front end
you're probably going to
want to use something
like like uh i don't
know like uh lovable
or something they're
kind of rudimentary like
we can do front ends
without question they're
just it's it's almost
like you know using
nuclear weapons when
you could use a bullet
or something i mean
that's a bad analogy i'm
sorry interrupted you
yeah go ahead go ahead
yeah i'm building
this pitch deck uh
thing just stupid idea i
want a founder to get
the deep research facts
and then build a pitch
deck for their idea
or for their company can
i build something can
we build something
like a back end that
provides this kind of
work yeah why don't we
why don't we do two
why don't we use alex's
animation system and I'm
going to get the swarm
to do that and put it
in build, you know,
uh,
create it in
the animator AI.
And then what we're
going to do is
write it while that's
building, we're
going to do a pitch
deck system and
we're going to use a
swarm for that. All
right. So we're
going to, we're going
to call it Alex
triple X animator.
All right. triple
x animator might
not go too well
maybe double x
ruve i find ourselves
here far too
often i don't know
how okay two x two
x five catch man
i i never even
thought that the
triple x was well i
just thought it was
lots of x's okay
yeah we'll go too
since this is being
saved to the internet
forever yeah all
right yeah so okay
two X's. My apologies
to Alex with two
X's. All right.
So we're going to
launch that. Oh,
that's, I didn't,
I didn't install it
globally. So we're going
to have to go back.
I'm going to add the
MPX. This is something
that happens. And
because I didn't install
globally, I've got
to add the at alpha.
Now I'm, I'm, I'm
usually running in my dev
environment where
I started globally.
That's why I just wasn't
thinking, but if I
installed it globally,
that wouldn't have
an issue all right so
i'm going to go ahead
and instantiate that
we can see here that
now it's launching the
swarm starting with
initial worker count
four it's using the
dangerously skip
permissions it's using the
auto spawn to launch
instances automatically
it's verbose so
it can see it it's
using the shared mcp
swarm memory usage which
will store the
information to the actual
shared memory, which
we can take a look
at here as well while
it's sort of starting
up. So we'll go
here to HiveMind.
All right. So now that
that loaded up, now
a couple of things
to look at quickly.
I'm basically what I'm
doing is I'm injecting
dynamic variables and
prompts. So you can
see here that I'm
giving it the HiveMind
structure, you know,
consensus algorithm
majorities and different
settings. I'm telling
it what the researchers
need to do. I'm
giving some other
information about the mcps
that needs to interact
with to sort of understand
learning and task
orchestration and
worker management and
then i'm giving examples
it's just a well a
sort of well-defined
prompt now at the bottom
here you can see it
instantiating it's
kind of flickering a
little bit which is i
know it's because i'm on
my smaller monitor
but basically i can't
really show it because
it doesn't let me scroll
too much but basically
it's it's instantiating
the memories and we
can see that when
i go to the hive system
here for a moment
We'll see that
it follows well.
And there's two
files. There's a
memory and there's
a hive mind.
And we'll let it do
its thing for a moment.
Take a sec to start up.
Now we can see this
is the introspection.
And this is the part
where it's going to get
interesting later
when I get to building
web-based dashboards and
simpler systems. This
allows me to see
what's happening within
the structure. So I
can see the collective
memories. I can see
consensus decisions. It
hasn't made any
decisions yet. I can see
different swarms. I
can see tasks. No tasks
I've started yet. So
this gives me the ability
to see what's happening
within the structure
of the system itself
in real time. Now,
this is the data. Now,
what's great about
SQLite is it's super
fast and I'm using the
write, I think it's a
head write. I forget
what it's called.
Basically, it's the
fastest option for
SQLite. And someone else
is probably more
familiar with SQLite can
explain exactly
what how this right
mechanism wal works and
we got another memory
system here this is
kind of a secondary
memory um i might get
rid of that but this
is just another
mechanism for the memory
i'm gonna let this run
for a bit basically
let's just we can sort
of see it thinking
a little bit we can see
it's you know creating
some information
now here's the part
that's important it's
it's it's working in
in a concurrent sort
of fashion you see
there's tasks and these
other tasks are sort
of basically writing
alongside the other.
So it can instantiate
and decide when it
needs a swarm or when it
needs to do a sequential
or how they need to
sort of optimize.
Interesting, quantum
computing animation
algorithm,
which is funny
because someone
mentioned quantum
computing.
So it's looking at,
it's researching that.
Now, while this does this
thing- Just a
quick thing,
Rufin, is that
there's a new
rewrite of SQLite
and they're
writing it in
Rust, by the way.
Yeah, I've been looking
- called the limbo
project it's not fully
compliant yet but
that's where that's
where they're going
and it's like really
fast we could probably
rewrite that and that
might be a project
and do right now when
it was with the swarm
like and that's a
lot of what i'm doing
is i'm rewriting
existing libraries so
for example when you
look at my neural
forecaster i took the
neural forecaster python
library and i basically
pointed it at my
swarm at that and
said build that for me
bed and the same project
yeah so let's let's
let's let's take a
look at limbo project
all right so let's let's
do let's do a swarm
let's do a swarm so
so let's go and i'm
going to type this time
i'm going to do npx
flood flow at alpha
but this time what i'm
going to do is i'm going
to use a swarm rather
than a hive mind
now the hive mind is
currently running you
can see a building here
in the alex with two
x's uh animator folder
it's going to build
it it looks like it's
probably going to build
it in i don't know
sure what it's going
to build it in i never
upload what language
to build it in and
it's i can't quite tell
there's no files yet
you know i guess we'll
let it keep doing its
thing um well while
that does its thing
i'm going to go and i'm
going to look at the
swarm settings so i'm
just going to type
swarm and i don't have
an objective so it's
telling me i need an
objective so this to be
honest most of the
work that i'm doing
involves using the the
swarm capability or my
github capabilities so
we go back we can see
here we got other
options so it depends so
when i get up in the
morning and i look at
my repo and i see
these various uh issues
like we'll we'll go
to my issues here and
you'll notice that i
i respond to some of
them you know, let's
see what we got here.
I'm using the GitHub
option to do that. So
here's a proposal for
a quick setup guide.
Someone, KoiGeek,
and thanks KoiGeek,
you've been providing
a lot of great
ideas here. So he
came up and he's
saying YOLO and
some other things.
So then I pointed
the GitHub at it and
it says, here's
your, here, I'm
Claude or whatever.
And here's just some
suggestions and
here's what we want.
want to do here's a
deep analysis so some
persistence so it came
up with an idea then
it created a follow
-up bug and then we can
take a look at that
and that's literally
how i created the sql
component last night
based on someone saying
well why doesn't it
persist only in the
hive mind you should
it should persist
other than hive mind i
basically pointed at
it and i'm not sure why
it's taking so long
to load that but it's
not sure that the libvo
project is fully open
source i mean it is
but i think they have
a closed repo did roof
freeze for you guys
yes yeah he's frozen so
this is a new
youtuber setup
that he had hey uh
rob can you text
roof and let
him know please
yeah i'm moving
faster than
the speed of
light and sound
or at least the
speed of information
so is this the is
this setting where
it's hitting the
github um like out of
the box now with
this with this alpha
uh no that one i
believe rUv had a custom
or github mcp yeah
that then pushes the or
manipulates github itself
uh the other option
is to use the github
cli make sure you
authenticate securely
into it and then you can
have cloud code
manipulate the github cli
to then make changes to
the repos you control
and so are there
specific requests so are
you are you just are
you are you going into
the github cli and
or are you going into
cloud the cloud flow
cli in the terminal to
authenticate and then
i let cloud code cli
manipulate the github
cli independent of me
That's because Claude has
native GitHub
integration,
and they rely on the GH.
It's not native, David.
You have to install
the GitHub CLI. Yeah,
you have to install
the GitHub CLI to get
it, but the capability
is built into Claude.
Otherwise, you've
got to use a GitHub
MCP, which I prefer to
use MCP because I have
more control over my
GitHub connections.
Sorry, you mentioned that
it's already included.
but we don't
have to do it.
It is not
already included.
No.
You have to explicitly
install it. You
have to install of
the GH, the GitHub CLI
command set. That
doesn't come bundled with
Claude. You've got
to do that manually.
But it knows how to
use that tool set once
it knows that it's
there. You don't have
to have anything else.
It knows how to talk
to GitHub once you
install the GitHub CLI.
but sorry i every
time i trigger uh one
workspace in github for
example do i have to
install this mcp
connection to github to be
able to follow there's
two ways you need to
authenticate your mcp
to github yes if that's
what you mean by
install it you need a
patch which is a
personal authentication
token okay all right
so there's two ways to
have claude communicate
with github One is
through an NCP where you
have a GitHub MCP and
your personal
authentication token, you
set that up, or it has
built-in code natively
that knows how to
talk to GitHub without
an NCP, but you manually
have to install the
GitHub CLI. Just do
it like an app install
on Linux. So there's
two options for you.
I don't like the built
-in way because you
have to follow the
anthropic methodology for
doing GitHub, which
means you have to do
PRs, you have to do
workflows, you have to
do issues. You have to
mention at Claude. You
have to do all their
workflow that's built
into it. You kind of
do and don't, but they
– and you have to
authenticate stuff. I
prefer the MCP way
because then you get to
do your normal standard
GitHub methodology.
The most important
thing is you do only
one of the two
methods. If you do both
methods, there will be
weird hallucinations
that are very
hard to untangle.
I've tried that as well,
Jed, man, and
it's not cool.
because it has GitHub.
Claude has GitHub
capability built in,
but that built-in
capability doesn't want
to naturally use the
MCP if you have it,
right? It wants to use
itself plus the GitHub
command line set.
Yeah, but you store the
personal access token
for the MCP. But
where do you store it?
you put it in a .m
file and then you
configure it in your
MCP config you ask
Cloud Code to draft
detailed instructions
on how to do the
thing I do it manually
if I have a command line
installed how do I tell
Cloud to use the MCP only
or do I have to uninstall
the command line
options so that when
it tries to use the
command line option it
gets an error interprets
that it's an error
and tries another way
yeah you only want one
you only want to use
one either mcp or right
github command line
if you can configure both
but it will hallucinate
if you're used to
using the command
line that means you
lose that if you want to
use the mcp but but be
careful right because
when we say command
line like most it's the
gh command line yeah
i understand yeah yeah
the gh cli they call
it right and and
normally you don't use
that you're just doing a
full install of git
and it's not the same.
Yeah, there are a few
small things that I'll
use GH for, but I hear
what you're saying.
And also, if
you're doing it in
a Codespaces, you
can avoid that.
Yes, Codespaces,
it comes, it's
already installed,
right? You get
the full GitHub
command line set.
Just a note, Ruben's
entire computer has
crashed, so he's rebooting
and coming back up.
And my understanding
with the GitHub, the
the personal token is
that given what it is
going to be used for
with the swarm that
it should be just for a
single repo and minimal
permission is restricted
to your account
you can't have the
token restricted to a
repo yes it's full x
it's full account based
well they could think
i don't think it can
do fine i i tried that
i did see find game
print control i never
used it it doesn't
it doesn't limit to
the repo it limits what
you can do in all
repos so only read only
write, only file issues,
only edit the wiki.
So what I have had to
do is create multiple
GitHub accounts tied to
specific organizations
and then share repos
to those organizations
with specific roles.
That way I'm able to
enforce slightly more
granular permissions
to make sure I don't
inadvertently
push to main.
for those of you
whose main branches
are dependent on
actual things.
Yeah, it is a little
tricky. It does get
a little tricky when
you are committing
back to a branch and
you're issuing those
commands, what's doing
it like you want to
be very careful about
it. And that's why I
prefer the MCP. I
get a little bit more
control the way I
want my normal GitHub
methodology. We could
probably use Cloud Code
to extend the MCP
so that only select
commands to GitHub's
API are exposed to the
LLMS tools. That might
be a better way to
fork it or improve
that specific feature.
Yeah, I think that's
a good idea is
to enhance the MCP
option because I
think I asked Reuben
about this and
he's using the
called Swarm, right?
And Flow are using
the GitHub MCP.
i forget the precise
um mcp version he's
using i know it's
not the official one
he's using some a
third party mcp for
github yeah there's
a there's a lot of
them out there actually
right it's quite
it's quite annoying
back ruve you there
oh it's like a seance
are you there ruve
who's got the finger
on the ouija board
So while we're waiting
for Ruben's return,
anyone else have
specific questions? Yeah,
that was like an
epic, that was an epic
crash. Remember I
was telling you about
the kernel panic?
Well, I don't know.
I had to restart.
And then I had to
get all the cameras
back up and running.
It apparently
takes five minutes
to get back.
Where did we leave
off? Let me pause for a
was everything i was
saying making any
sense yes to the point
where you do make
where we can make
sense of what you say
yes i last remember
you talking about
quantum animation and
then the whole triple
x uh mentioned so
whatever you remember
after that yeah
quick question yeah
when you start a swarm
do you ever need to
stop and resume or
change tasks change
when the computer
completely my computer
never crashes I guess
it was Zoom or something
but yeah we're going
to have to go through
that right now so
the higher resolution
of your camera plus
the transcoding for
YouTube is probably
taxing your computer yeah
I need a Mac I was just
going to say Windows
I was going to
suggest have a
different computer
do the transcoding
yeah that could be
maybe my ****** camera
what was the difference
this is a great
camera though i i
will say um but to uh
matt's question like
how do you how do you
recover from a like
an epic fail um well
we're we're about to
uh go through that
process if that's
interesting so give me a
sec i'm still getting
everything back up and
running um so just
to summarize multiple
modes two instances
up and running right
you had a monolithic
traditional Claude
you had a Claude um
i don't know it was a
swarm or flow whatever
doing the doing the
animation system and
you were about to
spin up a third one
to do the sequel limbo
yeah exactly all
right so just now i'm
gonna i'm actually
gonna switch to um vs
code i'm not i don't
i don't know what
caused that epic
failure probably zoom
it's not probably
not the the best for
high-resolution
streaming, I would guess.
All right. It's
live, so, you know,
you get what you
don't pay for.
All right. Here we go.
Let's see here.
I'm going to connect
to my Codespace.
I'm going to share
my screen again.
And so while I'm getting
up and running again,
if you get any questions,
I'm happy to answer them.
What GitHub MCP
are you using?
Yeah.
I know it's not
the official
one. I just don't
remember which.
Have you noticed that
that one isn't working
particularly well
recently? It was
working great and it
stopped. Or is it just
me? Not just you. I
also moved to the CLI.
Yeah, it was
it was amazing.
Oh, we lost him
again, didn't we?
Rob,
can you please text
Roof? Tell him to
stop using the VS
Code web page. I think
that's interfering
with something else.
whenever he starts
that up and tries
to share it it's
causing problems you
need better
separation of concerns
or just use vs
code desktop
yeah
but he was going to
use the desktop right
he wasn't going to
use that to make an
appropriate sacrifice
to the demo gods
maybe calling it
seraphim was a little too
yeah
yeah he's
I thought he was
going to not use
the integrated
web VS code, and
he was going to
go for the app.
I don't know what
he started to share.
Yeah, me either.
Could tell.
So, Jed, can we ask a
few questions as we wait?
Go ahead, although
it's probably
faster to put
them in the chat.
Well, I don't know.
I think my problem
is my camera.
It's the only difference
today is a much
better camera.
Zoom keeps crashing.
Way too much data stream.
Yeah. Maybe I
switch to low res?
Yeah. Good idea.
Let's see here.
Sorry. Did
someone have a question?
Yeah, I have a question.
We can wait
after the demo.
Mine was actually
on memory. It's
maybe related to
what you're about to
do, but the memory
management, like
in the case of
right now crashing,
is that kind of
where it comes handy
as well? Are you
talking about memory
as in RAM or memory
as in context?
No, the memory, you
have the HiveMind memory
management that you
showed us earlier.
So that is the database.
It's just a
database into which
snippets of
text are stored
on other config
and metadata.
Yeah, it allows you,
it essentially allows
you to resume. So
it has context to
what's happening in
exactly this scenario.
So, and I switched
to low res. I don't
know if that's
going to make it.
Hopefully this is
not going to crash.
This episode is a
little buggy. My
apologies. We've got
a new setup happening.
So, here we go.
I'm going to attempt to
restart this whole thing.
New terminal.
Now, it would have
lost the session. it
might have continued
for a bit but it
probably it probably
stopped let me just double
check where we are
yeah what i tried
and it worked really
well is i don't use vs
codes terminal i open
separate terminal
and run cloud there
while it's absolutely
fine works on the code
that i have in the
VS code. Are you
running locally, Elio?
Yeah, yeah, when I
run locally, yeah.
And I have...
That's a terrible...
You think my
system is going to
crash? You do
that, you're almost
guaranteed to
crash your system.
Especially if you're
doing anything under
load. You're going to
be spawning hundreds,
potentially thousands
of processes.
You know, you could
do it. It's just
almost guaranteed to
screw up your computer.
And probably why
I'm having trouble
myself because
I've done it.
If you do do it, do it
in a Docker instance,
maybe, or use the
Windows subsystem,
if you're in Linux
subsystem, possibly.
I just,
yeah, I would
highly recommend not
doing that. It's
just a bad plan.
But back to this,
you've got, you
might have noticed
that I just, to
resume where I
started, I did dash C.
So the dash C essentially
allows it to recover,
right? it's it's
kind of like there's
also resume option i
think is basically a
synonym for the same
thing so now what when i
do dash c and now the
drawback is here that i
had two different uh
systems so it looks
like it's instantiated
the hive one now i i can
say something like my
uh computer crashed
and i need to
resume uh review
the mem memory
and continue
Does Cloud C
automatically go
back to the Swarm
Hive, basically?
Because I know you
said, Reuven, in
the chat, you said
earlier on in the
WhatsApp chat that
asked the Queen Hive.
So what else?
Yes. That's
exactly what I was
doing. So it's
looking at the
memory. So you
see it here.
It It's determining
where it left off
and now you can see
it's spawning additional
agents to resume
where it left off.
Oh, I see.
So basically when
you recover, you
see, obviously you
use Claude C and
then dangerously
skip permissions.
But could I have just
said, once I start
Claude, could I have
just said, now look at
the memory in the file
system and resume using
the Hive Swarm approach,
continue? Because
I tried that it didn't.
Okay, all right.
That's exactly what
you could do. And
it depends if you're
using Swarm, like up
until last night,
I had a pretty
rudimentary memory system
for unless you were
using Groove Swarm,
which would have
the SQLite approach,
but the Cloudflow
was using essentially
a JSON structure.
which is okay, it
did work, but it
wasn't as elegant
as this. This allows
it for much better
introspection.
So now we can see the
concurrent tasks running,
doing writes and doing
the Cloudflow Swarm.
I can go back to the
Swarm and see the
memory. So now it
uses a combination.
So the Swarm memory
gives you a kind of
introspection into what
it's thinking about. So
here, well, I'm actually
probably using the
hive mind. So I should
go look at that one.
I think it crashed
before I got
a chance to
start the swarm.
But the actual memory
in, you see there's
different structures
for the memory here.
Now the memory for
the swarm, I actually
did quite a bit
more for it. So
when you go here
and you see memory,
this one's not
running currently, but
you see here that
there's a lot more
options. I've got
agent interactions,
I've got code patterns,
error patterns,
knowledge graph,
MCP tool usage.
So I've taken it sort
of a bit further.
Now these two can
work together.
Like you can
have the Hive
where you use the
swarm as well.
And often you'll see
both- Quick question,
Reuven, the SQLite
database that
you're using, is it
running on one of
the, on the machine,
on the Codespace,
or is it running in
a cloud instance?
It's running right here.
It's a local
Codespace, David. Yeah,
local Codespace. But
it's just a file.
I know, yeah.
Well, it's a little
more than the file.
I'm using the right
ahead option. But out
of the options I
looked at, it was the
simplest to distribute
because I could
literally just include
it in the MPM, MPX.
And there was no external
requirements, really.
And I did some
benchmarking, and it was
the fastest by far for
the types of things
that I was doing. Now,
if you're doing an
enterprise application
where you'd have
multi-tenant users and
other things. You might
want a more elegant,
but for the types
of things that I'm
doing, it was perfect.
Yeah, just so
everybody knows, right?
It's familiar because
where the actual
instance is running,
what machine,
either it's a cloud
instance or it's
locally on your dev
machine somewhere,
your dev instance. Yeah.
Now, to the gentleman's
point in regards
to running it in
different terminals,
that is actually a
really good idea because
you don't, as long
as those terminal
sessions are going to
some kind of remote
or at least containerized
environment,
somewhat separated from
your local environment.
If he was doing that
with Docker, for
example, locally,
that'd probably be fine.
If, you know, if you
wanted, you know,
additional GPU resources,
you could spin up AWS
instance, and then
just SSH into it. That,
that also would be
fine. I'm just, I just
reluctant to recommend
right now, anyway,
running this just in your
local environment
without any kind of
containerization i'm
just i've run into a lot
of problems with it so
i just don't want to
i still want people
thinking that's a
particularly good way to
start unless unless you're
like really comfortable
with devops and
you can fix your own
problems i think by all
means but but if
you're not comfortable
with massive configuration
issues then you're
just don't do it i i
everyone keeps emailing
me i ******* up my
computer how do i fix
that, you know, I
don't know, you got to
reinstall it. Right.
And I just don't want to
go down that road
and be the guy that
suggested you screw up
your computer. I think a
good thing to say,
Reuven, is if you're like
a one machine person,
like you have a nice
big powerful Mac and
that's the only thing
you use, don't do it
on that system because
it will, it will
splatter a lot of stuff
everywhere. And, and,
you know, if you don't
have other systems,
like I have like five
Linux boxes in my, in
my house here. So if
you're, if you only
have that one system,
don't run it on that one
system or containerize
it or mac i have a mac
mac minis and stuff
like that they use i
don't really what do
you do if it disconnects
from the code space
or you're like mid
project and you have
to tell it to come
back and and look at it
again because i've had
that happen a couple
times code space is
flexible on disconnects
it will stay running
for a couple of hours
well it depends you
notice that this didn't
it depends on how
how you disconnect so
yeah i'm I'm just
saying the code space
is flexible. The app
that you ran, the
swarm, that's going to
get a timeout, right?
Danny,
if you disconnect from
a terminal session in
the code space,
depending on how the code
space was launched,
it may also kill that
terminal session. So
what I've been doing to
allow me to resume a
disconnected code space
is using Tmux, spelling
down in the chat.
And I spin up
multiple Tmux
instances, each
containing a cloud code
session so that
I can disconnect
from my computer,
commute home,
reconnect to the
Tmux session, and
then see how far
it's progressed.
Oh, yeah, that's what
I was looking for,
because sometimes it
disconnects and then
I have to tell it,
like, it starts trying
to rebuild the whole
thing. I'm like, no,
no, no, you already
built half of it. Like,
stop. Just be careful,
right? Tmux, I
get what you're saying
to you. Tmux is a
little bit of a DevOps
tool, right? You got
to kind of know how
to run it. It's not
super user friendly.
Well, the good news
is that I asked CloudCo
to write me a very
detailed set of
instructions on how to use
tmux i didn't know how
to use it two weeks
ago i i know how to
use tmux i had to
learn it by hand and
so yeah but you you're
the man man i love
the way you do stuff
there uh what's going
on well anyway i'm i'm
uh you've got various
options available to
you you know i i don't
think i had the there
we go github i think
i think i just need
What? Is there a
reason you're trying
to install GitHub
twice? Or did you miss
a dash between GitHub
and Sheetracker?
There we go.
Oh, I did it twice.
Good call. No,
I'm all flustered
from my epic
failure earlier
is what happened.
But yeah, so
basically, I can go in
here, and I can
create GitHub. So in
this case, well,
now what's going on?
anyway guys the
today today's
demo is uh it
let's just let's
just do a swarm
i know that works
npx that we'll go in
here and we'll do quad
flow alpha it's
actually kind of good
though reuben to because
a lot of people have
this have this
particular problems which
is you know something
broke something
stopped i gotta stop
it or whatever and i
really really it's a
very common problem to
know how to continue
on from where you left
off either intentionally
or accidentally
that that's a there's
a very common problems
that a lot of people
are going to face
yeah yeah so so in
this case we we just
noticed i just noticed
there was a there was a
bug i i see here this
what this bug most
likely means i think is
it's not instantiating
clod code correctly
would be my guess and
i'm just doing a quick
test in the swarm
but now what i what i
would do actually what
i'll likely do is i
would spin up my actual
environment that i
have running for where
do i have that my
cloud float instance so
i'm gonna so this is
spinning up a swarm so
you can see here it's
it's injected the
memory patterns and it's
analyzing i basically
said fix my problem
it's it's not you know
it doesn't know what
my problem is i'm
just messing around
with it but in this case
i did notice that there
was a potential bug
so while that's going
and figuring out what
it's going to do i'm
going to go i've got
another vs code instance
and in this case
this one looks like
it actually resumed
interestingly so i'm
going to i'm going to
close this for a sec
and i'm just going to
confirm that there's a
bug so you notice that
i'm running this uh
this is the environment
that i'm running to do
with the development
of cloud code it's
or cloudflow itself.
You can also
do that as well
if you want to
use the wrapper.
And what I'm going to
test quickly is the
dot cloudflow slash I
guess spell it right.
Low GitHub.
and it looks like
the issue was causing
me a problem so I'm
gonna type that yeah
it looks like let's
just double check
yeah looks like
there's an error there
that's because I'm
probably in the wrong
repo so I'm gonna switch
to my other my 2.6.
I'm going to go
lazy on that.
Help.
Copy this.
I guess I could
type it out,
but I'm lazy to do that.
And we're going
to go here.
I'm actually in
Jed's repo. So I
don't know why
there's an error, but
I'm not going to
worry about that.
So, I'm going to go to my
actual branch
that I know works.
And I'm going to
stash and switch
to what was the
name of my branch?
I think it was v2
.6, v2.06, v2.06.
For everyone else
offering errors in the
chat, please include
instructions on how to
reproduce that error so
we can try to fix it.
Yeah.
And one of the reasons
I create branches
whenever I test
someone else's issues
or PRs is for
exactly the scenario.
So this one was
exploring the transparent
feature or something
like that. So now
I've got that going, I'm
going to just quickly
check that that is
no longer an issue.
So I'll go here and
we'll just, I'm going
to instantiate the
wrapper just because
I want to see if
that causes an error.
There we go.
Sorry, Jed, your branch
is having some trouble.
Now I'm going to
be the first time.
I'm going to go back
here and I'm going
to just double check
that the GitHub
stuff is either
broken or not. GitHub
and then I'm
going to grab
the GitHub I
think I tried the
issue.
Which one was it?
I don't remember
which one it was
at this point.
Issue tracker.
Yeah, issue tracker.
So I'm going to go there.
What I'm trying
to do is see if
I can create
that error again.
No, it's one of
those things. So
interesting note, it
doesn't happen when I
try to instantiate
it with the wrapper.
Interesting.
So there's a lot of
different ways to
instantiate it, right?
So if I instantiate
it with the MPX
and I add alpha,
we're going to try that.
Doesn't seem to have a
problem there either.
It's one of those,
this is a common
issue I run into.
It's the works...
So, you notice that I
did the same thing over
here, and here I had
these issues, right?
So this is, I don't
know what this is even
doing, let's just close
that for a sec, and
issue GitHub, issue
tracker, and then
we're going to just
run that one more time,
oops.
So this is how, this
is how, this is a
lot of the debugging
that I need to do.
So now that I see
there's an error,
oh, yeah, here we go.
This, all right. I
think this is, one
last thing I need
to check. I think
this is because
I'm not checking, I
think Claw's making
me log back in.
Yes.
So this is, so what
I didn't, so what
I did on the swarm
and what I did on
the hive mind, but
what I didn't do
on the GitHub is do
a check for whether
or not you're
logged in. So now
that I verify that
that is the issue,
I'm gonna go create an
issue that addresses
that. So I'm gonna
go back here and all
right. And then I'm
gonna go back to this.
But you're not
gonna create an
issue in the GitHub
UX, right? Yeah,
create an issue for
the following error
using, you know,
error. When Claude
code requires you
to re-enable the
token, I'm getting
the following error.
this was fixed in the
uh what was it in the
uh swarm function that
i got spelled right
create a issue with the
problem and solution
use the cli yeah back
to jed's point the
the cli i'm just using
cli for a lot of stuff
you know the mcps are
useful but at least
i know the clis work
so in this case i'm
a uh an issue
we'll let and then
oh man not
again so oh what
oh he's back
you're back okay
it's oh it crashed
again i think
we're good guys
i apologize
zoom's dead we
still hear you roof
we can hear you
guys we can yeah
we got your audio
can it be the
streams i don't
think he hears us
okay um yeah what
is this video we're
probably gonna have
to benchmark his uh
internet connection his
transcoding capacity
yeah well he he might
have changed his camera
pumping a ton more
data into his machine
than whatever webcam
he was using it's not
just that he's also
streaming to two other
locations yeah he's got
a lot and youtube so
like that's a lot of
transcoding maybe claude
flow can build distributed
system for him.
Can you share the
YouTube channel?
I haven't been
able to find it.
Just look up
Reuven, I think
that's what it's called.
If that's not it,
it'll show up in the
WhatsApp group later,
maybe the Discord.
All right, thanks.
Can I just clarify
something? So
I'm just trying to
summarize, so we
were on your branch
Jed, right? There
was an issue that
Roof noticed.
Did we actually
I noticed he was
creating a GitHub issue.
Were we demonstrating
the ability for us to
say when we notice
an issue about how to
report back? Back to
your comment on the chat?
I ran into my own
problem while using the
latest version of pre
-alpha clod flow and
basically it had to do
with resource exhaustion
my computers are
running out of ram so i
tried to i prompted clod
code to create an epic
as an issue in the clod
the rovnet clod flow
repo to detail a
solution that has the
swarm that makes the swarm
aware of the remaining
resources in the
specific environment and
to decide whether it
should spin up another
agent or to cue the
task for the existing
batch of agents to
consume later. That way I
avoid resource exhaustion
and the number of
agents hypothetically
would dynamically scale
up and down based on
the available resources
in the environment as
well as the collective
existing agent's
resource consumption.
Now, I spoke a lot of
words. I typed about
maybe 100 of those
words, and then it
generated a however long
epic, including testing
plans, feature sets,
user stories, that
a subsequent invocation
of cloud code
picked up without the
context that was originally
generated and pushed
into the issue,
and then started trying
to build and build
tests for within my
Cloud Code instance.
Hey, everyone.
It's David
Bratton here. I'm
the chair of
the foundation.
Reuven just messaged
Robert and I
that he's done.
His system has
crashed again.
Obviously, we'll get
some systems
there figured out.
There's a fairly good
dialogue going on
here. So I'm happy to
keep the stream going
uh uh jed braun and
ocean were active
with Reuven um developing
the system uh so
if they're if they're
down to continue this
discussion um i'm
happy to keep the
thread open uh otherwise
uh Reuven will not
be returning to the
stream unfortunately
good to know i'm
good till two o'clock
eastern so i've got
another 50 minutes with
all of you if you have
any specific questions
happy to answer them
i feel abandoned
just to just to
talk about monday's
question right so the the
question for you
monday was that
the the thing that
the the issue that you
described jed i'm not
sure that was the issue
that actually Reuven
was dealing with that
was the issue which
caused the branch that's
what led to the creation
of the brand in the
first place my question
was more like jed
going back to your
comment on the chat if we
are having an issue how
do we report it back
to you in a meaningful
and automated way so
what i heard from you
is saying if i install
cloud flow swarm alpha
and like that hook
error right if i face
it do i have the ability
to ask cloud code to
report it to roof's
repo as a github uh
um issue i believe so
yeah it should be easy
to test right now just
create a dummy issue
verify it can be created
and then close it
i think there's no
constraints on who can
create issues right now uh
jean i'm not sure
that's super easy to do
actually i think anyone
who's a member of the
of the repo can
actually create an issue
and this is where you
need to be careful because
all issues are now
going to be picked up
by Claude Flow and the
swarm and potentially
acted on. Well, that
part isn't automatic.
That's why we explicitly
have to prompt
Claude Code to pull a
very specific issue.
For that reason, we
don't automatically
pull all issues
for development.
So the human is still
curating the issue.
And that's the normal
process for GitHub
issues is that anybody
creates an issue And
then the dev team and
the maintenance or
the allocated sub
-maintainers would go and
review the issues
and decide which ones
they want to work on
and which ones get
pushed to PRs and PRs
get created and such.
I'm not sure that
the team has gotten
that level of
sort of process
yet, but I think
you guys are sort of
manually doing
that review phase.
In a way, I'm only
working on my own
issues. I know Ocean
and Braun are working
on super low-level
stuff that I don't
fully understand, but
I know that when they
get it working, it
works really well.
And then I do know
that I see other issues
being pushed into the
repo. I don't know
if those users have
explicit permissions or
access, so I'm going
to assume they are
submitting issues as
members of the public.
Yeah. So I assume,
based on that evidence,
hopefully this isn't
a hallucination,
but I assume it
also means, Monduit,
if you come up
with an issue that
can be reproduced,
it's possible to have
cloud code generate
the necessary
documentation to
reproduce the problem,
recommend a solution,
and then have a
completely independent
instance of cloud
code pick up the
issue that was left
behind by the first
instance of cloud code
to work on that issue,
resolve the problem,
and prepare it for
another release.
So it's a form of
swarm across entities,
but much slower
only because
meatbags are involved.
I hear you. So the
way a user is going
to use Cloudflow
Swarm is to use the
npx command, right?
So the big commands,
the four or five
step that Reuven
shared on WhatsApp
and on LinkedIn.
That's the way they're
going to get started.
Now, during the
process of work,
you're going
to get issues.
So if I hear you
correctly, what
I can say, ah
i've got the issue
so i'm going to
say okay please
explain why this
issue has occurred
if i'm sophisticated
enough i will create a
second court instance
that you have asked
me to do and try to
create a resolution and
feed it back to the to
the designated i guess
repository if i'm not
that sophisticated
the least i can do is
say okay document this
issue and report it
to that particular
repository as a github
issue correct the most
important step is in
is a set of detailed
instructions to reproduce
the error because if i
can't make it fail on
my machine the same
way it failed for you
i i can't help you hey
ocean welcome that
that's that's normal
that's normal github
process though jean right
i agree a lot of people
a lot of don't know
that here are not
technologists Yeah, I know,
man. We're going to
try to support them.
Yeah, so what I have
my hands up is, do
you guys want to
see how I'm actually
developing the swarm,
like using that kind of
methodology that
you've been describing?
Okay.
Yeah, man. Show
me how you did the
report that I picked
on yesterday, man.
You did an awesome
redo of it.
I love the redo,
by the way.
Oh, thank you.
has questions i'll
still be active
in the chat all
right so let's
take a look at this
um let's say so
right now there
are certain issues so the
most recent one
i submitted was
uh about roof swan
is issue 13131 about
roof swan machine
learning and then trying
to get that integrated
with the root swan
core because currently
the 27 neural models
are not actually
integrated into the rust
and then um so i'm
trying to get that
working and then and
that is what working on
and uh so via yeah
the i'm not using the
uh release version of
root swan right now
so i have to tell the
cloud code to use my
local uh response
test mcp server please
So you created a
branch and then
you pulled your
branch down?
No, this is a session
start command.
This is not part of
the Roof Swarm nor
the Cloudflow, but
it is how you can use
Swarm in another way
because the Roof Swarm
itself is a SDK,
so to speak. It's a
topology with neural
net optimizer. so it is
can be theoretically
used with anything
and here I have a
my own orchestration
system I guess similar
to hive mind but
by goes kind of like
I personalized to
me all right so so
now the session is
started it's a issue
131 is a test-driven
development for SWAN
machine learning
integration testing
and then let's get
it started and see
what should we do about
it assess the
situation please sorry
guys what was this I
missed if just quickly
I'm sorry interrupting
you yeah sure go ahead
so we're you know what
we're doing is You
know, Mondavit was
asking about if he has a
problem with the
system in any way, what
should he do? And Jed was
saying what you normally
do is you would
create an issue, have
Claude create an issue
for you. That issue will
go and get created
against a repo in the
master GitHub repo,
right? One of the repos.
And then, you know,
then it will get
worked on by some
other instance of
Claude, like one
of Ocean or Jed or
somebody else or
Reuven working on it.
And so if you have
a problem, that's
how we're managing
to fix problems.
Ted was saying you've
got to create your
issue so that we understand
it's reproducible.
The cloud system can
reproduce it, which
will give it enough
information to then be able
to work on it. What
Ocean is doing is he's
showing you how he
dealt with an example
issue, 131, right? And
where he's working on
a part of the system,
which is the neural
network system. That's
the part he works on
with the GPU stuff. So
he had an issue that
was already created,
and now he's pointing
his system at this issue
and how he's dealing
with that issue and
what his process is.
Exactly.
I guess I can show
you how to report
an issue once, you
know, after it works
on this and then
find new problems.
Jed took over.
Yeah. Hey, guys.
I'm having some
technical difficulties
with the new setup
today. My apologies.
We got your back,
Ruben, man. We got
your back. Thanks
for taking over.
Yeah. I'm gonna
take off anyway
guys, so I'm
not sure if you
want to shut
this down or...
We will keep it.
Implementation that
should be
separate issues,
please post those
on GitHub directly.
and yet i have
a question i
remember roof
saying that if you
want to help
and just point
your resources to the
repo but many people
don't know how to do
that so i think it would
be very nice to instruct
the the majority
of people because even
myself i i have no
idea where to start
to help so if that's
an option or many
people don't know how to
do it but at least they
can put resources or
cloud computing, then
it will be really nice
to have instructions
how to do it. I was
going to tell you to
have cloud code draft
detailed instructions
on how to do that.
But in the interest of
time, what I suggest
is familiarize yourself
with the repos URL.
It's github.com
slash rovnet
slash cloud dash flow.
So when you're
prompting odd code, you
tell it either through
the GitHub CLI or the
MCP, but not both,
to create an epic as
an issue in repo URL
that references a
solution to problem,
whatever the problem
is. detail it as much
as you can manually.
And then on the other
side, in a separate
instance of clogged
code, so it's not
using the same context,
you say claim issue
link to issue, and
then implement or
apply test-driven
development to resolve
the issue and ensure
that all tests pass.
Keep iterating until
there are no more
failed tests. And
in that way, usually
you get 80% of the
way you needed to
merge the code into
whichever main branch
is ready. At which
point flag, ocean,
brawn, ruvin, myself,
and then we can
so at least I will
review the code using
cloud code to summarize
what was changed
and then to validate
the changes against
what was described
in the issue to
make sure that it makes
sense and that it's
ready to include in
the next release.
The other thing I would
also suggest is to
prompt your uh prompt
the issue puller the
thing that's claiming
the issue to create
a new branch and to
also every time code is
committed to that
branch add a comment to
the issue so that any
other observers can
follow in near real time
what's being done to
resolve the issue does
that help do we need
to be a contributor
in order to to commit
to the branches i
believe so so in that
case you may have to
create a fork and then
a pull request that
references the fork but
in i believe you can
still file the issue
in the main repo okay
um cross check with
cloud code i may have
hallucinated i was just
showing like what jad
was saying that like
once you commit the
issue uh as cloud code
and then you do the
claim command, and
then so it did not
actually claim the issue.
It's supposed to write a
check the actual
patterns in.
So what this command
is supposed to do is
to write a comment
on the GitHub issue,
change a label to say that
this issue has already
been claimed by
somebody else's swarm.
So that when
you point your
swarm at all
of the issues,
they will just skip
that. So that is how
Ruben developed this
GitHub system aiming
for multi-user
collaboration on this.
I think it also
puts your, allocates
your user ID as one
of the associated
to the issue as
well. so we can
see who the owner,
the sub-owner is.
Yes.
So now it has posed
the comment to GitHub.
And this is just
the very standard,
simple way that this
one says it has,
it should label that
a claim. There's
something wrong
with the prompt.
I use a slightly
different setup.
So right now,
the issues has
been claimed, and then...
Oh, yeah, now it's adding
the SwarmClaimed label.
This is how other Swarm
can know that they
should not work on
this issue anymore.
And
then I guess I can tell
it, let's work on this.
Orchestrate and
make a plan.
Whilst this continues,
I think for those
of you who may have
seen this LinkedIn.
So there is basically
these videos. I
think one of our
colleagues has implemented
a mechanism to query
the videos. So I
think all these
discussions that we are
having is queryable
and it kind of can,
it's a natural language
-friendly query system.
That was, I think I
saw the LinkedIn post
today, which was quite
amazing, actually.
Is that a LinkedIn
thing? yeah so yeah yeah
yeah so I will ping
it on the chat here
so it allows you to us
to create any educational
content from all
these videos that we
are recording and query
if you have a specific
question around
whatever that is covered
by these videos you
can get that except
a specific clip of
video as well like so so
let me just bring it
to you slightly well
tangentially relevant
when i'm looking up
the latest information
about a topic i will
instruct clog code
to download youtube
transcript retriever
from github and then use
that tool along with
youtube search to
extract a minimum 50
videos from youtube and
their transmits to
write a detailed summary
about whatever topic
i'm trying to learn
about so in that room
i'm able to identify
across multiple experts
which areas they
agree and are presumed
to be general knowledge
for experts in that
space and then which
areas they disagree
so i can figure out
which rabbit holes to
burrow further through
yeah that's a good
idea the yeah the the
transcript retriever
is pretty good actually
it's just text which
is great so it's on the
chat now so zohar
basically he basically
built in the mcp server
for Kaltura where the
recordings are there
so that link if you
follow the linkedin link
that details it so up
until the point where
ru froze it's he we
got to most of the
parts that are completed
for the install right
that's because he
launched the installation
demonstration took
about eight minutes and
a lot of that was reuben
explaining uh components
of the system the
actual install i
think would take seven
commands seven lines of
commands yeah okay and
it also assumes you
already have node.js
running in your environment
yeah i was going
to mention that it's
it the npx and the npm
require node.js so a
lot and that's reuben
generally just assumes
that that's everybody
knows that what about
the deployment uh
because most of all the
videos most of all the
conversations we have
is a setting up getting
swarms going what
have you guys seen in
time or views for
deployment once what do you
mean by yeah what do
you mean by so once the
so once the animation
app is built then
and completed then you
and then i know it was
mentioned this is
mostly back end then you
add front end and then
you just you know what
go to aws gcp so or
how do you get it
running once what what
not how what do you have
you seen or what do
you recommend to oh it
depends on what building
so for example uh
if you go to let me put
the link in the chat
it also depends on
how you designed and
architected and told
it to design your
product as well so as
an exercise in full site
full software
development life cycle i
prompted broadcode to
develop a pose detection
algorithm that
uses your webcam to
put an overlay over
what it sees to identify
limbs now in the
course of developing
that i very explicitly
told it to conduct
all tests using a docker
container to build
the code into a docker
image and then run
tests against the
built docker image so
in my environment i
had to use something
called docker in docker
so that i was able
to have the tests
running inside the
docker container as
another docker container
It's a little convoluted,
very backwards.
Reuven would
probably disagree
with the solution,
but it is a
solution that I
got working for me.
So during that
time, when I
had the container
running,
the code space would
forward a port to my
local computer, at which
point I could access
it through my web
browser and then confirm
that things work. In
software development, I
believe this is
called user acceptance
testing. And so in that
moment, I'm able to get
the console logs from
the browser, the backend
logs from the Docker
image, and paste
those back into CloudCodes
context to say, hey,
this thing isn't working.
Here are the logs
from that time. Please
fix it. and then
it would **** along as
one or two concurrent
agents. It doesn't
really work if you're
trying to do it with six
concurrent agents. They
end up stepping over
each other, but it
takes maybe three to
five more iterations of
that to get something
legitimately working.
Now, I also want to
emphasize, while I do
know how to write
code, I know absolutely
nothing about how to write
TypeScript or generate
WASMs or whatever was
used to create the
application at that
link. I wrote the entire
thing using English
and copy-pasted logs.
So hopefully, Matt,
that gives you some
insight in how you
can complete the
development lifecycle
through to deployment.
Yeah, it does.
Thanks. And in
my case, I happen
to host most
of my services
on Kubernetes.
And so I use that to,
I use CloudCode to
generate other manifests,
which are basically
deployment configurations,
to take the
generated Docker image
and deploy it to my
Kubernetes cluster on a
high availability basis.
So while I happen
to know how
to write Kubernetes
manifests,
I didn't need to use
that knowledge to write
the manifests to
deploy to the cluster.
And while I don't yet
trust Claude Code to
manage my Kubernetes
instance independent
of me, because a lot
of secrets are still
stored within the
cluster, I am at least
confident in having
it build the necessary
manifests to deploy
any new application or
create in a well
-opinionated, resource
-constrained way that
doesn't kill the cluster.
The thing here,
though, Gene, is
that you know your
dev environment,
your production environment,
your environment
that you have available
to you for deployment
for dev, right? So,
like Matt, you need
to have an idea of where
you might be wanting
to deploy if you want
to deploy it in amazon
or gcp right you need
to tell it that in
the in that that
ultimately your what you're
designing is going to
be should be either a
kubernetes container
like microservice or a
docker and it's going
to be deployed in aws
you know or whatever
right or on a local linux
system somewhere or
whatever you need to
tell it you know it's
not going to it could
tell you but you really
want to use english
conversational language
to tell it what what
you're thinking okay and
i should also emphasize
i only am fluent in
english i haven't
tried this in another
language so for those of
you who are polylingual
uh try it i'm curious
to know how well it
would work good that's
a good question so
just do a really good
job of generating all
the keys the thing i
always run into when i
deploy an application
is there's always a key
somewhere that i didn't
get set up correctly
the first time right
do you find that it does
a good job of handling
that stuff what do
you mean by key like
a key value like a
security key like an api
key or so secrets
whatever there's some form
of digital key so in
terms of secrets i still
manage that manually
i have found a good
way to let cloud code
manipulate secrets into
the environment without
inadvertently sending
that secret up to
wherever the llm is
running that's what it
makes sense so you could
potentially get it to
generate a script that
would generate in my
case very keys but you
would still have to
manually then then uh
so what i do is i i
prompted to explicit draft
explicit instructions
on how to deploy a
secret into wherever
the deployment is and
then i separately in a
completely separate uh
web browser or something
generate the secret
using whatever tools
i have available to me
okay you you you have a
pretty good methodology
for managing secrets
right because you've
been burnt that's
your day job right as
part of your day job
is to is you use them a
lot whereas i find that
it you know as Claude
flow swarm as it's
building out your app
it's mocking up a bunch
of stuff it's mocking
up a bunch of you know
api calls and secrets
and api keys so it
will kind of forget um
you know and make
assumptions and then and it
and it just won't come
back around to it or
and you will get caught
out because it it
just won't remember or
you won't remember because
it's doing a lot of
work and it'll the
solution to that is
exactly what i'm showing
right now to break every
single task to issue
byte and then just
work on through those
issues which you can
actually observe in real
time and you can just
comment on the github
issue and say you know
whatever you're trying
is wrong try again
please yeah you're right
yeah that makes sense
right that that part
of it um that i'm
actually really excited
about the issues integration
stuff for reasons
like that it's it's
always that there's um
you know that either
it's really easy when
you're beginning to
make the assumption that
the ai is going to
figure out all of the
things that need to be
done if you ask it to
figure out all the
things that need to be
done and it really
it isn't quite ever
going to do that so
having an issue tracker
to say um hey if you
know if there's a gap
that that you identify
during testing or
something else or if i
identify something and
i can use issues to
establish that and do
exactly what you're
demonstrating now which
i haven't tried yet
so i don't fully
understand it but that
to me i think is um kind
of the right state
of the art for today
the cool thing about
it though is that sorry
sorry james no i was
always gonna say is
you're always gonna
have something right
now as things stand
today you're always
gonna have something
in a sophisticated
deployment that you're
going to have to get
involved in in some way,
shape, or form unless
you want to share
everything in the world.
And even then, if
you want to really
trust that everything
has been done in a way
that you can trust
the application moving
forward, you're going
to have to get involved.
So the issues thing
is good for that.
And part of my reason
for the question
is I'm kind of
in between two
worlds, of the world
and trying to figure
out the stack,
if you will, like
you know, for secrets,
HashiCorp, Vault,
Doppler,
do you use like
I use sealed secrets
and then I set up the
private key so that
it would take, I tune
the private key so it
takes a $100 million
amount of Amazon
compute to brute force
it. So the way I
see it, my systems
are only vulnerable
to state actors.
hypothetically or I
guess you know Tesla so
I just want to add a
little bit of methodology
of what I'm actually
doing here so to
initial initially I
pointed to a few issues on
github and then saying
that is what we're
going to work on today
and then I kind of
guide it to make a
very comprehensive plan
which I know is what I
want to work on and then
what I ask you to do
is I'm going to go
have lunch, please work
all of them out, and
then typically I just
go to something else.
Then a few hours
later, it will be
able to resolve
everything to a degree
that I am ready
to pick at again.
Then I will probably
start to sequentially
validate everything it
has really done to make
sure the test run,
there is no mock, etc.
Then I push the changes.
It is not getting
human out of the
loop. It is more
to automate the
part that requires
traditionally
technical expertise
to even write.
But what I'm doing
is managing the
whole software
development flow.
The role has actually
changed quite a lot.
Yeah,
so that's good
stuff, Ocean.
And to sort of close
all this, not as much
close it out, but
Mondavit, come back to
Mondavit's question. If
you have a problem, you
document it as an issue
and then do all the
reproducible parts of
it in that as well.
But you have the
power to also have it
work on and solve
your own issue is what
I'm saying. Once it
gets created as an issue
in the GitHub, it
doesn't mean that
somebody like Ocean
or Jed or myself or
whoever is going to
pick it up and work on
it. It doesn't mean
that that's going to
get fixed. It will
sit there as a known
issue, and someone
can look at it, but it
doesn't mean that it's
going to get fixed.
You have the power
with Claude Flow and
Roof Swarm to actually
have it go and
read the issues and
actually work on your
own issues. That's
what Ocean is doing,
right? He's saying,
here's my issues,
and I want you to
go and come up with
a plan to solve this
particular issue.
I think that's what I
wanted to clarify to
you is that if you've
got a problem, you can
have it documented as
an issue. It doesn't
mean that once it goes
into an issue that
someone will pick that
up and fix it for you.
You might actually
have to tell it to go
and pick up your issue
and fix it yourself.
I think David mentioned
a really good point
because what this
is doing is just to
add an orchestration
structure into this to
make sure that every
task is very well
divided. And this
goes back to the roof
swamp in terms of
context engineering. And
then so we only want
to provide what they
exactly need. And then
that's why I'm using
GitHub issue for all
of those contexts.
Otherwise, when
contexts get
bloated after a few
auto-compacting,
it will forget way worse.
And that is why I am
doing the main cloud
code as an orchestrator
pattern only.
All the work are supposed
to be done by the
task agent, such that
the main cloud code
can reserve its
precious context and
then won't really get
crushed. It will have
the capability to
double check, verify
the task agent's
work, rather than to
blindly just take their
words at face value.
This is another
type of interesting
pattern that the
Roof Swarm enabled
because previously
when you do this
kind of five-task
agent together,
you can directly
via Cloud Code, yes,
but this five-task agent,
they might conflict
each other's work
quite a lot unless
you get a very good
coordination going on.
Sometimes two agents
might add the same
file and then while
another agent is doing
testing and then they
say oh all of work
are done but then
when you get all the
work together it is
not done maybe each
individual task task
agent did their stuff
so that is why you
need some kind of
coordination system
therefore they do not
conflict and then and
then this five six
task agent are doing
one thing so that the
orchestrators is
very clear and they
just keep on going
okay one question here,
or one idea. Is it
possible to assign a
specific model from
Claude to orchestration?
For example, if you try
to use your resources
as Oppos for orchestration
and then Sonnet
for the rest of the
stuff, is it possible?
No.
Currently,
you choose one. Yeah,
you choose the pro
and the max 5 and the
max 10 or max 20
right uh max 10 5 pro
max 10 max 20 that's
all you can configure
as your back-end
model uh back-end
subscription and it's
other opus or sonnet and
there's controls with
opus or sonnet that
it will back off
after certain api
connections and messages
correct but i think
if i read correctly
somewhere in um tropic
you can try to force
it Yes, you can.
You can, yes.
That's why my idea
that you can actually
somehow define that
your orchestrator
will be your best model,
so it will be less
used to be fair, less
used, and then the
workers will be
sonet. Is it possible?
So that is what I'm
doing right here.
I don't know how to
do it automatically,
but I'm just
having Opus to
do the planning and
then have Sonnet
to do very early
orchestration.
When you invoke
Cloudflow as a
what's it called?
A command line call
instead of as a batch
tool, you can explicitly
say which model to
use. Opus 4, Sonnet 4,
Auto, and I think up
down to Sonnet 3.7.
So it is possible
to set different,
for lack of better
term, models
within a specific running
instance of Cloudflow.
yeah but the the
system doesn't do that
uh the old system that
reuben had and and
like the ruvy system
it could do this but
i'm not sure it
does that right it
doesn't switch between
between models based
on orchestration or
or planning or that
still requires human
curation yes yes yes
but then jet uh if
i'm not wrong the
example that you
mentioned that you run a
couple of different
terminals and in each
terminal you have like
a specific type of
orchestrator worker
and if you can use
Claude for the
orchestrator the opus
one and then you just
open the sonet for
the other ones that
will work or not?
Maybe I haven't tried
it personally but
that it sounds plausible
well there's a command
line switch within
claw to tell it which
model you want it to
use there's also a
switch there's also a
slash command switch
right yeah so since
you're running in
multiple terminals yeah
yeah so exactly that
slash model opus or
sonnet and then you
switch yeah you go
slash model yeah that's
that's that's simple
yeah all right so i just
asked opus to evaluate
the work of the
previous one and then
i'm just going to go
back to sort it to
continue please continue
um so what i want to
get out of it is to uh
have a more have a
smarter model to confirm
or to deduplicate
double check etc to
continue this autonomous
flow before i have to
personally examine what
they have done this
just add one tiny
iteration loop in the
middle to let itself
debug before I have to.
While we're watching
this, I just wanted
to cover one other
GitHub scenario that
you guys, some of you
might know about. And
there's another GitHub
scenario that deals
with issues on a
very automated way
called the workflow
and the runners system.
And GitHub, that's a
service that GitHub
will make available
to you. It's not free.
It uses certain minutes
that you have, three
minutes you have
associated with your
account. You have to
set it up. And what you
do is – and sometimes
it needs an API key
based on what it's
doing. It will go through
and review automatically
issues, and you
can put certain keywords
into an issue like
at Claude. If you put
at Claude in there,
it will trigger an
automated run through
an issue and actually
start work for you on
a Codespace machine
and actually start
working and do everything
that we're seeing
here. It will get
automated. But that system
only works with the
integrated Anthropic
Claude GitHub CLI
command system, not the
MCP GitHub. So it only
works with that, and
it will potentially
cost you money because
workflows and runners
are the sub-processes
that run around. You
can configure, we
could configure a Reuben
Swarm to be a runner
in the background, and
it could automatically
do what Ocean is
doing. But I don't
believe Swarm and
Flow are configured to
use the workflow and
the runner system yet.
Not yet, but I think
you are able to figure
out somehow because
there is official
SDK for the cloud
code that you are able
to just make into a
script. And then any
script can be part
of the GitHub action.
So what I'm showing
right now is
previously we did a
Swamp claim, right?
And then so
Ruben set up this
GitHub action
that will say,
oh, this task has
been claimed for 24
hours without any
updates. If you're
still working on
this, post an update.
Otherwise, we're going
to get rid of that
claimed label and
then allow others
to work on as well.
So a lot of things
you can to accompany
this one pattern.
Yeah, that's a cool
action, right? Or you
could say, you know,
if a certain keyword
is entered, like auto
-fixed by Swarm, it
will actually say,
oh, got it. I will go
and create a Swarm to
solve this problem.
And that will spin
up a Swarm and it
runs in GitHub on the
GitHub Codespaces.
So that's where it
costs you money. And
it will do all the
work you're seeing
here and actually
try to automatically
solve and write code
to solve your problem
based on its own
review of the issue.
So that would be a
way to automatically
solve problems, but
it's expensive and it
costs money and we're
not doing that yet.
Yeah, I think once,
if we're able to
find a way to get
Cloud Code $200 Max
plan to automatically
do that, the
only cost would just
be Codespace. Yes,
yes, and that would
be a cool system.
Of course, the cost
would go against
somebody's Claude
Pro Max account.
It wouldn't be free
because it would spin
up an instance of
swarm or flow in the
GitHub code space to
actually start working
on that issue. And
imagine if there's, you
know, everybody's
creating hundreds of
issues per day. Now
we've got hundreds of
cloud flow and swarms
get created inside of
GitHub to deal with
them. It's awesome
because a lot of stuff
will get fixed, but
somebody's going to
get charged for that.
Yes. So another way
that I do massive issue
-based development
is I would kind of
create way too many
issues that I can possibly
handle or any swarm
can possibly handle.
And then I'll go in and
then start to rearrange
all of this issue
into a nice sequential
plan. And then I'll
start just working on
one by one in the exact
order I showed. So
some of my crazier
attempts is not just on
so I want to mention
this the swarm pattern
is not just for development
and then the github
integration is not
just for software
development so for
example here is a academic
research project that
I did on a proving the
point of a rust based
rust based framework
that was doing for
capability um and then of
course like something
we know about this
vibe coding stuff is
you don't know what's
going on in terms of
like okay it works but
what is what does it
really make scientific
sense or mathematically
proven so um one thing
i did was i have the
swarm to go take a
look at all the rust
code and then start to
doing formal uh formal
verification and then
derivation of each single
component to verify
the claim i think this
is how the agentic
is becoming a science
in that regard very
cool um yeah so so
all of this stuff have
incredible amount of deep
research behind uh it
is coming up with its
own academic proposal
evaluate the novelness
of those and then it
is actually planning
to release those on
my journal. I'm just
like, I got to read it.
This is amazing, Ocean,
because it kind of
sort of a question I
had, which was, you
know, from a business
point of view, how
do you explain to
someone the benefit of
this? You know, for
a fee listing that is
just starting, for
example, they could go to
Cloud Code and spin
off number of agents
and, you know, know,
sub-agents and ask
them to address
different tasks and they
will get something up
and running at some
point, right? So how
do you prove exactly as
you've explained right
now, you know, the
impact in terms of
performance, in terms
of saving time, in
terms of orchestration
and so on, I think
it's going to become a
very important topic
going forward, yeah.
So this is a very,
I would say, this
is a difficult topic
to really have,
if you would try,
because it's very
technical, right,
Vincent, what we
see here is super
technical, right?
And when most people
that ask those questions
are business leaders,
right? Because they're
writing the check
to fund some project
or part of a business.
And it's quite, quite
difficult because, and
I had this, we asked
this question, I think
Chris Royce asked
this question a couple
of sessions ago about,
you know, what's the
point of, what is the
value of swarms? And is
it to do lots of work
faster or does it
increase the intelligence
of a system to actually
do better, higher
quality work, right?
And maybe there's other
value props as well,
but they are the two
major ones that come
up. And initially, Ruben
said, you know, it's
really, at the moment,
it does lots of work.
It's quantity, right?
It's a huge amount of
horsepower that gets
spun up parallel
batches and parallelism.
But it's evolving now
to actually increase
the intelligence of
the work that gets done
and so and so that's
part of the conversation
you would have with
a business leader
to say here's why here's
why you would do this
here's here's why it's
so a paradigm shift
and to use a system
like like swarm and
flow um because well i
think i think this is
but this is just just
want to add one one
more point which is in
safeguard of integrity
you know like you
maintain the integrity
of your project your
code base because you
can prove like you
said ocean and this was
recorded fantastic
you say then you don't
have to take things at
face value right yes
it's you know this
that and i think that's
the key here yeah so
a lot of this stuff is
really good when it
comes to things that
are like ai verifiable
and results like back
-end stuff it's like i
want this outcome and
the ai can reach that
outcome and say yes
i've achieved this
thing but that's why
reuben's like let's not
do front and stuff okay
it's it's too much
subjectivity right it's
up to the user to like
say you know i like
this or i don't like
this and the ai is
never going to determine
that and like one
thing you'll really
run into a problem with
or i did is using it
for say like databases
like i was building
a web app about a
database integration
into the web app and you
know a lot of things
where it's like you could
make one table and
then like have like
say 15 columns instead
it's over here making
15 tables with one
column right and it's
just making things
really really complicated
and uh like things
like that that kind of
has like takes a
little bit of human
subjectivity to go into
it it doesn't do so well
at but if you give
it like an end result
that it's like say get
to this point or hit
these benchmarks it'll
get there and then
yeah you might not
you might even want to
refactor a little
bit and make things a
little more efficient
and stuff but it's
really good at back end
stuff and then making
it test things that
it can verify like
you got to know what
you made so that you
can say as long as you
hit these points and
like in the database
or the tables it says
this this and this and
this at these points
right and you can get
those outcomes then
it's really good at
that but yeah you
kind of got to know
what you're making and
breaking it down to like
ai verifiable points
where if as long as
it's hit these points
you know the system
works type of deal.
Yep.
So one little
background on the Lion
thing. So I built the
Rust-based framework
in February over
a couple weeks.
But with the Swarm,
I was able to do
formal verification
in the morning.
All of that mathematical
stuff or the
machine proofable
theorem stuff, they're
all done in the
morning with Swarm.
Wow.
Yeah, it's great. that
stuff absolutely and
then the point is that
is once it does all
those formal verification
i can start going
back and pick all the
architecture flaws that
i initially designed
it as because some of
them might just be not
that great it works
but it's not great
what is no state of the
art or anything like
those but through this
kind of processes you
can intuitively refine
and then get to
where you want to get
properly yeah so that
actually Chris Royce invented
a really cool system
called the devil's
advocate that will
actually go and review
your the plans that
it creates and then
basically pick holes in
it and say well here's
where you're wrong and
that's a really good
system I'm not sure
Claude low or swarm has
that but it's a it's
a you could manually
prompt it to do that I
guess that's another good
way to do it yeah Yeah,
I've been building
this like cognitive
triangulation system.
So like how fair
am I, what I'm
playing with
now works is it
starts with goal
clarification.
And then you clarify
what works. And then
you also clarify what
tests work and what
benchmarks work. And
like you tell it to go
do something. It goes
and does the research.
It comes up with a
plan. And then it's
very important that
the system goes through
a lot of specification,
a lot of questions
to make sure it's 100
% clear what you're
doing. and then it goes
and makes user stories
and specs and then
it says then it goes
to a devil's advocate
and this devil devil's
advocate says okay
how do the specs and
the user stories match
up with the user's
initial intent okay
anything that's off we fix
now we go on the
next phase pseudocode
okay how does the
pseudocode align with
everything in the user's
intent okay good move
on now we go to
architecture okay now the
devil's advocate how
does the architecture
align with the
pseudocode, the specs, the
user stories with the
user's initial intent.
Okay, now let's
make the test. Let's
pass the test for
all the features.
Okay, now that we have
everything created,
let's create a model.
The model is basically
the architecture of
what did get created.
Like the architecture
is before you code
anything, but now the
model is after you've
code anything, this
is the architecture of
what does exist now.
Now, how does the model
align with the architecture,
the pseudocode,
the specs, the user
stories and the user's
initial intent? Good.
All right. End to
end test. Now, how
do these align with
everything? And so
everything kind of plays back
and triangulates
itself on the user's
initial intent is the
main point of interest.
Everything else is a
viewpoint on how the
system works towards
that. And that's how I'm
trying to get the system
to as closely align
as possible with
the user's initial
intention is what I've
been playing with lately.
I think that feedback
loop is amazing.
That's a really cool
concept. And I think
something that Cloudflow
should ultimately kind
of get there as well
as to have well-tested,
well-known feedback
loops built in to the
way that the agents
basically are held
accountable for the
output that they generate.
The output is really
good. Like the reason
I was doing this is
because I was playing
with swarms of like one
to 200 plus deep seek
agents running in
parallel. And by using
like this triangulation
technique, like the
outputs I was getting
were, were very on
point. It was quite
incredible. no it's really
i mean that's really
cool i love that i
shout out to chris man
he is the king of swarms
he invented his
pheromone swarm system
before you know rUv did
a first cut at it chris
went went crazy and
built an entire system
um and so he really
has put a lot of deep
thought into it that
the process flow that
chris just described is
in is in his pheromone
system it's not in
Claude Flow or Swarm
fully at that level of
detail, but, you know,
there might be a
merging of minds between
Chris and Reuven at
some point. And I also
wanted to say that,
you know, what Vincent
was talking about, what
Chris just described,
how would you,
you know, all that
verification, testing,
and cross-referencing,
imagine trying to do that
in a software development
company with all
the different teams,
that would take you
like weeks and weeks to
get all that sign-off
with Chris's methodology
and his system. He
does that in like
seven minutes. So how
much money are you saving,
time, effort, resources,
just to do that,
automated with a
system like this? You
have thousands or millions
of dollars. There's
a business justification
right there in
why you would want to
do a system like this.
So right now what
I'm showing is swarm
observability. So we
have been seeing they've
been using MCP a lot,
memory storage, and
then communication
and such, but there's
no way that we actually
know what's going
on unless you go see
this SQLite database.
So right now I'm asking
it to save. Go find
out which DB that
we used, and please
tell me, did the data
actually got saved are
they being persisted
and what are in
there so let's see if
there anything actually
in the sqlite and you
know of course once
you get things into
the sqlite you can
use it however you can
so right now it found
uh 41 agents in the
database 23 tasks
uh okay it's gonna
show me some of those i
i would in my opinion
i think uh this is
very great feature
and then all of this
data can be much better
utilized in terms
of the uh how do
we do the neural
network training for the
ontology optimization
but of course
there's so much to
experiment and explore
i i got the rust NCP
just functional as
of kind of yesterday.
So the Rust NCP is a
lot more stable and
then much quicker than
the current released
version. I'm hoping
to finish this in
a couple of days so
that the cloud flow
can be even faster
and then more stable.
yeah just so people
don't get confused
uh ocean you're
you're working on the
neural network component
with inside of of
Claude swarm right so
they um just you're
giving an example
of the work that
you're doing just so
you recognize that
so remember the roof
mentioned about his
neurodivergent that
has like supposedly
27 machine learning
models that
will optimize the
ontology the topology
of the SWAN
framework as you go.
Then that is what I'm
actually implementing
right now to get
those functional
and then with GPU
training support.
Yeah.
It seems to be fun.
It has all the data
persisted and then they
can be later on reused
and then validated, which
is the observability
part because then you
can go see whether
the optimization is
good or is it any use
of any use but even
without the neural training
this swarm pattern
itself is already
include increasing the
um quality by a lot which
is something i'm
most shocked at that
topology by itself is
already very very capable
all right um i think
that's uh it's a good
cycle of how i how i
resolve issue to use swamp
to develop swamp so
uh thanks everybody
yeah great great stuff
ocean thank you it looks
like we're we're at
the oh it's 11 o'clock
here in san francisco
did you want to uh
you want to close it
down or we're good keep
going well if you're if
you're willing to host
david happy to let it
keep going i do need
to hop off me too man
i got a meeting as a
reminder for everyone
else we do have the new
york city agentics
meeting this afternoon
this evening um i
believe the link is at
agentics.org so for those
of you who can attend
all the details are
there looking forward
to meeting a lot of you
in person tonight right
me too i gotta join
that as well thanks
everyone i will not be
there but uh but i'll
we're planning the one
in san francisco silicon
valley and then very
soon thank you guys