All right. Here we
are. Top of the hour.
The end of June,
six months into the
year. I don't know
how we managed to get
through half the
year so quickly. This
week, I always say
this almost every week.
This week was crazy,
but this week was
incredibly crazy.
We had a variety of
events. We had the
Toronto meetup where we
had 100 people and I
think, what was that?
450 people registered
for it. We had
Paris on Monday, which
went really well.
There's so much
happening. I I don't
even know where to
start, but I'm going
to start with Rob.
How's it going, Rob?
Good, good, good. Yeah,
it was a really busy
week, and lots of
folks are excited about
holding events all
over the place. Berlin,
Stockholm, next one's
up, and Indianapolis,
boy,
Belgium.
They're all
over the place.
So it's wonderful.
And, yeah, I'm
looking forward to
seeing this trading
platform today.
That's going to
be interesting.
The ability to build
out complex systems more
and more becomes
available to more people
more quickly. So that's
what it's all about.
We have a great lineup
today this week,
too, Roof and folks.
We've got Chris Poulter,
part of the UK group.
And Chris, he's a
serial entrepreneur, and
he's working on the
platforms to orchestrate
and optimize the
eugenic coding flow.
So right on target.
And then Everett
Clavin is back.
He's, again, he's the
founder of Evangelist
Technologies.
I think he qualifies
as a rocket
scientist. He's got his
master's in aeronautical
engineering or
aerospace engineering.
And again, working
on multi-agent
orchestration,
right, which is what
it's all about. And
then we're happy to
welcome the celebrated
Alistair Kroll.
So Alistair,
he's from product
management and telecom.
He built and sold
Coradiant to BMC,
and he launched
Year One Labs.
That's an incubator.
Chaired O'Reilly's
Strata and UBM's Cloud
Connect. He founded the
FWD50, and he's taught
at Stanford, at
Harvard. he's co-written
three books including
lean analytics which
is pretty much required
reading for startups
these days yes it's a
happy to have alistair
it's the bible and
his latest book which
is a really good one
is just evil enough
which i just kind of
love that name because
it sort of summarizes
kind of everyone's
methodology these days
so let's let's not let's
let's get to it there's
a lot to cover uh
again thanks and
thanks rob and brad and
the whole team in toronto
for putting together
an amazing event on
Tuesday, and the Tribal
Scale team for
sponsoring it, as well as
Vincent and the crew
in Paris. I wish I was
there with you guys,
but I could see the
Eiffel Tower in the
background. Very jealous,
but I don't have time
to travel these days.
I'm way too busy for
that sort of thing.
All right, so let's
get into it. I think a
lot of people today are
really excited about
this idea of an MCP or
Claude Code generated
and managed trading
system, But before
I go there, I've got
to give you a kind of
step-by-step to where
and how I got to where
we are today since
Monday, which is, this
is a lot to cover. So
I'm going to, I'm going
to go, I'm going to
go fast. You might
have to watch this and
in slow motion later.
But so I start
with the week,
I've been on a rust kick.
The rust has been
particularly good. And so
I started this week
was creating a platform
that essentially
allows me to create a
kind of quantum proof
series of tools that
allow me to manage
agents in a kind of
decentralized fashion.
So I created an SDK and
it's super fast, super
secure. It allows for
in the most simple
terms, it's a dark net
for agents. I know
it sounds scary. It
probably is. Basically,
it's hyper, hyper fast
and hyper secure
communication channel. It
handles things like the
use of passwords and
secrets and communications.
It has a built
-in economy system. So
as agents collaborate,
they can generate
value and share those
in the form of resource
utility vouchers.
Yes, REVs. They're
called roofs, whatever.
And then I've
included anonymous
onion routing components,
quantum-resistant
dark domain system. so
you can use it to create
sort of whatever.dark
.com and I like dark
because it doesn't
exist as a domain so
you can create your own
secondary darknet you
can change the dark
with whatever you
really want it to be and
you can plug that in
also to DNS services
like Cloudflare and
others if you want it to
sort of sit between
the dark world and the
real world it's all
managed through an MCP
everything I'm
about to show you is
kind of a cascading
sort of um you know
series of components
that uh connect
to each other
through imcp so this
facilitates the next
and the next thing was
sort of interacts with
the previous thing
so they're all kind
of building on each
other like one of those
russian dolls where
you're kind of peeling
each layer off and then
the next layer and
inside this and that
so it's really
interesting so you can see
i've got pop your
passwords i'm not going to
go in the demo this
because we just don't
have time to show you
everything i've built
so you can see here
i've got my resource
uh and so on but this
led to another component.
So then I needed a
practical application
of the SDK. So I
created a, what I called
a decentralized
autonomous agent structure
to essentially build
businesses on top of
the previous platform
that could operate
autonomously using
agents as a kind of core
worker in the
infrastructure that provides
things like an AI
power decision-making,
economic self-sustainability.
So these systems
can not only build and
interact and adapt,
but they can make their
own value, whether
that's real money or
crypto or their own
invented currencies,
whatever. They have
autonomous governance.
There's also the ability
for it to be sort of
self-determining. I
can put in guidelines.
It's quantum safe.
Again, it's kind of
the implementation of
the previous also has
an MCP on top of it.
So if you want to create
your own autonomous
agents that live in
sort of the world of
the kind of, I don't
know what you want to
call it, kind of latent
space darknet, if
you will, you can do
that. It has the ability
to be, again, completely
autonomous loops.
It even has the ability
to share computational
resources. So
these systems can
actually create their
own network that then
shares the capacity of
GPUs and CPUs, networks
with each other or
other people all on the
fly, which, again,
is just mind-blowing.
So between these
two projects, we're
looking at about 100
hours of continuous
swarm development
across 30 swarm
agents. So we're
sitting around 3
,500 hours of
continuous development.
and roughly two to
three million lines of
code, two or three
million lines of code. And
this is just since
fricking Monday. Anyway,
you can look at that
DAA. So that led to
the next thing. I'm
like, okay, so, so this
is all built in rust.
So then I came up, well,
we know that this
is interesting. Why
don't, and this is
something we did yesterday.
Well, I'm looking
at sort of porting
some of these Python
tools that are optimized
for creating neural
networks. And
one of the more popular
ones is something
called FAST. So the
FAST is the FAST
Artificial Neural
Network, which is built
in C. It's one of
the most popular C
-based neural networks.
It's complicated,
doesn't have really
good memory management,
it's verbose and slow.
So on yesterday's
live coding session,
I'm like, why don't we
see if we can implement
this in 90 minutes
in Rust, which we
managed to do fully
functional. Again, a
couple hundred thousand
lines of code. And then
it created something
called neurodivergent,
which I love. I
kind of love that name
because I think I might
be neurodivergent.
But anyway, what this
does is allows you
to create hyper fast
and hyper targeted
neural networks that you
can embed in just about
anything. And they're
super small, super
fast. You can see I've
got different types
of models I can
implement and neural
forecasting capabilities.
And here's the stats
that are crazy. If
you look at traditional
Python implementation
of neural forecast,
we're looking at
a 200 to 400%
improvement in terms of
speed. And this is just
me quickly doing it
on some ****** GPUs
that I got up. What
was it? Fly.io. My
inference speed increased
500%. On the crappiest
GPUs, memory went
down 75%, which is
just crazy. But look
at this. The binary
size dropped from
500 megabytes down to
five. So I can embed
this in browsers. I
can put this on IoT.
I can embed this in
just random objects.
Cold start times went
from 10 seconds to
50 milliseconds. Just
mind boggling. And I
built this in freaking
90 minutes. So all
these tools are leading
towards the thing
you're probably most
excited by is this
idea of a, where did
I put it? Here it is.
A training system.
So I'm like, oh, I've
got these tools. This
is built in Python,
by the way, because I
built it quick. But this
is essentially playing
on top of what I built
previously in the
cloud flow system. So
I'm using swarms as a
combination of all the
neural components you
saw before built in
those various components.
And then I implemented
it. I get basically
an interface in Python.
I might do a Rust if
I get time. But basically
what this does is
creates an MCP power
trading system, which I
ran most of the week.
I had a previous one.
and the results are at
some of the stats you
can see here i'm using
momentum trading i'm
using mean revision
swing trading and mirror
trading mirror
trading is interesting
basically i just pointed
it at the u.s senators
and congress people
and said buy whatever
they're buying but the
crazy part of this is
the time it takes me to
do it i was looking at
a kind of temp, I'm
going to make this up,
temporal intelligence.
So when you look at
traditional investment
platforms, a lot of
it's based on latency.
How fast can I trade
based on predetermined
sort of procedural
components? Like I'm
doing these certain types
of investments and I
just need to do it faster
than the next guy. But
what it's not doing
is adapting to whatever
it needs to do based
on the information
that's coming to it. So
it could be like a random
tweet from a leader
of a country or a
senator or some other
information. And I need
to make the determination
and understand the
ramifications of that
as fast as I possibly
can, rather than just
basing on the speed
of light and latency.
So I ran this on,
again, the cheapest GPU
cluster I could
possibly find and ran it
for several days.
And the results were
astronomical. I saw a
6500x, 65x, not percent,
but x speed up in
terms of capability.
Actually, I've increased
this to 21 tools
now, but the stats
that you're doing is
mind blowing. So when you
look at my traditional
environment, I, you
know, I'm seeing
now a 1.8 millisecond
response time for
complex types of decisions.
So those are like,
you know, taking
in A, B, and C and
deciding whether that's
a good sort of decision
to be made, you know,
rather than taking
sometimes, you know,
two minutes, I can
do the same result
in 1.8 milliseconds.
We're almost at the point
of doing nanoseconds
in terms of that.
And this is on a A100
with 80 gigs of RAM,
this cheap hardware.
I can't even imagine what
an H100 would look like.
Batch processing is
interesting too. So
batch processing is
the concept of taking
multiple assets,
stocks, bonds, whatever,
and then making sort
of a graph structure
to determine how that
all interconnects
to each other. I
can look at 128
different assets and
I can get a response
time in 24
milliseconds, seconds,
which is again, just
bonkers in terms of
capability, of
capability. In terms of
high frequency trading,
I'm seeing similar
things. I can, in
traditional research,
which would take five
minutes, I can do
in 47 milliseconds,
which is, which is
crazy. So I'm, I'm
not going to spend too
much more time on
this. I'm going to
jump in and actually
show you what this
actually looks like,
which is probably the
more exciting part
of this whole thing.
All right.
So I haven't published
this guys, cause
I'm, I don't, I'm
worried about getting
in trouble with
regulators and maybe
someone smarter than
me can tell me if I'm
even worried, should
be worried about
that. But let's just
go back here. So
there's a couple of
components that exist.
So it's an MCP. So for
the most simple part
of the MCP, we can
go here and we'll go
and look at Roo because
it's got a nice sort
of interface. So we
can see here that here
are all my endpoints,
but this isn't actually
how I'm using it. I've
actually integrated
with my Cloudflow
Swarm, but just to
visualize it, you can
see here, I've got ping,
this basically tells
me if it's working.
I've got the ability
to list different
strategies, get strategies,
do a quick analysis.
You can see the symbol
that I'm looking
at, whether or not
I want to use a GPU.
Sometimes I don't use
GPUs because I'm cheap.
Simulated trades.
So I can do a whole
simulated series
of trades. I can do
a billion simulated
trades in roughly
a hundred, I think
it was a hundred.
I don't know the
exact number.
I'm not going to
say how long it
was, but it
wasn't very long.
Get portfolio
status. Like how's my
portfolio actually
doing? I can do
real-time news
analysis. I can plug in
Bloomberg. I can
plug in available.
I can use fire crawl,
whatever I need to
get. I can get sentiment
analysis in real
time. Is this good? Is
this bad? So all the
different parts of the
swarm are looking at
all these different
parts of the equation.
So if I have a 50
agent swarm, one agent
might be geared towards
backtesting. The other
agent might be looking
at the optimization
strategy. Another might
be looking at risk
analysis. And this
is all happening
concurrently with them
all kind of collaborating
to figure out what and
how it should work.
Then I can, using
Cloud Code, I can plug
this directly into
any existing trading,
whether it's stock
trading, bond trading,
crypto, it doesn't
matter. And it'll actually
facilitate that. So
all you need to do
is point Cloud Code at
it and say, implement
this against ABC
API for trading and
it's done. It'll just
build it on the fly.
Here's the performance
report, similar
to what I was
showing a minute ago.
Correlation
analysis. Here's my
benchmarking. I built
a completely separate
benchmarking tool
just to prove
that I wasn't
hallucinating this whole
thing and this was
actually working.
Then I've got a neural
forecasting system.
So back to the other
system, I said, I
can create custom
neural networks that
are built explicitly
for a certain kind
of trade. And then they
learn and adapt and
get better as you
use it more. Then you
can train those on
the information. So
as it's trading, the
system gets better.
It's self-optimizing
and deterministic.
Then it can do a
self-evaluation,
neural backtesting
as well.
It's crazy. And I built
all this stuff this
week. So taking it
further, because I don't
have a lot of time,
and this demo would
literally be several
hours if I showed you
everything. but the the
first part i built here
was something called
claude flow neural now
we'll do help on that
so the clock flow
neural essentially is
allowing you to essentially
execute similar to the
original cloud flow
but based but
specifically optimized for
trading these stocks
so we can go to claude
let's go to claude md
and see if we can see
some details so this
is the core guidance
system all right let's
go here so we can see
that i've defined sort
of the the mcp which
i'll show you in a
moment and these are the
different guidance
tools we have different
you know availabilities
lots and lots of stuff
so this is basically
guiding it in this
and then we have p tool
directory here that
tells it how to how
to operate and here at
the neural trader
components as well so we so
a lot of stuff right
you can see that you
know the parameters
and strategy. There's a
lot of, there's a lot
of code underpinning
this. So let's go back
here and I'm going to
just, I'm just going
to straight up run it.
Uh, right. So we,
yeah, we've got
different neural
forecasting options
here. What do I have?
Did I include an
example? Yeah, here
it, here it is.
Uh, yeah, let's,
let's just run, let's
just run this one for
a cloud flow neural.
Oh, I get, I see an
error I need to fix.
I haven't, I haven't
published this publicly,
so it's not that
big a deal uh for
neuro we're going
to do forecast apple
horizon 24 i'm not
going to use the gpu on
this because i'm on a
code space oops did i
what did i do wrong
it was just come in
let's go let's go into
the actual tool i'm
not going to worry
about that at the
moment so we're going
to go i'm just going
to run claude uh
code dangerously skip
permissions and i'll
show you how this looks
So in, let's
make this bigger
so you guys can see it.
We'll go here.
So I've got
all these
commands, right?
So I've got, you
can see here that
I've got all the
commands for running
it. So we can
have the memory
system, the neural
forecasting, system
orchestration,
trading strategies,
correlation
analysis. So these
are all now
different commands.
So get new sentiment,
whatever it is. So
it integrates directly
with Cloudflow
as the orchestrator.
So you can see here
I get MCP direct
uses direct tool and,
you know, using
Project Neural Trader.
Let's just do that
and see what happens.
And now I'm doing
it singly, but
I can do this
again as a swarm.
So at this point,
you know, it
should execute.
It's going to
do a little bit
of thinking.
So now, you know,
yeah, let's, you know,
analyze, analyze the
Apple and I don't know,
Microsoft stock
using the MCP.
Now, again, all this
can be automated
because I've got command
line tools, right?
So this can just
run autonomously. I
don't have to, I don't
have, I'm doing it
manually just to
sort of show what's
happening. So now it's
spinning up a cluster.
And each of
those is running
as an autonomous swarm.
So these are all
happening in, oops.
Now, it's looking at
the different horizons.
It's trying to figure out
what the confidence
level is.
And now it's going
to quickly do
an analysis. And
it's going to
look at the neural
forecasting.
This is all autonomous.
Literally, once I
point it at it and say,
go do it, it'll go
figure it all out
for me. And I can then
say, based on this,
it'll give me a
synopsis, the current
and predictive values.
use, I think in this
case, I might be
using static data on
this because this is my
training environment,
but you're coming
from static data
that I imported to
do the training, but
I can import Bloomberg,
whatever it's, it
can be, it's live. I
can use the web search
capabilities. You
know, for example, I
can say, uh, use the
web search to get late.
And this is the
cheapest way to do it to
me the slowest but in
the latest data and
do a deep and analysis
so basically all
you're doing is
pointing this thing at
the problem or whatever
it is you want to
do or trade and it
goes and figures it
all out for you that's
it it creates the
swarm it does the
it does the analysis
it does a search it
does the trade it
can it can do this it
can do the trades in
1.8 milliseconds.
So just to put that
in context for a
moment, when you blink,
that's 100 milliseconds
for a blink.
I can do that at 1
.50th, I guess, of
the time it takes
you to blink. I can
make the decision
across multiple vectors
and then make the
trade repeatedly
forever and
let this thing
run, which I
did for a week.
It's just crazy. And
you've got all these
different options
you know here you can
see the mcp let me
run this let me let
me let that continue
over here because that
the web search is
actually the slowest
way to do it but
i'm going to go here
and i'm just going to
run cloud again and
this time i'm just
going to show you what
the mcp integration
looks like so you
see here mcp yeah oh
no i did the wrong one
and i guess i might
have to change the
naming convention.
Let's try to add MCP.
Yeah, I think I
might have named
my MCP commands
too closely.
But let's go back.
Basically, you've
got Claude.
And just I haven't, I
might write script or
something, but MCP.
Basically, you can add
MCPs to Claude. And
you can see here that
i've added that mcp
so it's basically i've
created a wrapper for
it i didn't bother
creating a remote
mcp for it because i
didn't really need that
but i guess i could i
suppose but basically
it it'll run against
all these different
vectors you can see
automation examples
tool combinations and
you're just invoking
these these options
correlation analysis
whatever it is you want to
do or and you could
say do it all give me
the world's best
trading algorithm and go
figure it out and I'm
going to go to bed
and tomorrow morning
it would have done it.
So now you see it
thinking through the
process. I completed
searches for both stocks.
It's doing the
analysis and then it'll
dream up the optimal
arbitrage in this
scenario for maybe
trading Apple against
Microsoft or something.
Whatever it is I
want to do, it'll
literally go and figure it
out in the most
optimized way possible.
Options up next?
It does options. It
does crypto. It does
anything that I can
get, anything that
has a publicly
available or privately
available trading
API, all you need to
do is basically say,
go use that API.
So name a, what
was that one that's
popular for like
day traders?
Robin, ***** trade.
Yeah, there's an API.
Think or swim.
Polymarket.
The prediction market.
What?
Oh, prediction market.
yeah what's what's
thinking about
polymarket polymarket
has they've got a
github repository
from november with
their own agents
on it okay let's do
this um add polymarket
ap polymarket
api to the uh trading
system now i'm going
to switch to a
different plan here i'm
going to I'm gonna
call this PolyMarket.
And this gives
me a branch
to the trading system.
Create as a
modular extension
and spawn a five-agent
swarm in parallel
using batch tool.
continue TDD and continue
until complete with
100% coverage that's
it that's all you need
to do to create anything
you can possibly
want to add to this and
and now I'll just sit
back and it'll go and
it'll add the poly
it'll research the
polymarket system figure out
how the api works and
see now it's creating
the to-do list i just
sit back and watch
it do its thing and then
i'll have polymarket
integration probably
before this call is even
done roof i mean um
this is obviously you
are on the base cloud
cloud code interface
right you're not really
using spark no i am i
am so yeah so i've got
to integrate it with
right here so you see
these clod commands
and and i've got the
source so and there's a
couple hundred thousand
lines of code that
underpins the mcp but i
you can see here i got
my gpu acceleration
here i got my memory
systems neural models
these are different neural
models i've created
uh but the what what
makes it all work is
the this trading system
and there's a question
as well yeah can you
yeah yeah i wanted to
ask so you mentioned
earlier that you're
you're currently running
like some training test
data are you running
this in production
with actual real-time
sources i'm not showing
you guys that because
i'm again i don't
want to get uh on the
sec's radar if i can
help it so i'm just
voiding things that i
think might get me in
trouble but you can
you guys can tell the
making you know the
difference between the
reason i asked that
specifically is because
obviously these models
have been trained on
ungodly amounts of data
which i'm not using
includes i'm not using
i'm not using those
models so this this
is not using llm based
inference for the data
i'm using custom custom
uh neural network so
this is 100% neural
network based on the
the neural forecast
system so this is not
a language model like
the language model is
doing like the swarm
orchestration but it's
actually using this
approach so basically
what i'm doing is i'm
using a a it builds
its own neural models
specifically for what
i need it to build for
so it's not biased
from whatever it's
trained on i'm i'm you
know you're kind of
training your own like
custom time series
models locally and then
running those in real
time exactly i'm using
n beats and i think
my the best model i
found was this nti
you know h model um
which basically gives
me time series neural
network and now i i
probably can't even
describe it because
it's probably beyond
my comprehension to
describe so i'm just
going to pop back in the
cloud here and get
it to describe it i'm
gonna we're almost
out of time i'm going
like hyper speed here
but we need to come
back at the end and to
see uh the integration
yeah so tell me
about the uh you know
model and how it
works are you setting
limits what are you
using to set the limits
i i've got a guidance
system there it's part
of the it's part of
the mcp so when we go
when we go back to the
mcp you'll see that
uh i've got i've got
different options for
that as well again
it's hard to show you
everything because there's
just so much going on
here but yeah there it
does it does everything
you know like that's
what you know in i
i really believe it
and you're putting on
full display rube that
in the next six months
there just won't be
a day trader on the
planet that is manually
looking at graphs and
uh you know handles
and waiting for the
perfect moment for them
to manually jump into
a position yeah so
it's gone you're you're
right so this so this
uh h hits is a natural
hierarchical interpolation
for time series
if you're going to do
this this is the model
you want to use i've
tried i tried 27 different
models this is by
far the best and what
this is a multi-stage
signal processing
uses multiple stacks
that process data at
different frequencies
through pooling layers with
various kernel sizes
decent to be honest
this is beyond my
comprehension all i all i
really know is all the
things i tried or the
swarm tried this was
by far the best one
hierarchical stacks
you got interpolation
mechanisms and then you
know i can explain it
to me like an idiot i
might want to say but
basically it's it's
creating its own model
on the fly in literally
milliseconds is
all you really need
to know fantastic hey
sorry use the news
feeds to influence
the the model so is it
just purely on numerical
data yeah no i'm
using news feeds so
uh i i've so much
bird i'm not showing
that because i don't
have rights to do that
but yeah i'm using
real-time news feeds
sentiment analysis
yeah and so all of
it i can then and
then one one of
the swarms is doing
simulation like in
the simulation
again is happening
faster than you can
blink right and so
yeah it's it's craziness
um i don't know
i i think everybody
wants this i'm just
trying to figure out
exactly how to make this
available without
getting in too much
trouble i think we i
think i might need a
lawyer or someone to
tell me that i'm not
going to go to jail for
this but uh yeah this
is this is It's the
last call to draft
yourself the appropriate
liability release.
Yeah, that's right.
You know, doing
my AI hackerspace
live from jail isn't
really up in my
list of things I
want to be doing.
No, that's right.
You're right.
So anyway, for
those who are interested,
I am giving, you
know, access, if you
can convince me, on
a case-by-case basis
to my GitHub. um you
you're gonna have
to convince me that
you're capable and
and worthy if you will
um but i have given
a few people access
including some
notable investors who
have reached out so
we'll see maybe if i
get the courage maybe
i'll release it next
week i don't know
we'll do a ton of
research for
us right yeah
that was a lot of
information i apologize
i went longer than i
usually do today but
But yeah, someone
mentioned the Millennium
Prize. I did the
Reitman hypothesis
there last year. I had
no way to prove it.
I can just comment on the
regulation part of it.
If you charge money,
you will be liable.
If you don't charge
money, it's kind
of gray area from
SEC perspective.
So gray.
Yeah, gray makes
me feel great.
Yeah, yeah.
Thank you, Ulas. confirm
the requirement for
good uh good you can
charge money you just
have to position it
yeah you'd have to
position it correctly
if you say this is an
idea generator this is
not a trade executor
then you know it's
it's more that you've
you've exited one legal
domain and entered
into another yeah i'm
going to call it sbf and
then open source
license and in general
the open source license
i don't know guys i
i see sam bankman
free yeah open source
license and let the users
you know install and
run by their own is
it's not your concern
basically i mean don't
supersede the local
governmental authority
no it doesn't it's
the problem i i just
want to say i think
everybody here is assuming
i think everybody is
here nope here's
alistair you you You take
it away, Alistair.
You're up next anyway.
Yeah.
Oh, we lost your
sound, Alistair.
There are no norms.
We don't live in
a time of compliance.
I don't think
you can trust the
SCT to do anything.
The reality is that the
reason that the stock
market exists and
derivatives exist,
according to capitalism,
has always been to find
efficiencies and
maximize the efficiency
of capital as a way of
directing our resources.
If we now have a
thing that can extract
the efficiencies of
the system and there's
no more profit to be
made other than, you
know, essentially a
machine allocating capital
algorithms. If you get
into the philosophy
of capitalism, what
you have is the sort of
Adam Smith's perfect
machine for market
liquidity. And once
enough of these machines
get hooked up, there
ceases to be any profit
margin. Because what
you have essentially is
this AI is using its
information to do
perfect capital allocation
in the market. Like
the whole reason that
we allowed derivatives
and future trading to
exist was to figure
out inefficiencies in
the market. This company
is not running as
well as it could be.
This capital is being
invested somewhere it
shouldn't be. This
savings should be put into
productive use. And
in theory, there was
a whole class of people
called traders whose
job it was to find
those inefficiencies and
tax them so they would
go away. That's kind
of how capitalism is
supposed to work if
you're a classical
economist. We now have a
system that RUV is
building, which looks like
trading, but what it's
actually doing under
the covers is finding
market inefficiencies
and extracting revenue
from them and so
if you want to get like
i'm talking to a lot
of companies these
days that want to talk
about how to make their
employees do ai better
but if you want to
take a step back we no
longer need the trading
system to make capital
allocation efficient
is what we're really
talking about yeah
well said and what i'm
doing is looking for
inefficiencies that's
100% what i'm doing and
i'm trying i'm doing
that using a gpu a
billion times a second
which is and which i
built overnight while
i slept amazing so
alistair we might um we're
in that segment the
guest segment so uh
and you're one of our
our three uh lightning
talk guests so welcome
alistair and uh hey
the floor is yours
hey uh hi i'll keep it
quick uh roof how long
have I known you for?
We met Alistair back
when I was trying
to pitch the concepts
of cloud computing.
I met Steven Pollack
and said, you got
to meet Alistair.
He's the guy. I think
it was Steven Pollack
and who was famous
for being one of the
first virtualization
company founders.
It was 2004, 2003.
So more than 20 years
ago. Yeah. Back when
once upon a time,
the internet was as
cool as AI is. And then
cloud computing was
as cool as AI is. And
then big data was as
cool as AI is. And
I think we've been
involved for at least a
couple of those things.
I also wrote a book
called Lean Analytics
that shows startup
founders how to use
data to make a better
business faster.
And I just wrote a
book called Just Evil
Enough about subversive
go-to-market strategy
that's pretty
funny. So if you're
interested in go-to
-market, you can grab that.
But what I wanted
to talk about very
briefly, I spent a lot
of my time talking to
all kinds of interesting
people. I was in
Dubai talking to the
heads of policing
from 60 countries a
couple of weeks ago about
how to maintain
legitimacy in an era
of technological
asymmetry. So kind of ADHD
as a career. The thing
that I'm thinking
about right now, Ruv,
and I'll give you
a very quick framing
of it, and then maybe
we can chat about
it, is every major
technology shift has
a before and an after.
And we allocated our
capital, our energy,
our resources, our
staffing, and then some
technology happened,
and then we allocated
it again. So there's
a misallocation
beforehand, right we had
lamp lighters then we
got electricity the
lamp lighters went away
um it is a career
and i'm not
a billionaire
chris so i'm not
sure about that
one uh so uh
we now have with major
technologies have a
misallocation problem
and i would argue in
tech there's been four
big misallocations
in recent years uh the
first one was the move
from desktop software
to software as a
service where a company
was built to like send
out discs and floppies
once a year and
there were big updates
and now it's just you're
using an app and it's
software as a service
and you and the entire
structure of your
sales and your
organization is different.
There was the move
from hardware to cloud
computing. I founded a
company that needed a
lot of hardware back in
2001 and we were making
appliances but you
know the economics
changed a lot if you just
use clouds. Why would
you spend money on
permanent hardware where
you can pay for it as
an operating expense.
The next big one I'd
say is social media,
where companies were
structured in order
to deal with paid
media instead of earned
impressions. And so
if you were a company
that set itself up
to use paid media and
traditional channels,
you were obsolete
when social media came
along. And obsolete
doesn't happen
overnight. It takes a few
years. But obviously,
we're in what I
would call the fourth
big miscapitalization
of tech, which is that
we are now allocating
money to developers
when we can't have
agents. And that's a
big problem that most
people haven't realized.
Most people are
looking at the first
order consequences,
like how do I do my
job better with AI?
Some people are
looking at the second
order consequences. Do
I need to hire another
person or can I
use an AI? And what
we really need to be
doing is thinking of
the third order
consequences. Does this
business continue to
exist when something
else can do this
function. Like I just
pointed out where,
if the goal of the
financial industry
is to, or the trading
industry is to make
capital liquid by, by
identifying and
removing inefficiencies.
And there's a system
that can do that better.
Maybe we don't need
trading. Like that's
a weird thing, you
know, speculative
trading. That's a
weird way to look at
it, but I don't think
we're thinking weird
enough. So I want
to share a couple
of thoughts, uh, just
off the cuff here.
I spent a lot of
time working with
startups. I run
a big conference
called Startup
Fest in Montreal.
And we talk about
unicorns in the startup
world. The whole venture
capital, commercial
capital world is
structured on this idea
of one in a thousand
doing really well.
And I think we're
going to go from
unicorns to millions
of tiny horses.
What I mean by that is,
imagine you're making
a scheduling and CRM
software platform.
You could make that
very, very generic and
then it becomes complex
to customize it to
lots of things like the
salesforce.com model.
But in that category,
there's a company
called Talk, T-O
-C-K, that's used
for restaurants
who want to charge
people for the meal
before they arrive.
High cost restaurants
where people will
book a reservation
and then cancel.
And so Talk is a
sales CRM scheduling
platform that's very,
very specific to the needs
of high end restaurants.
there's another
one um called studio
.inc I think that's
a for tattoo parlors
and in many cases the
tattoo artist doesn't
want you to know
where they live until
you've agreed to do the
tattoo so there's a
whole negotiation on
the artwork before you
confirm the appointment
it'd be very hard
to make one CRM that
can be configured in
all those ways but
you have like no CRM
that's better than the
studio for tattoo
parlors no CRM that's
better than uh talk for
high-end restaurants
And so I think
that's what I mean by
millions of tiny horses.
But the thing that
I'm really interested
in right now is I
mentioned one of the
miscapitalizations was
the introduction of
software as a service.
And the SaaS world,
in many cases, is
referred to as shadow
IT because once upon a
time, the CIO had
software licenses. They'd
stick a disc in a
computer once a year.
That was your new
software. And then all
of a sudden, some sales
guy put in his credit
card, and now you're
using Salesforce.
This was horrible
for enterprise IT. It
bypassed their immune
system. They lost
control. I talked to
CFOs that were looking at
Amex bills and finding
50 rogue Amazon
accounts. And so this
idea of shadow IT meant
that an employee
could install software
without the approval
of the organization.
But I think that we're
about to find a much
bigger problem, which
is shadow workforce,
where I don't install
SaaS as a tool so
humans can work. I
install SaaS as a console
so agents can work. And
so I'm not installing
a CRM. I'm installing
a direct inside sales
department. And so
that's not a case of
shadow IT. That's
shadow workforce. That's
not the CIO's problem.
That's the head of
HR's problem. And I think
that this is something
we have not properly
thought about that
is going to be *******
up every major company
in the next six
months is this idea of
any employee can install
a shadow workforce
and they don't even
know whether they should
give that guy a bonus
or fire him. So that's
what I'm currently
thinking about, Ruv.
You hit it dead on.
And when you look at
how I work with the
biggest companies,
I'm a lucky guy. And
what's happening is
I've reduced the
friction for them to
hire me. All they need
to do is go into my
little booking site,
put in their corporate
card, and they're
like, hey, Ruv,
how do I create the
Swarm today? And I've
got this idea that
my company said it's
going to take two
years and $5 million.
What can you do? And
literally within the
hour, we built it
completely. And I did
a presentation to
probably the largest, I
won't say who it is,
you'll guess if I
say what it is, but a
very, very, very large
company. And they're
like, we had this
idea, and they said,
we were quoted $2.5
million yesterday to
build this thing, and
you just built it
for us in 45 minutes.
I didn't really build
it, though. I took
what they said, popped
it into my little
swarm, and said, go
build me that. And then I
showed them some
PowerPoints and gave them
the code at the end of
the call. and that's
like a leading sort
of indicator probably
where we're going to
be and imagine when
everyone else catches
up what the world looks
like yeah it's it's
crazy yeah yeah weird
i had this same
conversation i'm i was at
a a function in san
francisco last week
alistair and um you
know you know this is
exactly we were talking
about puppet masters
and in bits and um i
couldn't agree with
you more that uh it's
certainly frontier and
i think the other
thing is we talk about
who's impacted like you
think about how much
of um our work is
outsourced to a third
world country like as
as much as people talk
about you know like
the fear of what's
happening i'm like well
it's already a mess
like it's already
smoke and mirrors and
gamification of a process.
I think it's going
to be rough, but I
anticipate a better future
because we're just
doing better things.
This is the
conversation I've been
having with the
government. So again, with
the ADHD thing, I
also run the world's
largest conference
on public sector
modernization and
digital government.
And those guys, most
of them are very much
like, I don't know
what I'm going to do. I
don't know what I'm
going to do. But when
you can do $8,000 of
legal work for $3 of
tokens, the taxpayer
is not going to put up
with a three order of
magnitude, more expensive
human. And so the way
I see this is, um,
right now, if you are
trying to do claims
benefits for our most
vulnerable humans,
that stuff's hard.
Uh, if we can get 99%
of those claims benefits
to be done for one
hundredth of the
costs, then as a human,
I am a hundred percent
fine with the 1%
being a social worker,
government employee
who goes and does a
safety check on them,
health check, maybe
brings them some food.
Like that's the world
I want to live in.
Like right now, I
firmly believe that a
fundamental human right
in the digital age should
be that nobody should
know more about you
than you do. It just
seems like a very good
tenet. But if we were
to enforce that, the
government already
knows tons of things
about you, it just
doesn't make it easy for
you to look at them.
So imagine that now,
because the government,
um, has AI running the
bureaucratic stuff,
um, that it can focus
on the good things
like a cradle to grave
timeline where you can
see all your tax history,
your vaccinations,
your medical history,
whatever else, right.
We can now build these
amazing things. The
real risk is that um
the reason fascists
lose is bureaucracy is
hard and if we make
a system that makes
bureaucracy unthinkably
easy it may be impossible
to install a fascist
state that's that's
that we cannot counter
as free-thinking
citizens so there's this
bet we're making that
we can get well-aligned
ai in the hands of
well-aligned humans
and and improve quality
of living and give
people dignified jobs and
more meaningful human
interactions faster
than we can give a few
people the ability to
surveil us so much
that no form of dissent
is possible that's the
alistair you're spot
on we have to come
back to that we've two
other guests we want
to try and sneak in
before the top of the
hour but then we'll have
an open session as
well uh after the one o
'clock thank you alistair
there's uh bang on
some uh incredible
insights and thinking
and conversations and
before we leave where
can folks follow alistair
maybe get get his
book i'm sure it's on
amazon alistair this
is your chance for a
little bit oh it's way
better if you go to
justevilenough.com and
buy it directly from
us because then i have
your email address and
i can send you stuff
yeah perfect all right
and alistair thank
thank you again for for
coming on and if you
want to stick around
we do it we have an
after show where we
usually go into crazy
philosophy yeah for sure
all right um yeah i i
I'd highly suggest
getting Alistair's book.
Lean Analytics
is actually
one of my favorites.
I've got a signed
copy. Thank
you for that, by the way,
from like 10 years ago.
You and Ben are amazing.
If you don't know
Ben as well, he does
some amazing work
with his startup work.
All right. Super.
Chris Bolter. Moving
on to the next.
All right, Chris.
Hey, Chris from the UK
group. How are you doing?
Hello, hello. Very
good, very good. I was
getting a bit confused
there because I
kept turning around
behind me. I'm like,
yeah, it's that book,
isn't it? So, yeah.
I've got a copy of
the book on my shelf.
That was very unexpected.
Thanks, Ballester.
Cool. So, yeah, a
bit of a tricky one
to follow up with.
I'll be very brief.
And like I say, change
your tone, really.
I've been working on
production code bases
with the Gentic tools
for at least 12 months
now. and one of the
toughest things i
found was how do you
actually um make sure
that what uh what
actually makes it into
production is not going
to break stuff that
kind of generally helps
right so the first
thing we tried to do
really was go okay how
can you treat an agent
like a junior engineer
right a very talented
one but just someone
who needs your
guidance here and there
So the first thought
was, well, let them
go away and do the
research and then come
back and be like, okay,
here's what I want
to do. Here's a detailed
plan. And you can
look at it and go,
yeah, that's all great.
We don't want you
to lose that library
there because
actually we're using a
different library
somewhere else in the code
base. So can you reuse
that stuff, please?
And where that
brought us to was
actually creating
these YAML task files.
Yeah, and all this
really is, is like a
runbook. it's a very
detailed way of describing
exactly what's going
to happen when the
agent starts coding. So
it's very much aligned
with that kind of think
left thinking from
the DevOps world, where
it's like, hey, if
we can make all our
engineering decisions up
front, then we can
work with absolute
confidence that whatever
it builds is going to
be in line with the
rest of production base
right so this was my
starting point uh we've
all started using Claude
code probably over
the last month few
months that kind of thing
um and a couple of
things triggered a step
change in this
because first of all i
watched a podcast i think
it was every guys and
they were talking
about how they use uh
github projects and
that sounded really cool
it's like okay i need
to check that out uh and
then i was also looking
at uh github actions
and how you can run
Claude code was in
GitHub Actions so it
started to kind of trigger
some thoughts for
me like hang on how
could you actually kind
of automate a system
around this where you
could start using uh
the GitHub issues and
projects to actually
manage the workflow of
your work previously
I'd had it in the code
base and that's a bit
clunky when you've got
teams working on stuff
um and it turns out
it's actually really
easy to do because
Claude code is very well
specified. It can
work very easily with
GitHub, GitHub issues,
GitHub projects, everything
else. So you can tell
it to create issues
very easily. This is
a custom command we
created and all it
needs to do is kind of
somewhere down here, I
think it has, yeah, it
just executes on the
command band GH and
whatever things it needs
so we can then create
issues from within
code code then we just
think about kind of
what workflow do we want
where we maximize the
agentic ability so
that we don't do the
legwork but we still have
these approval steps
right and so for me
it kind of came down
to two steps which can
be very brief when the
agents are good like
code code but nonetheless
quite important
so So first of all,
when we create an issue,
then we can use
automations to
trigger Claude
code and we can
execute our kind
of research task,
which if it's a bug,
then we'll want to
recreate the bug.
We'll want to see if
there's adjacent
bugs around it. What
happens if we change
the parameters a bit,
et cetera. If it's a
feature, then we might
want to understand
how we're implementing
similar features,
et cetera, right?
But the first stage
after that then is doing
the research, coming
back with a report and
go right here's all the
technical information
that you need to know
here's the approach
that we're likely to
take with it and that
gives you a really
early stage to say yes
that's great or actually
we should be going in
a slightly different
direction there yeah
once you've then approved
that then again Claude
code can do its thing
and it can go and
write one of these
yaml tasks which we're
looking at yeah now this
is really cool for a
few reasons first of
all we are forcing it to
load the context that
we want claude code's
actually very good
at context but cursor
wasn't so this is much
more important as cursor
but just like with
a junior engineer if
they're working on a
particular part of the code
base it might not be
obvious they actually
impact stuff in other
places that they haven't
seen therefore what
we can do from the
outset is go okay you
have to load these files
into context so that
you understand the
broader implications of
what you're doing here.
Then we can take it
through the steps
that we want and be
very specific about
the files and the
functions being edited.
And finally, we can
enforce our checks.
So we can say, hey,
you have to run
these tests. They
have to pass. If
not, you need to loop
through until they
work or until you
kind of give up.
So again, that
gives us just a nice
runbook task, which
we can have a look at.
Nine times out of 10,
we can approve it.
Occasionally, we'll
need to kind of make
some tweaks. But from
there, we can be pretty
much guaranteed that
what we produce in the
PR is going to be
good too much, because
actually there's very
little chance it's gone
off, done something
that we didn't want.
And ultimately, my aim
is always that if I'd
sat there and written
the code by hand, that
the end result from
the agent is exactly
the same as what I've
written. And so far,
this is the best way
I've found of doing it.
Interesting, Chris.
I like your approach.
The one thing
you might want to
consider, I also
integrate projects.
I've been doing that
for a while. You
might want to
consider using Claude
in the form of the
Swarm approach.
Make sure you reference
Batch Tool and
use the WorkTree
option within GitHub
and you can create
multiple trees that
each part of the
Swarm can work on
separate but concurrently
so it doesn't
necessarily conflict
with one another.
And then at the end
of the Swarm process,
that brings it
all back together.
Your structure would
be well suited to
that. But nice work.
Looks really good.
We don't have a
lot of time. I
apologize. But we can
come back to Chris
if you want to stick
around at the top
of the hour and
we can dive into
some other things.
Just as an update,
I think I've
created about 60,000
lines of code so far
for that poly market
addition to the
grading platform.
So I'm hoping by the
end of the session,
we'll have a fully
functioning polymarket
component as well. So for
whomever mentioned that,
thank you. That's a
cool addition, by the
way. So I'm excited
to see how that works.
Who's up next?
We have Everett.
Hey, welcome
back, Everett.
Did I get that
right? Master's
in aerospace engineering?
Yeah, yeah.
Thank you.
It is great to be back.
You know, I really
appreciate, you know,
Alistair's take earlier.
I think it's easy
to try to have a lot
of positive spins
on a lot of the
technical innovations,
particularly if you're
technically minded.
And I'm going to, I
had something working
and then I made a few
edits trying to get the,
because I've had some
success in the past
of vibe coding, a debugging
update within like
30 minutes of a
presentation before. because
i feel like that's
where we're always at
but um i want to give
a quick update on a
project that i presented
on last week um and
then also just kind of
share a couple of things
that are going on
um break breakage is
like our specialty if if
the demo doesn't break
halfway through you're
not doing it right
yeah um you know so um
for those of you that
don't know um uh two
weeks ago I presented
a project that I've
been working on for a
long time called
Archetype. And Archetype is
a simulation engine,
which is intended to
handle all the state
management so that LLMs
can then go and generate
simulation scripts.
And the goal there
being that once I get
like a Gemini CLI or like
a cloud code integrated
with this type of
a system that then
those agents can then
like generate simulations
themselves recursively,
potentially
perform some sort of
Monte Carlo tree search
to effectively explore
different realities.
And then they're only
concerned with like
on the token side and
usage side, declaratively
describing like
what simulation they
want to have. And so
prior to this, I had
shown everybody just
the toy examples, which,
you know, in
traditional physics, you
know, I come from the
aerospace background,
worked at Boeing Phantom
Works for a couple
of years straight out
of college and then
moved into the big data
space and big tech.
So that's that's the
area that I live in.
And so, you know, I
talked about some of
the technologies that
I use and everything,
but effectively,
we've got this naive
simulation here that just
updates a position of
entities after each
simulation step. and
then eventually you'll
just see the lines
that move from point A
to point B each step.
But that's not
really interesting
and it's particularly not
interesting to the
HMTX community.
So the thing
that I've been
working on is
integrating the ECS
processors with
an OpenAI client.
And this gets into
key bottlenecks
in like batch inference,
trying to test different
concurrency models.
As of right now,
Archetype supports
running multiple
worlds in parallel.
And so there's a
couple add-on modules
that are going to
take that from just
being able to run
this locally on your
laptop to being able
to run this on Array.
And then the goal
there is this is
effectively, as much
compute as you can
throw at this, you
can generate more and
more worlds, more
and more simulations,
more and more entities.
And this automates
a lot of the data
engineering and
state management
for these large
-scale simulations.
So the thing that's
not working right
now is this experiment
that I'd like to
run. And I think it
captures the overall
orchestration that
I think maybe a
lot of us use when
we're chatting with
OpenAI or any of
these LLMs where we
like to explore
different perspectives,
just evaluate a bunch
of different options.
And this is kind of
your classic ensembling
use case.
I've got a worker
and a judge, and then
the worker can go and
generate a bunch of
answers, and then
the judge will go and
evaluate those answers.
And so then the thing
that I was going to
present to you guys
today was that this
nested semifore-based
concurrency model
for this processor is
not optimal. And so I
was going to actually
use my own simulation
to come up with new
concurrency processing
mechanisms. You're
a super intelligent
AI, You'll be asked
to provide a code
snippet that implements
the prompt. The prompt
is, hey, I've got
this processor. It's
really freaking slow.
Make it faster,
you know, and
then it's instrumented
with that.
So the simulation
scripting semantics of
this are actually
still a little bit in
flux. But the long
-term goal is that we're
operating with, you
know, millions of
entities in parallel.
and that they can work.
And the entire
backend is built with
big data like
OpenTable technologies.
So reading and writing
from storage is cheap
and has like
minimal overhead. So
zero copy reads
and writes if
you're a big data
nerd like I am.
All right.
So we're almost
at time in the
first hour, but
it's just quickly,
what are the practical
applications?
Like, where
would I use this?
Yeah, so for Archetype,
this is effectively
going to give your AI
agents superpowers.
You have some sort of,
if you've got a system
like Cloud Code or,
you know, Cloud Flow,
instead of the agents
being concerned
with, like, going
and generating
all these simulations
and, like,
running it itself,
it is effectively
simply operating
as an orchestrator.
And what this ends
up looking like,
particularly for
code generation,
is that you can begin to
declaratively define
your evaluations,
your benchmarks,
your code generation.
And it means that you
don't have to compromise
on like or stick
to just one answer.
You're going to go
and explore the entire
solution space. So it's
great for exploring
open-ended questions,
scientific discovery,
financial
modeling, anything
that you want
to run at scale.
Cool. So is there
an MCP interface for
it? Can I just add
it to Cloud Code?
That would be,
it's in the roadmap.
It's in the roadmap.
You'll have it in,
what, 10 minutes?
MCPs are so easy
to play, right?
Yeah, that's,
you know, swarm it up.
i i expect to see it
by by the end of the
hour okay okay it's
actually like i'm not
even kidding mcps are
super thing and anything
that can have an
interface like whether
it's a cli should have
an mcp interface
and the ability for
everything that i'm
building to interact with
everything that i
previously built through an
mcp makes makes it all
kind of like a lego
building block sort
of approach right so
i like i like what you're
doing um i'm excited
to see so it's like
a world model system
simulation. It's,
it's, it's pretty cool.
All right. This is,
this is the open
part of the show
guys. And Everett
really appreciate
you taking the time
before, before we
go any, where can
people follow you
learn about what
you're doing, social
company, whatever.
Yeah. You can
follow me on,
on Twitter, on LinkedIn.
Definitely. Those are
the places where I'm
posting the most
content. I've also got a
YouTube channel and
I'm adding more videos,
updating folks on
my progress here.
Awesome. And share, if
anyone wants to connect,
share your LinkedIn
in the text area and
we can all connect.
And you notice that a
lot of us have our
little infinity logos
because we're of the
foundation, the Agentex
Foundation, which we're
trying to spread globally.
We've got, what, 60
cities where we have
ambassadors and things
happening all over
the globe. So hopefully
if you can't meet
online, you can meet in
person or vice versa.
But this is the
point of this is
the open part of
the show, meaning
that's the open mic.
So if anyone has
something you want
to share, say,
whatever, this
is your chance.
We got Dennis.
Take it away.
Hey, I need to leave
in a second going for
dinner with the family.
So but I just want
to follow some of the
stuff that Alice that
we're talking about.
And I have to say that
I also share a little
bit of optimism. I
think we can make this
work for the best. I
do think that Europe
needs to play a big part
in Canada, actually,
because I think we
are a lot more aligned
where we need to go.
The thing I want just
to comment is that I
feel if you follow
this sort of swarm and
in a way, you know,
Ruvn is doing some
ridiculous, crazy
stuff, right? But if you
follow this idea that
what we're going to be
doing is empowering
a lot more of the
smaller entity, I think
we will see a lot more
distribution, right,
of that power and not
that centralized top
-down model. And one
of the things that I
remember saying that
people thought I was
absolutely crazy when
I was in the corporate
world is I used to
say that every dev
team, every team in the
building, every part
of the organization
needs to have a
developer, an engineering
function, right? By
the way, I used to do
that in security. In my
teams, I used to build
engineering teams
inside cybersecurity.
And I think what we're
going to see is that
I think, yes, there's
a place for the crazy
stuff that Ruvn is
doing. But I think
in a more realistic
world, we're going to
start seeing a lot of
development, engineering
and experience being
hired by every single
function in the
business. Because every
function in the business,
and yes, some will
be made redundant,
but I think others
will actually be able
to execute a lot better.
So I think the dev
world is going to move
to that sort of packaging
and productizing
and everything in my
world is a worldly
map where you basically
have a lot of Genesis
stuff and then you
need to bring the devs
or the engineers and
the architects to
actually glue things
together and to make it
work, you know, like
the other guy that was
presenting that
making something work
reliable at enterprise
level is very difficult.
So I think there's a
huge opportunity to
actually bring a lot of
engineering excellence
and a lot of practices
that in the past
never scaled into a
lot of these other
business functions that
didn't exist before.
I get it. And I get
a lot of pushback
on the crazy
things I've built.
I'm building these
things not because
they're necessarily
impractical. I'm building
them just because I
can. Right. And if
there's no practical
application, that's
almost secondary for me,
for all the pushback.
I mean, oh, why
would anyone actually
want to use that thing?
Well, I don't know.
It doesn't even
matter, really.
But I appreciate
the insights. Oh,
and we've got
Chris, our friendly
neighborhood
vibe coder. What
crazy things are
you building today?
Well, I was messing
around with that cognitive
triangulation architecture
with the agents,
with having them
analyze different
viewpoints. And
that's been really
cool. But recently
I've put out Fairmine
and you can go to
fairmine.ai and you
can get access to it.
It's essentially an
agentic dev team follows
your Spark architecture
roof. And the dev
team basically walks
through the whole process
and it has, you know,
a shared memory system.
And not only does
it just build things
from scratch, but it
works with you. It moves
with you. Like when you
want to make adjustments
or improvements to
the program, you
know, it manages the whole
thing. and it's super
cool and if you'd
like to try it out it
works with you know
claude max you can use
claude flow with it you
know it's model agnostic
um so if you want to
check that out you
can go to fairmind.ai
and check that out as
well the link in the
channel yeah absolutely
oh there's cool i i
love this stuff you're
you're cooking up chris
you've always got some
something that that's
making me you know
ponder what i should
build these events like
the reason i create so
much stuff on monday
and is because of
this right every every
friday i get way too
many ideas and then i you
know the swarm builds
it all weekend and i've
got something to show
and i think uh chris
is a big part of of
that um i'm you know
again we're open here
to any discussions uh
we've we've got alistair
who's one of the best
thinkers i i think
i've ever met on so you
know alistair how's what
what are you thinking
about our show by
the way are we crazy
or what uh there's an
old adage that most
technologies start out
as toys when the car was
first invented it was
for rich dilettantes
and once some
little kid hand
cranked the front
of it he had to
walk in front of
you with a flag
it was a toy no one
ever thought it was
going to change the
world if you want to get
inside the OODA loop
of any technology, you
need to play with it
before its purpose is
obvious. Uh, not just
because that gives
you fluency in it,
but because you find
these weird use cases,
the problems of today
can never be solved
with the systems that,
uh, created them. And
so I think the, the,
I think play is
underrated, underrated. And
Ruv, I think I've always
known you to be the
guy who likes to play
um i think you you
you may want to talk
to someone about it
because you kind of have
a compulsion man like
like you may want to you
know you're compelled
to play with technology
whether that's
like cloud containers
or or the latest agents
but i think what's
interesting is tolerance
for play at technology
inflection points is
um what is necessary
and just the fact that
you got you know you're
building things with
your kids too uh so i
think it's important
just to remember cars
started out as toys
for the rich and the
sooner we play with
things the sooner we
figure out what they're
for but alistan you
mentioned the loop right
so you know about worldly
maps right uh yeah
simon and i are buddies
although when he
does the worldly maps
in the room i'm like
that's obvious and then
he leaves and i'm like
what it i can never
sustain it it's like a
reality distortion
field but yes i like
simon's way of looking
at the world so so reuben
and i think i just
hear now i call it i
think he's the typical
explorer right so you
try things out you go
out there you create
things you fail and
success is almost measured
not by he works all
the time but did you
did you move the needle
and then you feed on
each other right and
that's that's key part
of it that's a key
part evolution and then
you need the villagers
who take that and
start to sort of make
it work repeatable so
it's sort of like it's
usable by others and
then eventually becomes
a commodity and that's
when you've got the
town plans yeah right
it's i just like to
experiment and push the
boundaries of where
i'm and what's possible
just because i don't
you know is there a
reason beyond just
creating because you can is
that and that's a good
enough reason i think
for most of the things
i create you know
and and keep in mind
i'm doing that in in the
midst of my actual
job as a consultant so
i'm actually you guys
don't even see all the
crazy stuff i'm
building for like people
actually pay me you're
just seeing the stuff
i'm doing in adjacent
to that who else we got
here um i'd just like
to just add it um uh
an aspect there when
alistair's talking
about you know um the
myriad of of solutions i
can't remember the
name of the uh of the
paradox when the price
of a commodity comes
down its usage that
picks up right jevin's
paradox jevin's paradox
right okay so as code
begins to move towards
zero plus energy uh
gets faster gets cheaper
um the i know this
sort of uh i understand
it as um the uncovering
or removing of market
efficiencies as a
as a type of triage
where more and more firms
can more quickly become
aware of more things
and even on the
procurement side supply
lines and all those
kinds of things well
there's a weird tension
there if you live in a
world where everybody
uses salesforce it's
imperfect but salesforce
is doing its debugging
and maintenance once
if you move to a
world where now everyone
has their own crm that
they built themselves
now everybody's doing
maintenance on all
their own stuff so you
no longer get the
economies of scale and so
there's always this
tipping point about
economies of scale versus
the efficiency right
is it more efficient
to run the stuff to
manage those so there's
always the one lesson
that i keep coming
back to in looking at
like civilization like
at all of civilization
is that civilization
is a tension between
the individual and the
collective there are
times when it makes
sense for the rogue
coder to go off and
build their own thing for
the thief to steal
something for the individual
to speak out against
the tyrant um and
then there are times
when it makes sense
for us to get together
and buy an mri or
build a road or you know
fix the barn or what
defend ourselves and
if you have too much
uh collectivism then you
don't have innovation
and you have the
possibility for stagnation
if you have too much
individualism then
you don't get the
efficiencies that come
with economies of
scale and all societies
and all political
parties and even all
relationships are an
attempt to find, and it's
always changing, the
optimal balance between
individualism and
collectivism. And so you're
going to see the rise
of like incredibly
personal individual,
I've got my own AI stack,
but then I'm burning
so much extra energy
trying to maintain
that stack that maybe
I'm okay with using
one that's not exactly
tailored to me. I think
there's going to be a
negotiation in society
between those two
things. For the Jevons
paradox problem, It
doesn't happen for
every market. Jevons was
specifically studying the
use of coal in England
in an 1890 paper called
The Coal Question
because the British
were trying to figure
out James Watt's engine
was four times as
efficient as Newcomen's
atmospheric engine.
And the British were
like, okay, how much
time do we have left?
And the reality was
that cheaper stuff
makes people use it
more. So I'll shut up
after this one point.
There's a guy I love
to think about named
Herbert Simon. He
was a Nobel laureate,
invented the economic
term uh, satisficing,
which is sort of
sufficient optimization.
And Simon, uh, is the
guy who coined the
term, the attention
economy. Um, back in the
seventies, everyone
was talking about the
information economy.
He said, economies are
driven by what's scarce.
We have to ask to our,
we have to, thank you
very much. You can
listen to me for hours
if you're interested.
Um, we have, I do, by
the way, um, I do have
a sub stack. I'll
paste a link to it in
here because I read stuff
on it some from time
to time um so herbert
simon said look the
reality is that um
economies are driven by
what's scarce and we
have to ask ourselves
what does this thing
consume so information
consumes our attention
therefore we live in
the attention economy
and so the best lens
i've found for looking
at ai is to say what
does this thing consume
because that's what
will become scarce
and that's a very good
model i like that better
than jevin's paradox
yeah those are really
good points one thing
the economy of scale
is interesting now
when i can let's assume
this evolves quite a
bit further than we
are today and we're on
the cusp of what we
want to call it agi asi
i i have the ability
to create anything
that pops in my mind
right by just you know
thinking when when we
get to a point where
there's you know it's
their fidelity means
that there's no
exploitation, the bugs are
limited, and I can
create things that are as
capable as any commercial
-grade software,
you know, instantly,
which we're probably
not that far from,
maybe a few years away,
probably at the most.
You know, what does that
say to economies of
scale? I don't need
the 10,000 Google
developers anymore, do I?
Right? And that's their
competitive advantage.
They've got the ability
to spend $2 billion
or $20 billion on their
their ai infrastructure
yet i can compete
with any of the
largest companies using
the cheapest low-end
stuff and and out and
outbuild them by and it's
pretty clearly i maybe
it's not production
ready it doesn't it
doesn't have to be it's
it's it's ready enough
that you can take
cloud code point at
and say you know fix it
up for me or change it
right it just changes
the the uh the structure
a little bit i think
yeah roof but prevents
google like hiring
like 10 000 of you
and giving them like
billion dollar of like
token costs like and just
scaling here let's
look let's take let's
take a quick look at the
poly market just just
as a 10 000 versions
of me approach so while
while we were talking
it built the poly
market component and i
just ran sec on it you
know the our favorite
uh code analysis tool
and let's just go down
to the bottom here
and it and in the last
what it was basically
an hour it it's uh it's
generated 24 000 lines
of code uh 17 000 of
which were python uh
it estimates this is
totally a bs number
and this is to this
is to alistair's point
about sort of the value
and the more and and
rob's point about the
more you create the less
it's worth possibly
but anyway it's saying
it's worth a half a
million bucks 11 months
of effort and four and
a half developers you
know and and literally
i just you guys gave
me an idea to build
it and it's it's not
quite done i don't think
yeah it's still doing
the last sort of you
know testing phase but
it's pretty much there
i'll have this ready
to go here probably
in the next 20 minutes
and it was just this
is a this thing alone
you know would have
been a year's worth of
work for a team of five
people a month and a
half ago right that's
how fast things are
going we're in this kind
of exponential curve
of capability and it's
really hard to see
when you're in it but
it's pretty clearly we're
in some kind of massive
transformation in
the in our ability to
to build and create
things all right i'm
gonna stop allister said
earlier about that um
it's hr's problem and
it made me think about
the future of work.
And I wanted a question
for Alistair in
trying to figure out
if, so if I'm the widget
man and I make five
widgets and I figure
out how to make 10
widgets without the
same amount of work,
wouldn't the criticality
to the org be to
educate the organization
on um the value for
that individual to
the organization
rather than looking at
it from standpoint of
that person is maybe
cheating his job cheating
his work and just
re-educating or
because it seems very
much similar to the
whole devops process and
yeah if i was a ceo
now i'd be like look
anybody who can figure
out how to efficiently
replace their current
job with an ai
will get 20 of their
current salary for
the next two years
you don't have to do
that work anymore
but if it breaks it's
your job to fix it
and so then you can go
do another thing like
that would be the
best way to incentivize
because then i
can like go replace 10
jobs and make myself
an annuity right
but i don't see
companies trying to
incentivize them like oh
how dare you use that
tool or whatever.
There's a whole other
way of thinking about
it, which is like,
I'm going to give you
an annuity, a cut of
the profits for some
foreseeable window for
replacing that job.
I, I, I would, I,
I might be a little
biased because I,
I'm the energetic
engineer and probably
one of a small
group of people
even call themselves
that globally,
but the, you know,
out of my hundred
or so customers,
I think 17 or fortune
500 companies,
these are companies
that probably
north of $20
billion in revenue.
And of those, which
is a sampling, a
small sampling of a
much larger group,
mind you, they're all
looking at ways to
do exactly what,
Alistair, you just
said. They're saying,
you know, how can
we sort of augment
our existing people?
And how can we sort
of, you know, I don't
want to use the word
replace, but I'm going
to talk plainly for
a moment. How can we
replace a certain
portion of our workforce
with autonomous things
that do to do these
things better faster
and cheaper and that
part is scary to me
it's like i don't want
to be the guy coming
in and replacing you
know 15 000 people in
an afternoon which i
kind of can you know
what happens to those 15
000 people right that's
the nose are yeah
the thing that's missing
in the conversations
that i'm hearing is
what alistair just
said is the incentive
that incentive to say
how can you your job
is five widgets if
you can figure out a
way to make 10 and with
one hour versus 40
hours then you can have
the same money or
you can go sit on the
beach that part is not
in the conversation
that i'm hearing i'm
off what i'm hearing is
how can we replace the
person with ai what
you said so i'm sure
there are a number of
people here who are
further along in their
careers than i am and
i'm curious if you
get more work if you
finish your work for
the day and there's
still time left what is
the reward for me it's
been more work yeah
i just i want to
offer a different
perspective so instead
of thinking about um
jobs being replaced
think about the problems
you would solve if
you had the time
so that makes
my point exactly
yeah yeah and
sandy i think
we're looking
there's more work
right i think we are
really looking in
the territory of
intrinsic motivation being
more than a theory
it's become a reality
for me and for many
here i think like
we are not doing
this for money right
it is basically
helping us create and
solve problems and
money therefore follows
effectively um yeah
that's how i look
at but i mean this
point about like how
do you organizations
reward people for
creating this and
create a sustainable
kind of nvd that's
a great great great
thought actually
actually yeah i was
just thinking about
this you know um
and this kind of
gets into sort of
global issues but
like you know we
have all these
things happening.
You know, we have a
lot of weather changes,
we have microplastics
in the air and
the water and all
these different things.
And, you know, with
these capabilities,
you can actually
start, you know, the
conversations always
are, how do we
monetize this, right?
And getting plastics
out of water, it's
not very lucrative.
But with these capabilities,
you can actually
do this now. And
once we apply these
capabilities to robotics,
then we can do so much
more. And I think what
we're seeing is this
sort of dawning of this
capability where we
can actually, like, I
always feel like all
innovation is driven
by the ability to see.
and this technology
gives us the capability
to build tools
to see better and
to understand better
and then once we
can do that we can
actually build things
that we can't even
imagine and I don't
know I think that's
kind of so exciting
and also big fan,
Ru, this amazing
Yeah, I think
that's awesome
Sorry, I think that
I'm detecting a theme
I think we're all saying
very similar things
in a different way,
which is that these
AI tools are allowing
us not to be just
incrementally better
software engineers or
product managers or
whatever, but orders of
magnitude better. because
they're like all the
things that we thought
would be nice to
do but way too difficult
whether it be fuzzy
searching whether it
be massive data and
analytics suddenly it's
within our grasp um
and that's that's pretty
exciting yeah mark
but even think about
yeah go ahead well
i was just going to say
to mark's point there
was a a young lady
we just met on the
meeting earlier this
week. She has a son who
has a, you know, I'm
not going to say a
business or whatever,
but has a difficult
disease. And now with the
ability to have access
to these tools to
where, you know, you're
looking at where one,
you would used to
be able to be a deep
developer to make a
webpage. Now access
to these tools, she is
able to go out and create
something that could
actually save not
only her son's lives,
but others' lives. So
it's really, really
exciting and I apologize,
Sandy, too. Yeah.
No, no problem. So again,
like when I started
thinking about it,
I mean, like, why do
we have governments?
Why do we have, like,
we, maybe we,
you know, these type of
tools give individuals
enough capabilities
that some of the
things that um we typically
have relied on for
um local you know
public policy and stuff
maybe that goes away
i think there's don't
this is much bigger
just being able to code
faster so but we have
things if i can yeah if
i can point a point
one thing does anybody
here has anybody here
heard of the term
moloch m-o-l-o-c-h uh it
comes from alan ginsburg
poem um so moloch is
the god of perverse
outcomes uh humans have
coordination problems
no country wants an
army but we all have
armies because someone
else might have an
army things like tragedy
of the commons right
in a world without
perverse outcomes where
there is perfect knowledge
of all participants
game theory says
you can have that
idealized world we
don't need governments
governments and before
them and i'm an atheist
pretty proudly so so i
apologize if offending
anyone but governments
and before them
religions were excellent
ways to get people to
behave without
surveillance when a law
enforcement is legitimate
we pay a ticket because
we believe that it is
for the greater good
for people not to
speed or whatever right
um so governments exist
to fight moloch and
there's i'm going to
find it there's a liv
bori one of my favorite
thinkers uh did an
amazing explanation of
what is moloch um it
is uh it's it's the
dangerous part of competition
it's necessary that
we are all constantly
optimizing for stuff
because otherwise
we go grow complacent
but as soon as i'm trying
to get the better
of you um the system
that we're in benefits
but you and i don't
necessarily benefit i
win you lose because i
cheated and then you
get tragedy the commons
problems the pond gets
overfished or whatever
and so i think we need
to look at government
as a coordination
problem the real risk
here is do we want to
abdicate coordination
to a system that
thinks it knows best
because then the
coordination for the greater
good is defined by you
know what peter thinks
greater good is or
whatever and that's
obviously the issue so
what about so let so um
do i train it myself
you know like i i think
there is a danger if
we're you know i don't
want to turn over
my morality code to
open ai google or some
else like i don't want
them telling me what's
offensive not offensive
but and you know who
knows what's ahead
of us but could i
then And so do I build
my own group of puppets
that are based on my
view of the world
and my morals and my
ethics and how I think
and what's important to
me? That's where my
brain went, Alistair.
I don't think we
can have a society,
functioning society,
as in not pure anarchy,
unless we do two
things. One is we're
going to need to be
able to distinguish
generative speech
from real speech. So
there's going to have
to be essentially the
equivalent of chain
of evidence for facts.
So this picture was
taken and there's a
person making a claim
whose identity I can
verify. And mathematically,
it has not been
tampered with. So
chain of evidence, like
in law enforcement, is
going to be necessary
for all forms of
information. That's
the first thing. And
then the second thing
is, uh, there will
have to be regulation
on what is allowed
because any runaway
technology like biotech,
which can self-perpetuate
has always been
regulated. Otherwise
it will just self
-perpetuate. And so I
think we're going to
see strong regulation on
self-perpetuation.
I don't know how we
will enforce that, but
I think we're going
to have to see it.
And unfortunately that
may be fairly draconian.
Like it may even
be to the point of
there's a monitor on
every processor sold
that can do this stuff.
Like, I don't know
what it is, but I do
think that society will
not function if there
isn't chain of evidence,
probably some kind
of distributed ledger
and some kind of
very strong regulation.
Now, I want to leave
you with one scary
thought, which is that
when a crime is easy
to commit and has
widespread consequences,
the punishment is always
incredibly strong.
horse thievery in the
old west was punishable
by death because
it was super easy to
take someone's horse
but you left the person
to die in the in the
desert right and so
stealing a horse was
punishable by death
because they had to make
the punishment so
draconian people would
not take it um when
people um used to shave
coins if you're
familiar with coins they
used not to have these
ridges on the side
right and isaac newton
figured out how to
ridge them people would
shave a little bit
of gold off, not enough
to be noticed, and
the currency of the
realm will diminish. So
coin shaving was
punishable by death because
it was easy to do and
hard to prosecute.
I suspect we are going
to see certain things
that are easy to do
and hard to prosecute
around AI having
incredibly draconian
punishments, outlandishly
unbalanced, asymmetric
punishments because
of that potential.
All right, guys, we're
almost out of time
here. I got to jump,
but this is one of my
favorite uh episodes
yet i think i really
appreciate alistair
and chris and everett
and rob and everyone
vlad everyone that
that's that's uh
sandy's your we this
community is amazing
and i really appreciate
that everything that
you guys bring to to
this um just a quick
note you know we've
got the agentics
foundation and uh the the
crew always tells me
i need to promote it
more we we are a bunch
of volunteers that
come together for a
shared passion for
making agentic
engineering a thing. It's
becoming a thing. We
see other companies, big
and small, adopting
the terminology all of
a sudden. So we're
in the midst of that.
We've got a number
of events coming
up. I think Ocean,
you mentioned
you're, I'm not sure
if you're still on
the call or not,
but him, the crew,
****** V and the
crew in New York
are going to be
doing it on the
10th for anyone
that's in New York.
I think we've got
Indianapolis coming up as
well for those in the
middle there who want
to help out and if you
if you're interested
in doing an agentix
meetup we we're happy
to help um basically
putting this on luma
and you get 100 people
showing up these
days so really easy to
do we've got materials
for you we can get
you a t-shirt we get
some shirts come in um
rob have i forgotten
anything probably yeah
just um if uh if in
your city you want to
start what up go to
egenics.org slash
ambassador fill out that
form that kicks off
the process and then um
we got a new website
coming brad's been
working yeah so we
we're going to be fixing
all that all up i know
you those are paying
what am i getting
i don't know you're
helping us keep this
thing up the lights on
right now but we're
going to be better
organized it's again
we none of us are be
paid to do this we're
all volunteers and we
can actually use a
volunteer coordinator
very quick question uh
do you have somebody
in boston because last
week i am discovered
there is a alternative
group it was like
200 people meeting and
they're kind of doing
very similar with what
we're doing but there
can be only one
yeah do you have any
ambassador in boston
like or should i not yet
yes not yet no okay i
know that we have some
folks that'd be great
yeah we have a number
of uh yeah we have
lots of people there
we we need someone
that's willing to sort of
take on the responsibility
of saying let's
do this thing next
tuesday you're right so
are you in boston blind
yeah i'm in boston
yeah and i just
discovered the group like
it was very similar and
actually they charged
20 bucks like to attend
and there was 200
people i don't want
to charge i don't know
guys i don't charge
they just charge they
get better food like
in the beer so that's
right maybe we can maybe
we get a sponsor to
pay for the pizza or
something but i i don't
know about charging
i that's that's a
that's a different thing
that i don't i don't
want to go down that
road but um if but if
you're willing to
volunteer to help organize
in boston we could we
should totally do it
there's so much going
on there yeah yeah i
can all right nope if
you're in chicago ping
me um and maybe we
should be setting up
coordination over
there i'm not sure if
there's somebody else
already that's out there
not chicago ever would
that be great yeah
let's talk all right
guys i gotta jump i'm
gonna be late all right
thanks for everyone
this this has been
an amazing episode uh
alistair i love your
insights you're you're
such an interesting guy i
really really appreciate
it thanks for
having me this was i
really enjoyed this this
is awesome all right
Thanks, Al.
Nice meeting you. Next
week, 4th of July.
There's no AI
Hackerspace next
week. So I might
do Thursday, the
live coding
session, because I'm
probably going to
be coding anyway.
But there won't be
a Hackerspace. And
so anyone that's
interested in having
something to present
or you want to
show, get in touch
with Rob, and we'll
get you on and
get your segment.
You can show off
what you're building.
All right.
Till next time.
Thanks, everyone.
Bye-bye.
Thank you. Sure.