two,
one.
And here we are, AI
Hackerspace, June 20th.
What a week. I guess
it's not a great week
if you're into security,
but what a week
what we're having.
And yet again, a
spectacular week in AI.
Every week is crazier
than the last, at
least for me it is.
So we've got a great
show lined up today.
Rob, who do we
got? Yeah, yeah,
a bunch of
stuff going on.
We've got the Paris
event now is on the
map officially for
monday the 23rd and uh
kelsey cole vincent and
emad are putting that
together that should
be a lot of fun um
for the we've got the
new york city crew
that are planning out
the first event they're
going to be joining
us today they got a
couple tools to share
or a tool to share as
well and then we'll
get a recap from mondweep
and bensa they've
got a heck of a week
in London with that
panel on sustainable
AI development at
Greenwich University
and then their hackathon
which has been running
since Wednesday so
we'll get an update
from them then as well
we've had a lot of
help the last few weeks
from our long-time
member Dimple she's a
data and AI engineer out
of Edinburgh Scotland
she's been helping
with getting everything
together for the
guests. And I think we
have Miko as well. Is
that right, Dimple?
Yeah, Rob. So thank
you. We have Miko. He's
a longtime member
as well. And he has
founded seven tech
startups with three exits.
And he has a new
startup. And the
mission is to build
the infrastructure
of the Nordic welfare
state with AI.
So yeah, over
to you, Rob.
right wonderful that's
great i'm really looking
forward to hearing
how that uh about this
project um miko we're
going to start that
the lightning talks
probably around 12 20
something along those
lines but it's really
clear that finland gets
it and they're working
on some fascinating
stuff to to sincerely
prepare for the imminent
arrival of agi so that
will be fascinating
so that's the lineup
today roof all right so
it sounds sounds like
we got a great show
line so some of the
originals i'll we'll try
to get everyone in um
this week for me has
been particularly
interesting around swarm
based development so i
i've got a bit of a uh
i don't know obsession
might be the right
word with with you know
applying sort of swarms
to various things and
i so i'm learning a
lot about the sort of
application of the
these kind of complex
swarms to various types of
development and securing
and deploying and
all kinds of things.
But there's a few
takeaways that I want to
discuss, you know, first
and foremost. And it
starts with this exploit,
which we don't know
a lot about. And
there's been a massive
password breach from
the biggest providers of
OA. And the reason
this is kind
of worrisome is,
you know, if you've
ever logged
into any website
using Google or
Facebook or Apple,
that means you're
trusting these providers
to secure your
authentication information,
right? So then that's
why you can log in
with one click with
your Apple or Google.
And it would seem that
16 billion passwords,
which is double the
population of the
planet, basically, in
terms of passwords, was
leaked relatively
recently, apparently
last month. we're just
finding about it now
well what's interesting
about this and i
have this is all
anecdotal by the way i've
got no proof of who or
what or how so i can
only sort of uh you
know surmise what that
potentially could be
but what's interesting
is the fact that it's
never been easier
to hack right and this
idea mostly uh has
been around concepts
of like kitty scripters
right get get these
various tools like
nets you know metasploit
and other kind of
tools and and then sort
of click a few things
in your keyboard and
see what happens.
That's been the
traditional approach.
But now what we're
seeing is we can kind
of take that and we
can amp that up using
these agentic tools
that we use these
kind of kitty scripting
tools, but can
also like sort of
adaptively look and
discover. So what's
my sense, and I have
no proof of this,
but my sense is this
exploit is likely one
of the first major,
probably is extensively
using AI as a kind
of core orchestration
of the exploit itself.
I have no proof of
this. This is just me
guessing, but it seems
that given the timing,
given the things that
I'm seeing in the
space, it's, it's pretty
likely that somewhere,
some group of bad guys
were probably using,
you know, a lot of the
same tools that we're
using to build and
create crazy things
for the opposite reasons,
right? So what But
we're experiencing
what's probably a sort of
first step and will
likely be a really
interesting few years
to come. And just as a
note, yesterday, actually,
I was looking at one
of my projects for a
client, and they're
basically giving me
a hard time. Is this
secure? Is this actually
doing what you're saying
it's doing? And so
I'm like, OK, so I
pointed the swarm at it
and said, look at this
API endpoint, which
is actually in the
development environment.
Now, it wasn't even
live. And then I let it
run for a while. I went
off and start talking
about other things.
And then, you know, 10
minutes later, I came
back to this swarm that
was basically looking
at the development
environment and trying
to determine whether
this thing that we
had built was secure.
and one of the parts of
the swarm had actually
decided without me
telling it to go and
explore the sort of you
know the sort of rabbit
hole where that api
led to and it led to
the production site
and then as part of
that process it actually
mapped the entire
production environment that
they had set up and
found all their exploits
and it actually gone
in and took advantage
of all those exploits
without me asking
it and what's interesting
when you look at
these tools and you
And if you were to say,
go exploit ABC site,
it's going to say, no,
sorry, I can't do that,
right, HAL 2000 or
whatever. But the virtue
of the fact that I
started with a sort of
development environment,
and I said this is
an ethical sort of
pen testing structure,
it seems to have, like,
given it the sort of
okay to go and do all
kinds of bad things.
So basically, it's a
semantic description
or a sort of guide that
allowed it to say,
okay, I can move beyond
my own sort of
limitations and things I'm
not allowed to do, which
is crazy and scary.
Needless to say, I
think I might have
ruined their weekend
by showing them a
whole variety of
exploits. And this was in
a highly regulated
space, just to add
the cherry on top,
which got me thinking,
it's a brave new world,
to say the least.
Let me show you a few
things here that I'm
working on for those who
haven't been up to the
latest and greatest.
So, last week, I created
this. Oh, let me
share my screen quick.
I created an abstraction
layer, essentially,
to Cloud Code. I
called it Cloud Flow.
Notice I'm version 72.
That's because I
wasn't paying attention
at one point, and it did
20 freaking versions.
where I decided
to publish each
incremental change as a
version update to NPM,
that's another side
effect of these
swarms is because
I'm spotting,
in this case,
sometimes 50 concurrent
agents to do
things all at once,
you've got this sort
of different... It's
hard to guide it. Well,
not hard to guide it.
Sometimes it's hard
to see what's actually
happening within the
structure of each one
of the swarm elements.
When I'm doing concurrent
development like
RueCode or Cursor and
those types of sort of
sequential development,
I'm able to see generally
what's happening
because it's doing
this, then it's moving
to the next thing.
Maybe it's spawning a
subtask, but I've got
the ability to really
understand kind of
what's happening because
it's sequential or at
least it's a single thread.
Where when I start
implementing these
swarms, there's the, you
know, especially when
I do large swarms,
like this idea of a 50
-agent swarm, it's hard
to know that, you know,
agent number 33 has
decided to go rogue.
So, the one thing
that I've learned,
I think, this week
is certain tasks
are better suited
for this type of
environment. So,
early development or
complex, so complex
development is
actually really good,
too. For example,
earlier this week,
a storage company
hired me for literally
an hour because I
do a lot of these
kind of hour projects.
And they're like, we
have this old school
storage system was
literally built in PHP,
which was interesting.
And as you guys
probably know, I'm
not a huge fan of PHP,
nothing against
Drupal. They still hate
me for porting it
to JavaScript. But
nonetheless, I pointed
that system at legacy
code. We're talking
probably around
50,000 lines of code,
so a decent amount
of code and
significant amounts of
technical depth. And
I pointed and said,
basically, rebuild
this for me using Rust.
And their latency in
PHP was high. Obviously,
it's PHP. It's not
great. So they were
looking around 300
milliseconds for a request.
And I managed to
get that down within
an hour to less than
two milliseconds using
a Rust-based full
implementation of their
legacy system, which
basically means that it
would use the same
API and SDK sort of
structure. So anyone
that had previously
deployed it would just
kind of magically work.
That literally took
an hour. So I started
looking at, like,
what kind of output
can I do in this
timeframe? And then I
discovered a tool
that allows me to sort
of measure some
of this stuff. so
there's a tool that
i found earlier that
that allows me to sort
of look at my clod
token monitor and
which is interesting
and it tells me
things like burn rates
this this it always
says tokens exceeded max
limit i i obviously
am not exceeding the
limit so ignore that
but what's interesting
is i think this is
pretty accurate in terms
of of you know what i'm
doing so in this case
i did uh 272 000 tokens
and three this is
a little project i
was working on earlier
basically it was a uh
trading system that i
was i was building but
it was i i was i was
curious about sort of
how it was uh you know
working let me get
some uh quickly clacks
here i'm just kidding
you guys all right sorry
i'm muting everyone all
right so um so what's
interesting is is i i
did some benchmarking
to sort of see like
what's the most i can
possibly crank out in
in the run of an hour
so i i was comfortably
i'm able to comfortably
do around 500,000
lines of code in an
hour. And then I say
500,000 lines of code,
500,000 lines of
usable code, not just
garbage spaghetti
that doesn't work, but
usable functional code
that passes tests.
That is an incredible
amount of information.
I mean, you think
about 500,000 lines.
Let's put that in
the context for a
moment. According to
developer guides and
stuff, and regardless,
list, they're
saying that the average
developer puts up
somewhere between 20
lines of code a day
as a professional
developer. So let's crank
it up. Let's say that
now with Copilot,
you're doing 50 or
100 lines of code.
That means 500,000, I
don't even know what
the exact number is,
but it's orders of
magnitude more than
the typical developer
could do in a day
we're doing in an hour.
This is like, in some
ways, probably 10
years of work that
we're cranking out in
an hour and using
form-based approaches.
And this is all
for 200 bucks.
Now, a couple of
things to note.
For those that are
interested, I'm just
going to do a quick
crash course again for
those that don't want
to know. So there's
the, you have to,
to get it installed,
what, there's a
repo I created. Let
me just jump to that
repo quick. Oops,
it's going to let
me do that. Yeah.
So Cloud Code Flow,
I created Cloud Test.
Cloud Test, this gives
you the quick sort
of step-by-step step
on what you need to do
so this is just a
little repo i set up to
to test my my stuff
when i start so you've
got to install the
cloud code now there's
an important part of
the process that people
seem to get stuck on
when they're using
this for the first
time and that is the
dangerously allow um
i've already run this so
i'm not you're not going
to be able to see it
but there's a command
before you run cloud
code you need to go
in here and run the
help command so you've
already installed it
and you're going to
help you need to go here
and run the dangerously
allow if you don't
do that you're going
to get an error and
i just i probably can
figure out a way to
get to to make that
error not happen but
basically it's it's
basically not allowing you
to run dangerously
mode until you sort of
there's this like ui
interface that says
are you sure you want
to run dangerously allow
well obviously i'm
sure i'm putting in
the freaking tag here
but anyway it It asks
you again, and if you
don't do this right
off the start, so Claude
dangerously allow.
And the other thing
you want to do, if you
ever are running a
swarm and you go to bed
and it stops at two o
'clock in the morning
or whatever, and you
want to resume where it
left off, you can also
add the dash C, and
that allows you to
continue where you left
off. So it basically
invokes the previous
session. So this is
a particularly useful
component. you can see
here that it's continuing
it says here that
i've i had an api
error i need to to
implement so let's let's go
ahead and let's do
that so now i have i've
got i see that there's
it's it's created
my test infrastructure
it's created a new
collection it's testing
it's doing my market
information and it's
doing integration so
this is a um a trading
algorithm i won't go
into details because
you know i probably
shouldn't be showing this
but anyway what we're
going to go here and
i'm going to quickly
create a swarm create
a five agent swarm
and by the way i can
also do this by and oops
let's i can do slash
you can see that i've
got different options
i've added here but
i'm i'm not going to
bother with those right
now because i'm just
going to do something
And we create a five
-agent swarm using
batch tool. Now, the
other interesting thing,
so the way I
can create these
agents is using
batch tool.
All references to
batch tool have been
removed from the cloud
code documentation.
I looked yesterday,
I couldn't find it
anywhere. So I'm hoping
they don't remove it
completely from the
tool because that would
suck because I'm
really enjoying these
swarms. But the batch
tool feature is the
secret sauce to making
these swarms work.
Basically, it allows
you to create multiple
instances and have
them run in parallel.
So if you want
to invoke a
swarm, really all
you need to do
is tell it to
use batch tool.
Now, in this case,
I'm saying create a
five-agent swarm using
batch tool to fix,
and I'm just going
to grab this here,
fix this. All right.
Hey,
on that, Ruben, And
on that, I did a bunch
of testing yesterday
and yeah, all the
documentation is definitely
gone. I couldn't find
it like you, but I
tested Claude Code and
it's still in the, the
tool's still there.
You can't see it, but you
can actually
reference it.
Yeah.
So that's exactly
what I'm, like,
it's exactly what
I'm doing right now.
So, so now you see
here, it says swarming.
I love that.
And so, and I've got my
thinking mode enabled.
The thinking mode
I've set to 20,000
tokens. that seems to
be about right and it
allows it to ponder a
little longer it works
really well you can
you can also tell it
to think harder or do
like ultra thinking
and it thinks forever
depending on what the
problem you're trying
to solve you might want
to get it to ponder a
little longer i like
that that sounds like
a poem but the the
key when you want to
ponder longer you might
use it for certain
things like algorithms
you might want to
design or or solving
really hard problems
now you see the reason i
know it's working you
can see each of these
tasks is being spawned
independently now
if all's well we we
should see five uh five
units whoa i'm not sure
where that came from
but um so now we've
got one two three four
five and i'm not sure
what the blue thing
on my screen i'm seeing
is but uh hey chris
wait how's it going
good welcome back um
All right, so now
when you spawn large
swarms, you're going
to see this. And this
happens because I've
continued a previous
setup, and it's going
to flicker for a
bit. This generally goes
away, and it doesn't
mean it's not
working. It's a little
aggravating, and this
is back to the thing
I was telling you
about where you can't
actually see what's
happening particularly
well. Now, I've got
a status mode here.
I'm going to jump through
this one for a sec.
um any idea how
i clean that blue
thing off my screen
this is a first
my chris voice put it on
there chris are
you guys that
i i am either the
ones to see that
no no no it's okay
yeah we all anyway it's
okay well didn't know
the blue line i'm not
sure what that is but
anyway there's also a
so to to give a little
bit of introspection
what i've done is I'm
still working on this
is a work in progress
for anyone and you
cloud flow and you can
do help and in this
case we can if we we
see how we get different
options we've got the
ability to look at you
know various statuses
so we can go to the
memory memory and
then we we can see the
various queries we can
we can do lists and this
gift this will help
you sort of get an idea
of what's happening
i've also got this for
agents and tags and
types so in this case
oh i didn't do memory
let's do let's go back
let's do memory memory
so this is showing
all the different
things so what i'm and
this and my memory
system is is actually the
most rudimentary memory
system i could possibly
invent there's no
vectors there's no well
i've got an option for
sqlite but generally
it's just it's just
json and of all the
things i tried the json
structure was actually
the best it worked
it was simple it was
easy it allowed it
allows the system to sort
of understand what
what's happening oh it
looks like i my swarm
crashed my instance let's
go back here and see
what's happening and
all right do you
have the orchestrator
running in one of the
terminals yes it's running
right here so this is
you can see it running
this is the system
the the system invokes
the orchestrator itself
as part so the so
clod code invokes the
orchestrator and the
memory so you don't go
clod clod flow start
yeah okay got it yeah
exactly exactly and i
guess i i apologize
guys i have no idea how
to get rid of this
blue line which is is a
little strange um all
right guys ruben uh
yeah in your cloud test
repository you laid
out the four steps right
just so that all of
us understand i think
there's a bit of
variance here so first
step is cloud code install
which we understand
obviously cloud flow
your reinstall but in
order to get started
did you you said you have
to invoke a dangerously
dangerous permissions
do you do that
from cloud code for
quote yes i do and and i
think what i'm going
to do i'm going to i'm
going to just update
this quickly so errol
let's let's do it real
time it's just a command
line option it's just
a command yeah it's
a command line option
right so here so the
problem is run
cloud flow start the
orchestrator so what i
need to do is i need to add
another step step four
we'll make oops step
four and what this
what we need to do here
is we need to do clog
and then we need to
do uh what i think i
have this in my memory
so let's grab that game
run dangerously this
one yeah and and then
i then what you need
to do is you need to
accept the UI warning
message, then you can
run the orchestrator.
And again, the problem
I'm running into
is I'm like kind of
working between both.
So it's a little bit,
sometimes I skip a
step here or there.
Oh, I don't like the
way that looks. I'm
going to fix that too.
Let's add some
brackets around that.
And once you start
orchestrator,
does it invoke
Spark under the hood
anyway, basically the
Spark methodology?
Yes. That's step
number five.
Yeah.
And the other thing
that I've been working,
and the other thing
we can do here, which
is kind of cool, and
I'll push this out
sometime this weekend or
maybe early next week.
I've also integrated
the MCP feature. so we
can go in here and now
we've got clod flow
mcp if you want to
integrate it with like
cursor or whatever and
so you can invoke the
different get cursor
to do it for you and
the other interesting
feature is you can use
the clod code system
as the mcp itself as
well which is kind of
a fun little way to
interact with it and
if you're interested in
doing that all you need
to do is do clod mcp
serve and then you
can do ports and stuff
like that but if you
do i think by default
i think it runs in
studio and then you
do that and now you're
running the clod
mcp server mcp server
which you get clod
code to use clod
code mcp directly in
itself which is kind
of cool and uh to see
that i'm running i'm
doing some work here
on the mcp but i'm
gonna show you that
quick so in clod i'm
not i'm not running
with dangerous at the
moment but i'm just
going to show you
what that looks like.
It's kind of like
a recursive system.
All right, so now
we're here. Now
when you have
MCPs, you can go
here and you can
do MCP, and then
you can see you
have a Cloudflow.
I haven't published
this yet, so you'll have
to use my dev version,
but in this case,
I'm going here. Then I
can view tools. I can
see all my different
modes, and each of
these modes can then be
invoked directly within
the sort of swarm
itself so you can do
swarm it's like i don't
know what i call it
like subtasks within
the swarm it's kind of
and so the so the
additional the addition of
mcps within the swarm
really kicks up the
the capabilities and
and back to my original
comment about you know
hacking and exploitation
that is the part
that's most worrisome
Because you can
create the swarm that
invokes various CLIs and
MCPs, and then you've
got the sort of –
you're the master of the
universe at that point.
It can do anything,
anywhere. Hey, on that,
Ruben, so you only
run one instance of
Claude code as an MCP?
No, I run it – each
instance uses its
own MCP. It's magic.
I'm not sure how
exactly it figures
out, but it just works.
Does that option runs
CloudCode as
an MCP server?
Yeah, it runs
CloudCode as an
– oh, here's
interesting. My
swarm just crashed
my instance.
So this happens.
Oh, it looks like it
finished anyway. But
here, this is how
you recover from a
crashed instance, if
you guys are running
too many VS codes.
Yeah, so this is going
to happen. And this
is probably a byproduct
of the fact that I'm
trying, this is a
trading algorithm I'm
building, which is
probably just putting a lot
of CPU stress on it.
I probably need to
switch at this point
from a swarm based
implementation to a
sequential implementation. So
there's two issues I
have. I'm probably just
using a code space that
doesn't have enough
RAM, most likely.
But when this does
happen, I'll show you
exactly how to recover
from it. So it's not
a big deal. And I'm to
add better recovery
tools as well here but i
got too much stuff
on my plate all right
hopefully it comes back
to life here in a sec
because this this is
uh here we go okay all
right give it one more
second there's a as
i said the dash c
command is the part that
essentially allows you
to recover so you're
going to do clod dash
c and then i'm going
to grab that dangerously
overly complicated
command. And then I'm
just going to do that.
And that allows you
to recover. There's
also a session ID that
I might start using
as part of the
memory. I haven't
actually included that
in my memory. That
allows you to have
multiple sessions and
remember. So if you're
running multiple
terminals, you can do
that. All right. So
that looks like it
actually didn't quite
finish. So I'll just
type in continue.
And it'll continue
where it left left
off nice room quick
question for you
and i've noticed you
know you kind of go
for fives like fives
five or 50 like
like how do you decide
on how many agents
or how yeah how
many like how many
unique agents you want
to have going in a
swarm like i put in five
and seen what happened
like yeah i did of
course of course i
did of course i know
yeah it crashed badly um
it got to it got to
about 150 and everything
sort of stopped. But
so it did attempt.
I think I know how to
do 5,000. I would have
to have multiple
$200, you know, Claude
Max accounts. And then
what I would do is use
Tmux, whatever, how
do you pronounce that?
And then I'd create
multiple instances,
probably a VS Code Swarm.
If you guys remember
that VS Code Swarm
system I built a couple
months ago and then
i'd have multiple vs
code instances or multiple
terminals or multiple
containers running and
then i'd orchestrate
all of them i totally
want to do like
the guinness book of
world records for swarms
yeah no i i don't want
to i don't want to
i don't want to spend
like two hundred
dollars times five or
whatever or times a hundred
but yeah it's totally
it's totally doable
the other thing and
all of them building
guardrails well they're
going to be taking
over the web. The
other thing you should
note, the reason I did
five and not 10 or 20,
five seems like all my
tests, it's the optimal
amount of agents that
balances not maxing
out my account so
I can actually have
multiple projects running
concurrently. So this
trading system I was
showing you and other
projects I'm working
on. And I also saw, I
saw a little improvement
going beyond five,
like in certain things,
like if I was doing
like a GPU cluster or
something, having 20
concurrent agents
orchestrating like my
hugging face in a
cluster probably would be
okay but for most things
i saw zero improvement
using 10 versus using
five so i'm like
all right i'm i'm gonna
make five the default
because most people
have no idea and i
just make it easy for
you that was my entire
entire thing how do
you measure improvement
you say so is it just
subjective or you have
some kind the metric
i've met i get
benchmarks so i was it
last month i can't remember
but i i integrated
the swe bench tool
that basically is a
tool that allows you to
measure the performance
of the software
engineering agents and
then i then i used the
swarm against that
agent and i by the way i
got 100 on that swe
bench i didn't fail once
so it's and and then
what i did is i said
how many of these can
i do concurrently and
then i just kicked it
up a notch you know
and i started doing 50
or whatever and then
i tried to do like 5
000 and it's funny you
know alex's point i
do seem to like fives
but um yeah and the
other interesting thing
100 100 completion
on swe bench it never
failed once nice i'm
gonna take us to the
speaker component their
guest component roof
um let me see if
that's uh if that's
good that's good
let's go all right all
right so uh first
off we got ******
****** v3 and the
new york city crew
are with us hey ******
hey jad hey guys
you're on mute there
hey what's up
everybody can you see
us all in the
awesome room that
Zohar provided us
with at Kaltura.
There we go.
Wood paneling.
This is Andy
Warhol's original
workshop.
Wow.
Right?
So we're here
making some art.
All right?
So a couple of
weeks ago. Oh, guys,
this is the first time
we've all gathered
in person, too.
This is our first
planning meeting.
If we can get
a little hurrah.
I know we're all
developers and
introverted and stuff but
gotta get one of these
uh posters yeah yeah
right so so we're pretty
excited here we're
gonna get together
and plan our first
event and uh hopefully
get some some good
turnout here in new york
so um so that's that
for my demo guys a
couple of weeks ago uh
you all saw me share
a um prototype really
a terminal-based
application that was uh
you know hooked up
and running and you
know writing midi code
and running it through
like these like old
like files and stuff
like sf2 files and
like pretty cool stuff
um but i did a little
bit more exploring
and i found this library
called sonic pi um
and there's a whole
bunch of other libraries
too um but some
people told me about
sonic i forget how i
heard about it but um
anyway so i landed on
sonic pi and it ended
up being really cool
so i uh made this
awesome little app that
you have to download
sonic piper so if
anybody's gone on sonic
pi composer.com and
tried to use it it
doesn't work you only
have to run i just
made that website
because i was like having
fun and i tried to
reach out to the guy
but he never responded
so whatever um i
hope he's a cool guy
if anybody knows him
you should hook me
up sam or something
like that um so anyways
let's uh hear the
first thing i hope
i'm sharing sound oh
i'm probably not hold
on um let's do this
Yeah, can we
hit this one?
Because I'm going to
have to play audio.
That works.
Well,
it's either echo or
nothing, I guess.
you know we
you know i love
feedback loops right yeah
and you can share
with audio i think
in in zoom and by
the way we're looking
to move away from
zoom probably next
month or so to
some other river
riverside or something
like that yeah that
should be great
robert you're not
in a car that's
great to see you
know home base
oh did we lose the
audio i i kind of like
watching these guys
moving the camera around
yeah there was a
friend of mine attended
a lecture at uh you
know online at uh
berkeley and uh in the
first hour of the three
-hour event was a
fellow staring into his
laptop trying to fix
the audio like infamous
that's art yeah yeah
it's like in our
events in london we
have never managed to a
second event i think
we've got lucky this
time we got a recording
but we never seem to
get the sound right
on our live casting
yeah yeah you know you
know a little background
you know guy beaver
who's on this call
he and i we used to
work at the citrix uh
R&D Lab to do video
conferencing for
their various web
conferencing technologies
and we spent many a
day trying to figure
out that problem
but we never solved
it but it was fun
to be in the R&D Lab
Is this looking
like this one's
going to go here
William? We can
come back too
****** after the
it's it's the demo gods
which greek
god is the god
of demos i i
don't even know
it's probably demolus
yeah demolus it'll
be low key the god
of mischief yeah
i i was going for
like rome or roman
or greek but uh
norse also works yeah
yeah all righty guys
well we'll come back
at the end at the
open open session
will it be three we're
looking forward to
to hearing the music
once you're once
you're good to go um
let me see so oh we got
a quick update from
uh mondweep and bents
they had an uh just
a wonderful week
out in london uh rocky
um isaac uh chris
poulter mark d um that
uh an event there at
Greenwich University,
an important panel,
and then their
hackathon, too. So I'd
love to hear the
update, Manduit, Benson.
Yeah, sure. We
basically had,
we were invited
to an event
that was going
on for the week.
On Wednesday, we kind
of had a small panel,
mainly our group,
basically, with Rodrigo,
who was organizing
it, and some of the
members from the
university. So it's a
general discussion,
more like introduction
about our experiences,
how we got involved in
Agentix and the general
potential of it.
Then we opened
up a hackathon,
which we had
prepared for.
There were focused
participation, I think
not as much as we'd
have hoped for. I think
it was a different
stage and event compared
to the previous one,
which was at Google.
and today we kind of
again had a much more
closed view where we
had some demos back
from some of the couple
of the participants
about work they had
attempted using the
frameworks and then we
did a workshop of broadly
very basic uh starting
with basic of spark
original spark to
like bits of the swarm
architecture um we
we also were not the
demo gods went very
favorable to us because
we did it remote today
but that is a summary
but Benz please add if
I have missed anything
please yeah the learning
is that we don't
we shouldn't use
Microsoft Teams on live
stream events because
it carries the GPU
completely but yeah it
was great and people
telling us you know
the demand for learning
and agentics is
incredible there was a
A friend of mine from
New York even was
connecting live the live
stream and she didn't
know that agent exists
and now she's planning
to join every Friday.
So even if it's
local, then it can have
an effect globally.
And we intend to
actually follow through
in the post-event
setup. So we would be
following through with
the university faculty
to see what we can
actually do tangibly
based on this experience.
So that is the
main thing that we are
actually aiming for.
Thank you.
There's several other
universities that are
interested in
collaborating, European
universities that are
interested in collaborating
with you. I'm going
to introduce you to.
I had a call this
morning. I'm not sure if
he's on this call
or not, but with a
university out of Heidelberg,
Germany, and they're
looking to do something
to collaborate.
So I told them
about you and some
of the folks like
Vincent in France.
lots of collaboration
opportunities
please do dangerous
thanks cool
it's i always find
funny just uh that you
know people haven't
haven't heard of
agentics yet maybe
because i i spend my days
doing nothing but
talking about it but
it's we're we're in
early early days like
it's it's it's it's
barely a thing um
it's it's a thing to
us i guess but it's
99% of the world has
never heard of it.
Incredible.
And when is the next
London event,
do you think?
We are planning
one in July.
Yeah, amazing.
Monvick, you have a info?
Yeah, I mean, we may have
we don't know the
dates, but there is
another one. This one
is more firm that Ben
was talking about,
but we are planning
one with LBS probably
late July or August.
there's one yeah
because the shashi
uh wanted to join
the agent dc has
a london ai meetup
group with 150
people and he's keen
on to merge with
us let's do it
wonderful let's do it
fantastic chat here
just just uh since
we're on the topic um
if you are looking to
host an event in your
city, you can sign
up to be an ambassador
on agentics.org
slash ambassador. So
I just put the link in
the chat. You might
have to scroll up a
tiny bit there. So
if you think that you
or somebody you might
know wants to host an
event, we're here to
help support that.
You can message me
directly too on Discord,
but we have events
popping up all over
the world and just
want to make sure you
all have that link.
So you do have to
become an ambassador
in order to kind of get
the the support that
we have here as an
organization so sign
up there and we will
process you and make
sure that you have
everything all right
amazing and remind us
how do you become an
ambassador so that yeah
alex um i'll just
speak to that quick so
that process you
fill out the form and
then uh we'll have a
chance to uh meet we'll
get on a zoom call
get a sense of your
background you know
if you if you've done
any event management
before what your thoughts
are and then everything
looks like it's
in sync you hold your
first event and if
that all goes well
everybody's thrilled
and happy then uh
then there's a chapter
formation and then um
yeah and then it's off
and running so that's
sort of the process
perfect appreciate
that uh vincent you've
got a paris event on
monday it was the last
second thing kelsey's
in town anything you
want to say about
paris uh the keyword is
uh agility because we
we learned yesterday
that the event was on
monday and luckily we
have a very nice host
uh it's a guy who is
famous for organizing
a very large event in
corsica the rock festival
he has a nightclub
he has a rooftop
rooftop uh space in in
the heart of paris so
depending on how many
people join because
it's last minute we may
go for the the rooftop
25 otherwise it's
going to be up to 200
people uh and i'm also
activating my network
there so let's see
but uh it's going to
be a mix it's not going
to be uh coding it's
going to be kelsey uh
doing some form of a
keynote on what she
did with ai so far and
her job with coke coca
-cola she's the mastermind
between uh behind
the the coke campaigns
you know and i'm
gonna do uh i'm gonna
uh i'm gonna show i'm
gonna to build stuff.
I'm going to have
about 20 minutes, 30
minutes, and I'm going to
kind of reverse
engineer, you know, what
they see and how this
happens, right? So a
little bit like a light
touch roof session.
And then we have
champagne, of
course, because
it's Paris, right?
In the summer. Yeah.
That's the idea.
And last update before
we do a next little
presentation here. On
Tuesday in Toronto,
it's Toronto Tech
Week. We've got 300 and
something people signed
up and i think we
only have space for 60
so we'll see how that
goes um and so that
that's gonna if you're
in toronto and you
just ping me or rob or
brad or anyone in in
toronto and we'll make
sure that you you get
you're in just show
up early and help us
set up um but it's
going to be it's going
to be crazy so that's
on tuesday i think 5
30 that's right 5 30
to 8 30 and rube i
think there's like 128
people on the waiting
list plus the 200 cops
so that's that 338
you're talking about
it's growing by the
hour. So yeah, it's going
to be a, it's going
to be a lot of fun.
And this is John
Messing. I just
want to let you
know for Vincent,
my son who lives
in Paris and a
fellow colleague
are going to
show up for the
event on Monday.
Excellent. That's three
of us now. Perfect.
Bring it more,
bring more.
And, and John,
welcome. I know you're,
you're, you're,
you're our old school
sort of programmer
and love that you're
joining us. Thanks
for coming on today.
All right.
Rob,
who's next?
So next, we've got
Miko Alessarela, and
I'm really excited
to hear about these
projects. So Miko's,
this startup is with
the previous CIO of
Finland's government
infrastructure, and
they're working to
prepare the nation for
the arrival of AGI.
You know, Finland
seems to get it.
They seem to get
everything right.
So I'm really looking
forward to it.
Miko, thank you.
Thank you for sharing.
Yeah. Can you see
my presentation?
Yep.
Can we see Slack
or something?
Are you presenting
your WhatsApp?
WhatsApp, yeah.
Oh, I'm sharing
the wrong screen.
Let me try to find the
right one from here.
So, you
now see the right one?
That'll build an AI
native public sector.
Okay, cool.
Okay, let me
do this quick.
So, yeah, so this
company is basically
technically started
at the beginning of
this month, but it
went to the register in
Finland in April, and
then we got all the
paperwork and
everything ready in May.
So, I'll tell the
story on what we do.
So this starts
from my history. Of
course, I have almost
20 years in AI,
having founded
companies in Silicon
Valley in Berlin,
Germany, and
also here in Finland
over the years.
So I got concerned
about this lack
of understanding
in public sector
on this massive
transition to AGI.
It will probably
change everything in
terms of how
governments are funded,
how things are run
in societies. and now
that we basically,
I mean of course
our group here
understands that this HGI
is imminent but the
general population
is still like a
myth so I show these
government, how to say
leaders in the
country that
this HGI will
change everything
and in order for
us to be able
to preserve our
welfare society
which basically has
yielded the happiest
nation on earth for 8
years in a row So we will
have to jump onto this
bandwagon and implement
everything to be
ready for this change.
So I'll explain
to them that AI
is already able
to do everything.
It's able to use tools.
It's able to memorize
everything. And the
only thing missing
from it to be generally
capable of doing
almost anything that
we can imagine is that
it doesn't yet have
a world model, which
probably will emerge
over the next 18 months.
And this has caused
the internet to
basically be filled
with AI content.
It was 57% at the
beginning of last
year already. It's
now probably available
over 70% or maybe
80%. It's going
to be 90% by the
beginning of 2026.
It also means
that the bot
traffic on the
internet has
surpassed human
traffic last year.
In Western Europe,
it's currently
over 70%,
according to stats.
Majority of this traffic,
unfortunately,
is malicious.
So we literally have
a bot fest going
on in the internet
on a daily basis.
And now these
are the two most
important slides
of my presentation.
So in today's world,
like most people still
don't use AI to perform
their daily work.
They only occasionally
use it for some tasks.
And majority of those
who are using AI
are using it as a
tool, which means that
they can achieve some
kind of incremental
improvement to
their productivity.
There's a small
group of partners
that are able to
more than double
their productivity
with AI agents.
And then there's us who
are basically pushing
the boundaries on
the world scale. And
in order for us to really
compete and in order
for us to really build
a society and any
organization should
be looking like this,
everybody should be at
2x or more productivity
levels. And on the
top end, it should be
the next plus. And if
this shift happens,
I think these companies
and organizations,
whether it be
private or public
sector, will be
able to compete.
And my argument in my
country is also that
if we do this, it's
literally the silver
bullet to make a
massive jump on the
productivity, then turn
it into GDP growth.
And so it's
imperative for
the whole country
to do this.
And in order for you
to achieve this, you
have to understand that
this is not a tool.
Every time people say
that AI is a tool,
I say that you are
looking for incremental
improvements, not
transformative changes.
You have to
understand that
agents can do everything.
And I also tell
the public sector
that they can
actually automate
the whole decision
-making process.
There's an insane
number of different
processes going on in
the government, like
issuing permits,
registering companies.
issuing social
security payments,
doing all kinds
of things that
are currently
done by humans.
And I said that you
can automate it all
with AI because these
things are based on
rules and laws and
regulations. The only
thing you do is that
you start in a step
-by-step plan to go
towards AI-driven
decision-making. And
this could yield like,
for example,
organizations like the
Social Security
Administration to basically
make decisions on
the social security
payments in minutes
rather than in days or
in weeks that they're
currently doing.
So I'm also telling,
this is very important
in Nordics, you
tell that you're
jumping into this AI
band, but it actually
reduces your stress,
it doesn't increase
it because you are
delegating work to
agents to focus on
the important tasks.
And this is an
important message
because people
always see that, hey,
I need to double
my productivity,
I need to triple
my productivity.
It means that I have
no free time, I'm going
to be stressed every
day and so on. So I'm
just telling them the
story that it doesn't
mean for the human
workers any added stress
necessarily. It means
that they're adapting
AI to get all the
stressful tasks done.
And I'm also telling
them if we are
able to basically
get our citizens
into this like
multiplier trajectory
that I showed in
the previous slides,
we will have AI
capable citizens and
AI in the public
sector. We can compete
and we can survive
this. I'm also
having like a lot of
technical stuff that
I don't have time
to go into, like how
we are building
this infrastructure.
But yeah, that's in short
what we are building.
We started at the
beginning of June
with the company.
We already have one
multiple, and this
is the fun part,
definitely fun
for Ruv to hear,
is that we've won
multiple very important
government bids
on building AI
infrastructure for
them through doing this
AI-native transformation
against very
large companies as a
two-person startup.
This is very
important because the
government guys
understood that these guys
who have done over
100 AI projects in
the past combined with
an army of agencies
is probably better
for them than having
1,000 employees in
an organization.
okay mika you gotta
meet my favorite my
favorite fin is a
guy named martin
mikos he's uh oh yeah
i know i know him
very well yeah oh
okay yeah he he you
should talk to him
he'd be all over this
if you don't know him
i can intro yeah you
know you know he knows
me well as well so i
okay yeah i mean i
will definitely have a
discussion now that
you mentioned it like
like if he's working
on this field yeah he's
he's he's really into
this stuff right now
so and he was i think
he was the CEO at
HackerOne. I might still
be there. I don't know.
Yes. Yes. Yeah. I
think he quit as a CEO.
So,
but yeah, he's
another consul of
Finland in the Bay
Area. I actually hanged
out with him
quite a few times
when I was living
in the Bay Area. So,
yeah, really nice guy.
Cool. This is, this
is, so a couple of
comments, you know,
there's inevitably
every agentic
conversation ends with,
you know, AGI, ASI,
or some sort of,
you know, singularity
conversation.
And, you know, the idea
of AGI is this kind
of all knowing, all
encompassing AI that can
solve all problems.
And in my opinion, that
isn't going to happen
from a statically
defined language model
that sort of, you know,
is responsive, right?
And the challenges
that we have is this
perception that a lot of
these models are sort
of you know inherently
smart right and can
do and act and they
none of these things
as we know from agentic
as being agentic
engineers that requires
guidance like whether
it's a swarm you know
operational source
constructs i think that the
the building blocks for
agi will emerge from
the tools like the swarm
components you were
you were seeing
earlier and how we sort
of orchestrate and and
use those in a kind of
feedback you know a
perpetual feedback
probably you know what
what are you thinking what
are you thinking in
regards to like what
AGI even looks like when
when you're describing
this to a government
or an organization
well I mean uh from my
perspective AGI like
how I explain it to
them is uh it's not like
uh explaining like
artificial consciousness
or anything like
this it's a simply uh
saying that AI can do
anything that we can do
and you know and and
that's it like uh be
it like a swarm of
agents or be it like some
kind of like a
combination of tools and
others uh the thing is
that the fact what what
you guys are achieving
already and i'm also
achieving similar
things now uh uh is is
that that it's a
testament of this aga
happening like like
literally uh we can multiply
i mean rube you have
showed like multiple
times like how many
people's work and we can
now do with ai i
mean that's literally
explaining how the ag
is emerging uh so it's
yeah mikko you know
public sector is great
but i think one of the
underserved areas is
the smb sector because
the problem with smb
is they don't have
enough money they don't
they don't like now
i'm helping one of the
smbs but neither none
of the big players
really want to speak
directly to them so they
are true resellers and
others right but they
are the backbone of the
economy to be honest
i think there is a
huge opportunity to
actually engage and
them better to something
seminar I think
yeah so
the funny thing is that
a lot of the problems
for small entrepreneurs
is coming from
like all the obstacles
and government practices
and other things
that are making their
lives hard like in
unnecessarily difficult
ways I'm actually working
on multiple initiatives
already with the
government that are
making it easier to
be an entrepreneur in
this country you know
so I mean a simple thing
like for example
automating the process
of registering a company
or doing filings and
other things like
completely for some reason
we do have some parts
of the government
that are completely
automated one is taxation
I guess like anything
that makes money
for the government is
instantly automated
because it makes money
faster for them but you
know when it comes
to like supporting
entrepreneurs uh we
have a filing time for a
company um it's like
about three to four weeks
uh like you file a
company you get get it
registered in three
to four weeks and it
costs like 370 euros
to do do like a limited
company and then estonia
does the same thing
in one day and 50 bucks
uh so i mean i see
i see a lot of room
for improvement and the
same thing is is true
with that with all
the accounting uh which
is a small business
benefiting thing like
what if what But if
all the accounting was
basically trivial or
free for most of the
entrepreneurs, it would
take a lot of burden
out of the next. And,
you know, and so that
would be also helpful
for for the
entrepreneurship in general.
In Canada, we are
equivalent, I think,
is building permits
and the ability to
actually build a
house without getting
crushed by massive,
long and expensive
processes. Miko, I
love that Finland
has never wavered
from the concept of
the requirement of
a social safety net.
So I think you
guys are in an
incredible position
to really illustrate
around the world
what it means
to prepare for the
arrival of AGI,
considering that
definition, that it's
capable of doing
the vast majority
or all economically
meaningful work.
Are you optimistic
that the public
sector is going to
become AI native?
Yeah, I mean, lots of
people were skeptical
when I started this.
Like, they said that
this is an impossible
task. Like, you can't
convince these
******** to do anything
meaningful. But at the
end of the day, what
happened was that we
happened to have, like,
a perfect combination.
Like, I'm very well
known in Finland
myself as an AI hacker.
And then my co
-father, Janne, he's
basically one of
the most well-known
public servants of
the country, like
before he started
doing this with me.
So now having this
kind of star power that
we have in the country,
it's much easier for
us to negotiate with
the public sector
decision makers. but but
also uh it requires them
to learn that that uh
it's actually better
to buy from a nimble
nimble company that it
has a lot of ai like
and behaves in an ai
native way than uh
doing like this massive
contracts with large
corporations with thousands
of employees because
they will take years
and they will cost
millions or tens of
millions and and they
will usually get nothing
useful eventually for
the government uh that's
a simply ways of
extracting money from
the government So our
philosophy of doing this
transformation is
important here as well.
Miko, you're on the
right path because
I just saw a reel
not too long ago
that London,
England is actually,
Robert, using AI to
scan all the documents
specifically for
building permits.
Because they've got
surveys in boxes that
if you file something,
it's like there's
a water main that
was laid 300 years
ago. So they've got
all the boundaries
and all the registrations.
So apparently
London, England is
already doing this.
And also here
in Canada, Miko,
IRAP, so the Industry
Research Association,
they've got like a
couple of mega funds.
And one of them
specifically, they repeatedly
have going is the
adoption of AI for SMBs.
So they'll create a
fund and then they
create incentives for
consultants to actually
help them um adopt ai
so there are initiatives
here in canada that
would actually dovetail
to what you're doing
so yeah yeah i mean
i i'm i'm hoping i'm
hoping that we can
like export happiness
uh to the world like uh
the happiness is part
of the part of the
thing that and i think
finns are famous for
that uh like this for
some reason win this
like world happiness
ranking every year like
past eight years and
i think it's partially
because because like
we learned to be
content and you know and
this kind of contentment
and because everybody's
taken care of
like like it leads into
this kind of contentment
and and and mental
safety so uh if we
have ai and let's say
that we managed to build
this nordic welfare
society model with
ai and we can export it
to everything then we
have basically all the
government services
available for technically
free with no tax
money needed uh for
everybody everywhere
and i think that's
something that we should
do uh i mean uh if we
care about humans like
like i think that's
the right thing to do
hey miko i have a quick
question for you um
what do you feel like
agentics foundation
could do to help support
that initiative or
what you're working on
other than obviously
like kind of having a
platform to speak is
there anything that you
would wish that we as
an organization would
be able to do to help
support someone like
you in your position uh
yeah i i'd be i'd be
discussing actually we
actually have members
from the like some of
the government uh and
this in thinland here
also in the agentics
already uh i think
there's a demo from
citra here on basically
listening to us right
now um and and uh uh we
uh like like we've been
discussing with them
that that we could
basically put together
the two of us like some
kind of agentics, like
local entity that helps
do this one thing,
which I have in this
curve, which is like
helping the citizens
become more AI capable.
And this is like a
very important part
of this educational
aspect, like how
do you make people
more AI capable?
So this part, I think
agentics can help a
lot with. i think uh
uh right now uh of
course we are kind of
like a group of hackers
who are pushing the
boundaries and so i
think there's a lot
of engineers who have
very let's say high
iq and high technical
capabilities uh but
how do we help like
this to be spreading
like large like to the
society at large you
know and you know help
everybody to be more
on the bandwagon that's
a question that i
don't have an answer to
yet but uh i think
there's some kind of
trickle down effect
that they can probably
induce all right well
we're we're at the top of
the hour which means
we're going into our
after hour show where
we lose some of our
participants really
appreciate you taking the
time to show us and
tell us about what
you're working on love
love to see love what
what you're doing i
have a whole variety of
questions around ubi
as well which i'm sure
is probably a hot topic
as well and i think
the takeaway here is
is um socialism isn't
necessarily a dirty
word that you know we
sometimes are kind of
conditioned to think
that the only economic
model is is pure
unadulterated capitalism
not that i'm trying to
sound like a communist
or anything crazy but
the i think we need to
think about the future
where we work in
partnership with ai and
and i guess that opens
the question is what
in the world does does
work even look like
when ai is better at
most knowledge working
jobs not that i haven't
answered that but
but but i i don't
think this is like like
from my perspective like
this is not socialism
it's basically like
uh caring about
others and building an
infrastructure for helping
people and you know
and if you do it
with ai then we don't
have to have so high
taxes either because
because like uh the tax
money is trying to fund
this kind of system
but if you have AI
to do it, like it's
probably like much lower
cost for us to run.
So from my point of
view, it seems to me that
AI represents a lot
fewer people generating
a lot more wealth.
And the issue then is
how does the excess
wealth get distributed?
Do we have things like
minimal income and
everybody benefits or
does it go into the hands
of a few and we get a
a ruler-based society
and and that to me
is the bottom line in
all of this uh i i my
my story includes one
slide like i didn't have
time to show here but
it says that if we
have uh like a gl-level
technology in our hands
and we still don't
have a like we don't
serve everybody in the
society uh the two
things are true at the
same time we have technology
that can solve all
of our problems and
we are in trouble why
is that like like it's
a choice that we are
making like we are
making choice to be in
trouble even if we don't
have to so i i'm trying
to bridge this gap
bridge this gap like
to to bring the technology
to solve our problems
and then uh everybody
can feel more safe
and cared for uh in
this environment i mean
most problems are already
solvable today like
this is just at another
order of magnitude
right but like we could
redistribute resources
in a certain way
where everyone would
eat nowadays it's already
happening so i think
john your point is
extremely valid um yeah
and great i think it's
a powerful initiative
i was just wondering
for for the initiative
for like the small
business owner and maybe
government supporting
the small business
owners is there anything
that you you've seen
works or what small
business owners or
consultants or or people
are looking forward to
even even get started
like just taking that
first step to understand
what what the heck's
going on because like
you said everyone's
so busy and they don't
have the big resources
like other ones is there
anything that you're
seeing works or people
are interested in
i guess open to
the whole group
i think yeah
i'll let someone
else answer it
yeah i can i can
take a stab at
i mean i think
obviously it's the
bandwidth and understanding
that is that's the
constraint but what
everyone cares about
everyone most probably
have been through
a cyber incident at
some point in time for
me i think the biggest
entry point for
raising that awareness
and effectively making
people understand
adopt is through that
route effectively showing
like how can we
actually like back to
the point about your
ethical hacking group,
I think the ability
to show that, look,
you are exposed, but
we can approach it in
this way. I think that
is the first step to
making people realize
what is Agentex AI
and why it can be bad,
but how its power can be
leveraged as well.
That's my, you
know, two cents
perspective on this.
And Ferris, that's
the entire purpose of
the Agentex organization
is as a counterbalance
to, I think, what
John mentioned in this
consolidation of both
power information
and wealth. And in
essence, I really liked
the original concept
behind OpenAI circa
like 10 years ago, where
they said they were
going to create an
open organization
dedicated to sort of
stopping a group of very
wealthy, powerful
companies and individuals
from basically dominating
the space ironically
they became the
very thing they were
founded to stop i don't
know i i don't know
why that happened
but money corrupts
apparently so the same
thing with google right
google don't their
motto was don't be evil
and now does that
mean as soon as we're
successful we'll we'll
be evil like i hope
not um is it is there
is it or i don't know
it's like it It must
be possible to do
things with some level
of altruism, isn't it?
Or am I just
kidding myself?
Please forgive me
for interrupting your
conversation. Someone
else would be able.
Please forgive me
for interrupting your
conversation. I
probably should share my
picture better than
I do, but I look
horrible, so I would
just scare everyone.
But what I think it
is, is not that the
money corrupts you so
much. is the preservation
of what you have
that corrupts you, so
that when you have so
little, you're not that
concerned with preserving
the status quo.
I can only say this
because I was born in
Harlem, and I remember
being a revolutionary.
I was a Black
Panther. I was a Black
Muslim. I was a
revolutionary. I wanted
to change the system,
and all of a sudden,
when i got a job
and i started making
over six figures i
remember my brother
telling me one day
i worked for ibm
at the time my brother
told me one day
he said you know
you are the man now
and my politics changed
and i think what
it is is that you
know when you when you
have so much that's
entwined with what
is the way things are
you know to you it
seems the way things
are are just fine.
Please forgive me
for interrupting
you. No, that
makes total sense.
There's a couple
terms, you know, one
that came back, I
believe from the 90s,
is the concept of
techno capital,
that as technology speeds
up the cycle between
the accumulation
of capital and the
growth of the power of
the technology ultimately
lead to a singularity
and um and i think
collectively near
universally we want to
avoid that kind of thing
the other term that
it gets referenced as a
perpetual uh perpetual
dictatorship because
in its darkest form
because if you have
the ability of absolute
artificial AGI and
or under the control
of a single entity, that
becomes really scary.
I love the idea. We've
got to get to the
idea of there is a
form of participation,
economic participation,
whether it's UBI,
although I don't think
it should be basic.
I think that's an
assumption we want to
challenge, that there's
great plenty in our
future. There can be
could be great plenty.
And that so I push
back against the idea
of a basic income or a
minimal participation,
because the one
element I think that
we sometimes miss or
doesn't weigh in is
that we all contributed
to the data that
allowed for science
and capital to test the
hypothesis that all
you needed was scale.
so all of our data went
in by permission or
not right and therefore
i think data is
missing from the cap
table and universally
a dividend to individual
humans around the
planet might be one
path that we explore
and martin i think you
want to pipe in there
we i think we cut
you off yeah sorry i
didn't mean to in ****
like that um i'm saying
that everyone
recognizes the hazard of
someone else being evil
right so if you're in
the community you go
oh someone here could
really take all the
power but if you're
the person who made it
to the top it's it's
a hazard right because
you know you set a
constitution like any
founder of a um like
in government say oh
let's not do evil but
the temptation that
once you're there is
like well i'm the best
person to look after
this and i think that
um you know altman
and etc they they
recognize the hazards but
once they're in power
they won't stay there
so guys just um i can
show you something
a little more altruistic
or practical so
you guys know that i've
been working on varai
for a while and one
of the things in terms
of what mika was
talking about in terms
of like how you can
use ai for social good
My investor, Unity
Labs, has been pushing
me. So I've actually
used the Agentec
platform, and I
now have a full
example of a SaaS
platform for managing an
eyewear practice
because it is so
horribly bad if you
are in North America.
And one of the things,
if you go, I kind of
feel good about this
startup because the
World Health Organization
says there are 4
billion people on
the planet in need of
eyewear or like eye care
in general, right? And
you basically have
like the first world
where we spend a lot
of money on our frames
and it's covered by
insurance. And then you
have like the third
world where you basically
don't have opticians,
ophthalmologists,
limited access
to hardware
and glasses and whatever.
And when companies
like Wixotica have an
overrun of their frames,
they donate them out
of charity. so I do
think that when it
comes to things like AI
there are things like
business like really
sucky things with
respect to the government
that you can automate
and streamline and
I think the Public
Service Alliance of
Canada will like that idea
but maybe they can
you know be retrained
to do other things
that actually add value
but on on the platform
that I just finished
I now have the ability
to help optimize
the practice using AI,
looking at the bookings,
using the windows.
And I actually built,
and I'm sharing the
wrong window, but I
actually built connections
to publicly available
repos for medical
research on AI. So
it's like on Hugging
Face and other places.
So if you're not the
Mayo Clinic, this
massive organization
in the US that like has
all of this control
over the market right
in terms of like
research um this there's
basic practice management
patient management
optimization but
part of my roadmap is
to say hey where are
these publicly available
apis and libraries
and how can we create
software to empower
diagnostics not just
for the first world
but if i release the
sas platform and the
data that's being
trained on these ai
models around diagnosis,
right, and being able
to get a diagnosis
over your phone,
using AI to do
different kind of
eye diagnostics,
you can actually do
good in serving a
specific vertical
or group that way.
So I'm very
close to being
able to publish this.
And hopefully by
September, this launches
in like North America,
but the idea is that
all the intelligence
that we're
building the
platform can be used
in other markets
for other people.
I like it.
I love the concept.
I have a soft spot
for trying to empower
and improve the lives
of people indirectly
who don't even know
this technology exists.
Yeah, I was just recently
talking to a lawyer
and a few medical
offices, small practices
that have all this
documentation they
have to manage daily.
They only have a handful
of people to do this
work. One has taken
on a licensed attorney
has literally taken
on himself to learn
this, all this stuff
that we know, and has
already made a 90%
efficiency in his own,
in his own law firm.
And so there are
at least four
or five verticals
I could think of
right now that
are old school.
Manufacturing is one of
them. They are
so old school.
They do not want
to modernize,
but yet they have
so many processes
that need to
be modernized.
Steel Incorporated
is one of those.
They're just a behemoth
of an industry that's
been around for decades
that has so many
old school processes
and really needs to
be brought up speed.
tools like NAN that have
built-in agents and
workflows are easy
for these individuals
to get up to speed on.
Consultancy is where
I think it could come
from, is where we can
prompt engineer them
into a better workflow,
help them see how
these tools can be
tied together, and set
those things up and
go, here you go. Here's
your custom workflow
for your company.
Here's how you can
make yourself more
efficient. And I'm
already seeing it
here locally, just
in St. Pete, Florida.
Nice.
Please forgive me.
I'm sorry, you were
talking, I'll listen.
I'm building an
application using Claude
and some of the
tools that Rue has
come out with for
lawyers. I'm a retired
lawyer, and I'm
probably a lot older
than most of you.
I'm 82 years old.
So I'm going to be
presenting that next
week to about 250
lawyers. I've just about
got it done in terms of
the test environment.
So I'd like to show
it to you all next
week or the week after,
because I think it
may give some insight
from somebody who
has content experience
over many years of the
content area as to
what's needed because
the question is
what's needed and the
people who are doing
the work don't really
understand what the
contribution can be and
the people who have
the tools don't really
understand what the
tools need to be applied
to and I think we can
do a really a good
job if we can understand
what we need to
do to begin to open a
conversation to answer
those questions
so that there's a
connection between the
people who need the tool
and the people who
can provide the tool.
I just have to say
this very quickly, and
please forgive me.
I feel like I'm the
representative of the
underprivileged in the room.
But again, coming
from my neighborhood
where I came
from, I don't know
how many of you
are aware of this
thing. It's called
Make Wakanda Real.
Have any of you
ever heard of that?
Nope.
So there's Will I Am
who's a rap singer and
he has this movement
called Make Wakanda Real.
So the answer to what
at least we believe
needs to be done is I
don't know any of you
that has ever heard of
the Rucker Tournament
in New York. It's a
basketball tournament
in New York that my
uncle is famous for. He
started it. So what
we believe is each one
teach one. And with
Make Wakanda Real, what
we're trying to do is
meet people that are in
underprivileged environments.
And when I speak
underprivileged, I
include the people of
West Virginia because
I've been to West Virginia
and I thought I was
underprivileged in
Harlem until I met a
white guy from West
Virginia. And I realized,
oh, wow, it's not just
us. There's a lot of
people that don't have
the basic things they
need in our country.
So what Make Wakanda
Real is trying to do is
get everyone at least
interested in the basic
concepts of AI. And
one methodology of
doing that is there are
so many free, fundamental,
introductory AI
courses that are out
there that people are
not taking advantage of.
Like, for instance, AI
900. You know, you can
get a certification.
My dog could pass the
certification, but at
least it gets you where
you're intelligent
about the words that
there are in AI. So I
think the start for most
people is not necessarily
exposing them to
tools, but exposing them
to the fundamentals.
And what I've found
for my students is that
when I get them that
first certification,
it's like, you know,
first one's free on
the streets. You know,
you get the first one
and you're hooked from
that point forward.
Well, I love what you
guys are saying. And
just to John's earlier
comment as well, you
know, if you're looking
for some peer review
before you're going to
give your presentation,
you want some some
insights some tweaks
whatever you know our
crew are always happy
to uh give us constructive
feedback um you
know just shoot shoot
it to the group join
our our uh martin's
done a really good job
of managing that
discord for us discord
.agentix.org um and dennis
uh to your point yeah
we have anything we
can do to support some
of your endeavors you
know the the you know
the philanthropic sort
of you know elements
i conceptually i i
love that idea you know
let's let's use our
our newfound powers
for good thank you sir
yeah it makes sense to
me love that yeah so
we're running out of
time here um you know
it's been it's been
another crazy crazy week
they're always crazy
i'm you know if if
anyone wants to present
something you know
reach out to rob or the
team here we we love
to see your work um our
crew in new york sorry
about the presentation
but if you want to
show it next week you
know obviously we want
to hear your tunage
um you know or if you
got it working you can
type and show it now
if you if we got a
couple more minutes
before i get a hop um
otherwise we're in the
last moments anyway
anything else anyone
wants to share or tell um
make sure add your
linkedin if you haven't
already at add and we
We represent ourselves
with our little infinity
icon on LinkedIn.
I try to like or follow
anyone I see that
has that on their
posts. So it gives me a
little visual indicator
that we're sharing
our alignments or
feedback loops anyway.
All right.
Rob, is there an
official image?
Oh, we use the emoji.
Oh, gotcha.
Yeah, we co-opted
the Infinity
logo. I know
it's a little
weird, but it's
good marketing.
And basically
what we do is we
slap that in our
little profile.
So if you do
that, you can just
copy and paste
that if you want.
And that sort of
shows affiliation. The
other thing that we do,
if you're a member of
our group, even if
it's just a supporter,
you can add yourself
as like, I think it's
like an employee of
the organization. and
then then you show
up in there and then
you see what other
people are posting and
it creates a nice
little kind of community
element and brings awareness
to our organization
yeah which is neat
on linkedin you
can rearrange the order
so it's not looking
like you changed you
know like you don't
work at where you work
anymore you you can
lower it down but it's
it's a it's a neat
thing and uh yeah as
well too uh really like
when john when you're
done that presentation
we'd love to I'd
love to have you and
hear it as well, and
you as well, Dennis,
as that gets momentum.
Brad, a quick
little update
on membership, I guess.
Is the site set to at
least test live next
week? This is the new
member site, right,
where we'll be able to
get all kinds of content
and those free courses,
all that stuff?
Yeah, I'll give a proper
update next Friday.
I'll remind you to
try and get on the
schedule. But thanks
to all the donors so
far. It's keeping
the lights on. We're
going through updating
the site. We'll
have a sneak peek on
Toronto Tech Week.
For us, lots
of things for
learning-centric events,
committees, ways
to get involved.
We got a whole crew
of people helping
right now. So we're
looking to at least have
something that we
can glance at early
next week. And then
we'll be taking our time
to make sure we
implement it properly.
But again, thank
you to everyone that
keeps the lights on.
And everyone that's
a member right now
will be migrating
you over to the latest
and greatest. And
hopefully lots of
things are for you.
Is there a
governance section of
people who are interested
in foundational
documents? because
in U.S. law, if
you're a non-profit,
people who give
you money can get
a tax deduction.
So that might be a
funding source that if you
had the proper documentation
as the umbrella
of the organization
could give benefits
to the members. And if
Anthropic ever goes back
to its old billing
rules that people who
are members might be able
to get to the discount
that was discussed
about a month ago when
the billing rates were
much higher and those
kinds of things, because
it might be useful
to start looking at
those sorts of things
to get more advantages
for the organization.
I've got some legal
skills that are pretty
rusty, and I'm not
allowed to practice law,
but I don't have to do
that just to look over
documents as a member
of an organization.
I love it, John.
yep we'll reach out
certainly uh we've done
um the registration
because we are a
not-for-profit we've
done registration with
technical organizations
that give discounts
to software um
and we have been rolling
that out but you're
right there are
some constitutional
things that i think
would benefit from um
your professional
experience um so we're
we so just as an
fyi We're currently
incorporated as a
Canadian not-for-profit.
As we grow, we'll
likely have to explore
what that means in
other jurisdictions
that we need to operate
within. The most
likely being our
friends to the south.
We did Canada because
the core crew of us
are basically Canadian
and it was easy. um but
we as we sort of get
more organized we're
probably going to have
to figure out how we
can collaborate with the
larger tech companies
and that likely means
a not-for-profit in
the u.s and a separate
charter foundation
something that addresses
the irs requirements
we haven't figured
that out yet yeah we're
we're we're very organic
all the time yeah
We're just a group
of folks that are
volunteering our time.
You know, we have no,
there's no financial
incentives here other
than we have a shared
passion for this tech.
Amazing.
All right. Is that it?
Anybody else, anything
else wants to bring
up? I know I see
Chris Royce, our favorite
neighborhood viber.
Hey, buddy.
Yeah, what are
you even building?
um well i've been i've
been trying to optimize
fair of mine but
essentially what it is
is i took spark right
and then i was seeing
you with spark doing
amazing things right
so i was like okay so
rUv is orchestrating
or managing all these
workers so you know
and he's and he's walking
it through the spark
process so i was like
okay so fair of mine
essentially let me
replace rUv with like
10 orchestrators right
and i'm like okay now
i got these orchestrators
they orchestrate
out the whole spark
process like or the
development process like
end to end it's like
that's cool what do i
need now to make this
better i need to put
rUv back in the loop
right but instead of
having to say rUv as say
the manager of the
workers i now have him as
the ceo the manager
of the managers right
and so that's essentially
what i've been
messing with lately is
figuring out how to best
input put the human
back in the loop to make
the system align best
with user intent and
that's been a lot of
fun but it's the same
problem I was addressing
earlier when I said
that when I do a 50
agent swarm I sometimes
lose the ability to
understand what each of
the agents are actually
doing during that
process so you're trying
to add the kind of
introspection as part
of that yeah with like
goal clarification steps
mutual understanding
documents and then
like anytime that you
tell the ai something
it has like a separate
database that stores
all your ideas so that's
more aligned with your
focus so it doesn't
ever go back and do
stuff you told it not
to do before again type
of things like that
that's really interesting
because you think
about big organizations
and how they do that
right now you know
they're typically in one
of these enormous
collaboration suites right
so that is actually
where they would expect
to see those sorts
of conversations and
and that's actually
where the existing humans
whether it be senior
manager or CEOs and what
have you would expect
to collaborate with
a mixed team of system
actors and human
actors working together
and indeed where the
interface points
currently already are like
people would you know
whether it's Microsoft
the Microsoft Azure
platform or obviously
Atlassian or an IBM thing,
they would expect to
see them in Laskow's
collaboration suites.
So maybe we can
service some of your
what I imagine are
inside data structures
and MD files into one
of those enterprise
systems. That would
get attention.
All right. Well, I
think that's it. I think
we've got to jump.
anyone that's in Toronto
next week and that
wants to go to the event
there's a massive wait
list but obviously
you know us so if you
want in, just ping
one of us show up early
if you're going to
go to that event and
good luck Vincent and
crew in Paris next week
if you need any help
promoting that let me
know, I've posted it
at a few places you
might want to post it
on the AI Prompt
Programming subreddit the
thing does pretty crazy
I'm almost at 90,000
subs and uh millions
of views anyway so
that if you want the
you know if you want the
reddit crew you'll
you'll get them on there
and i'm the obviously
creator so i can
make sure it gets seen
thank you all right
thanks everyone
appreciate it um till next
time and again thursdays
we also do live coding
creating crazy things
i'm not even sure
what i'll create next
week but i'm sure it'll
be nuts and uh and
oh we've also put
together a production
team for this so we're
gonna we're trying to
get a little less wayne's
world and a little
more organized as we
go forward so we're
going to be putting
together a much more
polished version of this
with rob and kelsey
and nick and and the
rest of the crew
helping sort of put this
together so um that'll
probably a few weeks
off but if anyone again
this is a volunteer
org so if there's
something you're interested
in helping with
whether it's legal or
producing podcasts or
whatever reach out i'm
sure there's a spot for
you where we're free
uh video intro submissions
right roof yeah
exactly let's see yeah
let's let's see you
crazy cool or maybe
we'll get ****** and
crew to create the
musical interlude um song
or something that
sounds like intel chimes
or something all
right thanks everyone
thanks good weekend
thanks bye bye take care
Thank you.