There we are.
July 25th.
We're another episode
underway here. And
before we start, though,
I want to just quickly
apologize for last
week. That wasn't really
a hack so much as I
needed to do a better
job of using the host
tools. So this week,
we're a little bit more
locked down. So if you
want to share your
screen, I'm going to have
to manually allow you
to share your screen
um there's no white
boarding or anything like
that enabled hopefully
and uh hopefully that
doesn't happen again
but again thanks for
everyone that presented
last week and i
apologize it just because
it's a little bit uh
a little bit yeah a
little wasn't wasn't a
good way to end the week
but stuff happens i'm
to be honest i'm
surprised it took as long
as it did for for that
to be a problem for us
um but onward and
upward the the who do we
have today uh rob we
got uh so we got uh
braun field walker and
chris barlow this is uh
this is the week of
dashboards abstraction
layers over swarm
orchestration so lots of
really cool variations
and ideas about about
how to accomplish that
and what the visual
priorities are so uh
really looking forward to
that i was on with
the nvidia guys this
morning about about the
production support too
roof so there should
uh there should be some
some good stuff coming
from that and um uh
yes and just a note uh
we had indianapolis last
week cornelius and
brad um were there and
uh good turnout great
great bunch of folks
denver is up for august
13th and then uh august
12th uh the next
toronto event so lots of
stuff going on there
and i know someone said
they ordered a ton
of t-shirts make sure
you use the right font
guys this this is not
the right font for
agentics every time i put
on my shirt i'm like
ah i'm a font guy what
can i say just let's
let's just make sure uh
let's let's make sure
we we stay on brand
for that i'm probably
the only person in the
world that cares about
fonts but the only
fonts i i dislike are
comic sans and that one
from avatar whatever
that that font's called
but otherwise we're
good to go um all right
so yeah lots going
this week have you guys
noticed that the cloud
code has been uh down
a lot with the 529
errors i'm getting that
almost uh now actually
most of the morning and
what was interesting.
I was doing a call
with some folks out of
the Netherlands earlier
and watching their
screen, they didn't have
any issue at all, yet
I was getting 529. So
I think it has something
to do with like the
geography of where
the API is making the
request. So one of the
things I noticed quickly
is if I switch to a
different geo, like I
spin up another code
space or I spin up a fly
.io or whatever in a
different part of the
world, it actually
sometimes resolves it.
It's a pain because then
I got to sync the GitHub
or whatever. But if
it's a long-term outage
or you're giving a
demo or something, that
might be a quick, easy
way to resolve it.
So a few things to
cover. I want to go
quickly because I know
we got a lot of folks
that want to present
today. And by the
way, if you do want
to present, we do like
the idea of folks being
able to jump in and
show what they're
working on. I've locked
down the screen a
little bit, as you can
tell, just ask and
raise your hand or
whatever, and we'll try
to make that happen.
um some new features
as well that came out
this week in cloud
code which was cool the
the agent feature came
out yesterday which
i want to explore a
little bit and maybe
later if we get time
we'll i'll jump in and
take a look at github's
spark good good naming
convention they use
a k though so i'm no
homage to sun microsystems
like like mine
all right so let's
let's jump in i want to
show you guys so i'm
going to start with my
dashboard i'll show
you how i built it but
i'm really curious
really how how everyone
else is building their
dashboards i know
ocean's done really cool
sort of uh dashboard
you should share the
link to your uh your
latest dashboard which
looks amazing um mine
is is a little bit
more retro okay a lot
more retro this is
like if you see the do
you see the game war
games back in like the
80s i think it's it's
it's similar to that
so let's let's take
a look here i'm
gonna i'm gonna
hopefully i'm gonna
refresh my page here
You realize that
that computer was
called Whopper.
Oh, nice.
Whopper.
What? W-O-P-R,
man. The Whopper.
Okay, like Burger King.
I don't know,
but it's a name.
It's a thing.
All right. So as you
can tell, I might do
another version of this
that's a little less
Wargames Whopper
-like. But for now, the
important part of
this user interface is
probably the web services
that underpins it. So
what I've done is I've
essentially connected
all the various
Claude-flow-related
capabilities and Cloudcode
-related capabilities
through WebSockets.
So you get a little
dashboard. You can see
what's happening here.
There's a swarm
capability. This is a work
in progress. And for
anyone that's actually
interested in trying
it, you can go to the
Claude-flow GitHub and
take a look for the
agentic flow branch.
And you get what you
currently see here. it's
it's it's totally alpha
so i haven't published
it beyond the fact
that that i do do all
my development in in
sort of a live environment
so now i can i can
choose different tasks
to submit we can we
can submit them you can
see details here i i
can spawn additional
uh components i'm going
to add more i'm still
early i can add it i
can add that now i
can close this and you
can see different
different components here
um but the the part
that's probably most
interesting is how I'm
handling the Claude-flow
integration. One of
the things that really
drives me nuts when
doing a lot of these
swarms is the flicker
you get. And I have no
idea, I've got no real
introspection of how
the system's working.
So what I wanted to do
is one, be able to create
multiple swarms and
have them run
concurrently. So there's a
little plus button here.
I can add swarm one,
swarm two, and I might
add the ability to
rename it here later
this afternoon. We can
choose the different
commands and I might add
the agent, some more
agent capabilities and
so on later. But this
is, the first step
was just getting this to
work. So in this case,
I can select this
particular option. I can
see the actual prompt
that makes it work
here. So I, and I can
potentially edit that.
Some of the other various
options, I can clap
that. So now I can go
further, I can actually
start it up. Let's
fingers crossed that
Cloud Code is actually
functioning now. So
now you see here that
the initial system is
initializing. We can see
which tools it's using.
so it's using the
glob and the task and
all these various other
things i can actually
search through those
so if i want to go here
and i want to see
different options i can
see the system or the
assistant so if i click
assistant we can see
here that the different
messages so i can see
my token uses i can
see details of it i
can copy and paste the
json if i want to so i
can click the copy button
and and then i can do
like a sort of dump
if i want to do that
i can automatically
show all the jasons as
well by clicking that so
you can see all the
jason outputs now i can
also search as well
so i can go here and
let's say i'm just looking
for a certain thing
so let's scroll down
and see what's actually
happening here so
we've got different
assistants so again
we're not we're i'm not
concerned about the tab
i'm going to scroll back
up and just turn off
the assistant to show
everything so i'm going
to scroll down to the
bottom here you can see
that there's different
tool results task
ids so this allows me
to keep track of what's
happening so if i want
to go back or i want
to do a rollback i'm
going to add a button
that basically allows
you to roll back to a
certain point where it
might have broke so
this gives me a lot more
visibility right so i
can i can see what's
happening in in real
time the other thing
that i'm doing is i'm
using the json or the
stream JSON output from
Cloud Code, which is
really a really cool
feature. So under the
covers, I'm not actually
invoking directly the
interactive UI. I'm
actually streaming the
output from the system
itself, which allows
me to pause and sort
of redirect the output.
So if I wanted to go
to the bottom here and
say, stop and then do
something else, I could
actually click the
pause button and then
redirect it to do something,
fix something alter
something in real time
so again i'm getting
a real-time view of
what's happening here
so and now i for it
looks like i might have
broke the auto scroll
option i'll fix that
later but it's kind of
cool so now i'm going
to go back to the top
of the page here i'm
just going to stop that
for a moment now i can
i can i'm in uh swarm
two so now if i go
back to swarm one oh i
guess i'm swarm i gotta
do a better job of
showing what's what's
happening here so now
can spawn up a different
swarm in swarm one or
i can i can create a
couple more swarms
here and have them all
working together now we
can see a little icon
indicating that this
one's running that this
this one isn't early
days now you can i also
have mcp tools the mcp
tools allows for all
the various uh tools
in the system i think
there's like 87 of them
and you can you can
interact with it so
if i go here and just
choose the in it as an
example i can execute the
tool now you can see the
success so everything
that exists within
the structure of the
system that is generally
automated can also
be invoked manually or
through apis so if i
want to go to like my
github integration i
can see all my github
options or my dynamic
agent allocation
workflows all that sort of
stuff so i click that
we can we can set that
up uh two steps we can
say i don't know task
execute tool and then
we execute that we
can we can view the
memory so this shows all
the things happening
within so this one's
got a hundred and i
guess 12 i guess that's
12 715 tasks so i
can go in here i can
search through that i
can i can type in task
i guess there's
something for that one um
hope maybe and then we
click on that we can
see what what's
happening at each step i
can visualize all these
components we'll go
for those who like
terminals i stuck a terminal
in here just to show
you how to interact
with the terminal
programmatically mostly
so if you go in here
you can do that you
know i can go to cd
oop i gotta test like
that right so i could
whatever i need i want
to do and here are
the api docs so if you
want to interact with
the system you can
see that as well so so
this is if for anyone
building dashboards
that wants to interact
with either cloud
flow or cloud code all
you need to do is use
my my web services so
you can see my examples
here's some some
endpoints so if I want
to check the system
health which is the
most simple one I can
click here and then I
can execute and this
is running you can see
the headers raw the
raw information I can
see the web sockets I
still do some work
on this one I think I
think I need to change
this to my my actual
IP address but we'll
see what happens here
Oh, yeah, it's trying
to connect to a
local host. I'm actually
on an IP address,
so that's probably
not going to work
in the moment. But
you get the idea.
So I'm just going to
stop that for a moment.
And I'm going to add
an authentication
system. So lots of
cool features here.
Yeah, so that's
my dashboard.
Thank you for putting
this together. I
feel like it helps me
personally appreciate
the depth and scale
of like the tool that
you've created and
seeing it visually
is so helpful. It's
like, wow, there's all
these nooks and
crannies. And so just
thank you for putting
this together. It was
awesome. Oh yeah.
There's, there's a ton
of stuff happening
here. And actually I
skipped some of the,
some of the features
here and I need to,
I need to add sort
of another option to
keep it persistent.
I haven't done that
yet, but check this out.
I've got another, I
get a visual system
here so we can go, we
can see the hierarchy.
We can change
the hierarchy
as new instances
are added.
It adjusts, you
know, you can, you
can connect one
to another kind of
thing. Oops. Where,
where's that?
This is, I think I, yeah,
that isn't, is that,
that's not working
at the moment for
whatever reason, but.
Hey Roof, I got a
question about trimming
different tasks out
of, out of the context.
Are you able to do
that with this? Yes,
exactly.
Yeah, exactly.
So that is that's I'm
sorry, I'm not sure
who asked that, but
that is a really
interesting. So what I'm
able to do, I'm using
the stream output. So
now I am able to in
real time monitor the
stream of the output
from cloud code and
then adjust, adapt,
and change what it needs
to do in real time.
Before, I had no
ability to see what was
happening, right? So it
was kind of a mystery
when I went, I didn't
know when a tool was
done or what was
happening. Now I can see
exactly what's happening.
I can see the full
JSON response or
whatever I need to see
from it. And then I can
have sort of a secondary
agent sort of
monitoring. What I'm not
showing you in the
system is I've actually
integrated the Mastra
AI agent system. So I
can have secondary
agents that are actually
manipulating the stream
to improve, to train,
to alter, to spin
secondary components.
And this is
basically a real
-time view of the stream.
It's kind of cool. And
you can also better
see when there's an
error, if there is one.
Why did you choose
Mastra Agents? Light
and I like Mastra
because it's TypeScript.
It's light. It works
in a serverless
environment. It has
native MCP integration
input and output.
And LankChain *****.
Sorry, LankChain.
LankChain JS is
actually okay, but
the Python one.
And, you know, I
don't get why people
build in Python.
I know people
like it, but
it's just not my thing.
And as you
guys know, I've
built a lot in Python.
It's just, this
is all TypeScript.
And I, yeah, here's
an issue I see.
Tool result.
So this is a
perfect example
of something
I need to fix.
It's spawning,
it's using the
wrong tool. Now
I can actually
see when there's
a problem.
so now i could go to
the tool id later on
and i'll i can do a
review and fix whatever
whatever it was trying
to do here so it looks
like it was trying to do
a command notification
so error i need to
fix so now at least
i can a lot of these
errors were hidden in
the context of the clod
flow system when it's
flickering and doing
all kinds of crazy
stuff and i had a really
hard time to see when
there was a problem
like this now all i
need to do is is do a
filter for you know you
know whenever the word
unknown shows up i
can try to find and
i'll fix that as a a new
ticket so in this case
i could spawn here i
can go here i'll choose
i need to do a filter
i need to do a better
filter here i'll do
i'll add that later
but there's a github
option so i i could do
i could choose uh one
of these options p you
know a pr manager or
maybe an issue release
manager whatever needs
whatever makes the
most sense and then i
i would say you know
create a new issue or
something relating to
that so here i might
do issue tracker and
this one i might say uh
review and fix
you know and
i'll paste that in there
and then i spawn it
so this this would
be in a different
swarm and that's it
oh another another
thing to note for those
who are who are might
be interested in
helping me with
development i'm outputting
everything in the
console so not only can
you see and actually
a whole lot more here
so let's go here for
a moment and i'm going
to i'm just going
to refresh the whole
entire interface this
is a work in progress
you're seeing bugs
but you see here i've
got my my console so
this this will tell you
all the various checks
right now the the
the uh issue you're
seeing websockets is
it's trying to connect
a local host i need
to have a fallback to
127.0.01 or something
but that's a relatively
minor problem
yeah so that's that's
it that's my dashboard
hi quick question on
the architecture of
this so this front
end um is calling the
api as well as getting
data directly from
the memory files and
getting from the cloud
cloud control logs are
these three okay so
i'm doing yeah i'm
doing it from several
so in the most simple
sense in the most
simple sense i'm i've
created a ppt why i
think they call it that
allows me to interact
directly with the
console of the server
using WebSockets and
or API endpoints.
And once I've got
that, I can then
query the Claude
code, Claude flow,
or just straight
up the SQLite or
whatever else I want
from the terminal
itself in a structured
and streaming
fashion. So it
streams the output
using WebSockets to
the web interface.
Perfect, thank you.
that's probably the
best way to to to do
this sort of thing and
i think i think ocean
you mentioned you
were doing a similar
approach with with web
sockets if i i think you
mentioned before the
call started anyway
i'm excited to see how
what other people are
doing with dashboards
we can compare notes
quick question so uh
you're running the
dashboard on local host
but you're connecting
to github workspaces
that's running cloud
flow in order to
make sure that's in a
containerized environment
is that correct not
exactly so i am using
i'm using uh the
various types of containers
and i like github
because it's it's easy
but you you could you
could hypothetically
run this anywhere
and the drawback to uh
using uh github code
spaces is it doesn't
use local host it uses
the ip address and it's
just the way they've
got it set up and
most things expect
localhost but so what
i what i'm doing is i'm
using a 127.0.01 fallback
so if if localhost
fails then i just
basically say okay go
try the same thing
using the ip address but
you said that Claude-flow
shouldn't be run
locally because it can
wreak havoc and cause
kernel panics so how
are you able to get
around that issue well
i use docker i use
ubuntu docker and
generally i don't bother.
It takes up too much
space in my hard drive
to have all these
Docker images running.
So I just, you know,
I usually either
use GitHub code
spaces or some cheap
provider like
Railway or, you know,
I like Fly.io. There's
a bunch of them,
right? They all kind
of work the same
way. They're all
basically Docker
instances running in
the cloud somewhere.
Okay. So you're
running the Claude-flow
in a Fly.io,
Dockerized environment,
and you're
connecting that with
local host IDE in
order to connect to
your back end, which
is on the floor.
No IDE. I'm not
using an IDE.
So there is no
IDE. It's a command
line or Node.js
application to the
command line, but
there's no IDE.
Is there at least
authentication
between the
public IP address
and that
WebSocket client?
Sorry, I missed the
first part of your
question. Is there at
least authentication
between the public
IP address of the
FlyIO instance and
your WebSocket client?
There could be.
Currently, no.
This is a work
in progress.
So if you're
volunteering to do that,
it probably wouldn't
take a lot of time.
I haven't gotten
there yet. I was
more focused on the
core functionality.
Once I've got the
core functionality
working, then
I secure it.
If you're going to
run my super alpha
version of this,
just make sure
you don't make it
publicly available.
It should be fine.
It's the same
question, Jed, with
Codespaces. With
Codespaces, you open
a port, and once
it's open to your
Codespace, anyone
can get to it if they
know that you are
our IP address.
Yes. It's not
exclusive to your...
It's not over SSH or
something like that?
it could be it should
be but it isn't
by default they
just forward it just
forwards a port you
can set it up in code
spaces and you forward
a port and then
that port is open
for your code space
which is a docker
container running in
github's uh compute
environment yeah it's
the same that that
goes for any like the
aws would be the same
thing if if you open
a port you don't
put any security on
it then it's not
going to be secured so
same idea now what
i'll probably end up
doing is I'll probably
add like a JWT token
and like to the API
and something similar
for the web socket
and I'll secure it.
And so there's two forms
of security I would
likely add. If I was
actually going to do
this in production,
like let's say I wanted
to deploy this on a
serverless function
somewhere, I'd probably
use an anonymous key,
like some kind of
cores policy that locks
it to a particular
domain. And then I would
use some other secondary
form of user auth,
JWT or something.
And getting past
all three levels
would be pretty
difficult at that
point. You could fake
the cores, I suppose,
but faking the
other two would
be very difficult.
Do you think you can
do something similar to
Supabase, where they
have both anonymous
and API keys? So you
have the anonymous key,
and then you have the
API key on the server.
Dead on. That's
exactly what I'm doing.
That model is what
I was describing.
So the anonymous
key is what you
can see essentially
in your browser
if you were sniffing
the network.
And something somewhere
needs to communicate,
right? So the
anonymous key is a good
way to do that. And
then the second part
is the cores. Is it
coming from a trusted
domain, whatever.com?
Now, again,
hypothetically, depending
on how your domain's
set up, that could
be faked. But if
you're using the
latest CloudFlare
setup, that's going
to be really difficult
or impossible.
And then lastly, once
you've got past those
two, I'm using the
OAuth components from
Supabase or whatever
my OAuth provider is as
a user authentication.
So you basically are
having three levels
of security, the least
of the security being
the anonymous token.
And I have just one
more question. So you
mentioned that there's
GitHub code spaces for
containerized environments
with Docker, but
there's also Fly for
Dockers. Now, if you
look at some of the
Fly promotional YouTube
videos, they say that
the Fly Docker is
different than an actual
Docker. But I'm having
difficulty understanding
that because when
you define how the
FlyVM is constructed,
you basically use
commands similar to Docker
Compose. So I was just
wondering, in your
experience, how is the
Fly Docker different
than normal Docker?
It isn't different. If
it works in my local
Docker, it will work in
Fly or Railway or
Vercel or whatever. They
all work the same.
I never noticed any
difference. I do a local
Docker test just to
ensure it builds correctly
and do a quick run.
And once I know it
runs locally, and
when I say locally,
I'm probably running
in like a GitHub
code space. But once
I know it works
there, then I just
deploy it. And
generally, it just works.
And I just want to add,
Fly.io used to have
their own system for
Dockers. They don't
use the standards.
but they i think a
couple of months ago they
had to open a little
bit and implement the
standard dockers so
maybe you're looking on
the wrong videos or all
videos old it sounds
like old ones till
the old so yeah they
they've resolved it was
i think they resolved
that like in january
so last year it was
the biggest issue with
fly.io was they had
like these weird build
system and you had to
and and then you had
to try to use the they
had a local option to
do the build on your
machine and then you'd
have to do the same
build remotely but they
get they went away from
that and then now
they're more traditional
there's still a few
quirks but they all
like if you use like um
any any of these ones
that uses docker as a
deployment model they
all have sort of little
quirks you have to
try to work around like
versell is the same
way they've got a few
interesting things
they've chosen hey thank
you yeah um so who so
who wants to show their
dashboard next we've
got braun mr field
walker hey og hey how's
it going good man how
are you yeah good um
yeah when i was working
on swarm i was trying
to figure out what
exactly these things
are doing so here uh oh
host disabled i can't
share i can't share
pornographic images i
think i think you have
to request uh let's
see it just says
disabled i don't know how
to request uh let's see
i think you should be
able to grant him
access through if you
select on him yeah
let's see here sorry i i
locked it down yeah now
when you click share
it just says host
disabled there's nothing
there at all like it
should say send request
now it says okay is all
i got all right if i
see **** and and you
know really offensive
things i'm gonna i'm
gonna have to flip out
but i'm gonna turn it
back on here one sec
guys allow turn it on
turn it off yeah join
later that's yeah
yeah okay keep keep uh
keep all inappropriate
things to yourself today
all right you should
you should be good
all right let's see you
should see a sparkly
screen great nice okay
so yeah as everyone
knows swarm and all this
gets kind of confusing
so i first started
just trying to say
okay what the **** are
swarms there what are
they doing so i i i got
this uh sort of drag
and drop you can move
them around if you
hover over them you can
see what's inside how
many agents are there
what their agents are
doing i didn't spend
too much time it's like
the first thing i got
up just to sort of
figure out because if
you ask ai what it'll
do is he'll start
drawing all these lines
between everything but
they don't exist so it
took me a while to
sort of decompose okay
what is this warm how
are the agents connected
uh are there any hard
rules or are they
only rules inside cloud
code sort of virtual
brain but i'm seeing
that the screen sharing
has been paused does
anyone else see that
no i don't know you
can't see anything yeah
you still see the i
can still see it no i
don't see it at the
moment screen sharing has
been paused. Did I do
that? You know, I, I,
It looks frozen.
Stop share, re
-share. Yeah.
Braun has paused
screen sharing.
Uh,
paused. I don't, okay.
resume?
Maybe? I can
check on. Yeah,
there we go.
Now it's moving.
Can you back up?
I don't know.
I didn't touch it,
but it went off.
Anyways, okay. So,
um yeah this is 3d js
i think so um again
like what i want to do is
figure out relationships
and if i'm going to
build relationships
later i want to see
i want to see how and
if agents are connected
or do they talk so
if you when i first
did it if you just ask
ai it'll draw lines
all over the place but
when you actually dig
down they don't exist
like none of the swarms
are connected at the
moment they're all
independent and these i
i'd have to update the
actual agents but the
whole like mesh ring
star this is a let's
call it a mental map for
cloud code it's there
are no hard rules that
it cannot break out
of so whether cloud
code adheres to these
is up to cloud code
but anyways this was
just the start then i
thought okay you know
this at least tells me
i can figure out you
know which one is which
one's up which one's
working and you know
what the agents in it.
This was for the
server you're on or
container. I'm on
localhost, but I wanted to
know, okay, if I'm
running a whole bunch
of cloud codes, you
know, how much CPU am
I using, how much
RAM, actual disk space
and everything, because
sometimes you're,
I have quite a bit of
resource on this, but
you know, I can see
my RAM is almost
tapped out. So just in
case I need to scale
something or change
it i needed actual
stats for this and then
i got to the swarms
most of the swarm are
fire up destroy fire
up destroy fire up
destroy so um it's kind
of hard to benchmark
and figure out what
are the best swarms
what kind of hierarchies
work well what what
about your agent so i
keep the swarms and i
record them and these
are like this is what's
up right now so you
know this swarm's got
eight agents these
are the names of you
know the title again
all of this stuff is
cloud code mental map
so these are sort of
made up but you know
that's the whole thing
about prompting prompting
things like cloud
md everything it's
the cloud code tries to
follow it but you get
quite a bit of
different configs if you
just run a bunch of
swarms you'll see you're
getting all sorts of
different configs um
so you know i can clean
these up i can delete
them i can clean all
of them i can keep
them so if i like a
swarm i can keep it i
modified route swarm to
I can reinstate swarm
so if I use this
ID I can say reload
swarm that and that'll
boot up this with all
the agents inside then
I got this agent panel
so I was gonna make
it haven't quite got
there but I'm gonna
add let's call it
building swarm so I've
run 94 agents here I don't
really need to make
thousands more. So I
can start to go, okay,
I like these ones,
I can drag them
and drop them into
a swarm or modify
the swarm. So then
what I can eventually
get is, okay,
I only need, you know,
maybe four or five
swarms for my workflows,
I don't need to
keep building them
and destroying them, I
just going to be like,
run swarm one, which
will be like, coding
swarm. And these
agents, I'll just keep
customizing them until
I have exactly the
best combo of, let's
say, capabilities.
And again, I haven't
had time to totally bench
all these topologies,
but what's better
is the star ring,
or which of these
topologies is the best.
Then I'm getting
into these tasks.
For my, I don't know, for
my Linux system, if I run
the slash P, I got
to pay with API. So I
haven't been running
this, but I do keep
track of the major tasks
I'm doing. And then
as you know, the
flickering is a totally
annoying. So I got the
events on the right
here and I can filter
it. I haven't done
any in a while, but
last night I did some.
And right now I'm
also trying to
figure out what I
want to see because
I don't really
care about file
reads and all that
kind of stuff.
You get a lot
of sort of junk.
So, I'm trying to
filter out the junk,
you know, the
different types, how
long it took,
whether I've seen it.
I can nuke these. These
are not very interesting
anyway. So, I can
just blast all the
events. This is whether
I want to, you know,
I could turn off the
refresh, turn it on.
And then I did a
Claude history.
So if you want to
get the full history,
they are in your root
folder under JSON.
So I port them
over and then I
can grab one
here. So if I grab
like this one
and hit load,
oops, this one loaded up.
I can pick the
conversation
and then I get my full.
history so if you
want to go back a
week and go hey what
did i do and what
prompts did i use
what did i ask you
can get like the
full history and you
can search through
it because sometimes
you know your cloud
code crashes and you
don't have the you don't
hit continue you can
just go back and find
out what was going on
um and then i got so
that's this is all
going back to the ha
pools like when you when
i first ran it a lot
of the tasks were
finishing in milliseconds
so on the front end
it's kind of pointless
to be i'm like why i
got a live stream but
i can't see anything
that's because i'm
polling at let's say one
second and this stuff is
finishing in milliseconds
so i was like forget
it uh right now
i just dump everything
to the database space
and then it's it's
live like these forms
will appear in half a
second it's good enough
for me so then i i
got this other thing
here which is let's call
it the swarm showcase
so i a quick quick
quick question are you
using the uh the roof
swarm or clod uh flow
just all swarm yeah
just pure swarm there's
nice this is yeah
because i found because
everything is right
now since we're using
cloud code everything
is going into cloud ram
let's call it right
it you know we compile
as many orchestration
layers as we want on
top but so far i've
found swarm is more than
enough i can you
know because i can if
you've got the hierarchy
you you know you've
got the agent and the
and the hierarchy and
the prompt i don't really
need more layers on
top of that right it's
good enough for me
anyways um and then
yeah so then i gave um
this this what i'm trying
to get is i'm trying
to add the neural
net and then add the
ability to connect some
of these right i mostly
as i've been buried
in the architecture
of the events and also
for the agents um you
see how these are all
there, there's eight
agents, but they're
not active. It's the
agents are only active
for very short amounts
of time. So it's
pretty tricky to track
which actual agent is
doing it because again,
cloud code executes
the agent is another
framework for cloud code,
but it isn't, it isn't
like an agent with
an LLM in it. It's,
it's cloud code goes,
Hey, I'm going to be the
fact checker for a
little bit, But then
Cloud Code does the
work. So if I look at the
logs, it's like the
agent has one prompt
and then Cloud Code
has six. The agent has
one, Cloud Code has six.
So it gets tricky to
go, who finished it?
You know, who did it?
Anyway, so I asked, I
took, well, first one
of the things I did
with this swarm is I
said, okay, give me a
front end for this repo.
That's it. It's a one
-shot prompt. and this
was the what the swarm
made for itself i
again i didn't give it
three prompts i gave it
a ****** one line make
me a website so this
crazy thing was all
by itself this is like
an interactive swarm
builder and i think this
one actually looks
better than mine but um
i haven't figured out
how to get spinning
uh animations into the
3dgs yet but um this
is a full like you know
this would be i don't
know a 5 grand 10 grand
website if you had
to make it and this
thing just cranked this
out the whole thing
uh i got features core
features i've got mcp
tools these are all the
tools i've got this
is nuts the topologies
look at this thing
so this is made all a
graphic for each topology
hierarchy star you
know ring um and then
it's got performance
even look at this crazy
performance metric thing
so like i don't think
i could have made
this myself it would
taken me like i don't
know a day or two days
you know like to think
about it make it um
and this thing's just
cranked this out one
you just pointed it you
just pointed it uh it at
the repo i did nothing
i i have the repo
i said make use you
make me a website about
the repo that's that's
the prompt nothing else
zero that's that is
that is amazingly cool
like look out this
has got a little bar here
right for the different
mcp tools and it so
it's it's done like
a pretty awesome job
of building this out
and it's not you know
it doesn't have ******
fonts and you know like
it doesn't look like
if you would not believe
that ai made it by
itself with no help
right just organization
of content interactive
features like
especially these uh the
showcase things right like
these these like i i
it's pretty crazy that
it could make this ah
itself right it read
through the code base
it goes huh what would
a mesh look like and
it makes it right it's
what's cool is that
it actually figured
out that there are these
four topologies which
are core to the product
and that it needed
to accentuate those
and then like this is
better than mine like
i can build you want to
build swarms sure
here's a swarm builder
right like it doesn't
it's it looks way cooler
than my one which i
probably spent a week
on it's like huh so
we're getting pretty this
is where i was like
okay we're hitting a new
level of ai builder
right when when you can
build this with one
prompt and it's sort
of scary because i've
been web dev for 20 30
years like if someone
said make this this
you know probably take
a week in the old days
so to do that in 10
or 15 minutes with one
prompt i'm like this is
pretty amazing showcase
man oh what's possible
yeah yeah so that's
it that's fantastic
long story short is
i'm i'm still on swarm
and that's i'm just
trying to try to get
basically like agent garden
and permanent swarm
and then add the what's
called the neural
net and then sort of
connect them up so so
on this topology though
bron um but the when
you imagine the neural
net where are the
connections the connections
from the center of
the nodes to each node
or from the from the
agents to the to the
agents that's a kind of
a complicated yeah well
that's the thing
figuring out what should
connect should you
connect a whole swarm
should yeah and then
should you connect agents
from your swarm to other
agents or but that's
where you kind of need
like the other layer
right this is sort
of the playground but
and like you're saying
right the Claude engine
itself is actually
gets delegated and
actually does the work
so you you there's a
there's a mini to one
mapping yeah well that's
the thing cloud code
is really cloud code
is doing everything
you got to understand
right that these are
one sub millisecond one
kilobyte frameworks
for it they're not this
is not a whole bunch
of heavy duty code this
is like a prompt that
says you're literally
it's like saying you're
a ring and that's
it right so it's it's
not what's nuts is that
cloud code can follow
it you know like if
you gave this to most
llms you think they just
forget and you know
it does occasionally
cloud code will do too
much let's say it'll
it'll do half of it
in swarm and then and
then when it gets to a
bunch of tasks it'll go
yeah i've had enough
of swarm i'm doing it
myself and you know
it's it'll just because
it's doing it anyways
so it and yeah you
know cloud code isn't
dumb like you can do
what's called batch tool
so batch tool would be
like no mesh no agents
version of swarm
it'll do right five things
at once but when you
give it it's like you
know in the end we're
all going back to
prompt engineering you
know what what was
what is the difference
what is the system prompt
for anthropic right
it's all it's all
prompt it's so this this
is like prompt builder
for batch tool and the
best way to build a
prompt builder is to
use mathematical systems
and swarm topologies
and so i i think this
is great man because
this this really helps
people understand what
what claude swarm
and claude flow and
claude are you know this
is Mentally, getting
your head around it
takes a while. And as I,
let's say, as I prove
it's more than one-to
-one, I'll connect it.
But I don't want to
start with, like, if
I, when I first did it,
like I say, this had
roadmaps all over. And
then when I actually
grill it, it's like,
yeah, no, these are
just made-up rules. So I
need to see, okay, yes,
if you stick to the
rules consistently,
you know, on a regular
basis, I'll give you a
connection. but until
i could prove that
it's more than you know
giant these one-to-ones
then um i can't just
randomly appear this
is what it's like yeah
a bunch of yeah this
is you had a hundred
swarms but they're all
just hanging out doing
nothing right yeah so
braun was this created
with one prompt what
we're seeing here
visually was this what
the the output no this
this is the one prompt
see this swarm showcase
website this this was
the one shot right
is it like it actually
would work right now
or is it just the ui
no no okay this one is
uh live real time
interactive what is your
swarm doing how many
swarms you got how many
agents you have are
what are what's inside
them you know what what
tasks are they doing
this is this warm like
what did it do this
is the i nuked them but
you know events that
are happening so like
when you like rube
said with everyone
okay when you use cloud
code your screen goes
ballistic you can't even
read it so if you you
know i don't really
need to do more than
see what the **** was
my swarm doing you know
literally and i can't
yeah And, Ron, are
you using that output
format stream JSON
verbose to get the output?
Or are you just, like,
what are you querying
exactly? No, I use
hooks to push a whole
bunch of the stuff.
And then all of my, not
even hooks, but, like,
the NCP server itself
and the other actual
files that get run, I
dump into the SQLite
database. because SQLite
is a pooled instant
local database pool.
So because you can only
log, most swarms are
going so fast, you
can't, even if you
stream that, you're just
going to get a mess,
right? It's a lot
easier to just dump. I
realized with some
millisecond process, I just
dumped to the database
because I don't care
if I'm getting, my
brain isn't going that
fast. I one second is
fast enough for me I
just need to see it in
a clean organized you
know easy to digest
format and right now
what I'm trying to do
like when I ran this
I have a thousand events
in like five minutes
so I'm like okay I
don't want to see I
don't want to I don't
want to see all the
events so right now it's
more okay I can get it
all but it's like a
tidal wave so I gotta
I'm like did you have
to yeah spin up I was
going to say do you
spend a bunch of time
actually developing
code to to filter the
events that you're
actually most interested
in yeah the big headache
is that when you
get the cloud code hook
it's empty right it's
like give you a hook
okay it's a post hook
tool and it's on a
keyword uh you know file
write or whatever but
that that's kind of
it like you you have
to build every single
hook you want an event
you want you have
to make a custom output
for it right so you
then it's like well
i got and then i have
like 80 custom hooks
but but then i realized
i i don't really want
to bother wasting the
time resource or energy
on file read do i
really care about file
read maybe not maybe
i just want file
right only and so yeah
that you know it's all
about figuring out what
do you want to see
does it help you at all
you know is it is it
that mean you can you
can get it all it's
just what do you yeah
how does it help what
is it good good is it
and then yeah yeah if
you want to control
um you know i haven't
got to more control
because i have no
problem sort of launching
stuff and again my my
account gets disconnected
for some reason but
mostly i'm interested
in the connections like
this area here like
how in order in order
to go from we already
got swarms right let's
say we can make eight
or ten that's done
right so the next is how
do i get you know this
how does this whole
swarm work on something
the whole thing not
this one or this one
but you know how do we
get to let's say mass
or yeah because the
the the single swarm is
great but if the next
level is i can say
yeah use every swarm
here you know this whole
swarm goes nuts so um
really really that's
sort of the and then
and then we need the
we need the um we need
the the neural net right
we gotta have Yeah,
my Swarm connected
to your Swarm.
And then who knows?
Yeah, this is awesome
work, by the way,
Brian. I'm really
impressed. Are you going
to open source this?
Can we integrate this
with the Swarm project?
Yeah, I mean, my
stuff is a mask. That's
like my repo would.
You need a filter for
my repo. So once I
finish it to like, you
know, I'm kind of one
of those it's never
done guys. But once I
get it to 100% works,
the filters are clean
and everything else,
then I release stuff.
Yeah, so keep in
mind, there's a couple
things that you might
want to consider adding
that would give this
really cool feed function.
We've got the DAG
capability, which
would allow for a sort
of federated approach
to the swarms. So that
means that collectively
we could all connect
to your swarm securely
and collaborate,
which gives you a sort
of multidimensional
structure for tracking
all that information.
So rather than using
SQLite, you use SQLite
as a local sort of
cache. But if you write
it to the QDAG, then
you've got, you know,
you can create a share
button essentially and
say, you know, hey,
Jed, you can contribute
to the capacity
or the project or
whatever. and the and the
other part that would
be interesting here
would be using a kind
of hive mind structure
which allows it to uh
stay on point for more
complex applications
where you notice
after like 10 minutes it
sometimes forgets that
it needs to be in a
swarm it would solve
that problem yeah i
mean as ocean said how
long are we going to
stay with cloud code
because all of us know
we're working around
cloud code due to the
financial benefits but
not long i i've been
working on open code
all week to be honest
uh to get away from
cloud code but it's
cheap and easy for now
yeah exactly so long
forward to that nvidia
three thousand dollar
uh well tensor computer
well it's a little too
soon to say but our
nvidia is is offered
us uh some serious
horsepower to test our
swarms on you know it's
not three thousand
it's probably three
million but the um their
infrastructure they're
going to let us borrow
looks substantial
and then we can point
the swarm at it so if
anyone from nvidia
is on the call let's
let's hope they uh they
come through on that
um braun this is this
is amazing really
good work i love
what you're doing
and if you need help
and or contributors
i'm happy to jump
in and work on a
branch thanks yep
yeah this is awesome
has anyone awesome
work bra man
it's super
fantastic i love it
has brown have you
thought about open
telemetry or any of those
kind of hooks or existing
observability tool
tool chains i haven't
got past any of this
like between all the
other stuff i'm doing
um you know i just
debated i was debating
how much time should
i spend but i'm trying
to the main goal is
um getting let's call
the next level of
say swarm which is actual
swarm like you know
like we you want to
get to 100 or 200 or
a million or whatever
because when i first
loaded up swarm i
could instance 20 000
agents on you know it
was like maybe 10 megs
of ram and it took a
minute but then i'm like
okay i can i can
initiate 20 000 agents
but what could i get
them to do and who's
gonna manage how you're
gonna get you know
who's gonna manage
those that's you just So
we're almost there, but
you know, like right
now we're constrained
by the LLM cloud
code has a definite
max at around eight is
about its max efficiency.
So again, but once
the cloud code is down
and we have unlimited
API resource, then
it's just the framework
and the system. and
then you get into
there's an you know
there's definitely another
level of swarm
orchestration when you get
into it's it's like
a flock of a thousand
birds or whatever you
get in that kind of
thing right there's
other you know i don't
think mesh or whatever
is the right one for
thousands or millions
right you're getting
into uh i haven't even
researched like what's
the best way to control
a it's like ants
right and probably
that's the best animal i
can relate it back to
but when you have a
million ants you know
what are they all doing
and how do they work
together to achieve their
goal so uh we got a
little tiny high but
you know again once we
hook up if we can hook
up to if we can hook
up the whole agentex
.org everyone brings
their 20 30 even even if
we each have a cloud
code but we hook up
80 cloud codes you know
so there are we there's
a lot of configurations
and um but it's
cool that we kind of
broke open the box let's
say right now we're
all thinking about it
and you know we maybe
will be the first million
first million agents
form you know who
knows but uh i think
uh we have the toolbox
um and i also took the
because it's called
rube fan right so i i
actually got the fan
working right now i
can build my own fast
artificial neural networks
on the fly with cpu
or gpu and they can
um you know that's an
actual neural network
so i'm going to try to
integrate these with
the neural net and then
the mass mass agent so
because you know the
anyways there's there's
a lot of layers but
it's just round one
i don't talk to me in
two weeks or something
when i've had more
time i think i think
i think we got to move
on to the next uh
demo here i uh i think
someone else has a
dashboard they want to
show as well we have
a few today we had we
had chris barlow but
he's in new zealand and
i think i think he's
falling off the call
so um we had a open
session there was a
comment in there i saw
john petty had mentioned
that he's uh that
he has the agents
compete with each other
so he'll have a swarm
compete with another
swarm and then and i
just wanted to hear
that's that's just fyi
that there's a consensus
component within
the hive mind capability
within cloud flow
that that does that
wasn't that does that
so and you can monitor
how the consensus
within the agents and
how they collaborate
with each other and it
basically stores that
information in the
hive mind db yeah but
i'm curious to hear
what others are doing
Yeah, so I took
essentially that function
and spawn five different
examples of how
they would solve that
problem, have them
look at the problem
and propose solutions,
as well as the models
will create what
they're doing from a
score and prediction
standpoint, and then
Claude evaluates them.
And then the one
that ends up on top,
pretty much the top
two come out as the
win. And then it sort
of will go through,
depending on what
setting I have it on,
three iterations of
that. So it'll be
like two win, those
two stay, three
more come in, they
all compete again.
And then that'll
happen where like
three will stay and
then all the way until
there's, you know,
five that are all
scoring relatively
high, but in
different areas with
different approaches.
And then that
swarm will go
after solving
the problem.
I've found pretty good
success with that.
We're all learning
as we go here, by the
way. And we created
this system that
allows for a kind of
collaborative approach
to these sort of
ephemeral processes.
And I don't think any
of us fully understands
exactly how they
work, why they work,
or what the real power
of them is just yet.
I think we have made
the conclusion that
using these kind of
temporary ephemeral
processes makes these
systems work a lot
better at solving really
complicated things.
And in Bron sort of
set and forget sort of
example that he was
showing, he pointed out
a repo and create
me a web page, is a
perfect example of
this, right? If we had
tried doing that a few
months ago using Roo,
it probably would have
failed. It would have
taken a whole lot of
sort of finagling of
prompts and guidance
and back and forth. And
maybe eventually the
boomerangs might have
worked, but it would
have taken 30 hours.
Now what took 30 hours
is now happening in
a matter of a couple
hours or less. Yeah.
Hey, Rube, I'm actually
working on – it's
theoretical right
now. I don't have
anything to show as
everything is theoretical.
uh is a communication
protocol that
for those different
agents to somewhat
trim and evolve uh so
more of a long-term
agentic uh so so say
you have persistent
agents that are that
are doing different
automations and things
like that actually
communicating back and
forth with an orchestrator
and if they are less
um i want to say this
less um efficient
than another one or or
full of errors or
something like that then
the orchestrator can
cut that out of the
out of the system or
combine or combine two
agents into one system
um into another agent
so it's it's sort of
an evolutionary um
process so it's not
exactly in that same vein
but but it it still
has that how do we how
do we select which ones
are actually working
how do we you know
track that and how
do we you know have them
challenge each other
i think it's just a
different perspective
a different angle for
that amazing that's
that's so i love this
this is so i think i
like the way Watching
you and the rest of
the crew building these
things, I think it
just inspires me to
take it further. It's
really cool to see you
guys doing this stuff.
Here's a thought that
I would throw out,
Reuven, and the team,
right, is that currently
what we're building
here is all about
building apps, building
code, code development,
software coding
assist. but when we
start connecting swarms
together you're it
feels like we're
actually building it
becomes a really modern
framework for building
applications and
that actually you can
build an app and they
just it's just running
you know it's like a
really it's the ultimate
crew right or or
lang chain it's the
ultimate application
framework rather just
a decoding development
app yeah so I use a
similar backbone to
have it do marketing.
So research marketing,
go out, grab
information, bring it
in, run that across
intelligence, look for
viral content, all that
kind of stuff. And then
it creates a 90-day
roadmap of content. And
it's really powerful
for how much content
it can create. So
like, and it will live
update your roadmap.
So 90 days of content,
about 1,552 pieces
of social media content
across all channels
and even builds your
dialogue for your
videos and shorts and
TikToks and everything.
And each day it goes
in and looks at content
based off of what's
happening in the
environment and what
viral content is out there
and rebaselines and
moves that content.
There's so many
applications from
a, like this is
a foundational
framework and you can
apply it, you know,
probably to, I
think, anything.
So how does that
work in a, how does
the feedback loop
for that work?
Are you tracking
the metrics for what
amounts to the
earned media? Yeah.
Because putting out
a lot of content is
great. Yeah. Google,
Google ads, like all the
normal things that you
would be like *******
in from a metrics
perspective, go into a
dashboard and well,
this is speed traffic.
Yeah. I mean, it's
a whole website
and has, I can
probably demo it for
folks next week or
something, But yeah,
it's like a whole
website has like
multiple dashboards,
has a whole admin
center. Admins can
steer, reprompt,
you know, push, make,
create, or remove
content. There's a
budget section, how much
money you're putting
in, what are you
getting out, your CAC,
LTV, like all the,
you know, fun marketing
terms that I'm
not a market person.
So I just, you know,
listen to people
and see what I
can make. This may
be a worthwhile
expansion of
actual demonstrable
use cases of
agentic engineering.
Yes.
So breaking out
from app building
and breaking into
creative spaces.
That was my point,
Jed, is that we're
potentially going
beyond building apps
to a framework where
your applications
are just running all
the time in this.
And one of the things
you guys might want
to take a look at is
the neurodivergent
component we created
a few weeks ago. that
is made for time
series data. So the
reason I created that
was initially for some
of the work I was
doing with the neural
trading systems where
I was getting the
real-time stock data,
but that can be applied
to anything that has
time series data,
whether real-time
or historical.
And then you can train
the neural network
based on that information
to make decisions.
So rather than the
decision being sent to,
let's say the hive
queen and then being
interpreted by the
LLM, you're basically
saying, make the
determination and then send
that to the LLM to
execute upon. And
that's going to be
faster and more targeted.
And then the only other
thing Claude's doing
is basically being
told what to do, not
how to understand why
it needs to do it.
Sorry, I got a
question for John.
And how you managed
to do the competition
between the answers?
did you actually hard
code it somewhere yeah
there's I have a couple
different versions of
this like uh I forgot
who was speaking
earlier but the current
code base is a mess
because I've been doing
so many different
things in it just to
explore it more and more
and then like strapping
a lot of our code
into it too um just to
see like you know what
can you apply but uh
I have one version
where it's directly ML.
It's just ML models
that are trained based
off of like specific
outcome that I want to
see. And that's like a
more benchmark direct
approach. And then
there's an LLM evaluation,
the sort of like
using an O3 call and
an anthropic call using
those two judges and
then having those
judges evaluate outcome.
And then the other
one I've been playing
around with is like
the just straight
neural nets in
combination with the LLMs
using a similar
orchestration as the app
itself is doing. So
sort of like as you
have topical or changes
in subject matter,
the machine learning
is scoring and
applying that. That
goes into an index. That
index is feeding
input into the LLMs.
And then the LLMs
are reacting based
off of essentially
like engineered prompts
but you're not
training the model in
real time right
um i so i have an
experiment for that
that's actually in the
background right now
running on my 50 90
on hierarchical neural
nets and i used so
i haven't been able to
use the whole framework
yet i'm kind of like
still just starting
to piece this together
but i i created a
similar tool to what
Reuven created in this
that we that I called
nano agents and it
was actually for our
product um so I took
sort of like the nano
agents and combined it
with what Reuven did
and with the ML models
and ran that as
essentially like semantic
scoring on the front
end and that semantic
scoring um helps
steer the hierarchical
neural net at its chunking
layer at the first
input and then uh
i'm sorry at the
tokenization level level
essentially like at the
but well because
hierarchical neural nets
work off of uh bytes um
so smaller than tokens
sure yes yes yeah
so it actually makes
it easier and also it
also makes it inherently
multimodal because it
works at that level
so yes um but mainly
my experiment was
to see can i in real
time influence a model
as input is coming
in it added about 0.5
seconds of delay with
the model scoring but i
was able to see anywhere
between 15 to 23
percent depending on the
topic improvement i'm
sure with like some
tuning so actually i have
a 249 million wait is
that the right size
yeah um model that's
fine tuning it in the
background right now
and it's kind of fine
tuning itself based off
of hella swag so it's
just recursively running
through a thousand
questions from hella
swag and benchmarking
itself that using the
ml to score it the ml
then re-steers it and
then it informs the
essentially the the
models that are instantly
fine tuning like at the
top layer okay got it
that's a really good
architecture and and
what you're doing is
you're you can by using
a kind of secondary
i'm calling a
microscopic neural neck
attached to low cost
local models maybe low
performance models like
um you know any smaller
model you can get
substantially better
performance from them
because you're you're
not limiting yourself
to whatever that
small model needs to
do right so that that's
essentially I think
what you've articulated
is a kind of
implementation of that
strategy yeah it it I'll
I'll try to have it
in the place where
I can present it right
now it's like very
raw code but I actually
have a dashboard
that I watch while it's
doing fine tuning so
I can keep track of
it and see if it's
going off the first
couple batches actually
ended up with negative
results where the
model degraded but
I'm starting to see it
actually be able to
improve and re-steer. And
what's fascinating
is sort of topically,
the way I've built
it, or I've actually
gone backwards. The
first time I was
doing it was just
with one medium-sized
model. Then I started
moving into three MOE,
and then I moved
into a 20-layer MOE.
That MOE, even on my
5090, was outputting
similar benchmarks
to like GPT 3.5, all
running locally, only
using 30% of my 5090.
Quick question,
though. You're
not doing
distillation, right?
Currently, no.
I am not doing
distillation.
Okay, yes.
I'm looking
forward to seeing
this demo next
week, John.
I'm sorry.
We need to see a demo.
We need to see a demo
next week. yeah i'll
try to have i'll try
to have something
demoable by next week for
you i think jade was
uh jade jade was uh uh
putting you in line
for the demo nick for
next week yeah and and
just fyi you guys are
more obviously more
welcome to continue i'm
going on vacation
starting next friday and
uh if if i if i attempt
to tell my wife that
i'm gonna do this
while doing a road trip
i'll be in trouble
trouble so uh i i will i
will be away the next
few weeks are the kids
age that well they've
got what they call the
g1 license my 16 year
old which means he
probably can't go on a
highway but uh right um
next year then next
next year for sure but
yeah so i i won't be
back until i think the
uh whatever the week
of the 12th is so like
the 15th so two weeks
of demos demos demos
demos you guys are
more than welcome to do
whatever just just watch
out for for uh weirdos
and crazies to take
over this thing yeah
well i have that production
so we can probably
hold office hours rob
on thursday then or
thursday following right
that's a great idea
very cool no but it's
been it's been a wild
month though this well
actually month and a
half i guess you know
the the swarm stuff
only came out june 15th
right so we we've been
just five weeks crazy
yeah it's been crazy
anyone else have
anything they
want to show
present discuss
this is this is
your chance to
this is the
open mic portion
sure I just put
a little summary
of the webinars
we had I posted
it let me can I
share my screen
Confluence
yeah you know um
only because i
couldn't do it
elsewhere but
that's how i knew
how to do it so
uh can you see
my screen i think
you can yeah
um so all i did
was pull in um
some recordings
it pulls together um has
has the recording itself
it summarizes it
takes a summary and
then pushes that up
into top level table
so you can see
week by week what
was discussed nice
that's awesome
it'd be it'd be good
if we can put it
on a url so that
it's easier to find
and what yeah all
those recordings that's
all yeah we want them
to live in the member
site right the
community uh agenics.org
yeah so yeah i'm in
there great fantastic is
it yeah it's not a
problem and um you know
loom will actually
compress them so yeah
yeah it it will shorten
a given recording um
taking out the ums and
ahs and all the rest
of that as well okay
Then on the member
site, we can convert
this into either a
course or a tutorial based
on whatever information
you have. This is
awesome. Thank you.
Yeah, actually,
Loom, which is an
Alassian tool, as you
know, actually does
have a whole bunch of
ways of manipulating
video. So if you
go to up here,
Loom itself,
and then you can
edit by transcript.
How do we do that? Edit.
And as we're a nonprofit,
users for this
cost them about
$6. So it is
practically nothing.
This is taking a
little while to upload.
But as you can imagine,
you can do things
like remove silences,
all that kind
of stuff. It's pretty
standard nowadays.
um but it is useful
and we can um if
anyone's working on
building our content
we can give them
um a license to
um six bucks a seat
that's really good
okay um yeah um
that's it we have so
much content over
the last year yeah
and uh no thank martin
thanks for putting
that together that's
awesome i'm sure
we'll figure out a
way to use it even
if it's just a link
to that it's very
uh we very useful
one of the other
things people have
been asking about is
like our like
accreditation uh do we how
are we looking on
on that front, Brad?
What's that
process look like?
Yeah, so, yeah, we're
just getting started.
There's two
accreditations.
We're looking
for a sponsor to
help with our
not-for-profit.
So if there's any
sponsors out there,
a couple of bucks would
help to be able to
go be essentially a
learning institution. So
that will give us the
ability to get grants.
And then we're just
starting the accreditation
process for the
different levels. So I
think we're going to
be forming a group and
actually let's get
it done as quickly as
possible. And I'll
probably be talking to the
people that would probably
be passing the level
four or whatever we
call it, the top level
that we're helping
out with the
RUFAN as kind
of the leaders,
including RUF and Jed
and Braun and Ocean
and some of the other
top elite people to
make sure that we have
the accreditation.
Is that about a three
-month process or so?
So two different
things. If
we want the
accreditation,
before we get too
much further, it
does cost some
money. It's by course
I've gone through
to make sure that we
qualify, need like
100 hours of actual
real content and
all that kind of,
essentially the same
as what a college would
be at a high level.
There's different
programs in the U.S. and
there's one in Canada
that that we would like
to go ahead with. So
we do need some some
sponsors for that. And
then that's that's
on the one side that
opens up a whole lot,
a lot of money for us
for government grants.
And then for the
accreditation process,
we're just starting that.
So but I know we need
to get it going. We
just started a
WhatsApp, restarted it,
I think, yesterday for
the masterclass one.
uh one so uh initial
steps hopefully by
the time Reuven comes
back from vacation
uh we'll we'll have
a fair bit done so
if uh anyone wants
to get involved reach
out to me and uh we'll
get we'll get the
actual coursework done
well i'm gonna design
that i won't i will
not be able to at
this point be able
to pass the the final
accreditation i'll
need some training so
yeah we can also be
yes we'll all do the
course and then we'll
credit ourselves and
then we'll and and
once we're accredited
agentic engineers we'll
uh spread the uh you
know the the curriculum
far and wide or
something but i i
think i think our best
bet is to get get a crew
of us that are doing
this like what we
saw today and all
review each other's
work and and let that be
the first step yeah uh
scott you you've got
your hand up how you
doing hey um i wanted
to do a presentation
if we had a few
minutes yeah scott that's
right yeah cool cool
i'll share um so i
wanted to kind of
cover um the new stuff
in like the vllm space
um the lms are pretty
good at uh looking
at pictures now and
analyzing them and I
kind of wanted to step
through that and show
we can do now let me
share my screen so
to give a quick example
can you guys see
yep cool so if you
throw like a picture
into something like
oh three it'll start
digesting this image
agentically you can see
I say inspect this
photo deeply and tell
me the details about
the buildings start
thinking do a little
description and then
it'll start zooming
in on the image which
is actually pretty
cool and as it cuts
the image down it'll
start doing its image
description and then
reasoning about this
so in the foreground
you can see a tree
you've got the mountains
in the background
it's describing the
yellow buildings etc get
a little faster start
looking at the sky
start looking at this
building on the hill
and it actually does
a pretty good job at
describing the scene
and telling you a little
bit about the location
and i asked it to
figure out the location
at some point and
it was able to guess
somewhere in northern
italy um in the mountains
and it was completely
right so that's pretty
cool um so around
that we can start
building some software
um in response to
the palisade fires
i wanted to build
like an automated
***** inspector
which is like
the area around
your house that
comes up to the
wildlife areas
So I built an inspector,
prompt engineered
it, and this
is for, like, an
urban environment.
Let's see.
See a minimal risk.
It will tell you a little
bit of recommendations.
There's not much
for the urban
environment.
There's no hazards.
if we look at a more
rural environment with
like a wooden
house amongst
trees so it's
processing this
is a little
broken right here
but it finds
hazards gives you
a description
of those hazards
sees the grass it
sees the trees gives
some recommendations
and will tell
you quite a lot
about actually your
wildfire hazard
risk um this is a
job i kind of used
to do in the past
and i thought i'd
automate it and it does
a pretty good job with
off-the-shelf parts
so i thought that
was really cool
that we can get
to that point
with these
foundational models and
kind of want to
open up the floor
to to you guys
to ask about
what ways we can
kind of improve
agentic vision kind
of reasoning if you
guys had any ideas what
do you mean by improved
accuracy of the
context of the image
yeah just anything
that would make it more
reliable keep in mind
that most of these
image models are
actually just converting
the image to text right
when behind the scenes
so when you send an
image it's describing
it so to get a better
output you just
need to add a better
prompt that tells it
to describe it better
it's also nice that
it's segmented and
tag it the other um at
least with open ai
they accept images
represented in base 64
so let's assume they're
tokenizing against base
64 to represent the
image and then run
inference against that
knowing that you
need to remember that
the image that's submitted
to OpenAI is shrunk
to the smallest of
2000 by 768. So if
your image is bigger
than that resolution,
it will be shrunk
to that resolution
one. And then if the
subject that you're
asking questions about
does not materially
fill out the viewport
of the image,
it will not describe
that image well.
And I assume other
image-to-text models
operate in a similar way.
that's why like doing
something like
segmenting it and pulling
the segments out
and passing it for
identification would be
very helpful and also you
could tag it so
think about you know
terminators type image
of what you're seeing in
real time the other
side of this is also to
use lower level models
at a higher temperature
to increase randomness
and use a higher
level model to summarize
the lower level
models outputs to
coalesce where they agree
yeah there's a whole
category of vision
language action models
that are starting to
appear in robotics
that are really cool i
just i just dropped a
spatial lm in the in
the chat and it's it's
actually looking at
3d point data um on
different different
objects so it'll actually
give you the dimensions
of the object as
terministic data. So
models like this are
coming out and might
look at something
similar to that that can
structure it a
little bit better
so that you can identify
just based off
the point data.
And that spatial LM,
there's the one
on hugging face.
you can run it like
on local real easy on
like small hardware and
it is real time like
it is actually assessing
in real time and
if you stream what
it's doing with like
camera it can actually
draw those lines over
your output if you
do it right it is it
is mind-blowingly good
But there's even a
pocket LLM that runs
on your phone that does
that. You can send
it your video feed,
and it'll basically
give you an annotation.
And it can probably
leverage the LiDAR point
3D stuff, too. Yeah,
it'll take in LiDAR.
Spatial will. Yep.
Yeah.
I was going to say,
the other cool thing
is if you take
that and you record
the Gaussian blur
from it, and you can
actually go back
in 3D space and see
what it assessed and
how it assessed it
with the boxes over
it. It's awesome.
Yeah.
John, do you have a
name of the model,
the Hugging Face
model you mentioned?
Somebody dropped it in
chat, but it's
Spatial LM.
They have demos and
stuff, but I mean, I
have to say I played
with it and for the
size it is I my mind
is blown like it I
think this is probably
one of the most
impactful like
developments of the last
six months from a what
can like the power
and the demos that
I've seen of this like
in apps is just
it's it's incredible
so what what's happening
in like NVIDIA's
edge devices like Thor
and you know that's
going to be the
next gen or more and
google is putting out
they're taking a gemini
model and they're
reducing it to run on
a robot to do real-time
bla because you you
can't afford the event
loops have it step
on the baby before it
realizes there's a baby
there right so it's
really i signed up for
it but they haven't
you know they haven't
gone public with it
you can sign up to get
access to that model
but they're trying to
pare down the model
to do exactly what a
robot would need to to
be able to do in real
time and that's a lot
of that vision language
action stuff so really
cool stuff coming
on right now yeah it's
i it's really impressive
the ability for the
spatially reason
within the llm itself
that's kind of impressed
me the most the fact
that i can kind of
determine this is like
10 feet away and it
gets it pretty right
i'm there's a lot less
hallucinations than i
thought there would be
um i'm curious where
we'll be in like six
months or so but so
this is a fun topic i
don't know if you saw
the white paper by uh
yale and mit specifically
on physics and
math uh and llm so if
you take an llm and you
leverage it to predict
uh like an astral
body where it'll be
it will get very very
close it will predict
very very accurately
and it's sort of this
the nature of prediction
right is kind of
built into what an llm
does and and language
right the fabric of
our reality is how we
process information and
we start to create
predictions of where
these things exist but
if you tell it to or
ask it to do the math
it will do horrible
math right it has to
have tools or it has to
use something but like
if you just directly
tell it like hey
cool do the math for
this like you're not
you know if you're an
astronaut stuck in space
you're going to die
so it it's it's
fascinating it's a really
good paper i highly
recommend it i'll go look
for it and try to drop
it in the group um
feed but like it it it
gets back to this whole
like um digital twin
side of things the
prediction like and
creating these sort of
synthetic spaces similar
to what we're doing with
the like swarms but
if you take that and
you think about um
computer hardware like in
software um what's
interesting is i have one
code base that i've
been playing around with
essentially like using
an llm to simulate
an entire operating
system and it like
generates the ui like in
like as you're asking it
or you know using commands
now there's layers
and a whole bunch of
other stuff but it's
fascinating that you
can get almost like
an operational computer
just through prompts
interesting crazy so
that that's actually an
interesting concept if
we did a just-in-time
os where we use some
kind of uh you know
real-time compilation
as you make the requests
and it creates like
windows and things like
that yeah so i give
it you know i give it
indexes and formats
right so it's not jumping
all over the place and
doing crazy but But
it's essentially able
to, you know, you want
an inbox and it
creates an inbox and it
looks at what the API,
you know, that it's
calling, whether it's
Google or Outlook and
reforms its, you know,
input data to that API.
And it works like,
but, you know, it's not
the fastest thing in
the world, but to what
Reuven was saying,
like, you do something
with like what he's
built for that backbone
and and give it better
frameworks. And I bet
you could probably
come out with something
that's pretty crazy
below people's minds.
Yeah.
Well, we're almost out
of time. I got to jump.
Appreciate it. This
week went a lot
better than the
last. So thanks for
everyone who showed
up. I'm going
to be away over
the next few weeks.
So just to Martin's
point earlier,
someone other than me
is going to have to
create the zoom for
the next few weeks uh
and share it to uh who
has the um the control
do we have who has
the the team has the
control for that ruben
i have control of
the agent's accounts
so it makes sense if
i do it we're we're
going to be uh having
the production run
through new nvidia next
week let's let's let's
maybe hold off until
i'm back on that it
makes no sense to start
when i'm away yeah
okay well we've got
access to that we've
got access to it when
you when you do get
back or what have you
you know what we could
do I'm leaving on Friday
but what we could do
maybe if I could fit
in on Thursday is we
could use our live
you know vibe coding
session as a test
run of sorts using
whatever it is that we're
deciding to use
riverside or whatever
but yeah I think
it just makes more
sense to maybe start
that when I'm back
you've got two weeks
I think the way
it falls, it
sort of unfortunately
falls over.
I won't be back until
the 12th of August.
So whatever that
week is. So I think
there's two weeks that
I won't be around.
But we will see
you next Thursday.
Thursday I should
be able to do. Yeah.
Awesome.
So excited.
And shout out to
NVIDIA for helping
sponsor and providing
us some resources
to make it happen
is that a longer
term a long-term
thing guys we'll
see or just a one
-off sort of deal
we're still we're still
working through the
details but they're
they're currently
happy to help and we're
happy to accept that
help that's right yes
of course that's great
and while we're while
i'm saying it and
if anyone else you
know knows of you know
corporations or people
with money who are
looking to uh support
a non-profit you know
we're happy to have
that conversation and
obviously because
we're non-profit there
are tax benefits
apparently for folks who
are looking to use that
approach I guess if
you've got a ton of
really valuable AI stock
we're happy to help
you need to take a
donation through a
charity for them to get
the tax benefit that's
right so we're happy
to explore that but
otherwise you know we
can just do a great
uh financial uh
engagement of some sort
that helps keep the lights
on that's probably
a conversation for
david and others to
figure out exactly what
that means but uh yeah
so i decided to see
where this all goes
until next time super
jack i think so all
right peace everybody