All right, top of
the hour, April 18th,
2025.
Time's flying
by, although it's
still winter
here in Canada,
but it's a special
great Friday.
No, it's just good.
But thanks for everyone
that's joining on
this day. Maybe we'll
get a different audience
because it's a holiday
in a lot of places.
Hackers Race
Holiday Edition.
We're getting a bit of
feedback from you, Rob.
You sound like
you're in an
interdimensional portal,
which might be part
of our upcoming
presentation today.
Unfortunately,
the Roo community
manager couldn't make it.
I guess it's a
holiday, and he
didn't realize
he was signing
up for a holiday
presentation.
So I guess you
can't really
blame him, so
maybe next week.
But the Roo guys are
doing some really
cool stuff. And
the holiday guy,
Hans, I think his
name is, is based
in Edmonton,
Alberta, Canada. So a
fellow Canadian.
So that's kind of
exciting, at least
if you're Canadian.
But, Rob, do we
have anyone else?
Yeah, we have Vincent
from France. He's
got a project he's
been working on with
some Japanese clients,
and so he's got
something pretty
interesting to show.
So we've got
Vince there, and
then there's
been so much that
dropped over
the last week.
Roof,
congratulations on
the Spark. The Spark
framework is pretty
widely adopted now.
So there was a
Genics, a Genic
engineering, your
six-month preview or
foreshadowing of deep
research, the Spark
framework, and now
the Spark-centric
Roo custom modes.
It's blowing up.
Yeah, I guess it
needed the Roo guys,
but hey, it's
exciting to see it.
everyone starting to use
that sort of approach
and then and basically
you know if you
hear me blabbing
enough you realize that
you know it's just
basically adding tests
and a loop on those
tests but you know it it
doesn't need to be
the most complicated
solution in the world
for it to work i guess
and that's what's
kind of cool about the
idea of spark is give
it give it some plans
and an outline and
allow it to test and
and have the results
of that test feedback
to the llm to fix until
there's no more errors
that's it that's the
entire master plan
there but it seems to
work great um and if
the magnitude oh
what is it it's the
magnometer we'll get
into that you've got lots
to show this week yeah
before i do though
brad's got an update
for us from the world
of a the argentic uh
foundation which we're
still busy working
towards making happen
and thanks everyone
who's volunteered to
help. We've got a variety
of working groups.
Brad.
Thanks,
Roof.
Happy, good
Friday, everyone.
Happy holidays.
Two big announcements
this week.
We hit some
major milestones
with the Agentix
Foundation.
Thanks for giving me
the time for our plug.
We hit 800 official
members that
have signed up
through the website.
So we have 802
members right now.
of those 73 are
active we're starting
to have have a little
bit of money in
the bank so we're
we've got all these
amazing committees
doing a lot of work
we've gotten quickbooks
set up we've got
requesty set up we've
got we're getting all
the the infrastructure
set up so we do
actually have some
money in the bank that
we're going to be asking
the committee committee
chairs submit your
budgets because we
have to do some planning
from there so so
that that's some good
news is We're ready to
actually light the
fire under the rocket.
Last week's volume
was down by 3% from
the previous week,
but $390 net new.
LinkedIn, LinkedIn,
we, oh, sorry,
go on. $390
was net new,
net new people.
And keep in mind,
that is a MRR, which
is a monthly recurring
type of amount.
So assuming not
too much churn, you
can multiply that by
12 to get the sort
of yearly on that.
So it's not bad.
And thank you to
everyone that signed
up for Fantir,
agentic members or
above. We've had, I
just want to acknowledge
on Fireflies in
the recording, I
want to thank you
to Daniel, Rami B,
Sian,
Dimitri, Thomas,
Siad V, and Mandeep
C. Thank you.
Those are our newest
members this week.
Uh,
and, uh, last
announcement
is the, the LinkedIn, um,
roof. I think it's a
great viral strategy,
having the little
infinity symbol
and having people
sign up as associate
members. We cracked
the hundred, um,
associate members. So
our employer base, when
you look at LinkedIn
is 102 employees
and we have a 1352
followers. So that's
it for me. Thanks.
Thank you everyone.
Great. Hey, when you
said 70, 73 are active
what do you mean by
active uh sorry 73 when
i say active these
are active paying
members so these are
people that have an annual
subscription a monthly
subscription uh so
there's there's 73 that
uh that um that have
contributed um that
that are that are
members they they help
pay keep the lights on
right now and help
us um pay a couple of
the api costs and stuff
awesome We're still
we're completely a
volunteer basis, but
they're helping us keep
the lights on and get
to the next level. So
that's it. Thank you.
Yeah. So if you are
interested in helping
support us, it's
it's 10 bucks. And we
we're going to be
launching a bunch of
different services
that only members will
get. One of the things
that we're waiting
on approval from
Google is we're using
the Cal.com platform
to basically allow
you to have an agentic
style calendary.
you know it's it's uh
basically a clone of
that but it's it's a
nice little additional
value it's cheaper
than calendary by 10
bucks a month so um
you will and we're
gonna have a variety of
other sort of services
and agents and
things that that our
members will be able
to use that that's our
plan so what we build
will become you know
things that you you
can use as services as
a benefit to the
membership, if you will.
All right. So we've got
the little demo thing
here. And one of the
things that people ask
me a lot of is, you
know, how do you build
anything you dream up,
right? And literally,
a lot of this is
dreaming up new crazy
things. So yesterday, I
saw a new article that
was looking at this
idea of quantum sensing
systems. And there
was a startup that had
built the platform and
of course i was curious
like you know how much
work would it be to
sort of re and you
know reinvent reinvent
what they were what they
were doing so i went
into chat gpt's deep
research and i just want
to quickly show you
how i go from deep
research to a functional
implementation literally
overnight and this
is something i i was
you know i was up
relatively late doing last
night but it was built
between uh about nine
o'clock last night and
this morning so that
is this is what I want
to show you so I'm
going to start with
with the concept so for
those that are not
familiar there's this idea
of a quantum uh base
sensor system and what
this does is essentially
uses something called
magnometers which
measures the magnetic
sort of resonance and
oscillation within uh
sort of our place on
the planet both on it
below it and as well
as our sort of location
within this sort of
cosmic background noise.
I know it sounds
crazy. And I
was going for
the craziest
thing I could
possibly think of.
And so basically
what this does is
allows you to get
direct positioning
anywhere essentially
in the universe.
So hypothetically, if
you were looking to
sort of, you know, travel,
you know, in a sort
of interstellar fashion,
you're not going
to be able to use fixed
points. Everything's
moving. So you need a
mechanism to say, where
exactly are you, right?
and and this this
can work both on a
temporal scale as well as
a sort of multiple
dimensions i'm talking
like four dimensions
again it's crazy the idea
was to find something
crazy and so for for
use cases this allows
you to use essentially
um positioning for
things like robotics and
drones or the ability
to detect things within
the the earth itself
like you know deposits
of minerals or gold
or metal or, you know,
hydrocarbons, those
sorts of things. And
without the need to have
any kind of GPS system
to define the location
because it happens
underwater or underground
or in places that
aren't accessible. So
to, if that wasn't crazy
enough, what I did is
I ordered one of these
boxes you get from
China that allow you
to get all those television
channels for free.
I don't care about the
television channels,
who has time to watch
TV. But what I want
to do is use the chip
inside of it, which is
this Cortex-class chip
that basically is a
mobile phone. And rather
than having to go and
use a Raspberry Pi
or some other system,
I'm like, I could just
get this sort of Android
in a box for TV and
repurpose it to run
my, uh, my FPGA and
various components. All
right. The other part
is the cost of these
magnetometers, which
magnetometers are, it has
dropped from hundreds
of thousands of dollars
down to literally
hundreds or less now. So
the, the, the ability
to do this crazy idea
is now practical and
feasible. So the, the,
the next part of the
process was I go into,
my trusty Roo Spark
system. And I devise and
build the entire
structure, which is what
I ended up doing. So
the key here and how I
built it was a combination
of the research.
So I went into deep
research and I did a ton
of sort of, well, I
didn't. The AI did a
ton of research into
what it is and how it
needs to work. And it
goes into all the depths.
Then once I have that
research in place and
this is you know this
is a ton of information
right and then what
i do is i create a
plan and the plan again
this is the the spark
approach that basically
says here's here's
what the stack looks
like here's what how it
needs to work here's
how i bootstrap and
this is give or take
about 30 to 40 000 lines
of code that's being
implemented and mostly
without much involvement
for me so then you
can see here that it's
building out the various
models it's building
out and it built out
an mcp interface so i can
i can programmatically
interact with
directly from the the
llm and all the other
other stuff but give or
take uh about six
hours of it working and
about twenty dollars in
cost it actually popped
up the entire functional
um application
and this morning and
you know in a fully
capable manner and and
essentially and i can i'll
show you the cli
working here in a minute
but basically it gives
you the ability to
do things like gps
repositioning so for example
i'm not too too big on
the military context
but hypothetically
you can use this to
avoid you know uh gps
uh jamming devices and
or or moreover being
tracked so gps can track
anything that's connected
to it it's literally
the most efficient
tracking system ever
devised so you can
bypass that essentially.
So for things like
stealth for, for, you
know, aerial and drone
systems, if you want
to have swarms of micro
drones, you can use
that with, so you
don't have to have the
overhead or, and power
consumption of a GPS.
You can define
all kinds of other
crazy, you know,
types of use cases for
it. So that's, that's,
that's basically
what you can, this
is like pushing
the boundaries of
what's possible.
If you can build this,
you can pretty much
build anything um this
afternoon i'm finally
going to uh publish my
client side implementation
of the mcp um i've
published i've
published my dashboard
you can this will be self
you can host it yourself
but basically what
this will do will allow
you to go and create
an integrated mcp
that's that's directly
resolvable and operatable
on from the browser
versus a server So
that means any website
can communicate with
any other website. You
can test it. You can
create little agents.
You can go in here and
see. You can create
your own configurations
if you want,
endpoints, all kinds
of stuff for MCP. But
for those that are
interested, this is
specifically web-based,
browser-based. That
means it doesn't
require any server. Once
this is compiled to
VJS, it'll run basically
in your browser and
do everything you
need. So it's kind of
a cool way. I couldn't
find anyone else that
had done a client
-side implementation
of either MCP or A2A.
So, you know,
I wanted to do
that mostly just
because I could.
But you can see I can
create agents. I can
run those agents. I
can create tasks. So in
this case, I've got an
edge function if you
want to deploy additional
agents. In this case,
I've got a local agent.
So I can do a simple
query or an echo, and
then I can run it.
You know, and we can
see here that I actually
am operating the
actual SSE. you can see
the artifacts all
organized various other
parts so if i want to
create a new template
i can create templates
based on different
different i've had a
whole bunch extra if
i add those back so
all kinds of different
options for you you can
see i've got you know
different uh skills
available this is this
is just the default
one but depending on
what you're choosing you
get lots of different
options but you attach
files productive
week for random
creation of stuff to say
the least i'm going
to pause for a moment
there that was a bit
of me rambling about
quantum sensing networks
and any any any comments
am i am i losing it
am i totally crazy
or what isn't it for
sure no um no this is
wild i've been i've
been prompting chad to
be at the same time to
just try to translate
the complexity of
this so simplifying it
this is basically like
the evolution of the
compass it's like
actually using magnets
like or like like very
hyper specific like
magnetic signals and
i guess they're every
single spot on the
earth or i guess in the
universe apparently
is has like a unique
magnetic pole and it's
not impacted by weather
or anything like that
so this is this is
wild yeah and that
was that was often an
extended body of existing
science that had not
yet been actualized.
Is that right, Roof?
Yeah, I saw an
article about this
company that came
out yesterday.
QControl has a product.
Yeah, QControl.
That's the company.
So QControl announced
that they had done
this breakthrough. So
I'm like, all right,
that sounds like a
hard problem to solve.
So I basically pointed
at the deep research
at QControl and said,
reverse engineer it
wow yeah infinite
intelligence uh i just
have another question
uh ruf are you able
to do a demo of the
quantum gps how it works
so i can kind of wrap
my head around it
well i'm i'm i'm getting
going now for some
reason my my code
space is giving me
trouble but uh i i will
i do i have it it's
pretty exotic hardware
involved in that how
are you doing like the
quantum entanglement
that you need to to
be able to do this
uh running i run
simulators and unit tests
so the between the
two that gives me
a a framework for
here i i i did of
course it's going
to give me an error
right when i want
to do the demo
let's see here one
second yeah exactly
And one of the big
things when you're going
through building this
is using Roo to create
all the plans. And
then you mentioned the
TDD, like the test
-driven is the big loop.
Roo Spark. Yep.
Roo Spark and then
the test-driven. Yeah,
and the tests provide
a kind of feedback loop
of sorts that allows
the system to understand
how to operate and
what the sort of
structure of that operation
is. And so essentially,
as I'm building, I'm
using a theoretical
starting point that
basically describes
what's the structure
of how these sensing
components need to receive
information, and then
what is the response
of the appropriate
output of these sensing
devices in terms of what
does it need to look
like if it's true and
factual, right? So
what I'm doing is I'm
creating a test-driven
simulation of all the
required hardware
components that I obviously
don't have access to.
And then it iteratively
goes and builds, tests,
builds, and tests
until all the components
are functional.
Once it's functional,
what I'm doing is
I'm implementing a –
let me just pull up
my VS Code for a moment
so I can show you
a little bit more. I
think I promptly broke
it right before the
call this morning.
I should have quit
while I was ahead.
But so if we go here
for a moment, and you
can see I've got MCP
and I've got different
sort of interfaces
for it, FastAPI. But
in this case, what I
did is these tests.
You'll see that I've
got all these tests to
sort of define whether
or not the system is
true, factual, and
capable. and then I've
got data that allows
me to define the other
structures itself so
the system is one self
-learning it allows it
to iteratively build the
scaffolding but that's
not the part that's
probably most important
the part that's
important is it's self
-optimizing once I've
built it I need to find
coherence in the output
that validates that
the information can be
you know interpreted
it in real time because
speed is going to be
really important because
i'm i was looking
at sub millimeter um
sort of defined
location on on and multi
-dimensional vectors
basically based on that i
then need to be able
to make sure that i'm
building an algorithm
that's capable of
understanding that
fast enough that
it's faster than
the thing is moving
or you're potentially
moving so i'm assuming
that that this will
be anywhere from you know
a person a stationary
object to a supersonic
you know avionics
or something and
everything in between and
that's what what these
systems are essentially
testing all along the
way so then i need
to you know run
different plans and tests
and let it run forever
and and that's that's
what we eventually got
and then the the last
part was i needed to
um i think the sim nav
is the one i i can
run here then i then i
needed to simulate it
you know and so i use
an mcp to sort of
simulate back and forth So
if I go into my scripts,
I think I type on.
Oops, I'm getting
errors this morning.
I apologize here. Yeah,
I moved everything
to a new folder and
promptly broke everything.
But basically, I could
probably fix this
in two seconds, but I'm
not going to do that
right now. But basically,
it will run and
simulate everything it
needs to simulate. And
then the move from a
simulated environment
to a hardware, a true
hardware environment,
is a matter of just
making a few tweaks to
the API or SDK that
would likely involve
directly integrating
with the hardware itself.
That was a long
-winded answer,
but hopefully
that made sense.
the dynamics of
being able to take uh
concepts in science and
turn them into something
that is testable
within 24 hours yeah
and keep in mind for
those who want to
fool around with it
this is meant to be the
most complicated
project possible so but
that said point point
your room or your
codex at it it'll fix
any of the problems
i i've been running
this all morning
without any issues up
until I broke it 10
minutes ago. But isn't
that always the way?
Yeah, so again, if
anyone asks you, you
know, if AI development
is there yet,
just point them at
a few of these and
that should shut
them up pretty quick.
One more question,
Roof. So are
you using Claw
3.7 on Roo? or
are you using
GPT-2 4.1 models?
I can't get GPT
models to work with
Rue. I don't know
if maybe you guys
have had more luck
with that than
I have, but I
struggle with that.
The problem is the
actual prompts are so
specifically tailored to
Sonnet that they don't
seem to translate
particularly well to
other models. Now, it's
not that those models
like Gemini 2.5 are
bad. It's just they
require different
prompting. and so there's a
lot of trial and error
to get that to work
and it literally, you
find it can't quite
follow the boomerang
instructions for creating
new tasks and completing
them consistently
no, it's not the boomerang
the boomerang task
is a little easier
it's pretty fine as an
orchestrator it's not
good as an implementer
yeah
the orchestration is
pretty straightforward
it has to know that
new underscore task
attempt completion
or something
things it needs to do
but once you've done that
it seems to
work pretty good
Would you mind
sharing your
initial new underscore
task because
there's a few of us
that can't seem to
get the orchestra
to hand things off
Oh okay yes let me
show you that quick and
this is a problem
people seem to run into.
So I'm obviously
trying to fix my Monte
Carlo simulator as
we speak, but that's
okay. What I'm going
to show you quick
is, so the prompts.
So we go to prompts,
you can see I've
got all my different
prompts here and we've
got global modes.
So this is what describes
the orchestrator.
So this is, we can
get off my gist. Oops,
it's coding. But essentially
what this is just
specifying how to how
it needs to orchestrate
now the key here is
if you're if you're
not using sonnet 3.7
thinking you need to
kind of remind it that
it needs to use the
new and the uh what
was it i think it's new
underscore task yeah
so for whatever reason
it needs to be reminded
of this so oh okay
stop coding already
and what once you once
you're reminded of
this if you're not, if
you're not using the new
task. And then there's
the other part that
needs to be reminded.
It's, I think
I put it near
the end here, if
I'm not mistaken.
Yeah. Attempt completion.
So basically
attempt completion.
Oops.
It's sorry.
It's all right.
It's doing a few things
here. Sorry guys.
It just ran, it just
ran the simulation.
All right. Okay.
So I'm, I'm
jumping around
my, my ADHD is
getting the best
of me today.
Um, all right. So two
things, two things are
happening simultaneously.
I fixed the Monte
Carlo simulation. So
back to the quantum
for a moment, uh, to get
to the quantum coherence
that I needed, I
needed to create a
simulated environment.
And I found that, uh,
uh, a Monte Carlo
simulation was actually the
best mechanism to do
that. So now I can run
the multiple iterations
of the same and look
for a convergence on
the coherence, which
I didn't think I'd say
in a sentence today,
to get the optimal
location. And once I did
that, so now that I've
got a sort of simulated
world view of the
system, I can then
interface it with other
models and AI systems.
And then I can do
mapping overlays and all
kinds of stuff with it.
But essentially what
I'm doing here is a
Monte Carlo simulation.
And I can
hypothetically do that
on GPU a million
times a second.
So, Ruf, obviously, in
multi-color simulations,
we look at different
scenarios, and we
are trying to converge
onto particular
specific scenarios.
So, have you actually
defined the virtual
world in which you are
actually trying to
locate a particular, that
you're trying to navigate
through this app?
Yeah.
So, I'm using
publicly available
data sets that have
mapped the surface
and subterranean
surface of the
planet, and then
I load those maps.
um and again it's
it's it sounds like
science fiction i i even
try to describe it is
is actually hard to even
describe efficiently
but in this case
we've got mapping
and so there's a whole
interpolation 2d grid
component so what this
does is essentially
loads in a vectorized
version of the
topographical structure
of the planet based
on a combination of
magnetic signatures,
oscillations, and the
quantum signatures
of those in relation
to where you are. And
more importantly, to
make it useful, you
can then define, you
know, based on a sort
of model, what and
how those correlate to
things like what kind of
minerals are underneath
you. Is it water?
what's the density
of that information of
that of that material
once you've got the
idea of what the
density of the material
is you can make the
correlation between a
hydrocarbon versus h2o
or gold versus silver
or or any other
number of different
you know tactics and
capabilities that relate
to the the velocity
in which you're traveling
or where the planet
is situation in
relation to the rest of
the universe we need a
gold detector quantum
gold detector out of
those this is what
it is it's essentially
it is it's a quantum
gold detector you
could do diamonds too
i'm thinking like i'm
thinking like a gaming
interface on top of
it with to give a
virtualized experience
would like really be very
engaging for a lot of
let's do that so so
so let's let's let's use
my spark orchestrator
as an example i'm
going to create a quick
uh i'm going to create
a quick uh branch
here because i don't
want to screw up the main
branch but let's say
we want a a uh you
know ui so we'll call
it uh call it ui or
something sorry just just
to step up back a bit
so right now you have
a way to find precious
minerals and then
being able to gamify it
so you can have hundreds
if not millions of
people to play a game
to actually research
for precious minerals
is that kind of
where the rare earth
minerals like this
is where the potential
crowd sourced uh
crowd sourced um
top of graph why not
dream big uh yeah
topographical map of
magnetic magnetic
signatures that are
contributed by various
users of this flat
platform in slash UI
has a, uh, node JS
Vite JS application
modular use a, uh,
DVD based, uh, approach
and, you know, use
new underscore new, new
underscore task, uh,
for each
Sub tasks, you
know, start with a
detailed multi-phase
development plan as a
series of, I don't
know, MDs in plans
subfolder. Something
like that, right?
We're vibe coding here,
right, at this point.
And so this was like
a random idea. Yeah.
So I got thinking
turned on for the
orchestrator. I use 3
.7 for the implementer.
I've got the
Spark orchestrator
turned on. Now, if
all is well, this
should automatically
spawn subtasks.
This is literally
just by coding where
normally I'd have a
much more in-depth plan,
but whatever. Let's
just see what it does.
So now the first step
is- So you are running
your Spock system,
Reuben. You're running
your Spock system-
Right now. With this,
it's MCP, right?
I do use MCPs a lot,
so not currently in
this one because I'm
building MCP, but this
actual implementation
includes an MCP UI.
What I was thinking
for the MCP component
for this is if you
had a series of swarm
elements like sensors
or drones or whatever,
they could all communicate
using a quantum
sensing-based
communication channel. So
the other use case
for this type of
technology is you can
create subterranean
communication channels
that aren't limited by
the density of rock
or metal or whatever,
because it uses a
quantum interference.
So that works
underwater, it works in
outer space, it works
under a mountain.
So I was thinking MCP
could be the unit of
interaction between
each of those sensors.
And again, this
is sci-fi. Yeah,
I know. We're
talking so far here.
You've just got to seven
espressos this morning.
Yeah. Oh, Canada.
Oh, right.
Yeah. But yeah, but
everything you're seeing
is 100% validated by
it. Right. And that's
the but so it sounds
unbelievable. But
it's, it's if you dig
through it and run all
the tests, They all
pass. They all work.
They're all verifiable.
And they're all
backed by actual
research. And it's exactly
the same thing that
the Q control guys did.
Sure, sure.
And just to
clarify, in your VS
Code IDE, you are
running Spark, your
Spark 2 system,
right, to help?
Yeah, so you're seeing
it run. So now it's
come up with a
crowdsourced topographical
mapping system that
you guys suggested.
I just, you know,
let's rumble a bit.
Basically, anyone
who has these
devices can
contribute to a
global sort of
mapping system.
You're right.
So this is how easy
it is. Once you
build the core, then
you can just vibe
on additional
use cases for it.
Graphical user
interfaces, a mapping
system, a mobile
phone app, whatever.
So it's going to
create the plan. After
it creates the plan,
then it's going to
implement the scaffolding
for the updated
code. Then it's
going to do a series
of tests that iterate
back and forth.
And who knows,
maybe by the end of
this call, you
guys will be able
to see it fully
functional. But
this will now run
until it's done.
Can you show the
file view in VS Code
so we can see if
it's building out
files as it's
going there, right?
Yeah, you see it's
currently building out
additional. So I
stopped at the MCP
implementation last
night. So basically, when
I went to bed last
night, give or take
one in the morning, I
had the core working
and verified. Then
I'm like, okay, I
need to have a MCP
interface because what
doesn't have an MCP
interface these days?
And then I went to bed.
And then in the morning,
the MCP was fully
built. I tested
it quickly.
Everything worked.
And then I published
it. You can see
that, you know,
it's created various
scripts. We've got,
you know, the data
structure, you know,
a notebook, get the
locus, get different
examples, and then
we can see the actual
core. So we've got
the filters. So this
filter is noise.
We've got mapping,
MCP components.
It even did the MCP
documentation here.
We've got, you know,
lots and lots of stuff.
Again, give it to about
30,000 lines of code.
The token cost.
Sorry, you said the
token cost. cost 20
bucks 20 bucks well
less i think i let
less i think i i took
a look i don't have
exactly this is the
only thing i was
working on overnight
so i get the general
idea here let this
is this is how this
is how i can tell
let's uh let's go to
uh requestee and see
what my my last uh
oops what's going on
here so so did you
actually did you
actually integrate the
um the codex as well
into your because
generally it shoots
quite a lot high in my
experience but did
you use codex as well
i started codex
didn't get me very far
unfortunately it's not
very good automation
it it it basically
did about five
percent so costs
let's just do 24 hours
this will give us a
general idea we'll have
to subtract from my
work yesterday but
you can see you
can see it working
overnight a little bit
i'm not so basically
the cost this is
how much so this
is basically it's
less than $27 to
I spent $27 in the
last 24 hours 24 hours
yeah so I think it's
probably about 20 bucks
so I started this around
around 7 o
'clock last night
but apparently I saved
$89 in the process
I have a question about
session tracking you
say let it run overnight
what if something
happened your laptop
battery died whatever
and you want to resume
the session is there a
way to instruct you to
keep track of milestones
so that if the session
restarts it doesn't
have to start from the
beginning yeah I've
got it I've got another
I've got another
system that I've devised
that does that i can
run vscode instances
remotely as code spaces
or just on vms and now
the benefit of that
is i can you know
interact with it through
a agent that basically
pings it every now and
again checks what the
status is and then
can interact with the
um extent the the root
code extension
programmatically um i i i did
publish i think i published
it i don't remember
let me let Let me
just check quickly. I
create so much stuff,
it's hard to keep track.
But if you go to my,
the agentics org,
yeah, there it was,
agentics org edge agents.
And let's see if I,
did I push it? I
don't even remember.
In the Spark folder,
is it Spark scripts?
Actually it
might be scripts.
I didn't, I don't
think I published
it yet. I will
publish it. I've got a
VS Code implementation
that does it.
I create so much
stuff, it's hard to
remember what I publish
and what I haven't.
Yeah, unfortunately,
it might be one
of my, here it is,
VS Code April 12th.
I just haven't published
it yet to main.
So if you go to one
of my subs, this is 79
commits behind main,
but whatever, you'll
see that there is a
scripts folder and in
the scripts folder
you'll see there's a
vscode remote mcp this
allows you to remotely
interact with multiple
mcps as a or sorry
multiple vscodes as
an mcp that's already
here's the readme i
should publish this i
don't know i get so
much **** but for those
who are those who
are worried about it
going to sleep in the
middle of night that's
how you solve the
problem it'll uh it'll
it'll it'll work out
in in vs code for you
uh i'm taking too
much time where's
we have vincent
yeah we have vincent
here today he's
got something to to
share us how are
you with us vincent
there he is i am
indeed hello everyone
hello um yeah nice
to see you again
guys sorry i could
enjoy the last couple
months i was in
japan and time the
time zone was uh
i'm middle of the
middle of the night
for me like 4 a.m so
sorry i couldn't join
but i i i did learn
a lot over there and
um i want to show
you something today
which is around
hospitality so my
my my intuition was
that with the growth
of inbound tourism
in japan uh drastic
growth there will be
issues with multi
-language translation
so i went there to test
that hypothesis right
and i met with hotel
and i asked them about
whether they had
issues with language
translation and so on
and i did the famous
mistake of building
before testing the market
and i wasted my time
because what i thought
what i thought was the
problem was not the
problem so i'm going
to show you two things
so it's a suite of a
system for the hospitality
industry okay so the
mistake is actually
a nice product and
i'm going to share my
screen in audio so this
is based on the real
-time api um uh from open
ai and it's basically
a real time translator
in multi-language
translator the the key
learning here was um
how do you make an
assistant act as a parrot
is more hard than
expected like even if
you force the prompt so
that they don't inject
any other thing that
you want them to
repeat, they still
struggle to act as parrots.
So I had to create two
assistants talking
to each other.
And that's what you're
going to see in a minute.
So this is a
multilanguage assistant.
I'm going to speak
in English, and
it's going to
translate in Japanese.
So you see the
screen, yes?
Yeah.
Hello, I need a taxi
right now for
the airport.
so getting to that
point was so hard uh
fortunately in the um
real-time api there
is a response that
creates that reset the
prompt every time
you send a message so
basically i have two
assistants that i reset
for every conversation
and therefore they
act as parrot and they
talk to each other
by just repeating
what i say in french
or in japanese uh took
me a couple of weeks
to crack that one
but it's working
nicely. But that was not
the problem. In fact,
in Japan, they are
very well equipped
with translators. So
they don't need that.
So then I had to
explore further.
And actually, the product
became this. So
let me show you.
How can I help you today?
Can you please search
for events nearby?
Looking up
events for you.
I found two events
nearby for you.
One, the art of
the ramen bowl.
when March 7th,
2025 June 15th, 2025
Can you tell me
exactly what is
going to happen
in this event?
Certainly here's a
detailed description
of the event The
Art of the Ramen
Bowl event name
Can you search for
French restaurants
around this area?
Let me search for that
information for you
I found some great French
restaurants near
Nishi-Azabu, Tokyo.
Here are the top options.
Could you please
call the first
one and book a
table for two
at 8 p.m. in
Japanese, please?
I've initiated
the call. Okay,
wait, wait. I'll
let you know once
the booking is
confirmed. Do not make
the call. Do not
make the call.
So that turned out
to be the problem.
The problem is people
can book restaurants.
You have long queues
of people going to
ramen shop and so on and
so forth. and you need
to book but they
don't speak english so
you need to speak japanese
so the problem was
how do you make
bookings in japanese and
that's the perfect
solution you have your
assistant making the
call talking in japanese
and we did that with
with no expectation
about what would happen
and um at 9 p.m we
went there and the
full staff was was was
there like the chef the
manager and they were
like you know like in
back in back in the
future when he comes
back from the you know
he's in the 1940s
and the guy from UPS
comes and they made a
bet who somewhat come
at that time at that
day under the ring
same situation everybody
was here really?
you make that
call through AI?
so it shows me
that the market
is way less advanced
than it is in
the US or Europe
with voice AI
telephone eBay's AI
they haven't seen yet
was the first call
ever in Tokyo for that
big huge restaurant
and it still gives you
like a VIP status
you know like wow so
cool AI call to make
the booking and so on
and so forth and the
real problem in fact
is for restaurant and
hotels if you use an
assistant and you
actually ask the user to
give a credit card
to make the call then
you have a way to
make them pay if they
don't show which is
the real problem people
booking restaurant not
coming and then the
restaurant call
the hotel for the
cancellation fee. You
avoid that by just having
an assistant in between
that can make the
call and take 30 card
numbers, you know.
So that's what I wanted
to show you today.
I view that
using A. Yeah.
You got the latency
down too. What is
that? Is that right
around three seconds?
It sounds like you've
had an interesting
experience with
using AI for
making restaurants.
She's commenting.
So now I get, no,
it should be sub one
second with the real
-time API translation.
because of that back
and forth between
assistant is a
little bit longer.
But on the phone now,
it's sub one
second, yeah.
Fantastic.
You could probably
reduce your
latency by using
Grok as well.
Pretty much
everyone for these
apps uses Grok
for that reason.
I could tell you're not
using Grok by the delay.
No, no, I'm not using
Grok. I'm going to
explore Grok. I'm
just using the real
-time API because it's
needed to be real
-time multi-language,
which they do pretty
well. But yeah, it's
not Grok, that like
crazy ex-AI thing,
but the Grok service.
With a Q?
Is it Q? I don't even
know. Yeah, the Q.
It's unfortunate.
I have a question for
Vincent. Did you Vibe
code this app or did
you manually code it?
Well, I used to
code, and I have to
say 90% was Vibe
and 90% was AIDR.
You know, I use
Klein and so on, and
AIDR is much more
laser-focused, you
know, and the code
base now is like, I
don't know how many
files and millions
of code, but I have
to be targeted, so
I'm using AIDR, and
AIDR is fantastic.
I tried actually
with Rahead, which is
something that Rav you
showed us something a
couple of months ago
um before cortex and so
on um cortex and so
on you know ride would
do the planning just
like spark right and was
very disappointed
like after a while he
would just go uh on
the tangent and i would
have wasted my time
yeah so either was the
invite coding for 90
percent the 10 percent
is when really it was
so obvious the bug
that i could just fix it
myself it'll be faster
and cheaper and then
i switched to um
gemini x 2.5 day and
night with sony 3.7 and
the cost uh you know
tenfold less so yeah and
so a question is is
how long did it take
for you to uh to build
the build the app well
the the front end uh
took me like uh let's
say a day but but
behind this i have a
platform that i've
built over the over over
six six six months
now and my key focus i
didn't show you but
it's it's the trust it's
the safety because if
i'm going to give this
in the end of a hotel
or restaurant uh it
has to work with 100
accuracy right so i have
a number of capabilities
to do uh pre-test
with test scenarios i
have evaluation that
the user can define i
can actually monitor
the call in real time
with through a web
socket to listen to
the conversation and
interject if something
goes wrong so this is
where i spent most of
my time the front end
itself yeah a day a
day for the front ends.
Yeah, I mean, they're
not that complex and
elaborate. You can
make it elaborate, but
they're pretty easy to
crank out these days.
Yeah.
What do you use
for the video?
It's still the same old
trick that I've been
using the last time,
which is I pre-generate
an MP4 with the
combination of enough
syllables and voils so
that it looks like it's
almost matching,
almost matching the lip
-syncing, but it's not.
But people don't care.
And I save 20 cents
per minute, right? So I
don't do lip-syncing.
Yeah, I just pretend.
So Vincent, quick
question. So I've
been working on a
conversational agent
as well. And I
was running into a
lot of issues with
the responsiveness.
Were you using a
different API before real
-time API? Did you
have any of those
struggles? Or have you
always been using real
-time API through
OpenAI, and have there
been any issues with
it listening clearly,
handling interruptions,
responding contextually?
So two questions, but
the real-time API,
sometimes when you
speak, not in English,
in French, let's
say, or Japanese,
sometimes it goes
completely crazy.
It's going to basically
actually play an audio
file, I don't know
what it is, of someone
shouting or screaming,
it's not under control,
right? So I would
not put this into
production for a
conversation more than
five minutes long.
So the other capability
I'm using is a
straightforward 11 labs
or VAPI, but at the
end of the day, it's
going to be 11 laps
for the text-to-speech.
For the speech-to
-text, it's DeepGram,
V3, when it's in
English, V2, when it's
in other languages.
And that is okay. I
haven't had these kind
of very outliers
incident that I saw
on the real-time API.
But it's only when
I was speaking not in
English. In English,
it was always perfect,
always perfect.
Okay. So, I mean,
I'm getting sometimes
like, I'll be speaking
English and all of a
sudden, I'll get like
some Chinese back or
like a random phrase
or something along
those lines that
returns and it's like so
out of context and
then it starts looping.
I had that, yeah.
In French, I had that,
yeah, but not in English.
So, you know, I'm
puzzled because this is
probably beyond the
Studio Ghibli stuff,
right? Probably their
most valuable use
case at OpenAI, the
real-time API. And I'm
still puzzled that
they haven't tracked
that. And I'm not the
only one. You go on
the OpenAI forums and
you search for real
-time API. That's the
first thing that you
see on the forums,
right? It's like, how
come we still have
these odd incidents?
And I don't know why,
but no, it's it's it's
not ready for prime
time if you want to
go more than five minutes
you will have this
kind of stuff yeah
yeah thanks benson well
it's interesting right
uh voice agents is
one of the top four
use cases man it's it's
up there it's surprising
and uh i don't
know i don't see a
lot of people talking
about it but but you're
at the cutting edge
and um you know rag
and coding man still
number one and number
two but uh clearly this
is a this is a hot uh
interesting use case
there's a it's uh yeah
there's there's an
interesting project
i'm working on and it's
for uh you know doing
permits for like like
basically housing yeah
commercial real estate
and stuff like that
and a lot of the data
that exists in the world
of permits turns out
isn't accessible on
municipal websites because
you know a lot of
these places just don't
you know have resources
or their backwaters
or whatever and it
turns out that you know
i was able to get most
of that information
using fire crawl and
different sort of
automated features
for the collection
of information.
But it was the most
valuable information
that I was able to get
wasn't through using
fire crawl, but was
by creating these
agents that would
literally sit on hold for
hours sometimes, and then
eventually get through
to some bureaucrat in
some random municipal
office somewhere and
ask a question, you
know, what is this?
Or where do I get the
permit or how to or can
i submit the permit and
and what you just
showed i think the hotel
example is a perfect
perfect example so it
turns out that
there's still a lot of
information that you can
only collect from people
and the these people
don't really want to
talk to anyone and as
long as it's it's um
close enough to sound
in like a real person
they they're they're
more than happy happy to
be helpful and give
you the information and
then i just pop that
into a database somewhere
and I've got the
missing 5% of the data.
You're running a
Turing taste on
them without
them knowing it.
Oh, we've long
since passed that.
They've got no idea.
And what's more
interesting, I can
customize the voice agent
based on location.
So if it's calling
Quebec,
I have a French version
and it's not just
French, it's not going
to speak crazy Parisian
French, it's going to
use Quebecois. Or if
I'm calling, you know,
Texas, I can use a
West Texas accent versus
a, you know, it turns
out there's different
Texas accents. Who
knew? But that's crazy.
Yeah. And what was
interesting is when
the when the receiving
agent, random person
in office, you know, is
interacting with someone
they think is local.
And so accent wise,
they are more helpful
then it sounds like if
it's someone with the
wrong accent that's
super funny man good
luck with my kiwi accent
i i have never had
any success with siri
at all for the whole
time that she's existed
is there is there a
voice library roof
that you use or is that
like 11 labs like what
do you i'm just using
i'm just using bland
it's easy bland's a
little bit expensive
but at the I think it
works out to like $4 an
hour, but that's $4 an
hour is still a lot
less than the cost of
having someone sit
on a call for several
hours because no one's
being paid $4 an hour.
Very cool.
Yeah.
You can make some
very neat stuff, man.
Yeah, really
good work there.
Excited to see where
you take that. I
think the idea of UI
and UX, specifically
UX, is probably
critical. Yeah,
that's where we
should focus our
time on the UX
for sure, yeah.
UX and trust, yeah.
Hey, on that,
Vincent, when you say
trust, can you expand
on that a little
bit? Because I spend
a lot of time in
the area of data
governance and data
trust, in the
enterprise space mostly.
But trust is, what
do you mean by trust,
right? And how do
you think about that?
Well, you know, put
yourself in the shoes
of the front desk
person that's going to
say, OK, let's use
this AI concierge to
help guests, you
know, book restaurant.
Between me testing
this and being happy
and them doing
this at scale with
Chinese and Korean
and the worst case
scenario is it screw
up. It doesn't work.
Everybody's ****** off.
My reputation goes, you
know, down to
the, you know.
so trust by trust i
mean before i go to
production i want to
make sure i've simulated
thousands of conversations
and that it passes
all the time um so
what i've done in my uh
platform is when it goes
through the scenarios
and it fails it
actually updates the
prompt on itself it takes
into account the the
failure points and then
it updates the prompt
to make sure it passed
the next time so
i i just want to have
the confidence that
when it's going to go
live and talk to people
it will be 100 perfect
and that's the trust
uh that i i want to
bring to my customers
if i'm not if i don't
trust if i don't trust
this myself how can
anyone how can expect
anyone to buy this
right so this is why i
focus heavily on on test
scenarios on evaluations
on um giving also
this is something that
comes from the clients
they wanted to be
able to listen to the
conversion in real time
if they wanted to
and take control and
i'm not just talking
about handoff you know
on the phone they're
going to the human i'm
talking about web socket
uh stuff where you
can take take control
listen if things and
you can inject message
if you want to or just
stop and and talk right
because people are
so nervous right now
about about this so
the the more you can
appease the tension and
you can show that you've
been thinking about
everything before
during after the easier
the sell otherwise you
you have the friction
of really can i trust
that and that's it
even even if it's ****
solving a real problem
that is going to be
the major uh blocker
right right yeah yeah
good stuff thank you
that i i think uh
that you're working on
some some amazing work
there and then i think
that uh you brought
two interesting points
that i've been hearing
a lot this week
this idea of you know
i just vibe coded it
versus this concept
of agentic engineering
and for me what you
described wasn't vibe
coding you you have
a solid plan you have
an architecture you
you've got a background
in coding so you you
know the right structure
to either guide it
or define it so just
when when people are
are saying vibe coding
what for me is an
absence of a plan that
means that i'm kind of
following the rabbit
hole. I'm not really
sure where or what
I'm doing. I just kind
of want to discover
something I didn't
know was possible. And
that's a lack of
engineering. Now, for
those of us who are
doing this commercially,
I have customers that
show up and want me
to build something
specific to solve a
particular problem point
or operate in an existing
business structure.
I'm not vibe coding
that. I might vibe
code a UI to show them
what's possible. But
when it comes of the
practical implementation
of whatever it is
i'm doing i'm creating
a really detailed
structured plan
architecture test framework
and other elements
that allow me to guide
this in a way that's
scalable secure and
beneficial so anyway
i have a question or
agent agentics on one
side vibe coding on the
other it's a spectrum
sorry so i have a
question on that on
that reuben is um one of
my problems is i have
this product that
me and my co-founder
have invented and it's
You know, it's a
legacy code base, man.
It's like two years
old, right? And we want
to do some radical
improvement to it. And
I'm like, ****, man,
we're going to vibe code
some prototypes and
change. So how do you
– is it – can you easily
inject this modern
agentic engineering
into and on top of
an existing legacy
code base that's, you
know, not – that's been
manually hand-coded?
Yeah, see, that's the
easiest part. So when
I'm describing this
idea of a plan, you
know, and the plan for
a net new system, a
plan is like, here's
how you build it, here's
the structure, here's
the architecture,
here's the security,
whatever. But if it's
existing, that's easier
because all I need to
do to describe the
plan is to point the
Spark Rue system at the
existing code base and
basically say, first,
define the existing
architecture, both
functionally and technically,
algorithmically,
whatever. then once
that's defined create
a step-by-step phase
process to implement
this in xyz language
or environment and then
i literally go to bed
and i wake up in the
morning it's been
built and it's totally
functional and it works
better for existing
and so a lot of times
what i'm doing is i'm
i'm borrowing existing
code bases from
github and those code
bases might be 10 years
old But conceptually,
it might be built in
Java, and who the heck
wants to use Java?
So I'll take the Java
or some strange assembly
-based approach and
then, say, translate
this into Node.js or
Python or something,
and it works great.
So it builds out the
Spark 2 scaffolding
document template for
you based on the existing
code? And that's what
the Spark code or
the Spark Rue mode
system does, right? it
has a pseudo code
outline which says okay
here's how the general
flow of the structure
of the application
needs needs to look
like about explicitly
doing it all then i've
got an architecture
that says how is it
all connected and related
then it then we've
got the implementer
that takes it and
actually writes the
fully functioning code a
tester that iterates
back and forth and a
final documentary says
what's been built and
what what's left to
do sort of thing and
each of that's created
through a subtask and
it yeah it'll just
build it and that but
All those functions
are built into Spark 2.
I've been trying to
get Spark 2 running,
and I'm not having
a lot of success.
I checked it out,
and I'm trying
to follow your
instructions, and
I'm just trying
to figure out...
That's different from
Spark 2, actually, Dave.
It is? So that's
Spark-centric
custom Rue modes,
right, Roof?
Yeah, let's talk
about Rue modes.
The Spark 2 is a
different approach yet
again. So Spark 2
essentially acts
as an MCP that allows
me to concurrently
spawn independent
agentic coding
agents. It's very
similar to what the guys
at OpenAI do with
Codex, but the
difference is I'm
using an E2B container.
Yeah, they're
containerizing it
slightly differently, but
architecturally
it's very similar.
So Roo Modes doesn't
need SPARC 2, is
that what you're
saying? No, no, it
doesn't. And so
Roo Modes is way easier.
The only thing you
really need for that
is a thinking mode
for the orchestrator
and Sonic 3.7 as
the implementer.
And basically, I
basically use a
very similar
approach to the aidr
architect editor
model, which basically
one architects
and one edits.
I'm doing the same thing.
Okay.
One tip, David, is
if you go into the
legacy code base, if
you create tests first,
based in whatever
legacy language it
is, And then from
there, it does help in
the process to
translate it into a more
modern process because
it's the exact same
steps that are tests
that have to work.
Yeah.
Hey, Rube, what
requesting model are
you using when you,
because I noticed
that you said 3.7
thinking, but behind
it, there's a
requesting model and
I can't seem to
figure out which one's
3.7 thinking. I
know you said 6,400.
Yeah. What was
that? I think it
was Rob that told
me about this.
Let's just take
a look here.
Yeah, it's the
models that have the
1,064 or 16,000
after them, after the
3.7. Those are the
thinking models,
and that's the
tokens being a lot of
people are thinking
they're doing.
So I use the middle
of the road one.
It's, I think, 16K or
something like that.
are curious i know
every week i show the
same thing so if you've
seen it last week just
tune out for a moment
but um so this this
is what this is what
my my setup looks like
right so i've got
different different uh
profiles here so depending
on on what i'm doing
or what i'm testing
i'll switch around
you know so lately i
was playing with the 03
and the 04 mini and
stuff like that so i
create different models
and then and then i
usually add a little
uh emoji to sort of
indicate it's a thinking
model just because it's
easier to see it
quickly so and you know
that's just that's
just me adding that to
the title and and and
then here you can see
all the different
options available to you
know so the most important
one is the orchestrator
so the the orchestrator
will essentially
use of thinking and
then the autocoder
uses the direct
implementation of sonnet 3
.7 still it's still the
best i haven't found
anything that works
as good as this what
temperatures are you
using for those uh so for
the thing well you
can't set temperature
for thinking models uh
first of all you can
only set you can only
set temperature for a
non-thinking model that
said you can fake a
instruct model into
behaving sort of kind
of like a thinking
model by cranking the
temperature up if you
don't have access to a
thinking model. Um, so,
so, but for, for this,
I think I set it to,
where'd I set this?
I, I generally set it
to 0.2 or where was
that? I forget
where. You don't even
have a check for this
one. It's unchecked.
Yeah, I don't. Yeah.
So this one I don't,
but It's because
I'm probably in this
repo, but generally
I set this to 0.2.
And actually through
DIP, this looks
like it's not
configured correctly.
I usually set this
down to about 90.
Now the most
important part
actually is this
part down here.
This is what allows it
to operate autonomously,
all these commands.
So over time I
just added enough
where now it does
everything I need.
You guys can
take a screenshot
of this if you want.
Awesome.
Thanks, Ruru.
Yep.
Question though, is
there any like, I mean,
is there like a self
-learning element to this
where it's like it
would like read your
logs, like you have an
agent that's like checking
out the logs and
essentially like it's
just creating that cycle
of self-improvement.
Yeah.
Where you're going
to have the one
adjusting it, but
it actually like
the SPARC tools
is getting better.
Right here.
It's the orchestrator
does that. Yeah,
so the orchestrator,
yeah, so it follows,
you can see it follows
the boundaries, it
tells the structure
about new tasks and
how it's signed. So
in this particular
scenario, it knows
the different modes
available to it. And
I'm always adding new
modes and doing things,
and there's some
validation of code and
things that I don't
want to do. Again,
this is particularly
important for the end,
and the new task is
particularly important
for the beginning.
i don't know it's
what it's it's one of
those things like i
for whatever reason it
works for me and
works great apparently
others are having
some others are having
trouble with it i'm not
really sure why some
people do i think
the the issue is just
basically i i have a
tendency to just be
repetitive and how i
tell it to start where i
i tell it to remember
to do subtasks using
new underscore task
and stuff maybe that's
why it works better
for me i don't know
I customize, yes, I
customize the root
prompts for each
project I'm doing.
So there's a folder here
for, where is it, root.
I don't think I did
it here. This is one I
was working on last
night. So it's a little
bit more rudimentary.
It's implementation.
It's currently
building up that
UI we were talking
about earlier.
But basically,
that is, let's
just go back
here for a sec.
and we can see
that global
modes, I think it is.
Yeah.
So I just go in here
and I just grab,
you know, as you can
see here, I have a
Supabase. This Supabase
is really useful.
Oops,
still coding.
But the Supabase
essentially
allows it to use
the Supabase MCP.
Yeah. Come on, stop
jumping. But as far
as things that I've
learned in the last
week, this is the most
useful because it can
do really complex
user authentication
protocols and structures,
data triggers, all
the things you create
really, really.
Because mostly every
app is at some level
just an abstraction
of a database anyway.
This makes that
really easy.
so if there's any if
there's it's get a
postgres or or supabase
style mcp and let it
just let it run build
build until it's done
kind of thing and are
you also using the client
rules as well i do
yeah i do the client
rules um when i get
deeper into the project i
use those when i'm like
this right now it's
just building this uh
crowdsource whatever
it's building so i
don't really care about
the rules because i'm
literally just vibing
it but um later on
let's say i let's say i
like what this is i'll
get it to create specific
client rules for the
implementation the
further implementation
of whatever it is
that i'm building but
you can see this has been
running the whole
time i've been on the
call and it's building
all kinds of stuff do
you have a set budget
that you kind of have
in mind before you
start projects so you're
like okay this is going
to cost me 500 bucks
just like oh yeah and
nothing's going to
cost 500 dollars i built
i i built that quantum
computing or the
quantum system for 20
bucks yeah it's like
you know let's go back
to my monthly burn like
it was at peak february
was like ten thousand
dollars but uh let's
look at the last yeah
i know my wife said
what the **** are you
doing but anyway um
so this this is my last
30 days 1200 bucks and
i've saved multiple
projects clients yeah
yeah this is this is
this is per day savings
it's crazy yes
yesterday you know i go
through phases where i
go and build a bunch of
stuff and so some of
them but how was it how
does it do saving how
is it what is it doing
to save you money
it's using the it's
stripping out extraneous
uh prompt which which
jacks up the price and
then and then i can
go further and i created
a custom prompt for
uh where did i put that
you guys might want
that actually so i
created a custom system
prompt for ru that
strips out even further
uh ru code text yeah
this this is the this
is the custom uh prompt
so you can take this
and you can grab that
like this go back
in well you actually
you can do it in
requestee as well now so
you can go to requestee
and then you go to
your i think it's
prompt library if i'm
not mistaken and you
can create a new
prompt you can see i've
got different prompts
and then we can We
can go in here, we
can call it Rue code,
pop this in here,
call it Rue code.
That's what I
was asking about
because I knew
there was something
tricky to the
system prompt.
Yeah, and now
I can go and
I can use that
if I want to.
So if I want to use
this, I click attach.
Or the other way I
can do this, I can do
it directly in Rue,
but this is easier.
This will auto
-replace it. so I'm
currently using this
one but it's basically
I'm sorry I just
want to make sure
is this like a
variable this is like
a mask for your
API key or is this
like a variable
for a prompt it's a
it strips out
extraneous it strips out
extraneous tokens
and descriptions that
aren't needed and
in the case of this
it saves me 70, 76%.
So I, and so then
I, I, it'll automatically
use this whenever
I make the request
to a given API.
So in this case I can,
I can select which
API key I want to
attach it to. So let's
say I want to select
it to roof or whatever.
This is like your
rule, your rule for
requestly requestly.
Yeah. But it completely
abstracts it and
does it magically.
Right. I mean,
so it's basically
just rewriting
the system cross,
right? Yeah. Yeah,
it overrides it.
Yeah, can you share
the link for this?
It's, yeah, it's
just my gist. It's in
this gist, yeah, I
saw it yesterday.
Yeah, and it's just
a *******, so you can
optimize it here. Just
create new API keys for
different models and
things or attach it.
Now, what they need
to do here, I think,
is they need to
be able to attach
it to a specific
LLM. Right now, it's
only attached based
on the API key,
which is kind of a
silly way to do it.
But, and then you
can test it here
and they're doing
a great job.
Could you put like
an open router
API key in there
and have it, I
mean, would that
be just pointless?
I don't see why
you wouldn't. You
could probably do
the same thing if
using open router,
but the open router,
you'd probably
have to manually,
they don't, the router is
not a proxy,
it's a router.
So you still
need a proxy.
The better way
to do it if you
want to do it yourself
would probably
be to use a
light LLM proxy.
And that light, I
think it's a light LLM
proxy provides
basically, I'm pretty
sure that's what
request he built it on.
I never asked, but
they probably did.
I would guess,
that's how I do
it anyways.
But this allows
you to basically
create a proxy
of anything and
then replace
it in the same
sort of style.
Yeah, something in,
something
alternative out.
Yeah.
But I don't need
to, I like the guys
that request these,
so it's good enough
for me. I'll just
use their service.
It doesn't cost
me anything.
Saves you.
Yeah. They have a
smart model. Save
you 76% and
charge a 1% fee on
top. Well, I'm
more than happy to
spend a 1% fee if
you're saving 76%.
Yeah, it's kind
of a cool system.
yeah a little
echoey today
anyone else have
anything you want to demo
show this you know
we're pretty easy going
today it's a holiday
so this is my only call
well other than the U
of T guys this morning
I can talk about some
of the things that
I've been playing
with your room modes
set up roof. And I
can talk about some of
the things that I've
experienced that.
So I was playing
with the other
models, like 4.1 as
like the instruct.
And then like Gemini
or like 04 Mini as the
orchestrator. And the
problem with the bigger
context windows is
the price skyrocks if
you even utilize those.
And one thing that's
cool about 3.7 thinking
is your orchestrator
never goes over 200K
context because that's
the limit. So that
really keeps the prices
down so that you
can actually run it
overnight. When I was
using a bigger context
window for the orchestrator,
the context window
just kept stacking
up. And then every
orchestrator call was
going up to, you know, I
mean, it was getting
up to a dollar, dollar
fifty two dollars, you
know, depending on how
big it would get.
And so that was a big
benefit to having the
smaller context windows.
And then I set it up
so that the system was
doing micro tasks and
doing smaller tasks.
So it would send
out, it would switch
modes, do a small task
and come back. And
that was keeping
the context windows
very small so that my
API calls were like
between one to two
cents instead of
getting up to like
three to five cents.
And doing it that way
seemed to help a lot.
and then I added in the
software architecture
problem prediction
ontology that I built
and it helps guide it
when it has problems.
It like tells it what
to think about. Like
if it has this problem,
these are the logical
outcomes to think about
and it helps guide
it and navigate it
a little better. And
then I like adding in
the perplexity research
on top. So anytime
it has questions, it
uses perplexity. And
what my system is doing
is it's using it a
lot to look up best
practices for coding.
and that's really cool i
like that and then yeah
having the i and then
i changed it around
so that it just
automatically builds
in the cumulative
and recursive
tests as it goes and
so like all those
tests that you show are
like what my programs
look like too and it
kind of like builds
it out by itself doing
that too so those are
some fun little additions
i've added on to
it and things i've
discovered are you using
the free version of
perplex the api or paid
the paid version but
i I mean, it uses it
so little that you can
code for like 24 hours
and you'll have like
a 60 cent fee, right?
It's not like it goes
to it all the time.
You know, the Firecrawl
guys have a free
option, which probably
be even better.
I'll look into that.
Yeah, I'm a big
fan of Firecrawl.
And they've got a new
agent option, which
is pretty cool. So
not only can you
extract data from
whatever site and find
related sites, but it
can actually get it to
now interact directly
with the site, fill
in forms and be more
than just a scrape.
It's kind of a nice
feature. I think
they came out with
that earlier this week.
So, Ruv, I'm just
wondering why you changed
your mind about Firecrawl.
Because I believe
four weeks ago, you
mentioned that you
could just make your
own implementation of
Firecrawl and it's not
necessary to use it.
I firmly reserve
the right
to contradict myself.
I don't know. i i like
it now that's hilarious
that is hilarious
i don't know yeah
just because i said
it you know two weeks
ago doesn't mean i
still believe it um i i
i my my mind is malleable
and open to change
i don't know what to
tell you so hopefully
i don't spend all my
time contradicting
myself i played with
fire crawl man i found
it was inconsistent
on tough websites
like you know if you go
to like yahoo finance
stock listing it pretty
much is 50 success
rate okay yeah it
depends what you're
doing but um i i've
had pretty good success
with it i'm doing
several projects with it
so right yeah yeah
yeah it's not it's not
it's not bad the um
by the way that that
crowdsourced
cosmic, quantum, whatever
system is still
being built.
I'm still watching
it do its thing.
So it's...
That's going to be neat
to take for a spin.
Yeah.
I'm not sure the
longest I've had
this run. I think
I've had one
run for eight hours
non-stop once.
So it'll work.
Chris mentioned something
interesting and also
I think one of the
folks... Sorry, I
can't remember who. i
brought it up earlier
in terms of tracking
progress and i know
chris um uh you had
mentioned back a few
weeks ago you were
experimenting with uh
um node 4j is that right
yeah i've been i've
been building a program
out but i kind of
got sidetracked by
having to do some finals
for school but right
right right right and
uh and roof how do
you track the actual
uh the structure or
do you? Do you have
it set up to... What
are you asking? Like,
say, either the task
logs in Roo custom
modes. Is that something
that you sort of pull
in as a progress?
No, I don't because
I use phases.
So the phases seems
to work better for me.
anyway so when i do
numbered phases then
i to be honest i
don't generally leave
this thing 100 autopilot
i usually say do
phase one then i go
off and do a zoom call
or something and then
and then it's done
all the tests pass and
i do a quick review
of whatever it's done
in that phase then
i create a new chat
for phase two a new
orchestrator for phase
two and rinse repeat
and so i'm doing
each phase using the
orchestrator but
independently so i'm not
trying to do one
giant uh orchestration
across 10 phases i'm
creating 10 chats for
each so one chat for
each of the 10 phases
yep and it keeps it
you know sorry please
finish yeah yeah go
ahead okay no yeah
when you showed
earlier on about the
different models for
the different modes
in the blue modes
okay Do you have a
list somewhere like
which model you will
generally use for
which of the nodes?
Yeah, people are asking
me about that. So I
don't, but I should
put it out there. So
for anything involving
analytics, like analytical
thought, so like
architecture mode,
writing modes, like
document writing and stuff
like that, I'm using
a thinking model. and
depending on one of
the drawbacks to the
thinking model at least
in Roo is it doesn't
auto clear the context
window so depending
on the size of your
code base you might not
be able to use it
that way but if you're
starting fresh it generally
is fine so anything
involving like thought
process architect
but anything involving
editor then you're
going to want to use
an instruct model
so for that I use
generally.
That works pretty well.
Thanks.
Hey, Ruf.
Based on last
week, I've built
something. So I was
asking about Codespaces.
And I've built
something which
is the Poormans version
of it. Basically
not using
Codespaces, but using
a bash script which
is spinning up
on the host machine
my VS code and then
opening up that in
a docker container
basically and I can
have like five different
code spaces on my laptop
plus Taskmaster.
I don't know if
I mentioned it
last time but I
integrated Taskmaster
into the setup
And if you want,
I can show that.
Yeah, let's see it.
It sounds awesome.
Yeah.
All right, then let
me screen share.
So you're basically
creating VS Code
instances in a
Docker container.
Exactly.
You've got to take a
look at my VS Code MCP.
That would be an awesome
use case for that.
It'll orchestrate it
through the
MCP interface.
I just need to restart
my Zoom because
I needed to give
it permission.
So I will be
there in a bit.
We'll see you shortly.
That's a new
error, but I'm
sure we'll be
back in a sec.
So anyone else build
anything cool this week?
A bunch on the go,
but not to demo yet.
If it's ready, it's
probably too late for me.
Yeah, it's fun to build
this stuff for sure.
I'm just, oh,
quantum magnet, it's
almost there,
passing the test.
All right. I'm back.
Sorry for that.
Oh, good, Marco.
All right.
And all right, I'm going
to share my whole screen.
Do you see my screen?
Yes.
Okay, perfect.
So basically, I have
a template folder
with my dev container
JSON, a Docker file,
root code. I
have some rules.
I don't dig into it.
I have a script
folder which is
related to
Taskmaster I'm going
to show you
Taskmaster in a bit
I have an env
template which is most
important for
Taskmaster and I have my
room modes, I
changed it a bit for
make it work with
Taskmaster and
introduced the text
complexity analyzer but
I'm going to show
you that in a bit
and
using it with
with Bash script is
actually quite simple,
so basically I'm
spinning it up. I'm just
giving it a name. Let's
say demo2 or demo3.
Basically, then it
opens VS Code. It copies
all from the template
folder and then
it asks me to reopen
that in a container.
Basically, now
it's spinning up
a Docker container.
It's still not there.
It's still building.
Basically, my Docker file
is getting
everything done.
Maybe in the
meantime, while it's
running, we can just
take a very brief
look into it. So
basically, what
I'm doing is I'm
getting basically
the version, like
a Python version.
I'm installing Node.
And I'm installing
the Taskmaster,
basically. I'm doing
some, like there
have been some
issues with
Taskmaster, so I
needed to do this here.
So basically, the
traces are kind
of broken, but
that's fixed now.
And then I have
some post comments
here as well. And
I'm taking from my VS
Code settings from
my host machine,
the settings
file, and copy it
into the Docker
container as well.
And I'm installing
Roo as well.
You can put, like,
any extension
here as well if you want.
So I hope. It usually
doesn't take so
long. I don't know
why it takes so long.
Probably Zoom
or something.
But maybe I can
switch to a different
folder, like this one
here, the demo folder,
which is already a
little bit bigger.
So basically, I run
just like a test
to just see how
Roo works with new
Roo modes, basically,
in Taskmaster.
Speaking of Taskmaster,
maybe like one or
two sentences regarding
Taskmaster, which
is actually quite
a cool application.
You can check it out.
Basically, what it
allows to do is it allows
you to give instructions.
instructions and
based on the instructions
it um it creates a
prd and based on the
prd it creates tasks so
basically if i switch
back you will see a
task folder here um and
then those tasks are
um basic basically um
splits of the bigger
tasks and what i'm doing
then in my room modes
is i'm going through
each task um do my
tests do my basically
building it and then
once this is built i'm
focusing to the on the
next tasks and so forth
and the cool thing
about this here is and
i can open maybe the
um the console log here
um the cool thing is
um it's cool for i it's
cool for myself what
i mean by that is um
i can um i can see my
my lists um taskmaster
list um and the cool
thing is so all of
those are done um and i
can always um refer
to like very simple
instructions to the to
the agent so for example
taskmaster next and
then it just picks um
there are no task now
but it just picks the
next task from here
and it creates subtasks
when the job is too big
or because you mentioned
perplexity it has a
taskmaster analyzer
complexity analyzer
and then it uses
perplexity to analyze
based on the PRD
how complex or based
on the task how complex
it actually is and
how much it needs
to split the task
and how many subtasks
it needs to create
and i found it to um
to work quite well
because it has only the
task in the context
so yeah um that's
pretty cool task
master task mask master
Yeah, I can paste
it into the chat.
Yeah, I'm totally
going to use that.
So you're basically
creating task
-based MCP modes
and implementing
using those indirectly
or directly.
Exactly, exactly.
Yeah, and here we
are. So this is
demo two, which
I just sped up.
exactly and yeah if
you want I can share
that as well once it's
stable I can maybe
open source it and I
mean it's just a bash
file with some some
files so you know
you can interact
directly with the VS code
instances using the
remote protocol for
VS code and that
includes both terminal
scripting and extensions
so you could are
using that remote
capability or you still
require you to
go and invoke it
by clicking the
UI or whatever?
I think you could just
I think you can just
spin it up without me
clicking on the UI.
Because it's basically
it's a remote
dev container.
I think once I just
like... Actually, it's
a good question.
In the end, I don't
know. I would need to
check it out. but I
think it should be
possible to spin it up.
Well, it's definitely
possible. That's what
my VS Code MCP is
doing. But you've taken
it a step further and
you've introduced, you
know, defining sort
of a templated rule
set that you can pass,
which is really cool.
Exactly. So
when you see my,
basically this is
now inside my Docker
container and roo code
is installed as well.
So yeah, I mean, with
all my sets, settings
um so all my settings
before and here so
everything is there so
i can just like start
doing my stuff
so yeah that's
pretty cool nice
work that's perfect
so all right we're
almost out of time
here guys let's just
check in on my on that
dev and see and see
see where where it
where it ended up
um actually i can't
share it to my mark
oh here we go. Okay.
Check this out. So
this was building
basically for
the last hour.
And now we've got
a quantum magnetic
navigation community
contributing
system. And it looks
like it's decided
to do San Francisco
as a prototype.
Magnetic topography plan.
It started that
created some sort of
crazy startup. I'm
sure that this will
get funded in about
two seconds but
yeah that's it's
you just build stuff
there you go quantum
pulse yeah i didn't i
didn't even tell it
what to call it there
you go all right we
vibed a new a new startup
somewhere all right
yeah i guess we're
out of time uh thanks
everyone have a happy
long weekend for
those who celebrate um
i i will try to publish
some of this stuff
thanks everyone who's
had a chance to present
today this is great
uh we're doing some
amazing work here so
it's exciting um and
if though anyone that
wants to help contribute
to our various uh you
know philanthropic
opportunities we you
know sign up on the
agentics.org site
for a membership 10
bucks you know and
you'll help keep uh keep
our lights on there
that was my unsolicited
ending.
Brad should be happy.
And Brad's got the
link for the sign
up for the committees
in there as well.
There's really neat
stuff going on in
research, safety
and responsible
deployment. Of course,
all the various
teams, the
internal dev team.
There's tons of ways
to get involved.
All right.
Until next week,
I'm excited
to see what
you guys build.
Like always,
if you want to chat,
we're on WhatsApp
and we're still trying
to get that discord
channel and you know
martin's been busy
trying to push us
into that channel but
we're we're hanging
out in both places
okay see you next
week see you guys bye