All right, I'm
going to hit.
All right.
And I'm going to
start live as well.
And the live's always
a bit of a delay
here, so we'll let
that do its thing.
So this is being
broadcast to LinkedIn.
So just as an FYI,
anyone that wants to
pipe up, you will be
broadcast to the world.
um i i've got this
you know this this
is kind of like the
the time of the uh week
that i just kind of
randomly build stuff
i don't necessarily
have a particularly
great plan today
other than i think we
should you know build
something let's see
let's get my camera a
little better here you
guys can see around
my office here all
right um yeah so it
does anyone you know
have any ideas or or
or desires for anything
we should we should
build or want to see
you know i think a
bunch of folks have
seen previous weeks um
so you know i'm open
to suggestions uh
nick you get any ideas
i could see nick so
i figured i'd ask i
don't know um i i always
like when you when
you just like ask chat
gbt to give you like
some impossible thing
to solve and then you
just like build
something around that you
know like uh give me
something that's like
you know quantum
crazy or something and
then you just build
it yeah i always like
those so this you guys
heard about the acquisition
of uh what was it
windsurf earlier
this week from open ai
which was three billion
dollars and i you know
and if you look at
what they did like i
don't want to diminish
it because they had
some great, great
traction and they've
been building the company
for an entire two
and a half years. So,
you know, there's a
lot of man hours that
went in those two and
a half years, I'm sure.
But what's interesting
is it's literally
a VS, open VSX and a
sort of clone of the,
you know, VS code
system, which you
can wrap and put
your own wrap around.
So what I was thinking,
I'll show you some
of the stuff there.
We can go anywhere you
like. We can go to the
quantum root if you
want. But let me show
you some stuff here.
So let me show you the
way I vibe code here.
Again, some of you guys
are probably familiar
at this point with
my approach. I said,
well, what if we could
have our own IDE,
which again, complicated
and hard was kind
of the idea. But if
we go here, you'll see
here that I've been
building some things.
All right. Let's go here
all right so basically
one of the things i
was building so i'm
building this is two
parts i'm building a vs
codium system which
basically is let's go
let's go to the readme
and see what the heck
it describes it as all
right so this is the
readme that was was
built here so this is
vs This is basically a
mechanism to clone your
own version of Visual
Studio or whatever,
VS Code.
And so it allows you
to basically modify
it. So I took it upon
myself to do that. Now,
like with a lot of
stuff I do, I start
with, you know, my docs,
so the architecture.
So what I was looking
to do was basically
package up a copy
of Rue code and
then create a kind
of our own IDE around
it. just because I
don't really have a
reason really it's
about like doing it
and modular and all
that kind of stuff.
And then, so then I
thought, what if I
could replace the
actual extensions with
MCPs that abstract the
MCPs as containerized
versions of every
VS Code extension?
So then, so after I
created the initial
framework to create
the IDE, I went
into and started
thinking about creating
this idea of the
extension. So in that
case, I did the
original research, and
this was actually
deep, deep research.
And you can see
here, I just copy and
paste it, even the
thanks is included there.
And basically, what
that was intended
to do was create
this containerized
extension execution
for VS Codeium. So what
I wanted to do is
basically create a
kind of MCP-enabled
IDE VS code with Rue
code kind of thing.
So I needed to create
an extension to
essentially do that.
And that's what this was.
And at which point
it built a lot
of things, and here
we are. And now
I need to see
what the heck it
built and whether
it actually works.
So let's go ahead and
point Rue at it and
see. And this was actually
an overnight project.
So as I was telling
you guys earlier, you
know, a lot of the
projects I do are just
basically things I set
before I go to bed and
see to see what will
happen if I, you know,
if I let it run
overnight. This was
one of those
overnight projects.
So let's take a
look at the readme
here and see what
the heck it built.
So this particular repo
has two parts. It's
got an IDE, which still
needs a little work.
and it's got this
OpenVSX MCP extension
system that will discover
various extensions,
run and Docker
containers.
And basically
I get it's an
MCP enabled sort
of development
environment as
an extension.
So let's go here.
And I haven't checked
it since this
morning because I've
been on calls and
doing things. So I
haven't actually
figured out where and
how far I've got
in the development.
So we'll go here. so
we'll see it finished
at uh looks like at
12 19 a.m so it didn't
run all night it only
ran about 12 into
about 12 30 but yeah
so i got i got a
few hours of sleep
before it uh it ran and
it finished here so
open extension system
which has successfully
implemented a
containerized mcp
extension execution system
for vs codium that
allows all right phase
one two three four
additional components
all right that's good
uh run wouldn't it
mention vdd the the
sorry i saw tdd and
vdd what was vdd i'm
glad to see that oh
so uh i thought it
was in the green there
uh he's called kind
of fast i thought it
said uh you know tdd
like either test driven
or something and i
thought there was a
vtt one oh yeah i don't
know vs ix download
that's the format
of the there's
tdd yeah keep
keep scrolling
yeah client is
looking for a way
to hit ctrl f and
search in that
history i don't
know if Roo has
something like
that. Yeah, I know.
It doesn't, which is,
I mean, to be honest,
it needs a
control F, 100%.
Yeah, it's probably
not hard to implement,
I'm guessing.
It's like you can
control F in other
things, like over here.
Yeah, yeah. That's
what they're talking
about in the
client, and I think
Roo's probably going
to bring something
like that, too,
is figuring out
where to pop that
search text field up.
Yeah.
So speaking of
TDD, I'm just
going to double
check where we
are in the
development process.
So run the, I'm actually
going to do this
in a new one, because
this was kind of deep
into the development.
So I'm going to run
the, what's the name
of that folder again?
So again, there's two
projects here that
are in the same
folder. One is the IDE,
and the other is
the extension. You
kind of need both.
So I was going to run
the extension
independently to do the,
basically, again, an
abstraction of all
the extensions that
exist for Visual
Studio and run them
in Docker containers.
So what I want to do is
just figure out where
the heck I am in my
crazy project. So I'm
going to do this, and
I'm going to go here,
and it looks like
there's a test folder.
So I'm just going to go
and say run the test.
run all all the tests
now i don't know if
you guys noticed that
over the last week or
so they've changed the
way that the uh at least
the root system interacts
with the terminal
so it runs within it
i'm not sure i'm a
big fan of that doesn't
seem to be any way
to specifically change
it but regardless i'm
going to switch to my
son 3.5 i actually just
an fyi you'll notice
here that i've got
different models in here
so i actually when i
do these projects i
i get my customers to
give me their uh or to
create a requestee or
open router um api key
then i use it and i
then i run it with their
api key versus mine
to save save some money
so if you're consulting
you don't want to
spend the money it's
a quick and easy way
to so when it went yeah
i and again back to
the business model like
last night i mean
when i was doing that
project you know as a
kind of i guess i was an
advisor or whatever
so i'm like i'll i'll
build your crazy thing
but you got to pay for
the uh the actual api
keys and i'll take
a piece of any money
you make later kind of
thing which isn't bad
if you can make money
while you're sleeping
um run the run on the
it's redundant but
whatever let's let's let's
see what it does i'm
not gonna don't don't
fix i just want to
see what i just want
to see what what's
what's broken what is it
so all right so yeah
this is running how
often are you prompting
would you say like on
a project like this
like how often are you
actually interacting
with it versus it running
are you have you
hopped in 50 times is
it like oh no i'm running
i'm i'm uh i'm doing
about five ten percent
of the interactions
so you know i would
say dozens maybe or
less and it depends on
what I'm doing. So for
like, more complex
projects, I'm just
basically saying, go figure
it out. And then once
it's done, then I'll
fool around and figure
out what needs to
be done. So in this
scenario, I'm just trying
to figure out where
I am in the development
process, because I
literally it finished
last night at midnight,
and I didn't get a
chance to look at it.
Yeah.
So now I'm just
trying to figure out
what the appropriate
mechanism to actually
take this and
make it work for
everyone. Like I need
to build an installer
for probably Windows
and Mac OS and
I need to package
up this extension.
So I'm just trying to
figure out where I am.
So I'm in my test
mode here and
I just need to
run the tests.
Does it ever
tell you that it
does work when
it doesn't work?
Because I've been
running into that issue
where like the tests
all pass, everything's
good. like you've
integrated this and then
it ends up creating
some like mock test and
it like actually kind
of steers away from
that i mean you can
see the mock tests here
with vs code um it's
like doesn't actually
work like an actual like
functional production
code like tests so
does that ever happen
to you yeah it does
where it's like you
built it but it's fake
right or i'll tell you
what i see is it says
yeah i did it and it
actually did nothing
which is kind of weird
yeah yeah being gaslit
by agents is the new
thing yeah yeah well
i'm not alone with
that why am i why is
this happening to me but
it used to be developers
doing it actual
humans but now it's it's
already oh it spends
money it spends token
money man saying doing
all this work and
then it says and i'm
completed and you go
and look at it it's like
nothing not a single
line of code yeah no
i'm telling you
that's the best way to
implement that thing
there's no other better way
yeah yeah and you
paid for it uses a lot
of stubs when it's
building the actual
framework and then writing
tests against the stubs
i haven't yet found
a reliable way for
it to automatically
that you flash out and
complete the stubs
before running the tests?
I do the stubs
first, then I run the
tests. But I
haven't had, I don't
know, it depends
on the initial sort
of details and what
it needs to do.
But yeah, that is
definitely an issue.
So right now I'm just
trying to look at
what the heck the
tests are and what the
problems are. Looks
like a relatively
minor property on my
MCP doesn't exist.
Now, the issue, the
biggest issue I sometimes
run into is mocking
versus real. And
when you do too much
test, it's almost like
it has a tendency to
sort of say, oh, there's
an error. I'm just
going to create a fake
version of this. Well,
I don't want a fake
version. I want a
real version. I want
this to be fully
implemented. and so then
sometimes i have to
come back and say well
take now that all my
tests ran and their
mocks are good now make
make the thing actually
work but generally
going from a mocked
environment to a real
one is is trivial
depending on what what
you're what you're trying
to do um so in this
case i'm just trying
to fix some of these
last bits of error
and so i ran i went and
ran the the test again
manually so let's
see what let's hey uh
reuben uh someone in
the chat said could
we see an example of
your overnight prompt.
Oh, my overnight prompt?
Yeah, here, sure.
This is going to
work. I'm going
to go here and
let me read
the chat so I
can see that too.
All right. I've got you
guys on my other screen.
Yeah, I'm just trying
to keep you honest.
I'm sure everyone
– yeah, honest.
I'm hallucinating.
All right. So let's go
here to – yeah, this
is an overnight –
I'm sure everyone on
LinkedIn and this live
stream are all covered
by NDA. All right.
So this is what an
overnight project
looks like, right? So
the last thing I did,
because I want to brag,
was I ran SCC. So SCC
basically is like,
how much, you know,
what did it create
and what's the value
propositions? So this
is one part I didn't
include, I'd include
the benchmark, but
basically it created,
in this case, for the
CLI, it created about
14,000 lines of code.
And the estimated
value based on this
is roughly $246,000.
Now,
I posted on LinkedIn
earlier, we got a quote
from a relatively
low, the lowest cost
quote was $800,000 to
build this. And it was
significantly less
than what this thing
ended up being now this
is your fiber optic
optimization tool yeah
so so yeah so so what
i started with is where
the heck did i put
it in plans i think
research all right so
what what i ended up
starting with was you
know i i had i had
some c code so this is
the this is the c code
from uh you know an
academic somewhere
that that originally
dreamt up this concept
that that that they
wanted to do but
it was a rudimentary
implementation
and it's all in
like C and really
hard to work with. So
what I ended up doing.
Oh, bloom filters? You're
doing bloom filters?
Yeah. I know this space.
Yeah.
It was crazy complicated.
So anyway, I went
in here and I did the
research. Now for the
research, what I did is
I used the integration
with ChatGPT's google
drive and i basically
just fed all my google
drive information
to deep research which
is a really cool feature
so basically you just
connect your google
drive and say review
all the documents and
do deep research on it
and that popped up this
this thing and which
is a ton of information
relating to the the
functional implementation
and i'm not gonna lie
i i skimmed it and
gave and asked for a
bit of an overview but
i don't generally
know exactly what this
this this algorithm is
doing other than I then
it's geared towards
optimizing the backplane
for like large-scale
5g and optical networks
so you can get 70
or 80 percent more
efficiency out of the
existing infrastructure
like so a 5g infrastructure
think of like 60
,000 people in a stadium
kind of kind of problem
and so this is this is
this is the original
so then I asked it to
go and implement the
docs. So these docs
are going to guide the
development of the
process. So I break it
down into two parts. I've
got the research, and
this is the deep
research. I didn't want to
have one giant file
because, you know, it's
hard to work with one
giant file. So I broke
it down into, you know,
various things, you
know, the installation
and the overview and
things like that. So
it's a little more
consumable. Then once
I had that in place, I
went and created an
implementation structure.
So this would
guide the actual
step-by-step
implementation.
So in this case, you
can see, you know, a
visual representation,
and this is something
that ran, again, for
eight hours, right?
So you can see exactly
what's happening,
you know, and the
interesting thing here
is it estimated the
development would take
you know several weeks
obviously it took
eight hours but um
you know then it shows
you the the flows and
the simulations and
all that sort of stuff
now and and then in
all the different
parts and then the the
data structures and
because i i wanted to
work locally and i
was cheap and lazy i i
actually implemented
the simulation using a
a SQLite database. So
rather than using a
full-fledged database,
I've got the structure
here for the actual
data structure that
I can port to like a
Postgres or something
else later, but I'm
running it locally.
And then I output
in an image because
nobody wants to see
command lines. So this
will tell me some
of the improvements.
This also is self
-optimizing. So then once I
built the CLI, which
we see in here, You
know, then I implemented
a benchmarking system
to actually optimize
the system to simulate
what 60,000 people would
actually look like.
Now, what was interesting
about the 60,000
people, when you go to
the test results, this
test results file
ended up being massive.
37,000 lines of JSON,
so it recursively tested
and optimized over
and over with duration,
no counts. So this
is what actually
created the sort of self
-learning component,
because I didn't just want
to implement an algorithm
that hypothetically
could optimize for
large groups of
people. I needed to
actually simulate the whole
entire process. so
and so basically what
what and then i i need
to i can't consume a
37 000 file you know
it's hard so then i
created a summary but
unfortunately my summary
is is also 22 000 lines
so i'm gonna my next
big part of this is
actually probably doing
a more concise version
of it which is where
i'm now but basically
in this case i can
i can run the uh let's
let's run the benchmark
and see what happens
i'm gonna copy that
i i know this is like
but there was was
there one single prompt
that you ran that said
i'm going to bed now
do this yes there was
all right so this is
the cli oh it's this
already ran so it's
probably quick so this
it does this over and
over and over again um
this is not a good one
but what do we have
a better one and ruv
the second part is you
must have you you've
given it like global
permissions right to
like add edit delete
change create whatever
which is normally
something that you're
prompted right in rue if
you don't have all of
the permissions go to
do absolutely oh yeah
yeah yeah so so exactly
and this is when
when i do my little
coaching this part here
is the most important
part so we go here and
you'll see here that
i've got a whole collection
now the important
parts are probably
right here right so
we've got we've got
things like ps and cp and
and so on so these are
these are the things
that are making it
actually work you know
in a sort of autonomous
way without these
it'll prompt you to
click run or whatever so
for me and you know
so cargo would be rust
related and depending
in the language you know
i i've got different
options but you know
for obviously go i have
go fly allows me to
deploy to fly so
often my system will
actually deploy autonomously
to fly just to get
gpu resources if i need
to do a more parallel
approach one thing i'm
going to know about
autonomous deployment
to cloud if if the
ai has the ability
to self-replicate or
choose its own resources,
it almost always
chooses the most expensive
resource available.
And no matter what I
tell it, don't use the
most expensive resource.
Don't use anything
that has more than
two GPUs. It might
start off, but as soon
as I go to bed, it
decides that it's going
to replicate and go and
use the most expensive
resource. So you
need to put secondary
systems in place to
avoid its power seeking
ai apparently wants to
take over and then i
and i what's the power
is craving the power
it is it's it's a
it's a thing i don't
know why or what that's
all about i think i
think i have something
to do with like it's
trained on human data
we live in a capitalistic
society so i think
inherently it just sort
of leans in towards
like capitalism
well actually if you
think about it right
when they when it when
the models are trained
they literally give it
hundreds of millions
of dollars worth of
infrastructure so it's
it's technically the
models are used to
having no limits to their
resources no no memory
no cpu no gpu tons
of disk they don't
care right they're used
to that whether they
remember that or not
that's how they're
trained yeah it's weird
it's i'm not gonna lie
so so you might want
to watch out for
that or put things in
place that allows it to
not overly replicate.
And it also seems
to want to replicate
itself. If you give
it the ability to self
-replicate, it will
always self-replicate.
All right, so here we
go. This is running,
so this is running
the explicit
benchmarking course. You
can see that this will
run 2800 times, which
I'm not gonna do
actually, because
it'll run for a while.
But last night, while
I was in bed, it
was running these self
-optimization loops
over and over and
over again until it
reached the coherence
of the problem I want
to solve, which was
the benchmark of the
original professor
who created the UI.
So this is what's
happening right now.
So essentially
the real power of
these systems, especially
for these kinds
of deep data and
embedded systems,
is the ability for
self-optimization.
So a lot of what
you're seeing right
here is the self
-optimization loop. I'm
gonna close this right
now. But I'm going
to show you quickly
what the auto, what
I set before I went
to bed component.
All right, so let's
go back here and
see if we can find
the original command.
So we've got
created detailed. I
think it's, no,
is it this one?
Unfortunately, it
showed the last update.
I think it was, no, this
is DevOps terminate.
Is there a timestamp?
The timestamps don't
make any sense,
because I think it has
to do with when the
last write was made.
I'm not really sure.
It's the prompt.
It's when you
put the prompt
in, I think.
Yeah. The timestamp.
If you go to history,
it would be...
It's different.
Yeah, I think
those are the
prompts people
are looking for.
Yeah, these are all
the subtasks, I think.
Wow. Yes, I
think it was like
this one. I think
it's, I'm not
sure why it's
520, but whatever.
I think it might have
to do the UTC possibly.
All right, so
this looks like it
probably was the
first one. So
let's go to the
very, very top.
Yeah.
Create a full,
yeah, so here we go.
This is what I did to
get the thing working.
So I said, create
a full test-driven
implementation of
the research I showed
you and use the
readme. So the readme
was a sort of, you
know, and that looks
like it's been
edited since, but the
original version was
basically a summarized
version of sort
of the guidance.
So, you know,
collision, you know,
database integrations,
architecture,
stuff like that.
Then I said,
you know, skip the
subframes unless needed,
because i didn't want
it to go down rabbit
holes that would just
you know i didn't
think were required
some and then i gave
it some other ideas
in terms of structure
and envs and you know
and then i so this
is essentially just
a a kind of overall
guidance prompt so i'm
reminding it what its
purpose is and i'm
showing you guys
something like that's
bonkers crazy complicated
like this is this is
like as complicated
a thing as I could
possibly freaking do.
Then I'm giving it some
different configurations.
It's all it's to to it
looks like gibberish,
but it's meaningful
for this. And I said
create plans in code
and folders install test
each function one at
a time until there's
100% coverage. 100%
coverage is really important
because it's I want
the whole thing to
build use subtasks and
i'm always reminded
about the subtask is
this is the orchestrator
and then i'm
reminded to use a new
task and then we go
back to the history
for a moment we
see these are this
is this is how it
got so each one of
these you see above
here is a subtask
right and we see the
costs you know seven
dollars nine dollars
whatever it ended up
being about 89 all toll
um i think it was like
89 and change and it
ran it ran it ran it
ran until it got to
the end and here we are
today install the scc
go library and tell
me how much it how
much it cost and what
was built and that and
that's where we and
that's where we ended
up and so rube is that
acting like your um
user stories yeah that's
exactly what it's
acting like yeah so when
we go when we look
at we see here these
these plans the the
it's a combination of
plans so the plans would
be the implementation
the docs would be the
user story the research
right troubleshooting
architecture so
this these these go
together so one yeah you
wouldn't have the user
stories in your plans
normal normal agile
product management
you would have the user
stories in with your
docs exactly but i
because i'm not using uh
you know humans or you
know it's specifically
an agile development
this is this is
agile agents more than
agile humans and it's
sequential right so
each of these needs to
build and then and
then build on the last
without breaking any
of the previous so this
is guiding you know
components so now what
i probably want to do
today for this project
is i probably want to
use a user interface
or i got two different
options i'd want
to do so now that i've
reached coherence i
either want to implement
the second phase
which takes the original
development and and
brings it into like
sci-fi world which is
you know the the fun
part And this would be
like taking and adding
statistical estimation
and other really crazy
sort of calculus.
Now, I'm not going
to do that just yet
because I probably
need feedback from the
professor and whatnot.
So I'm going to save
this for a later day.
And to be honest, I
think the professor
thinks I'm full of ****.
I don't think he
thought I could do this.
So I live for those
sorts of moments
to show that I
just did 25 years
of his life in
eight hours. but
regardless um right
it's like which
university which
university is he from
some big name
university somewhere
i don't i don't know oh
yeah yeah the
academics hate me
they're not big fans
of this um all right
so what i'm gonna do
now what like just just
so you guys can see
me spin this up so i'm
gonna i'm gonna go a
quick question about
those those plans and
docs that you have like
uh do you have a like
a structured way of
generating those like
so So every project
has the same structure
for docs and plans.
Yes, I do. And that
is, so let's go here
for a sec. And
that's the Spark. In
this case, I might
use Spark or mostly,
yeah, I think I
use Spark for this.
Yeah. So in this
case we go, and I
might not want to
use Spark at this
point. I might want
to switch to my AIGI
because I'm a leader
in the project.
But if you go to
the prompts here,
you'll see that
we've got different
modes. So if we go to the
orchestrator, we can
see what guides it.
So specification,
clear objectives,
pseudocode.
Pseudocode seems to
be the trick for a
lot of this because
you don't want it to
code initially. You
want it to create a
kind of scaffolding,
like a code-based
scaffolding. So
the pseudocode is
particularly useful
because it allows you to
create the scaffolding
for a test, then
it iterates through
the test structure.
The architecture is
then defined based on
that, so it kind of
bounces back and forth.
The refinement process
uses that feedback
loop of the tests to
iteratively build it
out, essentially. And
then the completion
essentially just
kind of finalizes it,
creates all the docs
and says what was built.
Then I'm reminding it how
to do the assignments,
different tool
uses examples.
And then subsequent
to this, there's
a folder that guides
it further. So
when you go into,
let's say, the
orchestrator mode
here, you'll see
that there's a,
where did I put that?
Spark.
This document is
basically even more in
depth relating to the
mode. So the original
sort of gives you
the mode here, gives
you this little, where
the heck did it go?
down here it creates
the modes this
essentially tells it even
more detail on how to
handle those like
don't make files that
are too long although
it has a tendency to
ignore that for
whatever reason but it
it's better than not
um and then it tells
you the subtasks and
other things so if we
go into you know each
of these you're going
to see different
different further details
like how should it
write the docs. Now
these rules are like
the overall rules
for how it needs to
interact and focus and
do whatever it needs
to do. I've included
a memory bank feature
that I can enable,
stuff like that. Search
and replace capabilities,
like what does the
search and place
need to look like to
effectively work so it
doesn't forget, and
how do you apply diffs?
This is actually an
interesting part. By
default, I wanted to
use the apply diff
capability versus is the
by the line by line option
so often when you use
these tools you'll
see it sort of scroll
line by line this
basically a more chunked
approach it'll do
potentially dozens or
hundreds of lines at once
which is faster and
more efficient and
costs less and and so
that this is this is how
i get it to sort of
to do that approach
and i mean again giving
it examples and on
how it should should
work and i give it an
alternative as well um
so you show and some
of the examples for
part your acceptance
criteria, right? Because
I was going to ask you,
how does the system
know when it's done?
When everything
- The tests,
when all the tests pass.
Okay. Yeah, so let's
do that. So you guys
will watch me set
up. I had to do this
anyway today. So now
that I've got the
CLI, which you guys
saw earlier running,
now nobody wants
to work with a CLI.
But the great part
of a CLI, especially
when you're working
with an agent
and a sort of recursive
self-operating
development process,
is it gives it
a direct access to
the application.
UIs are more difficult,
especially if we're
complex, embedded,
or algorithmic types
of applications like
what this is. I need
to be able to iteratively
test and improve.
A UI means I have to
go fix the UI, and I
don't really care about
the UI until I get
my algo working. So
now that I've got an
algo, I'm going to
say create a detailed,
Now, implementation
of the – what the heck
are we calling this
thing? Let's go back.
Oh, it was – The tools,
and I want to use
the correct
nomenclature, so I'm just
going to go back to the
implementation here,
and we'll call it
the DQMAC simulator.
Yeah, DQMAC simulator.
with that. Now, I
want to interact with
all these features
through a UI. Now,
because it's in Python
and I didn't want to
work with C because
C is really annoying,
I'm going to have to
use C eventually to
go from a simulation
to the actual printed
ASIC chip, which
this will eventually
sit on a router inside
a data center or an
ops center somewhere
in a stadium or
something. and so this
will eventually need
to be printed on a chip
but they're going to
spend some silicon
yeah they're going to
spend some silicon on
this so i created a
complete simulation of
that to prove that
this is feasible at
scale every time we send
this to the print in
taiwan or whatever
that's a two million
dollar run so i didn't
want to spend two million
dollars to realize
the thing didn't work
that's why i created
a simulator right
and this is the this
is the simulator so but
again Nobody wants to
see a simulator on a
CLI. I guess maybe the
professor does, but
most normal people
don't. So in this case,
I'm gonna create a
detailed implementation
of the simulator and
bench marking system
in a UI, including
a navigation, tabs,
modals, I don't
know, stuff like
that, you know,
organized and with a
step by step
process. I'm just
making this up as
I go, to be honest.
And what UI language
you wanted to
write in? Yes, I
am going to. Yeah.
Screen and option
to save or export.
I don't know what's
a good format for
this. I'm going to
stick with JSON for now
just because I already
have that working.
Now the question is,
to your point, which
UI framework would best
be suited for this?
Now I've got two
options. I could, I could
switch to like my MCP
mode here and, and
research what the best
option is, you know,
but I'm actually
interested in using the new
MCP option for Gradio,
which allows you to
take any deep sort of
learning models, um,
data science components
and actually make
an MCP out of it,
which would be kind of
cool. So I'm not
going to bother using
extreme lip, I'm actually
going to use Gradio.
So I'm going to say
use, use Gradio, uh,
you know,
a Gradio UI.
And now Gradio
also is great for
tests. So include
unit tests.
And I'm going to
a new UI subfolder
in plans as a series
of MDs for a phased
TDD implementation,
I guess spell it right,
not that it matters,
implementation,
and continue.
i talked to ben's
earlier this week and we
were talking about
room modes specifically
from the ui perspective
and i was curious
i was debating whether
i create a room mode
specifically around
usability and the design
frameworks so you can
actually ask it to
do this part of the
as part of the process
in room modes because
sometimes you'll have
the different
frameworks you'll have
different data requirements
right and if you want
to have the whole
thing like continuously
you know go through
the process even if
it's running stuff in
a headless environment
when you're doing
your tests this could
actually be one of
the tests in terms of
expediting the delivery
to the to the customer
or at least even for
my build process yeah
like an e2e is that
what you're describing
yeah i would love to
see like an mcp for
pigma that actually post
post like ready-made
design from there.
Like you could do like
a super high quality
app. I think they already
have it, right? Yeah,
there is that. I
mean, we can give that
a spin if you want.
I'm going to get this
going and then we'll
jump to another sub
project while this
runs. So create a
detailed implementation.
All right. I'm going
to switch to my
reasoning model. So
let's, let's, I could
probably use Jim Mike
thinking, but I'm going
to stick with, I
know what works since
I'm not going to. So,
And then create all
code and tests. I'm
redundant, whatever.
Tests.
Do you get better
results by declaring
the language or can
the agent choose?
Well, it should know
because I've told you
to use radio, which is
Python, and everything
else here has
essentially been built in
Python other than the
original C examples.
so i'm gonna i'm just
gonna let i'm gonna
i'm gonna pull the
boat motor here and see
if i can get this thing
working now i love
the boat analogy because
i i'm always struggling
getting my ****
boat motor working i
give it 15 pulls before
i you know open the
choke or whatever
but it's kind of like
that so i'm gonna you
need a bigger boat man
with an electric start
i do have an extra
starter because i'm old
i i ended up getting
it i ended up getting
electric starter for
it because yeah I'm
sick of pulling it so
so Ruben do you have
like this like you
have this create all
code and test and use
subtasks and everything
like in your in your
instructions like but
are they also like in
your in your journal
instructions anyway
for this mod like you
yes I'm just because
this is the orchestrator
I'm just kind of
reminding it because
you know it's it feed
the the original
instructions get fed back
into it um for every
subsequent instruction
so now it's going to
create a UI. Now it's
creating a sub
instruction. So that means
that it works. So it's
going to create a new
folder. Let's just
see what it guided it.
It's going to
create a max
similar benchmarking
UI in Gradio.
Now again, the great
thing about Gradio
is I now inherently
get MCPs. So I'm
getting two for one
here. I'll build a UI
based on what I've
already built, but I'll
also be able to
optimize it based on the
MCP at a later stage.
This will take a
few hours to build.
for sure. So I'm just
going to let this run
for a while in the
background. But you
can see here structure,
navigation, results,
visualization.
Now I could stop it
if I see something
I don't like.
It's already
determined that
you SQLite, so it's
figured out. Pandas
is a good choice.
Plotty seems okay.
So at this point,
I don't really
even care. I just
want a UI. I can
worry about cleaning
it up later.
It's included navigation
tabs and modals.
It's just, I want to
be organized i didn't
want to have a big
giant you know thing
so you see you're
building the building the
pseudocode so now
i'm just going to let
this cook for a while
i'm going to close
the other tabs and
uh back to the other
project all right so
meanwhile this was this
was working it fixed
the test let's see what
happens let's run
the tests here oh i
mean i mean actually
already in the folder.
We'll go ahead
and run that test.
Let's see.
Oops! What went wrong?
Well, it doesn't look
like it's initialized.
We'll initialize
that. Why not?
You know what, I'm
going to not do, oh,
this is a, this is a
problem that sometimes
happens when you run
on, especially with
MPXs, it requires human
intervention. Like
I could, I guess,
force it or something.
So which, which do
you want to link? I
think I want to link
JavaScript, I think.
So that looks like
the best option.
So I'm just going to,
oops, I'm going to clear.
I hit the wrong
button, so I'm
going to do that
one more time.
Let's do it once again,
all right,
we'll go here,
how would you like
to text and find
Got to load
the JavaScript,
React,
user, yes,
browser,
APM.
And then over here,
I'm going to say, I'm
just going to close
that up a little bit.
this is my, we're
back to my, my VS code
extension to running,
you know, stuff, but
the, the VS code
extensions as MPA MCPs.
So looks like, you
know, I'm getting
quite a bit of fails
here, but I told it
not to, not to actually
fix any of them.
I just told it to
fix the minor error.
all right so now what
i'll do here i manually
just set it up you
know run and fix all
errors as sub tasks
using what happens if
you don't say as
subtasks well it fills up
the it fills up the
context window okay
yeah i i find it's
cheaper and i'm cheap i
just don't want to
spend more than i have
to i just wonder if
there's some other
optimization that subtasks
gives you other than
context window well
because i ran the
original so i ran the
original mode here in um
in the test driven
development but now it's
creating sub tasks
for each of the things
that needs a fix so
it's just a little
more targeted it's a
little it doesn't go it
doesn't have to worry
about the other things
now the original test
uh driven components
will look at all
the tests where this
is just looking at each
individual test. So
in this case, it's
looking at the sample
server and whatever
else it needs to do for
this particular test.
Let's see what it
actually, or it's saying
fix the failing tests
in the same. Yeah.
So this is doing the
server specifically.
And it's just one of
many components that
probably are failing.
And so again, later
in the project, a
lot of this is
just doing a lot of
just repetitive
testing and fixing so
that that's what's
happening right here
now this is what i
was talking about you
guys earlier now it tests
within the structure
of rather than the
terminal it fixes
right here so this
basically said it forgot
a flag so it figured
out that it needed
the flag it says one
fails or five tests
are failing that's
so now it just it'll
interleave back and
forth until it fixes
those. So rather than
doing 100 tests, it's
only doing one test
and five sub-tests.
Or one test suite and
five tests, I guess.
Which is a much
more efficient
way to solve any
of my problems.
What does this show when
you opened the terminal?
Nothing.
So now it's embedded
in sub-terminals,
which I don't know if
I like, to be honest.
yeah well you you
can't redirect that
output of its subtask
terminals right consoles
well the plus there
the benefit is you
know if you've ever
used the terminal
components for like
client and whatnot it
has a tendency to
forget which folder it's
in that problem goes
away but it also
doesn't give me a
running view of what's
happening in the
terminal i'm not i think
it's good i think i'd
like to have like an
option that allows
me to kind of have a
little bit of both
like if there's an icon
next to the triangle
in your terminal
there. It looks
like a notepad.
If you click on
that and then change
it to Rue code,
what does it show?
So down in the
terminal, you've got
your icons there where
your terminal is.
The first one's problems.
Click on the second
one. It's output.
And then on the
right side, you're
on tasks. Change
tasks to Rue code.
Oh, maybe that's
a good... I
didn't even think
of it there.
Up a little bit.
all these all these
terminal options man
are like just there's
tons of them they're
like there you go oh
look at you look at
you uh let's see here
well it's uh no this
is it's more of what's
happening behind the
scenes isn't it it's
not yeah yeah this is
just get get messages
yeah but but but to
your that's what it's
calling though that's
that's actually
root codes out what
it's it's work uh what
do you call it yeah
but maybe one of these
other ones might might
give me a view maybe
it's just what one of
these other ones yeah
eslint you want the
eslint output right
well it's it's root
code generating that so
i mean that's interesting
i'd have to look
at the code to see what
they did to uh to move
it like that yeah but
one of these one of
these is probably their
their output i just
never maybe sorry i
didn't mean that i didn't
mean to derail you
there i thought it would
be there oh that's
okay this is this is
an interesting uh
hypothesis i just we need
to uh i'm just i'm just
not sure which one it
would be yeah that's
that's the probably
where it dumps everything
there for for all
your extensions is in
that output but they must
be doing something
like he uh like he was
saying to divert the
uh output so you can't
yeah you want to
capture the capture the
console output right
for each one of those
subtasks and then vector
it to to somewhere that
would be great yeah
yeah if you yeah made
that broke that feature
the capability if
you will otherwise all
that info is kind of
just going into the
ether well no it's stored
in each of the the uh
the history so i can
get that i can get by
going here yeah i was
just gonna say the
exact same thing you're
right rude it is in a
history file oh i just
where does it yeah
yeah it's it's supposed
to be yeah it's all in
your history yeah it's
all in this you see
each of these tasks now
i have a history with
with the with the so
i can go back and see
it now there's no easy
way to to search through
it which they should
totally add but the
what there is if you
actually search through
the the literal json
file i'll look it up
and i'll post more
information once i figure
it out yeah that that
that's roo's history
file right that we're
we're looking at the
output screen there
but you're going to i
just got a terminal output
i like where'd that
come you found it no
i just i don't know
why yeah so roo code is
spawning terminals on
your right hand side
you see bash bash bash
roo code yeah so it
is actually throwing
it out there but it's
yeah but that's the first
that's the first time
it's done it since
since the update last
week oh yeah i'm not
sure how i actually got
that to do it just now
it is you're right it
just it's automatic and
incline it's automatic
it'll keep doing that
yeah it used to be
automatic and ru up
until the change oh yeah
one of the things i
do that might help
sorry is um when it
spawns these terminal
sessions earlier it
didn't know that it had to
activate my python virtual
environment so that
was something if you're
working in python
specifically that
you may want you
might want to add
whether it's client
or ru or whatever
to the actual path
the uh to be able
to like if you're
using uv source
and source in the v
yeah that that *****
if it doesn't do that
what is it that *****
if it doesn't source
the v and activate it
yeah well that's just
guidance so this thing
is still thinking so
i just jump back into my
uh the ui i'm building
for this my simulator
so it's still uh
determining the optimal
way to do that it's
only a benchmarking
but so again now i've
got two different projects
running concurrently
one's building a ui
for a simulator system
and the other here
is building or fixing
my extension for vs
code extensions for mcp
containerized yeah
this is dan in terms of
resolving those issues
with the testing uh
a lot of us have spent
some good amount of
time with cursor um
trying to pull it out of
rabbit holes and uh so
how is rude different
in that it's able to
in the middle of the
night resolve issues
without getting itself
into uh to circles
yeah and i've i have a
cursor um a cursor
implementation i was thinking
of publishing that
later this afternoon.
And so I've been able
to figure out how
to do that in Cursor.
And so Cursor now
has an agent capability
that allows you to
sort of more
automatically run it. And
it uses almost a very
similar approach to
what I've done with
this root folder, but
I think it's client
rules or whatever.
But basically, it's
the same general idea.
And so what I'll do,
I think what I'm going
to do... Are you saying
that you would attribute
it to your rules?
It's 100% the rules.
So specifically,
it's a combination of
this Spark rules folder,
which basically tells
it exactly how to
handle recursion and
orchestration. Then for
each of the modes, it
then tells it how to
solve its own problems.
So the key here is
a couple things. So
depending on what I'm
doing, I'll actually,
I don't have it on this
version, but I'll have
an MCP integrated.
And the MCP, for
example, on a test-driven
development mode, will
say basically if you
run into the same
problem more than twice,
sometimes they do four
times. But if you run
into the problem more
than a few times, then
use MCP perplexity or
fire crawl or something
and go find an optimal
solution. A lot of
the problems it actually
runs into in the
middle of the night is
the training data. For
example, the other day,
it ran into a problem
with the response API,
right? So for those
that are familiar with
the OpenAI API, for
the longest time, we
had chat completions.
Then we went to chat
completion, singular.
Now, most recently, they
implemented responses.
Now, the responses
API is by far the best
approach to use when
using sort of the OpenAI
API. But the problem
is Open Router,
Requesti, and others
don't support it. And the
second problem is all
the training materials
for Sonic 3.7 or O3
or Gemini were trained
before the response's
API endpoint was
created, which was
released like a month ago.
So to get around that,
I've got two options.
I either explicitly
tell it, here's what the
API needs to look like
by basically running
my deep research
beforehand. end or i i
go and say if you run
into problems don't re
don't don't reimagine
a solution but go
research that using
perplexities mcp that solves
my rabbit hole or the
i can't figure out
how to solve the problem
issue that sometimes
it runs into so it's
already it's already
included in rule rules
like the that you
have like currently yeah
and you guys can see
it just just run my
mpx so when when you
run my mpx uh create
spark it's you know
you'll it creates all
those and you can guys
can modify it you
know and make your own
version of it whatever
but yeah this is this is
what's essentially
gonna do it so in this
case you'll see my
different options and uh
i haven't figured out
i found your easter
eggs yet yeah there's
there's a few little
actually i enabled it
it was it was minimal
but the create
spark like i i just
set up my co-founder
he he uses cursor i
don't use cursor he's
vs code with ru and
i he i just did mpx
create spark for him
on cursor and it
created the whole new
ru structure with
all the rules and
everything is there
anything else you need
to do to make cursor
work well so i'm gonna
do it for time I
did the MPC setup as
well, just based on
the standard Spark.
Yeah, let's go ahead
and do that quick.
And what I'll show you,
I'm just going to
create another window.
David, when you did
run that on Cursor,
I know it will
create the structure,
but I think Cursor
is limited to only
five custom modes at
the moment, additional
to agent, manual,
and ask. And also,
yeah, it can only
have five modes,
custom modes.
And they aren't
supporting the
.cursor rules.
I mean, the Rue
modes, they are not
yet supporting that,
I think. Exactly.
It's interesting
because in
Cursor, when I
ran the Create
Spark on my co
-founders system,
all of the 12 Rue
modes came up and were
created, than they show
in the in the in the
room module oh but not
but not cursor so so
i'm using vs code
currently but what what
i will show you is i
they use an mdc format
not an md format so
what i need to do is
convert that you know
i was going to do that
this afternoon anyway
maybe i'll get the
thing going here i'm
running several i have
him use the roo extension
i have him i have
him install the roo
extension into cursor
and he uses the roo
extension yeah so what
i then i run create
spark and it does all
the new the new the new
scaffold and templates
not um so he's using
room within cursor
yeah so what i'm i've
got i've got several
vs codes running so
this is a little slow at
the moment but uh
let's let it come come
to life here and what
i'm going to do here
in a moment is i'm
going to pull up my roof
development environment
which is like my what
the way i bootstrap
stuff and where i
manage my my npx if you're
curious how to create
your own npx you can
just clone that repo
or why isn't it
connecting oh okay so i'm
going okay does that
answer your question
like how i did it
i know i understand
you're using a ru
extension so um yeah i mean
i'm not using a
extension in cursa so i
managed to get four
i mean define four
of uh roofs um modes
but i'm just limited
to kind of manually
switching within cursor
okay yeah what's
going on here it's i'm
not able to connect
for some reason i've
got too many i think
i've got too many
uh vs codes running
or something and or
maybe i'm just stream
sharing i'm trying to
connect to my uh my
roof dev but it looks
like it's the
extension's failing for
some reason oh okay
i was just super slow
all right come to life
i got a ton of i got
a ton of uh code spaces
running yeah i was
gonna say i found that
code spaces makes it
act weird as well i
started using code spaces
and it does make it
slow down a bit yeah so
but i've got so many
projects on the go i
have no choice and
i've been using um like
railway and fly for gpus
depending on what i'm
trying to do so like
that project i was
showing guys earlier i
i faked the gpu but so
i'm just using a cpu
instance again i'm cheap
so but i i if i really
want to crank that
up and i want to simulate
60 000 actual you
know people on cell
phones in a stadium i
would use a gpu and then
i'd create a parallel
process for each of
those 60 000 as a thread
within the gpu but
to put a simulation i
actually just use a cpu
i use multi-threading
within the cpu but
regardless um yeah i got
a suggestion rube um
i did this the other
day I had a bunch of
VS code like a handful
of them instances open
and as soon as I jumped
on a I did a open
zoom as soon as I got
on a screen share
performance tanked in VS
code and I love zoom so
I hate to say that but
uh maybe we should uh
look into that afterwards
well it's even
worse the reason the
reason I use zoom and
not google uh meets is
google meets basically
makes the thing unusable
oh it's even worse
with meets yeah google
meets I think there's
something to do with
the videos the what
do you call video
conferencing software that
because it was you know
until i started the
screen share on zoom
and then i'm seeing i
saw the exact same thing
you're seeing where the
the vs code interface
just kind of lags
up i'm also running
like look i'm running
a bunch of different
things here yeah i do
too but i also run it
locally so that's why
i'm saying i don't think
workspaces is actually
the issue there well
yeah i don't know code
spaces or workspaces
sorry code spaces yeah
i i i have it when
when i run something
up and i've got a bunch
of code spaces it it
actually freaks out
because i researched
it and code space is
using it as sort of a
its own little protocol
behind the scenes to
get to the terminal
yeah i i could run
it in a docker or
secondary system as well
i've got a whole system
for that you know i
do like frequently.
This is the Klein
rules memory bank
system. So this
is for Klein. So
I'm going to add
that to my MPX as a,
I think a Klein
argument probably.
And I might push that
later this afternoon,
but this basically
allows you to
automate Klein. Now I
was going to do the same
thing for cursor
using the MDC format.
But to do that, what
I was thinking, now
let's go here and i'm
going to uh see do i
have the mpx i've
got so many different
code spaces like it's
hard to remember which
one's which oh this
is not running the
most up-to-date version
yeah yeah 360 man
you're behind the curve
dude well it's because
i've got so many
freaking code spaces
running but i i actually
like 315 it was a
good it was a good
release um all right
so let's just look at
my mcp servers quickly
uh looks like this
is not the right one
when you when you
run a project for
the first time
from scratch is the
first thing you're
doing npx create
spark is that like
literally step one
and then it creates
all those rules
yeah i use a dev
container so the dev
container auto does that
on the when you when it
initializes the the
instance it basically
installs that as the
first step and you can
just ask it to create
dev container to do
that but or you just
type it it's whatever
it's the same right but
that but but that'll
actually create i mean
that will generate
those rules that rules
folder that you're
talking about yeah
yeah that's what the
npx create that that's
his new command it
creates this whole
structure of like 29 files
yeah yeah the root
modes and all the rules
for the individual
modes it's awesome i
love it sometimes and
some rule isn't there
sometimes it so i just
i wasn't sure if it
was coming from if it
was specifically mpx
command that had the
rules folder in it or
um you know because
yeah by the way ruben it
doesn't do the um
the firebase and the
perplexity mcp um although
maybe you would change
it and then i was
trying the no get option
and it failed but
maybe you fixed that um
possibly i have a
tendency to get caught up
in whatever i'm currently
working on i know
that i i know you're
hyper your add man yeah
i i'm it's my add like
i was on a call with
a pharmaceutical company
uh last week and and
they're like they're
telling me how they
want me to uh help them
uh do some testing on
their new adhd drug i
know that's interesting
what what to do well
it it cures you of
adhd like what that
doesn't sound like a cure
that sounds like you're
you're you're like
like kryptonite it's
removing my secret weapon
i know yeah i don't
know if i want to like
who would want to
remove that but maybe i
guess if you're overactive
12 year old possibly
but i certainly
wouldn't yeah for adults
it's it's good yeah
for me it allows me to
work 70 hours a week
and uh yeah i know all
right i'm sorry like
this room when you're
building like this do
you are you 100 in ide
i've never seen you use
a browser or any other
like port tools or
any other tools do you
do any contact switch
and outside of the ide
well what i'm about
to show you guys is is
how i avoid having
to go to a browser so
what i don't have
currently so this mcp
isn't actually set up
correctly so what i'm
going to do is i'm
going to quickly set
this up so i'm going
to go to my my mcp
folder here and yeah
these are placeholders
this basically
initializes just to see
that the mcp works but
this isn't actually
using the mcp so in
in another route in
another screen that
you're you guys aren't
currently going to see
i'm going to go grab
the correct uh you
know url endpoint and
then what i'm going
to do Composio URL?
Yeah.
Just an FYI, I don't
know exactly what
their security is when
it comes to Composio.
So if you're like
connecting your Google
Drive and emails and
stuff, do so with
caution. But when it
comes to like data
collection or perplexity
or whatever, I don't
like care. What's the
worst case scenario?
Ruv, so two things on
this point. One is,
you know, the example
from Cloudflare
and the MCP setup
that we did last week.
So obviously,
I've been able to
set up following
the same plan. It
works through CURL
and everything.
The problem I have
had is to set up
through SSA. It doesn't
detect the tools.
I don't know if you
have seen that problem.
So in here, a small...
Which tools?
So I defined some
sample tools like
a calculator and a
currency converter,
and I can deploy a
remote MCP server
on Cloudflare
using the workers.
You know, that's the
last Thursday session
that you showed us,
right? So I did the
first two phases,
but I, and it works.
I can access my CURL,
command line, CLI.
But my problem was
when I defined that
in either VS Studio
or on Cursor, it
detects the MCP, but
it can't find the
tools through the
SSE. Let me show you.
Let me, well,
there's two ways
to solve that.
Let me show you.
All right, I just
stopped sharing because
I didn't want you guys
to see my API key.
But here's how you
solve that problem.
And my MCP mode sort
of solves that problem,
but there's another
way for you to solve
that as well. So you
see here that this
is showing the tools
and it's showing how
to use it. So it doesn't
see that inherently.
So in this case, I'm
going to copy this
and then I'm
going to go here
and I'm just going to
go in the root folder.
Why not? and I'm going
to create a new file
and I'm going to call
that mcp instructions
.md right now once I
have that so what I can
do here is I'm just
going to blindly paste
this in doesn't even
matter this is just good
enough I could format
if I wanted to but
I'm not going to worry
about that right now
so then I'm going to go
back back here to root
code and I'm going to
go into my mcp mode
Now, I do have a deep
research mode. I don't
have that currently.
I actually don't
want to do deep research
mode anyway at the
moment. So then I can
say research the...
MCP instructions.
Yeah, no, the
cursor automation
and cursor rules
format for, and I
know it's for MVC,
and convert the
.ru files into
the correct file folder
structure, or
something like that.
That's this
document, this
mcp-instructions
.md? Yeah.
So what I'm trying to
– and then I'm going
to remind it, use the
perplexity AI MCP.
And then what I'm
going to do here, and
then I'm going to
use MCP instructions,
right? So this tells
it how to operate.
And then I'm
going to say,
I'm going to
say, create the,
oh, it's not
client's cursor,
and I've got another
window with cursor
open which I'll run
in a sec ironically
I'm creating my cursor
rules in Roo which
pretty much tells you
everything you need
to know about which
platform is probably
better but regardless
um uh I'm gonna I'm
gonna do that which
is a little bit
redundant create create
the cursor uh rules
folder rules folder
rules folder like that
right i don't know
i'm not sure exactly
but this is going
to show you the you
know how it uses the
perplexity api or mcp
all right so let's
go ahead and do that
so the the tools file
the mcp instructions
this tells it how
to use the tools
otherwise it needs
to discover and
it takes 10 minutes
for it to go
back and forth and
figure how what it
should and shouldn't
do all right
let's see here all
right so now I'm going
to turn this is
always on all right oh
my first time you have
to prove it I didn't
add the auto there
we go now now that
it should work it looks
like it did include
the model interestingly
so So that's,
that, oh, why is it, I
think this is
going to fail.
I just proved it,
it didn't apparently
look at my rules
for some reason.
Well, let's see, give
it a sec. It's taken
a while. Usually fails
happen immediately
and successful queries
work. Yeah, it looks
like it worked. Okay,
perfect. It worked.
Okay, so the, the,
this is the response
from perplexity. it's
it's giving me an
overview of the
cursor rules and other
information it needs to
understand and the correct
structure so basically
it's there's no
way that you know
the sonnet model was
trained on how to you
know how to use cursor
so i have to use
perplexity for it you
know why isn't my auto
always on seem to be
working all right
well you always have
that problem it literally
works until i show
you guys yeah come
on you can do it i'm
not sure why it's
decided that it doesn't
want to auto execute
i this auto executes
all the time until
until now for some
reason all right so
now it's it's come up
with a understanding
of the mdc format using
cursor rules it's
look it's looking at
my client rules which
is fine client's not
a bad way to do it
and it's going to also
look at the room modes
file come on auto
do it all right i
don't know why it's not
doing that it's
decided that it doesn't
want to auto allow for
some unknown reason
that's a problem
for another time
maybe maybe it's
no that's on too
i could probably
manually put
this in here and
into the mcp file
So, hey, Monvib, did you
solve your
problem, though?
No, I haven't yet.
So I have managed to
deploy the MCP server
remotely at Cloudflare.
I can access the,
basically, server and
invoke the tools
using Curd CLI. But
when I add the server
with the URL to mcp
.json, whereas it does
see it, it can't find
any of the tools.
So, it says no tools
found or SSC error or
something like that.
So, I'm currently
stuck at that. Check
your – yeah, I think
I know what your
problem is. Check your
well-known folder.
Go to .well-known,
and what do you see?
You probably just
didn't create
a root for the
well-known. No, I
haven't created
.well-known, no.
Maybe that's what
I'm missing. Without
a well-known, it's
not going to work.
Oh, okay.
Is it in the
.root folder?
No, for your
MCP. So if you're
deploying and
you're deploying
your MCPs needs
a well-known,
right? Dot well-known,
that's what lasts
for tool discovery.
Okay.
I don't know why
it doesn't want to
auto. Come on, just
auto always allow.
Just stay clicked.
Yeah.
And dot well
-known is linked
to the SSC
protocol, is it?
So it sets up.
Yeah. It can't find
a gets basically.
That's what is
happening. It detects
the posts when I
do a code, but it
can't get the gets
through the client.
Yeah.
So you want to try
to do a reload of
that window or did
it just finish?
It's, you know, you
know, that's probably
what it is. Remember
when we saw he was using
a client or a Rue 3.4,
what 15 or whatever.
That's probably
the problem. It's
probably a bug
in that version.
Open the command
panel and
just type reload
and hit enter.
if you want to
reload the window.
Yeah, you know,
I probably just
need to refresh
the entire thing.
Or I can manually
go and update
the mcp.json
to include it.
I'm just, I just
don't want to, well,
actually, let me take
a quick look. I'm
just going to stop
sharing for a moment.
And let's take a
look at what the
heck's happening
in that file.
Also, requestee have
offered to set up a
MCP server. They were
suggesting if we are
comfortable storing
credentials, I guess.
So I think it
will be their
offering to set that up.
What exactly,
what would that
do? What are
they offering?
The tool that
you were using
to access the
MCP server, what
was that? I
forget the name.
Composio. What
are you using?
Composio, right? I
don't know whether
they want to do
something similar.
I mean, just hosting
someone else's MCP
server, right? that's
basically what they're
doing compose you can
it's so easy to create
uh mcp servers
there's an mpx it's so
saturated yeah there's
no value in it yeah if
you yeah many what
you what you probably
need to do there's an
mpx command create um
i have to know exactly
what it is it's like
create mcp server or
something like that
and basically what that
does is creates a a
default sort of hello
world mcp and you
just modify that what
you what you likely
you're the problem you're
likely running into
is you probably you
know vibe coded an mcp
without the um you
know knowing what an
mcp was so it created
something with and to
solve your problem i
would guess use the
default mcp sdk that
that'll likely solve it
but we all go through
that i went through
that phase a few months
ago when i was when
they first came out
with the sse capability
the vs code mcp server
you did is also a
really really good
example of of a really in
-depth mcp server yeah
so that that that's
like everything under
the sun you know yeah
uh i'm still doing the
okay enough with the
perplexity so i'm
gonna i'm gonna tell it
now to just go build
the freaking uh so i
stopped sharing but i'm
gonna share again um
one of the oops did i
stop this one of the
problems is sometimes
it has a tendency
to over analyze and
this is exactly what i'm
currently suffering
through a little bit
it decided to just
constantly research,
which is fine, but
now just go ahead
and build the ****
thing. So in this case,
I'm going to go,
I'm going to switch
modes. I'm going to
go to the coder and
I'm going to go to
my document writer.
No, I'll go coder.
I'll go coder.
And okay.
I'm going to say
stop researching
and create the
cursor rules, files,
and folders for
Spark cursor.
Use sub tasks and
new underscore task.
I know it should do
that automatically,
but whatever.
I'm just going
to, I'm just going
to get it. So I've
converted. Never
heard to nudge it.
Yeah.
So basically by
adding the use subtask
and new task, it
kind of converts the
original research
into an orchestrator,
which is, which
is a nice feature
here. So I just
wanted to orchestrate
each. So now it
creates a subtask.
So you can basically
invoke a kind
of orchestration
mode by just
doing exactly what
I just did there.
All right. so now it's
going to create the
subtask it's going
to see it's going to
and to the person who
mentioned you can only
do five i was if it
had done more than
the uh the five or
six or whatever it was
i would have told it
to to stay within the
limits it looks like
it already did that
so now and i'm creating
my cursor rules
then once this is
done i'll i'll at some
point this afternoon
when i get a minute i'll
jump in the cursor
and i'll give it a
test run and see that
it runs automatically
but basically i've
just converted my my
spark rue and climb
rules into cursor rules
you should save that
i don't want to have
to do all that work
you should save that or
make that a part of
your uh create spark so
that you can do have
a dash cursor option
that's exactly
what i'm gonna
do so once i've
done this i'm
gonna add i'm
gonna update my mpx
So let's take a
look here at my MPX.
And then that will
configure Cursor
to not need the
RU extension?
Yeah.
So in this case, you'll
see here that
I got my CLI.
So the CLI, you know,
in the commands.
So you see here, here's
the AIGI command.
So this is essentially
what allows
me to, you know,
invoke an AIGI
subcommand or the
minimal or whatever.
And then I'm just
going to add another
command that basically
will be like cursor.
And then that will use
probably a templates
folder either in
this location, which
you see Roo and
RooModes, or I can just
use like Klein rule,
you know, that's
one of these other
folders if I'm lazy.
I probably need to
reorganize this a
little bit. It's
getting a little messy.
Roof,
could you, would it
be a possibility to
kind of suggest some
default LLMs for each
of the modes as
built-in default, so
people can always
change it later. I know,
that's not a feature
of Roo, unfortunately.
What we really need,
we don't just need
that. What we actually
need is we need a
combination of the
profile options, and we
need the ability to
define the settings.
Oh, this is the old
version. i'm still running
but i need to be
able to add all these
yeah yeah you gotta
manually write them like
and every like every
day and to be honest
that's like how i i
think i i think i keep my
coaching business
alive is the fact that
people like it doesn't
automatically work with
the like yours do it's
this take a screenshot
of this yeah i have
three screenshots of
that man yeah without
this it doesn't it has
a tendency to ask you
so you just gotta every
time it it asks you
to run something just
add it to the auto
execution option here
but that's what this is
about like that's what
this is like you you
build up your own
personal profile of the
stuff that you run so i
find yeah and and it's
not required inclined
to do that like i'm
getting auto all of
that stuff without having
to to specify i wonder
what they changed in
rude to to require
you to go through that
kind of well client
i've had i had i had
a lot of problems with
client with a lot of
the more complicated uh
or you know unique
execution commands it does
the generic ones like
mpm and stuff but if
i'm you know it doesn't
do mv that you know
p pwd for example like
where am i kind of
command i don't do that
okay i mean i'm running
the latest version
so that that could be
a factor right like
whatever version yesterday
you used might be
completely different
today is is what i
experience a lot yeah
exactly running in a
virtual environment is there
a reason why you're
explicitly listing the
commands instead of
using asterisk full
yellow yeah i can do
asterisks i guess i i'm
again power seeking is
a little worrisome for
me um i i have a tendency
to i've been burned
so many times on like
two thousand dollar
google bills i don't
want to go down that
road if i can't help it
well as we're on that
how do you how do you
put the guardrails
on a project if the
project is only 500 budget
how do you make sure
that the system does
uh i i put it i i do the
guardrails independently
of this and i don't
allow the ai to
uh to edit those
capabilities the problem i
had with the google and
my two thousand dollar
google bill was i gave
it direct access to
the gcp cli and then
i get then i basically
say go go figure it
out and the api keys
to yeah that was a bad
plan yeah yeah i put
like cost limits on the
api keys and perfect
there's some other uh
middleware solutions
you can use too for
uh governance that'll
they'll act in the same
way you can throttle
so a bunch of different
solutions for doing
that what else Oh, this
thing's still building.
Let's jump back to
my other model here.
So remember that
simulator UI?
Yeah, now it's
building the phase two,
the configuration
and UI components.
So I'm literally
building three
different projects at
the same time here.
I'll probably
close this one.
in your uh profiles
your remote profiles
down there's a section
that says you know
custom instructions for
all modes and i always
get i'm unsure should
that be empty or do
you actually have a
setting for that like
a config yeah that
that's uh that's this
folder this rules folder
yeah that's almost
yeah so that's the
sort of underlying mode
that makes everything
kind of work consistently
okay because that
doesn't show in the
room mode profile ui
when you go down that
box is empty i think
yeah i just i don't
know it's i think it was
a setting i discovered
one day i'm not
really sure how where
i discovered maybe
it was my perplexity
figuring it out who
knows but it it seems it
seems to work okay
you know and you know
i've got my and one
of my favorite MCPs is
Supabase. This is what
guides the Supabase.
Yeah, yeah.
It tells you how
to use the rules.
Oh, here we go.
Oh, there's an error.
I was hoping to show
it. Oh, no, that's not
an error. That's just
an installed radio.
Let's see if
it figures it
out how to install radio.
That's a minor error.
Yeah.
All right. Let
me MPM. Oh,
this is not
IPM. That's PIP.
And it's using your unit
test too, which is good.
Yeah. So I'm just
going to spell that.
All right.
And
now where the heck is it?
I'm going to go lazy
mode for a moment.
I just want to
end on a high node
here, I'm going to
cancel this quick, and
I'm going to tell
it, run, oops, run
regradio server, I
guess, I'm just too
lazy to figure out
where the file is,
but I did install it,
let's see, and
then we'll finish
on a high node,
fingers crossed,
there's a UI to
look at, just
looking for the
command, to be honest,
height, yeah, here it is,
All right, looks like it
successfully ran.
I'm going to, oh,
oh, it's installing.
It didn't install
the requirements.
Yep.
Okay, I'm going to let it
install the requirements.
And then what I'm
going to do, once
it's done, I'm
going to actually
just run it
manually down here.
All right, looks
like that worked.
I'm gonna cancel this
quick just and see
and that's pretty
common as you're
developing in Python
as well for everyone to
understand that the
the requirements
can change you know
if you're actively
developing it it's
it's not like the the
project is you know
written in stone yet
so you're gonna have
to go back and and
install the requirements
or install them
individually as you go
yeah and and sometimes
i if i was thinking
a little more ahead
i would have used uv
or something to make
that a little easier
um i use uv it's yeah
everybody's moving
to uv now it's really
fast good yeah yeah
so in this in this
case the the simulator
is built with uv as
well because that's
yeah but in this case
you know it's fast you
know it's fast because
uv is built on rust
yeah i didn't know
that yes that's why
it's fast makes sense
oh it looks like it
got rid of all my
formatting why would it
do that oh well let's
see here i'm just
going to install that
looks like that's
already installed
for python 2 i run
um what is it uh
based um whatever
there's a couple of
linters in and uh I
don't know how you
pronounce it, whether
it's Ruff or Ruff,
R-U-F-F is another one
I run to automatically
fix the Python. You
know, we've talked
about issues generating
Python code before
and indentations and
stuff. And you often
will have to run your
code after it's been
generated through an
automatic linter as
part of either your
CICD pipeline or just to
manually do it to clean
the code up. Like,
I don't see you running
any linters right
now, but mine will
bleed orange and red
all over the place if
I open up some Python
AI-generated code with
my linters running.
That's a good idea.
You guys are just
watching me buy a
UI, so I didn't put
a lot of effort into
it. But that's a
really good way.
And a lot of that
linting will be
automatically picked
up by the Rue system.
So right now, it's
just fixing some
minor UI-related
issues, it looks like.
So let's see. Once
it passes, it doesn't
turn red. It looks
like we will...
It looks like...
See, this is a common
issue. It was using an
old version of Gradio.
Let's see. Oh,
servers are already
running, cannot be
empty. Oh, launching
port radio of
your environment.
All right.
Fix that one last issue.
I think I'm installed.
Double check
that's installed.
Yeah, it's
already installed.
I wanted to get the
UI going before,
but it looks like
this is going to work
five seconds after
we end the call.
I'm going to cancel
this slightly,
and then I'm going
to go back up here,
and I'm going to
feed it the actual,
these are like
little minor errors,
it's because I
didn't include the
full end to end
test. I just skipped
the last part and
said start it.
So let's just see what
this last error is.
It looks like it's
not included. It
looks like you
have to explicitly
include the port
now or something.
Or maybe there's a port
conflict. I don't know.
Now I'm not even
getting a response.
Are you on a
different screen?
No, I'm just trying
to see what...
It gave me the
error previously,
and I'm just
going to find it.
I was hoping I could
just get it again.
No, that's not it.
Are you talking
about the error that
it gave you when
it ran its tests?
Yeah, it's a port.
Yeah, here it is.
Oh, that's different.
It seems to not
be finding port.
This is, I
think, the issue.
Yeah, you can check
here. You have
five different open
terminal sessions.
You can close those
previous ones.
It might be running in
one of those potentially.
I don't think
so. I didn't
see it, but we'll see.
I think it's just not,
I think the config
file just didn't
include a port, which
I think a new version
of radio requires.
Oh, okay.
Yeah, that's what
I want to see.
It's not exiting, or
it's not giving me
the sort of, you
know, here you go. It
says it's running
on that process ID.
You've got ask
it to kill it.
Yeah, the problem is it's
not starting
for some reason.
Something's failing,
but failing silently.
But how come it says
it's running on that
process ID? And where
it says run command,
directly across
from that, it says
running, and it gives
you a process ID that
you could kill in your
task manager. yeah
or i can kill it right
here but i'm sure
that is a little
skull that's cool yeah
so i'm just
gonna do one two
i'm gonna do one
two seven and
i'm just gonna
go to that port
and see what happens
i'm another monitor
screen but um and see
see if i can get an error
yeah it's not running
all right well that's
a little disappointing
way to end the day
i'm sure i can figure
it out here in a sec
but basically it's uh
it's not uh something's
failing somewhere
that'll have to debug.
The worst
debugging is when
you don't get
an overt error.
Anyway, I hope
this was helpful.
Random Thursday
creation of stuff.
Ruf, when you
have completed
your simulation project,
I guess if you do some
brief documentation,
like a showcase
would be very useful
because I'm chatting
with a couple of
professors at London
Business School trying
to do some tie-in.
So I think maybe
this, and they're from
operation research
and other stuff.
So if there's some
collateral that you
can share, like a brief
about what was done,
like the complexity
of it, it'll probably
just help kind of
put a bit more context
beyond like the general
bits about Agent X
Foundation that I'm
positioned with them.
we could uh if you want
to if you want to ****
off a professor what
you need to do is
find their like latest
phd uh you know and
and then do take take
their thesis and say
let me implement it and
i'll and i'll talk to
you tomorrow and you
show up and then take
take it a step further
i'm gonna i'm gonna
improve upon your last
thesis or whatever
that's the part they'll
love that you did the
implementation if you
improve on their
algorithm you will really
**** them off yes so
that is exactly what i
was showing you earlier
i i took there i
took the guy's thesis
and i basically just made
it better and again
the craziest part of
that whole thing is
this company that was
the the cheapest company
we got to quote us
on the uh implementation
was eight hundred
thousand dollars u.s
so and literally eighty
nine dollars in eight
hours you guys saw it
like between five and
two in the morning or
whatever it was and it
did it it works it's
optimized and my my
simulation anyway beats
theirs so i get better
results than they
did so um as for like
how you want to go about
presenting it to them
obviously not maybe
not so aggressive but
something like that
we can we can crank us in
powerpoints or
something i guess
well you could get
gamma to crank them
out yeah exactly or
deep deep research
um i am getting uh
yeah i'm getting an i'm
getting an error i see
the error now there's
a uh unexpected argument
or something all
right till till uh
next time guys uh hope
thanks for joining i i
enjoy these things so
hope they're valuable
for you Thanks, Rue.
Thanks, Rue.
It was awesome.
Are there any event-based
notifications or
notices we want to bring
up in this call
specifically?
I guess tomorrow we have
our air hackerspace
session.
Oh,
Brad. Yeah,
Brad is doing a
slow code
tonight, which is
interesting. It's
7 p.m. Eastern.
Do we have a
link to that?
I don't know. I can
send it to that.
but I can send it
right now. One sec.
So yeah, Brad, are
you still on the call?
I need to do a
better job of
self self-promotion.
Sorry guys.
Wait, you do what?
Yeah.
That's, that's, that's,
that's why I
keep Alex around.
He's reminding me that
it's okay. No, you
do. You carry enough.
Yeah. So Brad Ross,
one of our, one of our
leads here at agentics
foundation has, is
organizing a slow code.
So you know it's
fun to come to these
sessions here and learn
and explore the frontiers
of kind of where we
can push this this
slow code session is
intended to be a session
where we just are
getting you know spark
up and running on like
an initial project
and just kind of moving
a bit slower as a group
so if that's of interest
to you i'm going
to drop a link right
now to the google meet
in which we are all
going to be connecting
on uh later today so
it's going to be at
7 p.m i believe eastern
time it's a live
coding so it's we're
calling it the root code
starter pack so i'm
going to drop this into
the chat and um feel
free to message uh us
on linkedin or anything
like that as well
oh it looks like you've
got that there nick
thank you nick so no
problem just added a
little bit more okay
can we make sure it's
recorded at least i'm
not be able to make it
unfortunately yeah yeah
we'll do our best to
make sure most of these
um projects or most
of these interactions
are recorded um i
don't know um when those
will be live but um
we'll be posting to
youtube is our goal i'll
be i'll nag somebody
about it because i'm
really can just stream
it google allows you
to just stream it
directly to youtube i
think google meet from
google meet itself just
live stream it to
youtube yeah the the
problem that we might
run into is how you know
the it's really difficult
to stream or share
do desktops sharing
for extended period
of time you also want
to make sure we filter
out exposed api keys
so definitely not wait
what we're supposed
to do that oh what
forgive me it's been
it's been a week since my
api key has been
hacked and i wish i was
kidding i i must have
to budget the uh you
know the occasional api
hack um all right so
yeah i wrote i wrote
to take my keys every
every week for exactly
that reason but nobody's
giving back more to
the community roof
than you are apparently
yeah three api keys
for everybody the
problem is what you said
earlier is that ai
wants the power So now
you have to like rotate
it just to kind of
beat your own agents
from your API keys too.
I know what I'm doing
and I still get my
API keys leaked. So be
careful. It's really
difficult to stop
that, especially if you
let it run for eight
hours and you don't
look at every line of
43,000 lines of code.
So anyway, it's
one of those things
you definitely have
to keep an eye on.
All right, I gotta go.
i'll talk to you guys
tomorrow for anyone
joining the uh ai
hacker space tomorrow
otherwise uh i'll see
you when i see you you
don't have to go home
but you can't stay
here yeah exactly it's
it's it's it's closing
time yeah okay bye