It's the 18th
of July, 2025.
We're more than halfway
through the year.
This is, you know,
it's, this week has been
sort of defined based
on sort of a combination
of lots of bug fixes
for the Claude-flow
system which keeps
just going and going.
And lots of interesting
meetings and
opportunities including
one where, what
was I talking to? The
guy who says he did
the tech on the
Matrix movies back in
the late 90s and early
2000s. And he was
telling me all the
background stories
on what he was doing
as part of sort of
the team that built
the Matrix movies.
And actually, one of
the most interesting
parts of the story he
was telling me was the
fact that he said
that, according to him
anyway, the first movie
to where they show someone
typing on a keyboard
and using the space
bar was the matrix
apparently before that
movie all the times
you would see someone
typing on a keyboard
they didn't hit the space
bar and if anyone's
ever typed knows that
it's really hard to
type anything without
hitting a space bar if
you want to have a you
know more than one word
so it's it was uh it
was an interesting sort
of observation i i'm
hoping it's true but
uh interesting story
nonetheless um thanks
everyone who who always
supports me on these
coaching calls i love
doing these and i know
a bunch of you who
are on today are probably
active uh supporters
of mine so thanks
for that um we've got
a we've got a really
good uh i guess show
livecast whatever we
call it these days um
hackerspace lined up
today uh rob who do we get
lined up oh we've got
a great assortment So
today, one of our OG
members, Jen Arden,
he's got a demo on how
to set up Rackspace,
use it as a target for
DevPods for dramatic
savings and excellent
compute accessibility.
So I think we're
all looking forward
to that one. And
then John Hessing
is going to share
his talk with us
that he gave to his
legal community.
And John is one of our
elder statesman
engineers.
So it'll be
really fascinating
to get his perspective.
We have Mark
Roddock. He's got, as
we saw a little bit
yesterday during
your coding session,
Reuven, he's
got a front-end
swarm visualization.
Quick demo of a front
-end swarm visualization.
So I got a sneak
peek. It looks great.
And then Mondweep
has been pulling
together resources
from the various, your
repos, Reuven, and
the materials for
Hackerspace, getting
it prepped for the
learning platform.
So he's got some
stuff to show us
there. So lots today.
All right. So it's,
well, before we
do, we should jump
in. I guess there
was a AI, our Gentex
meetup in Orange
County last night.
Anybody go to that?
They can give us
a little update
on how that went,
what was discussed.
Is Canal on today?
If not, I saw it. No,
I was on it, though.
This is Mike Watson.
There you go.
Oh, hey, Mike. How's it
going? Hey,
how's it going?
Great.
Yeah, it was good.
It was almost all
educators and different
people, mostly across
the full spectrum
of there's a student
there, there was
administrators there.
And we were shown
just, you know,
the slides for
Agentex and then just
a little bit about
some of the pet
projects that he
had done himself.
introduced a little
bit about like what it
is and how it works
but all of them except
for me were coming
from an education point
of view either they
were in public education
or private or charter
or doing some type of
tutoring or doing some
sort of platform on
it and all of them
were interested in how
do you really they talked
a lot about how does
this fit into traditional
education or not
and how does this
flip everything on its
head uh or not um what
do we what do they
have to do to bring it
into the thinking of of
education uh so it
was it was interesting
yeah well and and uh
thanks for making the
trip down you know yeah
probably wasn't too
far for you i don't
think oh yeah it was it
was far but that's
traffic oh it was oh yeah
yeah la is terrible
for that it's awful and
i left too late so oh
but it was still good
i got i got a chance
to listen to uh just a
bunch of podcasts and
stuff so it was good
good alone time yeah
well yeah i i hate la
traffic to be honest
it's a nightmare and i'm
in toronto which has
is notable for having
you know equally bad
traffic because we got
like one highway but um
yeah la wins you know
i remember one time
actually i was driving
from uh from the inland
empire wherever you
guys call it there down
to san diego and i'm
driving along in my
rental car and all of a
sudden there's this fire
on both sides of the
highway and this and the
traffic had completely
stopped and i'm
feeling the heat from
the fire on the side
of the car i'm like i'm
not gonna i'm not gonna
burn this car so i
bolted along the side
of the highway where
you're not supposed to
drive there's like fire
flying flying off the
side of the car and
when i when i took the
rental car back to the
airport it was a white
suv but it was totally
covered in black and
the side view mirrors
were partially melted
and they're like what
and and it seemed like
a normal occurrence
to this rental car
company they didn't i had
to pay the damage
deposit unfortunately but
it wasn't it wasn't
surprising apparently
but anyway that's and
i am here uh i was i
was uh i was on the i
was on the zoom or on
the on the linkedin uh
link but here i'm on the
zoom here uh but um
yeah the uh mike thank
you so much for coming
uh yeah we it was a
room of mostly educators
uh and uh that's my
that's kind of my
world uh and I think uh
really sort of exploring
how agentics work can
be potentially you know
I've been I've spent
my entire career in
education 20 years
maybe it's 30 at this
point I don't know uh
trying to turn upside
down turn education upside
down and I've been
i was in the private
sector for a while and
then when generative ai
when chat gpt became
public i was like oh
my god finally i think
we have a chance to the
like i think education
is gonna be forced
to change now so i
that's what brought me
back into public education
uh and um and sort
of seeing the energy
around that you know
there's a lot of there's
a lot of haters too of
course um there always
is when there's a
big big change happening
uh and especially in
a place like education
that does not want to
change that really
really does not want to
change um i think we've
we've uh we've got a
chance to to really
upend it so it was really
great i hope that we
can uh i hope i can
help maybe also to sort
of lead some got you
know k-12 kind of kids
what does that look
like uh with agentix
and so uh it was a great
it was a great session
and mike thanks for
coming awesome well
i really appreciate
putting it together you
know that that was a
great uh the feedback
has been really good i
got a few messages
this morning um at some
point i'm gonna have to
get myself back down to
the states and attend
some of these in person
but until then i really
appreciate everyone
kind of putting
putting in the time and
getting these things
we should get some t
-shirts for you guys when
you do these like that
that would be the
least we could do so at
least at least we're all
wearing these t-shirts
i'm not wearing
mine today i'm i was
literally just about to
uh ping ping rob asking
him for a t-shirt for
the denver one so right
on cue yeah let's do
it let's do it yeah
there i do have a lead on
a custom hoodie company
that uh was was
offered to help us with
hoodies i'm not sure
how if anyone wants to
wear a hoodie in the
middle of july but uh
we'll figure that out
um so today i i'm not
gonna spend a lot of
time on the demos, but
what I want to show you
guys a little bit was
my flow for how I
handle all the sort of
tickets and things and a
few more tips and tricks
on the system that
might be interesting
for you guys. So I'm
just going to spend a
few minutes showing
sort of how I handle my
GitHub updates and things
like that, if that's
helpful. Because one of
the most useful parts
of this platform,
besides the fact it can
do a lot of things
all at once, is how it
integrates with mcps and
other tools so you'll
see here that i
recently did this like
recently like i think in
last night i pushed the
alpha 61 uh version of
cloud flow and you'll
see that i it's an
amalgamation of bugs
and and little issues
here and there that relate
now i'm i'm organizing
all of this through
the the cloud flow
system but i don't always
actually directly
use the the dot cloud
flow or the uh the mpx
cloud flow at alpha i
actually once i've got
the system instantiated
you'll notice that
there's a bunch of slash
commands that that
allow you to use the
system without actually
having to use the cli
directly so what i
want to show you guys a
bit of that so right
now what i'm working on
when in between all
my various calls and
whatnot is the the next
release so i don't try
to do everything at
once because if i'm if
i'm trying to fix
everything under the sun
there's currently 69
issues open which is good
because it was like
90 earlier um so what
i'm trying to do is just
group group problems
in combination of
things that were they've
been open for a little
while versus things
that i just want to add
so in this case this
morning i i sort of
prioritized you know the
swarm status which was
a recurring problem
where the mcb tool
didn't actually give me
the correct status
then some architectural
improvements i'm working
my way through linting
and other errors and
you'll see here that
i've got you know i at
one point i had something
like 7 000 typescript
errors and now i'm
down to about 400 these
aren't things that
actually affect the
operations they're mostly
sort of they just
don't look good um and
and other various things
and you'll notice here
that i said i'm i can
i make them related
to the actual bugs people
are posting because
i want to i want this
to be a community so
this particular release
is mostly just fixing
things people are
saying is aren't working
for them like it
doesn't work right on
windows or i'm getting
issues on mac that kind
of stuff now the mac
one is hard because i
don't currently have
my mac mini plugged in
so i probably should go
and do that but um but
i'm running it i
generally know what the
error is so it's not
necessarily something i
need to worry about
since here as the system
progresses about an
hour ago it updated the
various parts so i'm
going to show you a
little bit of kind of
behind the scenes of how
i'm doing this here's
another major update.
As the swarm progresses,
it's basically
using the GitHub
issues as the central
location of where
it coordinates
and updates. So not
only am I seeing
the changes, everyone
else is as well.
All right. So in this
case, what's it doing
now? All right. So in
this case, what I'm
doing is I'm just
doing some final checks
because I'm going to
push the alpha here in a
moment. And you'll
notice here, I'm just
double checking that the
swarm data is persistent
because sometimes
there's regressions.
It actually works fine.
The other thing you'll
notice that when I'm
running in my dev
environment, I'm actually
not using the MPX.
So for those that
aren't familiar with
the concepts of an
MPX versus an MPM, or
in this case, a
global install versus
a remote install,
using this essentially
allows me to sort
of run it locally
without running it
remotely. So when I'm
going here and testing
it, you'll see here
that but I'm actually
using the dot
clod file that's get
placed in the root.
Now, right now what I'm
trying to do is basically
make sure that
there was a minor
error earlier and
which you might be
able to see, where
did I put that?
There.
Yeah, I was getting
some minor errors with
the SQL, which I fixed
and I was getting an
error where it wasn't
finding the architect.
Yeah, here it was right
here. So you'll see
here that the architect
was missing for some
reason, so I fixed that.
Now the architect's
working. now the only
thing i see i see two
two check boxes which
is weird but you've
got different so the
system is actually built
not necessarily for
human interaction this
is the part that a lot
of people get confused
by so when i'm going
in here and i'm typing
doc flawed or flow you
see a million different
options oops i gotta
type it right and
and then within each
of these options you've
got sub options so for
example if i'm looking
at the hive mind
status or i want to do
some training, you go
in here and you run the
training component and
you see there's a bunch
of different other,
like the neural train,
there's the pattern
learning. Now, I haven't
pushed the neural
network components as a
default option,
although the swarm has a
tendency to self-discover
it and use it. But what
I might do in an
upcoming release is make
that as a default option
because yesterday I
ran a benchmark, which
I want to show you
guys quickly before I
go back to my GitHub
stuff i'm jumping around
a little bit here but
if you're curious i
everything i try and test
i'm actually posting
here to the system
itself so where do we
yeah here it is so someone
asked maybe it was
jed someone asked you
know what's the
difference between running
sort of the default
swarm versus running one
with sort of the
the micro neural net
optimizations so you know
i did a quick sort of uh
a b test that basically
looked at the sort
of performance of one
versus the other and I'm
seeing substantially,
it runs substantially
faster. So what it's
doing is it's making
a prediction of what
it needs to do with the
next step. So it kind
of optimizes, it self
-optimizes the next step
and that ultimately
improves the performance.
Now, I actually was
doing this as well
yesterday using alternative
models other than
Claude. And I think I
was using DevStroll,
the open source model.
And adding a sort of
secondary neural net
alongside a sort of
less proficient coding
system has a dramatic
effect as well. So the
success rate is a kind
of indication of that.
And on DevStroll,
I actually saw that
closer about 70% increase
in success. So when
you're looking at
success, that means making
a request that results
in something that
doesn't create an error
or is not right for
whatever reason, like
it's got an extra quote
or a bracket or
something like that. So,
and this is funny, the
memory efficiency is
better, but it was
such a small number
that it didn't even show
up as a number. It's
like in kilobytes, but
that doesn't matter.
So I'm running these
sort of optimization
processes. So you can
see here the default
configuration versus
the sort of swarm
configuration. And
that relates to another
feature that the system
is using that you
probably don't necessarily
see all the time,
which is actually
this feature of the
coordination system.
So you notice here that
there's a coordination
system. And a lot of
this is happening when
you don't look, right?
So if you run
coordination, you'll see
that there's different
structures for how
it can initialize and
different topologies
for how it's going to
organize the agents.
And again, and hopefully
we see a little sort
of demo here from the
UI components, but
a lot of this is
happening under the covers
and you don't get to
see exactly what's
happening because I don't
have a nice graphical
user interface to
display it. But I think a
few folks are actually
working on that as
well. But moral stories,
if I run it, they'll
just run that quickly.
You'll see here that
it's initializing and
that essentially is
initializing this
information to the database
itself. So it's
basically saying here are
the agents available
and here's how you guys
can essentially communicate
with each other.
Now, the other thing
I want to show you
guys quickly is often
when I'm running this,
I don't actually use
that command at all to
instantiate. I'm actually
going in here and
using the dangerously
skip permissions option
and i'm just going
to copy this because
i'm too lazy to type it
i go back in here and
i'm just going to do and
if i want to continue
i'll use dash c i
don't want to continue
because i'm just
showing you guys how it
works but almost all
the real functionality
you want in the system
is actually in the
slash commands these
slash commands you can you
can also customize so
when you see the cus
these folders these
are the system this is
how the system works
you know from like a
human point of view so
rather than trying to
type this big long
command in into a command
line which really
doesn't work particularly
well this little user
interface is actually
easier for copying
and pasting you can go
in here and type things
like github and in
this case you've got
you know issue tracker
code review so i can
spin up a code review
swarm to to explore
someone's pr you know or
i i can use this to do
my own pr or i i can
prep my release to prep
for the npm publishing
so i'm using the system
but i'm not using
it i'm using it directly
within cloud code
so in this case
i'm going to select
this one and i'm
going to say uh review
the you know i
gotta go figure out
what which one i
want to look at let's
let's do this one
this is an issue one
oh this is yeah
this is the
issue and see
and see if there
are any ways to
further improve
the neural network
components.
It's pretty well
optimized at this point,
but you know, worth
a shot. So now what
happens when I do
that is it's invoke,
it's using the commands
from that particular
issue tracker, which
you can go here
and take a look at.
So we hear, we see
issue tracker, and
you can customize all
these just by pointing
cloud code out
and say, you know,
customize it for my
particular repo or
whatever I'm building.
so you can see here
it's telling it how to
use the mcps it's telling
you know giving it
the guidance it's
saying that this one's
optimized for roof fan
you know but you can
see the different options
and i might have to
customize these a
little bit more to be
honest and make them
maybe more generic um but
here we are so now
it's looking it's it's
it knows how to work
with it now it's it's
spinning up a task not
a doesn't always need
a swarm in this particular
case the question
I gave it doesn't
really require a swarm.
Now, I could have
asked it to spin up a
three agent swarm, but
I don't think I need to
do that because it's
a really simple sort
of request I'm giving
it. But anyway, long
story short, a lot of
what you're going to
want to do involves just
either modifying the
commands folder or
invoking these different
options. Like if you
see self healing or
session memory or smart
agents, you basically
can just say, you know,
use the smart agent
capability and spawn
agents whenever you
need. And it tells it
sort of how it needs
to do that. You can see
this one's using the
roof swarm approach.
And I'm leveraging a
little bit of several
of my NPCs to do that.
Hopefully that's
useful for you guys.
Again, there's a ton
of features here.
There's probably
more features than
you can possibly
sort of understand.
But But point it
at it, try it,
modify it, do whatever
you want. There's
lots of ways to
use the system.
It's kind of unique.
I'm thinking now that
I see it, I'm probably
going to have to go.
And now that I've
actually better
integrated Roof Swarm,
which you can
actually go here and
try as well by doing,
check this out.
Roof? So Roof Swarm,
yeah. I see you
doing completion
within, tab
completion to expand,
and we'll have you
within Claude code.
Can you also have
shell expansion? So
if you're on the
Linux command line,
you could hit tab and
it would ask it to
inquire us what the
sub options are.
I'm not sure I
understand your question.
Well, you say you
could pass them on
the command line,
but it's better
because it will
introspect to find the
options when you're
in Cyclawed itself.
So what I'm asking
is whether you can
do add shell expansion
so that if you're
on the Linux command
line, you can
hit tab and Linux
would inquire to the
shell, sorry, inquire
to your system
to find out what
the suboptions are.
uh sorry martin i'm
not sure i understand
what you're you're
asking me but i i i do i
i do have all all the
commands for the system
to under to sort of
understand how to use
the system or either
in clod.md right so
this this tells it how
how it needs to discover
things or expansion
no i'm not sure what
you're referring to
okay let's let's let's
let's let's move on
guys um yeah but we've
we've got some we got
some good uh presentations
lined up and i don't
want to take it
too much time today so
let's uh we can come
back to that martin a
bit and i'll i'll try
to i'll try to
understand that better um
uh rob who do we have
first up on deck here
oh i i think i guess
guess rob is uh he's
muted me sorry i'm
talking away to myself
why don't we start
yeah why don't we start
with mark uh he's
got a quick uh swarm
visualization and then
we can uh welcome john up
hey mark how you doing
hey rob hey roof um
so so look i'm not
an easily intimidated
guy but this is a
pretty **** intimidating
group to demo anything
to especially when you
are a ceo thinks you
can code so um last
night i spent some
time kind of you know
stimulated by the
conversation we had yesterday
thinking a little bit
about how we might
visualize more complex
swarms operating
together and in effect
even in overlapping modes
let me share my screen
quickly i promise
this won't take very
long um give me one
sec here sorry my uh
my mac has decided of
course to ask for
permissions there's no
dangerously skip permissions
unfortunately demo
gods yeah well we i
think we named the the
greek god of demos
democraties or something
all right well let's
yeah so it'll it'll
show me now all right
so you guys see this
now yeah it's loading
here we go all right
um so the idea here is
to be able to sort of
step back and visualize
all of the swarms
that are in flight and
some of them will have
started you know before
others have finished
uh and so you can
sort of see that the
the main orchestrator
line is this gray line
down the middle and
um this is a kind of
a swarm ******* off
here you can see there's
a few different
participants um and you can
always take a look at
the beginning of the
swarm and understand
the prompt that was
that kicked it off
if it's linked to a
particular GitHub issue
and its current status.
So you can kind of zoom
around and see
what's running.
You've got the ability
to kind of interrogate
more about this. So
I can click on it and
say, well, how much
is the token estimate?
What was the
prompt that was
used? How many
agents are running?
And what was
interesting about
this, when I built
this last night,
I asked it to create
the ability to add
a swarm. And so it
created this little,
you know, what kind
of swarm do I want
to give it a name? A
swarm button. Swarm
button, right?
Medium priority, high
priority, quick
description of the goals.
You know, whether
I wanted to kind of
pick a really good
prompt template that
would help me write
this more quickly.
And then I could pick
from the swarm team.
And it actually named
the team much like
Serafina ended up naming
herself. It named the
team. So I could say
I want to, you know,
a front end designer,
a full stack developer,
a DevOps engineer.
and then i said well
what if i could like
pick methodologies you
know and it would
sort of pick its own
governing methodology
why the **** it decided
waterfall was a good
agentic methodology i
don't know but whatever
um and then you know
some kind of some kind
of other settings so
i know this looks a
bit like the london
underground um and
that may give people
some fear and uncertainty
but i just when
you're thinking
about really complex
swarm um methodologies
Being able to visualize
how they're all
starting and stopping
and kind of in
parallel was something
that had been causing
me some kind of
mental grief. So for
lack of a, you know,
whatever, that's
my contribution to
the visualization
ideation exercise.
And how are you
integrating?
It is completely
unintegrated
at this point.
It's purely
hypothetical because,
again, Reuven, I did
it last night just kind
of, you know, after
dinner. so you know
well that's perfect
then i don't have your
jedi knight capability
no no this this looks
amazing by the way
and i love the colors
dark dark mode 100
and uh so there is a
not well documented
feature in the system if
you guys run the uh
cloud flow uh command
start and space dash
ui that one of the
most it's not fully
built but one of the most
useful parts of
that is actually the
WebSockets component. So
the WebSockets is a bi
-directional communication
system directly
back to the main
runtime of the platform.
So everything you're
seeing here can
be integrated using
the WebSockets for
a real-time update.
So as the system
spawns and creates
and orchestrates,
your graphics
would essentially
be updated in real time.
So I don't think it's
probably too much
work to actually
add that capability.
and make this actually
work. Now to do
that, what we likely
are probably gonna do
is take your source
code, create a branch,
and then essentially
point the swarm
at it and say, integrate
the web sockets.
And I don't think
it'd probably be too
much work. And
maybe we could even
add this as an option
to my current UI.
So when you run
that UI command,
it sort of kind of
works, I need to do
more work on it, but
we could add that as
like a tab or a new
feature or something.
And what UI system
is this built in?
So this is just a
little TypeScript
app. I don't know what
the actual library
is choosing to
use this because I
didn't really dive
too deeply into it.
Declarative.
But I sort of said
to it, look, I really
want something that
looks like train
tracks or the London
Underground. And
it sort of decided
it would pick that.
I mean,
but Roof, to be honest,
I haven't really even
had a chance to go and
check what decisions
it's made. But I'll
happily share this with
the group in whatever
the easiest form is
um and if you guys want
to run with it uh or
help me run with it i
would love to do that
well there's there's
a couple folks on the
call that have been
working on on similar
concepts your your
illustration is is quite
useful as as a kind of
temporal you know just
description of it it
kind of reminds me a
little of like a
combination of star trek and
star wars and we see we
see with that demo why
it is that people are
now postulating the
end of the ide entirely
i i i think this is
a good point rob because
you know i've when
i started this journey
uh i you guys don't
know the story but i got
on a plane from vienna
to toronto eight months
ago and said screw
it i haven't coded for
25 years but this all
this agentic ****
i'm sure I could code
something. And by the
time I landed in Toronto,
it actually coded
something, but I was still
very kind of IDE
centric in my mentality.
And it's taken me
months, but I now
spend very little
time in the IDE.
I spend quite a
lot of time just
chatting with Claude
Code and looking
at the kind of
Claude Flow swarms.
And then that, I
guess, maturation and
kind of relaxing away
from having to see
all the code all
the time has been a
mental shift for me.
But being able to
visualize the swarms
graphically like this
just felt like the
one missing piece
that I needed to kind
of understand what
was going on because
I was getting a
little spooked by it
all happening behind
the scenes, so for
what it's worth.
I love it. Looks awesome.
All right. Thanks, guys.
Well done. Very neat.
Okay, so we have
up, thank you, Mark,
John Hessing.
John, are you there?
There we are. Hey,
John. It's actually
John Messing.
Messing, I'm sorry,
John. That's okay.
You're welcome.
Thank you very much.
I need to be able to get
to do screen sharing,
and most of the
Zooms I've been on,
there's something that
comes up on my screen.
So if you could
help me along
here, I'd sure
appreciate it.
Right down in
the middle at the
bottom of the Zoom,
there should be
a green button
that says share.
Yes.
Do you see that?
Yep.
And then… Do you
see my screen?
No, then you
got to, I think
you got to choose
the window.
There you go.
Okay.
So this is a
demonstration that
I did for a group
of lawyers along
with a number of
other lawyers.
And I was going to take
from this presentation,
but then I found
it's now behind a
paywall. But the reason
I want to show you
this page is one of
my co-presenters, a
gentleman by the name
of Masai Brown-Andrews,
we've made a connection
through LinkedIn
since, and I believe
he's on this call. I've
asked him to consider
this group, so I wanted
to let everybody know
that this is happening.
This is the, I built
this system as part
of a project to deal
with court documents
and hallucinations,
which is a big issue in
the legal community.
The judges are very
upset when they come
across hallucinated
citations, but there's
two parts to this project.
And I call the second
part the ********
sniffer, because far
more serious than
hallucinations is the
deliberate misrepresentation
in court documents
in ordinary court and
ordinary trial practice
of the proposition
for which the cases that
are cited are supposed
to stand. and there
was a lawyer in my
community who used to
say if you can't dazzle
them with brilliance
baffle them with ********
and the problem is is
that we're beginning
to see the second
part of that become a
cultural norm in a
lot of our dealings in
the world so I think if
I can do both of those
I'll do some service
to the legal community
and maybe to the whole
rule of law notion,
because I think it
undermines the rule of
law. So this is a
pretty simple interface.
I started this in
Rootspark. And before
Reuven said, don't
put it locally on your
machine, put it in code
spaces so you don't get
the panic screen and
get your system *******
up. at the advice of
my bot friends which
were chat gpt and
anthropic i put it
locally and sure enough
i got the panic screen
and the things weren't
working right which
when you're trying
to do a demonstration
that you don't know if
you really are going
to be able to complete
it in time puts a
certain nerve-wracking
uh condition on it but
i got far enough um
just uh dealing with
Claude as a chat bot
to have this work
enough. And I want
to be able to take it
and take it to its
final conclusion.
So let me show you
what I've got so far.
This is a document.
I'm sorry. This is
a document that I
prepared about, I'd
say 25 years ago, 15 to
25 years ago for
court filing. It's a
preliminary draft. It's
fine for this purpose.
And I know it has
no hallucinations in
it. So let's take a
look and verify that.
And sure enough, it
shows zero suspected
hallucinations. Now,
one of the difficulties,
there are three
or four similar
kinds of systems
that have
come out since I
developed this.
But one of the
unique things
that I have
over here is an
ability to change
the sensitivity
of this algorithm,
because if you get zero
hallucinations, you
don't know what you
don't know, which
is, did it miss? Is
it so insensitive that
it actually missed
the hallucination?
So this was something
I built into it to
do as a double check.
And if we go ahead
and take a look at
it, it has four
suspected hallucinations.
Now, this is where
it needs a little
bit of polishing,
but it's possible to
determine that
these are false
hallucinations. This
is one variant of it.
It comes up differently
for different cases.
But the very, if you
see, it comes up with
four hallucinations,
but it gives the same
cases. This is actually
hooked into a, I
should have mentioned
this earlier, into a
repository of court
decisions that is maintained
by the Free Law
Project, the horrific
institution. And the
thing that's most
important for my purposes
is that it is a dynamic
system. As cases are
generated daily, they
are brought into the
system. So the idea
of having to work with
a static database that
while the law is
growing every day is
eliminated by tapping
into this system. And
this is a free API, and
it's a REST API. But
what it does is it
takes and does a fuzzy
kind of determination
on matches. So my system
is taking and extracting
the citations of
the cases, which would
be more like this,
the 543rd, 729,
and sends that off
to the REST API,
PortListener goes
into its system and
brings back what it
matches out of it.
And it has because
this is some of these
are let me see if I
can get down here.
It might be United
States in their system.
So it has to match,
mix and match various
things. And what it's
done here is it it
has tried to match
some things and it's
not it's not elegantly
done. This needs to
really all be suspected
false positives.
And the way I was
working with just
the chatbots, they
were not able to
do this modifying
the Python code.
I can see that's really
going to be critical
for a period of time,
that hallucinations
don't intentionally
or unintentionally.
make their way into
a court of law.
Exactly.
And the judges
are very, very
suspicious of this.
Now, if I take this,
we can bring it
into the interface.
You see, this
becomes a workspace
now. If I go back
to these spaces and
view the case.
Well done. Let's
take a look at this
case right here.
You see, a workspace
is being created.
This is the case
itself. And by checking
the names and the
citations, I'm able
manually to verify
that those are false
positives. So the purpose
of the sensitivity
has now been verified
that, in fact,
70 is probably the
right setting for
this system. And so
let's go and take a
look. We've got to
wrap it up soon here,
John. Sorry. We have
two more to get to.
Okay. Let me just
take this over here.
That's the case as
well. I'm sorry. This
is a little bit of
a stretch for me.
Come on.
There we go.
And you see it comes up
with a hallucination.
And if you view the
case, it's a different
case. court listener
is trying to match
the false citation,
which is 221-111, with
the closest match.
And this also could be
done a little bit more
elegantly. Now, the
other part of this that
I would like to deal
with is... Oh, dear.
Last 30 seconds, Sean.
Okay. Give me a second
here. Yeah, yeah.
That's okay. Yeah,
it's a little. I know.
I know.
Okay,
here we go. Let me
just switch the window.
No, I'm not able
to get this up.
Let me just see if it's
underneath here. It is.
So now if I
Take this down. I
built this in Gemini,
where you enter a legal
proposition on a case
citation, it gives
you a rank relevance.
I'm not going to go
through that right now,
but what I wanted to
do in this system,
yeah, here we go,
was to be able,
for example, in this
case, to have an
overlay where what
I just showed you in
Gemini, You could
query the case in this
workspace, which would
really help lawyers
and judges understand
what has been presented
to them, whether it's
a junior associate
or whether it's
opposing counsel or
whether it's a litigant.
So you can quickly
get a handle on the
issues in the case,
probably save at least
50 percent of the
time in terms of
being able to respond.
So that's basically
where I am now.
I want to do this
in Swarm and not in
Claude code for a
particular reason.
I think that the Claude
Swarm represents a
paradigm that is much
more advanced than
the Claude flow. So I
am willing to change
from having training
wheels on my little
bicycle, which I think
flawed flow represents
to a lot of people,
and go straight for
swarm because in a
very personal way in
my community, we are,
which is Tucson, Arizona,
we are totally dependent
on groundwater.
And under the cover
of NDAs, a company
came in and made a
deal with our political
leaders to put in three,
not one, but three
data centers to use
our groundwater for
the next three years.
And it's going to
juice up our electricity
prices enormously.
And fortunately, there's
another step in the
process where a lot
of local people are
going to get involved.
So this roof fan kind
of architecture, which
doesn't rely on large
language models,
doesn't rely on data
centers, has a very small
footprint in terms of
its resource requirements
and its impact on
the environment, I think
represents a paradigm
that is much more
important for this
group than simply, you
know, helping people
understand how to get
the first steps going.
So that's my presentation
to you. Any questions?
John, great work
here, by the way. This
is very impressive. I
love what you're doing.
And you hit the nail
on the head with
the sort of architecture
of the roof fan
and roof swarm approach
that I've taken.
You know, one of the
challenges that you're
going to have in these
anti or mitigation
of hallucinations
is what's true and
what's not and having
a system capable of
learning over time as
users or the system
can sort of interact
with the information.
And that if you ask
an LLM to say what's a
hallucination and the
LLM itself is giving
you the hallucination,
then that's going to
give you a false positive,
right? Right. It's
literally you're
asking the system to
hallucinate to tell
you whether or not it's
hallucinating. So
the secondary source
of information
you have here through
the I think you
said there was like a
repository of sorts of
data and cases would
essentially act as a
kind of unsupervised
learning that allows the
system to sort of
ground itself on real
information. So that's
exactly why we collectively
built the Rufan system
using that kind of
what we call a WASM
that essentially takes
the neural network,
places it in a browser,
and allows you to train
for hyper-specific
types of information
like what you're doing.
It's literally the
optimal use case for it.
Nice work. It's cool.
Really, really,
really like
what you're
doing. Hats off.
Yeah. Well, thank
you very much, and I
wanted to let you know
that in front of all
the people who watched
this presentation,
which were about
277, this was the
acknowledgement that
was at the bottom of the
page. So let's do it,
fellas and ladies.
It beats the time
that lawyer got
disbarred for
using my early bot.
Full circle.
Yeah.
I embarrassed that guy.
He should have just
did a Google search
and checked that the
information was correct.
but that was that was
lazy research on his
part not my bod but
anyway excellent thank
you so much john wonderful
thank you so next
up we've got jed jed
arden is going to uh
show us how to set up
a rig that uh will uh
supercharge we may need
to disconnect john's
shared screen i can't
there we go there we
go thank you so did i
get that right jed uh
spending 15 months for
a combined 24 cpu
cores well this is
rackspace spot and
here is my panel
so i'm currently
anticipating spending
about $4 for a
combined 24 CPUs and
135 gigabytes of RAM,
which power probably two
dozen workspaces that
are currently running
within this cluster.
So way cheaper than
way cheaper than
Codespaces provided
you're willing to
learn Kubernetes.
Now, I have prepared
nothing. I'm going
to wing this as much
as I can because
I forgot to make
in offering to the
demo gods, so
hopefully this will
also be educational
for those of you in
terms of getting
yourselves unstuck.
So assuming
you've created
your Rackspace
spot account,
we'll stand
up a new cloud
space in Hong
Kong just because.
Spot servers,
memory heavy,
no one's bidding, so
I can probably get
away with 16 cores
and 120 gigabytes of
RAM or five cents
an hour. And keep in
mind, this is the bid
price. This is not
necessarily the price
that we're going
to pay. We'll find
that out in a moment.
Most importantly, we
don't need things like
a load balancer. We
don't need ingress
into the cluster or
a way really for any
other public URL to be
exposed because we're
not using public URLs
or public services.
default clusters let's
call this agentists
hong kong
when you say you're not
using public services
how do you get to the
get to the servers
ssh okay sure
pure ssh good
that's what you're doing
so this is my
estimated cost for
an absolute
beast of a server
hopefully i don't get
outbidden that
there's capacity
So while that's
being prepared,
let's go into my
existing cluster.
Is there an API for
this? Do we have to
use this? There is a
Terraform endpoint.
I don't like using
it because I cannot
control it well. So
if you're willing
to foot the bill,
by all means, let
Serafina use the
Terraform endpoint. But
I very purposely
am using the GUI so
that most people can
maintain control.
unavailable capacity
okay so they probably
don't have that beastly
server available let's
try something a little
more accessible chat
i mean i use spot a
lot i never use the
rackspace if somebody
outbits you your server
goes away right server
goes away but the data
is still preserved
because the data is
stored in block storage
that is separate from
the server uh and that's
usually like i know
like i use it a lot
with amazon google uh
that's a fixed cost
like that goes on top of
the the storage right
yes storage i think is
five cents per gigabyte
per month so you can
configure in the devpod
sh window how much
storage you want to
apply to your devpod and
then as long as you're
aware of the cost it
should be fine okay
cool so that's going to
take little bit to
deploy. In the meantime,
this is the
DevPod interface
that I use. So
once the CloudSpace
is deployed in Rackspace,
you create a
new provider,
select Kubernetes, these,
name it appropriately.
So I think
I call it the
Gentists Hong Kong.
And then from the,
from Rackspace, you'll
need to get the, what's
called the Kubernetes
config file. Store
that locally on
your computer, and then
make sure you point
this path to that
kube.config file, the
correct path of the
kube.config file. And
then just, I leave
all of these default.
You can change them
later. It's definitely
not a type one or
irreversible decision.
And then from
there, if I want
to create a
new workspace,
I'll add, what was
it called, agentists
quick start as an
example, and then
choose the workspace
basic branch.
This is just an
opinionated environment
that I use to spawn a
development workspace
that It includes all
of the languages I
generally work in,
the extensions that I
need, and other
important configurations.
That's pre-built.
In this case, it's
not pre-built. So it
will build the container
as it's being...
Well, it will build
the container live
in the cluster. You
can pre-build images.
I tried doing a pre
-built image, but I
ran into so many different
permissions issues
that I still need
to unwind them. So
this is how I make the
experience consistent
for everyone else
who's trying to get
on the first rung
of the ladder that
Reuven, Braun, and Ocean
have been building.
So while that's building,
we'll launch an
existing one.
and this is a running
workspace on top of
a rack space cluster
that within which i
already have cloud
code uh so you're just
using the remote
explorer the right um
correct plug-in to
attach to it in vs code
uh correct and you can
also ssh connection
that's right and
it's authenticating
using the kubeconfig
file that you configured
earlier more
importantly you're not
limited to vs code you
can also open in vs
code browser and it
also has hooks to cursor
zed and jetbrains
among others so i'm
hoping this expands
the breadth of users
who are able to get on
uh remote development
for incredibly cheap
yeah maybe it's s
it's not limited to
rock space right you
anybody who does spot
and you can apply this
to any place that does
kubernetes dev pods
supports any kubernetes
provider so i do have
this running on a
local cluster that runs
in my home lab what's
the most amount of
compute you can kind of
pull down from that or
kind of leverage i mean
it's essentially like
you could have like
a supercharged code
space and could i run a
a thousand you go with
google and amazon
it's the beast so like
people spend billions
basically beast mode
absolute biggest clusters
i are nodes i believe
are either 16 or 32
cores and then your
devpod would be restricted
to that one servers
worth of cores worth
of compute so so on
this unfortunately
creating the cloud space
takes a while so i don't
think i can demonstrate
that part live but
if we were to add
another hypothetical
server see gpu let's see
what we can add here
and then i guess roo
does a high 48 cores
128 gigabytes of ram the
current bid is 70 cents
an hour and i believe
these are h100s so
Reuven i have no idea
how much fly io compares
to you but uh it's
available cost 70
cents an hour you're
welcome to try it for
six hours at a stretch
how does rock space
pricing work because i know
with amazon you're
paying the price who's
the previous bidder
right so if you bet
hundred so this is second
best bidding as far
as if you look at well
if we look at my cost
like i'm spending 28
cents in storage so
yeah that's seven
gigabytes little maybe a
little less um let's see
where can i see available
compute capacity
like this is my
utilization of the cluster
i've got three different
types of servers and
i'm spending let's
see 72 cents a month
so that's one tenth of
a cent per hour are any
of these gpus none of
these are gpu instances
david i haven't yet
gotten around to actually
building something
that could use gpus
yeah yeah i'm i'm
doing some sentiment
analysis on large corpus
of uh financial documents
oh i remember you
sharing that so yeah
and so i'm thinking
about i computed locally
yeah i'd like 71 cents
an hour you can outbid
the current winner
i don't know how you
had a question there
no no could you spin
up um the code spaces
via api on this thing
so once you have your
your server uh yes so
as long as the q the
cube um cube cuddle
file or the cube config
file is set up you can
launch a dev pod from
cli you just need
you just need to have
the dev pod um cli
application installed to
your computer i just
happen to like using
the gui because you know
pretty pictures yeah
um one thing about
gpus they're actually
very hard to get in
this on the spot like if
you want to get
large gpus with large
quantities it's just
not enough capacity and
people constantly it's
constant fight for them
like yeah that's also
true but i don't know
how many servers are
in this pool for at
auction i just know
that at the moment i
can get a server for 70
.01 cents yeah i'm not
because i constantly
run in in a problem
like And another thing,
if you go with very
large clusters, I burned
myself a few times,
but you need to do like
thousands, basically
notes, is that you
can outbid yourself.
Like, so that's what I
did once with Amazon.
Be careful about
that one. And then
I needed to double
the capacity,
so I increased
the price, and it
shut down the half
of the cluster.
Oh, that *****.
Tom, do you
have a question?
Yeah, sorry. I sort
of jumped in there.
I'm not as familiar
with how the bidding
process works, and so
I just was curious. I
heard you say that if
you – and people are
discussing right now
about getting outbid,
but you're bidding on
the hour. So if someone
outbids you for that
hour, it presumably
lets you hang on to
the remainder of your
hour, right? It doesn't
cut you off in the
middle of your hour,
does it? So that's a
question for the
Rackspace spot engineers.
Supposedly, they're
able to track billing
down to the second.
So, in theory, if you
are outbid in that
moment, they will switch
to the higher bid and
start building on a
prorated basis for
the rest of that hour.
But if I've been outbid,
I haven't felt
the impact of it.
Yeah, okay. So, just
to follow up on that.
I mean, obviously,
as long as there's
enough space and you're
doing it at a low,
low time, there's
probably lower chance
it will happen. But
if you lose your bid
and you're in the
middle of executing,
does that literally
terminate whatever
you were, you know,
if you're running
a large swarm and
it's the middle of
doing what it's doing,
it just truncates
what you're doing
and shuts you down?
That's my first question.
And then my second
question is, if you're
running GitHub with
remote storage, like
if, I mean, you get 15
gigs free on Google
Drive. So if you're
using an MCP connected
to your storage there,
could you, in theory,
just sort of hotspot
and just pick up back
up where you left
off? If you were outbid
in the middle of it,
you could just keep
your storage remote
and just fire up your
next instance, use
the same connectivity
with the MCP to your
Google Drive, and
then pick up where you
left off, even if you
got sort of punted in
the middle. So, yes,
there is persistent
storage, which survives
a cluster or a node
being outbid into which
your data survives.
So when the pod restarts
itself, assuming
it gets a node assigned
to the cluster,
the data, this persistent
volume will get
reattached to that pod,
and you can continue
more or less where
you left off. However,
you would need to be
sure that Claude code
is consistently writing
to its memory and,
more importantly, can
recover from partially
written memory. Yeah,
that's the problem,
right, with having
the infrastructure
taken out, ripped out
from underneath. It's
a problem in principle,
David, but I have
yet to encounter that
problem in practice.
Yeah, it's true.
You're right. It's a
theoretical problem
that very infrequently,
in corner case, it
infrequently happens.
By the way, guys,
that's why we included
the resume capability,
and we've got the
Byzantine fault
tolerance components
that we included in the
system. So if you
are running a kind of
distributed swarm of
agents across multiple
machines, and you lose
a couple of machines,
it doesn't affect the
overall operations,
and you can resume
where it left off.
So this is a perfect
use case for that
particular feature
where you wouldn't
really need it on
a single machine.
Yeah.
Actually, I don't know
how Rackspace does
it. Amazon can send
you a signal like that
should be an outbeat
and they shut you down
and they give you like
a few minutes sort of
things that you basically
can't do. So Rackspace
does have a Slack
webhook that they will
pull. So as long as
you can interpret the
Slack webhook that's
being sent to you, you
can react to it faster.
Okay. So there is
a window, because I
know Amazon gives like
five minutes. The problem
with that, though,
is you've got to write
that into your code.
It's kind of weird
how it's calling
itself. So that
gets weird. That
gets funky. I
haven't needed it.
But when the
need arrives,
we'll build the solution.
Yeah, and that's also
why we included the
WebSockets component,
because I think
Slack actually uses
WebSockets as well for
that scenario. So
hypothetically, what
we could do is tie
it directly to that
component and have it
communicate when it's
ready or when it
fails kind of thing.
Yeah.
And also used to be
a trick. I don't know
if any providers
still allow that. So
when Amazon used to
build per hour, not per
second, you can
actually engineer your
bid that you're very
likely to be outbid.
Because when you outbid,
you don't pay for
that hour. So if
you've been running for
40 minutes and you
got shut down, then
you got yourself 40
minutes of recompute.
I mean, at an estimated
$15 a month, I'm
not going to try to
optimize below that.
That's a lot of mental
effort for saving
you like 37 cents.
Guys, we're just
coming up at the
top of the hour. I
just want to put a
place marker as we
roll over for Mondweep
because he's got
some stuff he wants
to show as well.
So I recognize I
couldn't show most of
this in real time,
but hopefully you're
able to at least
connect the dots and
start spinning up
your own spot swarms.
That was pretty
cool, Jay. I just got
out of it, so which
one of you did it?
Would you say that
Rackspace Spot is one
of the cheapest services
for the, I guess,
amount of resources
that you can get?
Yeah, it's basically,
I'm basically
paying less
than it costs in
electricity to
run the servers.
Right. That's
great. So it's not
sustainable, not even
in the best case.
But the unit
economics, at least for
now, are worthwhile,
so I will
exploit it as long
as I can. Sort of
like what we've
done with CloudMax.
You think that
they're going
to shut it down, though?
No, they're not going
to shut it down. The
most recent innovation,
if you could call
it that, was to
change the UI so that
the floor is now much
higher. I assume their
actual unit break
-even costs. I happen
to have a grandfathered
cluster, so my
actual bid is 0.3
cents. But for that same
node, you can no
longer bid 0.3 cents. I
think the floor is 1
.5. Still cheap, but
not as cheap as I'm
currently exploiting.
Pretty much cost recovery
for them, though,
right? I mean, the
servers are sitting
there idle, so it's
costing them to run it.
I don't know the
specifics, Tom, but I
imagine someone has
already run this through
a spreadsheet and
decided it was a good
idea. I'm sure they
thought about it, yeah.
But all cloud providers
have this spot market.
Yes.
So you can go with
Amazon. So usually you
just shop around.
So if you run like a
thousand nodes, then
it actually matters.
I would love to see
any one of us running
more than a hundred
nodes. I run thousands,
particularly for
bioinformatics workloads.
I mean, they're not
for the swarm, but,
I mean, I've been
doing that for...
A thousand nodes
for what? What
are you computing
for a thousand
nodes, on a
thousand nodes?
Mostly like
bioinformatics,
genomics, like workloads.
Oh, okay. Yes, that
makes sense. Got it.
Yeah, because there
are actually things
like NextFlow that
will, you write
your pipelines and
they will go procure
machines. It
all happens like
automatically, so I
guess... Right, right.
I mean, if you're
doing, you know,
computational fluid
dynamics, modeling,
then sure, yeah,
you need a thousand.
All right, guys, I'm
excited to see what
Manjweep has to show here.
That was fascinating.
And Greg suggested
we take a look at
Coder.com, which is a
sort of alternative.
Oh, yeah.
I've got one Coder.
It's very similar
to DevPad, but it's
web, and it has
some features that's
good. Yeah, so Coder
is also very good.
All right.
Hello, everyone.
Hi. I'll be quick.
Well,
I started off here.
Remember, Sandy, a
few of us were talking
about, like, how do
we explain this
technology to others? And
you were saying
there was, I mean, I
think, Rude, this was
when your laptop had
some problems with
the new camera, right?
So you were on and
off. So we were
chatting, like, how
do we explain this?
How do we make it
easy to explain this
to other people who
are not probably
close enough to this
group as we are?
so and also like i um
a group from uh i think
you met uh ravi and
others yesterday like
they they wanted us to
know about rule code
and spark so they
invited me and then mens
and i went to speak to
them on tuesday i think
so it's like can we
create something and i
was thinking about it
and for me like what
uh what we thought about
so let me just move
the screen from here
so i can see things is
like can we create
kind of a interactive
platform starts with the
basics of spar and kind
of can we create some
kind of a learning and
certification process
right in terms of
like a maturity process
um which is kind of
leverages mcp and all
of the other stuff this
is still work in progress
and there are two
versions which are nice
let's go on i think
now so i said like Ruf,
you've gone through a
journey, right? You
started the journey with
Spark and your GitHub
code basis. I said,
should we not actually
look at your GitHub
code basis like Spark,
Spark 2, Create Spark,
basically the NPM and
Claude-flow stuff?
Why don't I throw
that into a swarm and
read that and kind of
create me? And there
was a prompt I used.
I think there was a
PRD here, which I will
show you. So all I
said in the PRD was
that it's somewhere
here. I must read it
up there. It's there.
So I said, okay, that's
what you do, analyze
your methodology
and kind of create,
and also because I
made the presentation,
which I never really
made this presentation,
I said, can you create
some presentation
material for building
Spark apps with
Spark, a hands-on
introduction, and these
are the repositories
for you to analyze, and
it did create all
of this. so i threw
this into a swarm i'm
not sure if i use hive
mind or just swarm
i can't remember now
but after doing so
it came up with a few
things uh before i show
you the actual thing
uh the bits that it
actually came up were
these things so a
technical architecture
your prd did you
handcraft that prd or
did you have some
an ai created i
basically vibe so i i
type something and then
i said okay prd
based on this like a
paragraph of typing
whatever I was
thinking, and just
create it. I mean, I was
literally playing
as well, literally.
So he created, for
example, this one. I'll
open these first and
I'll show you the
output and then we'll
go to the platform.
This and the MCP
server setup because
I think, Reuven,
you said create an
MCP for everything
you create, right?
So I said, why don't
we create an MCP?
So it created
like what happened
in 2023, what
happened in 24, kind
of gave us a
view. So this is
content creation
effectively, right?
Then bits of about, I
mean, it's quite small
here, but if I zoom
it, it kind of has
details around it. So
without going too much
into the details, but
you can see it created
a host of content.
And again, this is a
public one. So please
have a look yourself.
This is open to
the community.
Then it kind of
said, like, what
introduced what
design patterns?
Like, so what did
CreateSpark introduced?
And again, you could
say whether this
is right or wrong,
but it seems like
scaffolding engine
was CreateSpark. Spark
one had the AI
assistant integration.
So it's fairly
reading your code
base and so on
and so forth.
Then here was the
system integration.
So it talked about
various other
integration work
that we had done. It
had basic integration
architectures,
and lots of other stuff.
This one was about
a live guide.
I think it
might be, okay,
there was a background.
Anyways, so
that's the output.
Now, what does this
look like? So somehow
we decided to create
two versions of a
UI, which looks like,
I'm just looking for
the UI now. It's one
of these windows.
Yeah.
Two versions of an UI.
Yeah. So there is this,
so this one effectively
is like, you've got
a playground so like
the way this works
uh and ben and i were
having a chat about
this earlier on is what
it has done is um there
is some content here
about let's say how to
write specifications
how to write pseudocode
and think about it
like um a journey where
people learn like how
to write proper
specifications so back to
your question i think
uh dave about did you
write this prd yourself
so it's like not
assuming any knowledge
right from basics so there
is this one then
learning like you know
you could you could
start a module and yeah
all right so um so just
to i'll be quick now
won't take too long
here i will just move
across today so let's
say learning right um
say you have a learning
so this is you go
through so this is one
version the other version
was you take a module
you go through a quiz
and it could be anything
right so here for
example if i answer
incorrectly it knows
that i'm actually going
to start answering is
incorrectly if i say
correct and i do so
this is kind of what
comes after pseudo code
okay this is very basics
right but you complete
that and that module
should open up there's
some gui errors why
this doesn't get
updated at the moment
whereas it does on this
this version it does
uh but in interest of
time there is this
certification bit where you
could we could go through
like a foundational
level and we could
decide what foundational
level training is for
a practitioner badge
like from the foundation
right for being
a spark developer what
is necessary and this
is currently just a set
of quizzes here like
this right you could
go through that could
be much more
complicated could begin
programming language
programming exercises as well
and i think ben said
an idea i forget now
feel free to kind of chip
in you were suggesting
something earlier
today um yeah so this
is broadly what it is
it was the integration
of um open air cloud
api to get answers
before you actually do
it uh this is this is
tremendous guys because
really it's the missing
piece so um you know
we had a sponsor
step up and and cover
the ticket for the
community disco site um
tribal uh cafe and uh and
that is uh and the disco
site is specifically
uh a course creation
platform and we just
you know there hasn't
been the collective
bench strength to start
to bring together all
the materials so uh
it's wonderful to see
and it's been there's
a lot of talk about
conversation about
accreditation so right
on the right on the
money this is pretty
awesome man good job
man thank you now
here's the here's
where the funds did
because i need your
help now to make this
production ready right
so obviously there
are bugs in it that's
the source for i
guess looking at the
community to kind of
really make it work
and meaningful for
people so it's out
there contributions now
please have to you know
as a subject expert
to verify the content
and the flow and we
are planning to you
know add some animations
to make it less abstract
you know how the
agents are working
together sequential
parallel agents and so
on it looks looks awesome
i think that this is
extremely useful and
would will play a part
like everybody wants
to get an agentic
engineering accreditation
i think that that's
been a recurring
conversation that a lot
of us have been having
It's like, you know,
when you look at the
things that we're
building and the tools
that we're making,
they're not intent. They
can be used for Vibe
coding, obviously. But
the intention is to
create these systems,
methods, architectures
and approaches that
are essentially user
guided and defined by
us as, you know, so
-called agentic experts.
And I think what
you're describing is a
really good step
towards that sort of
opportunity. and
really appreciate you
putting in the time
to make that happen.
That code space will
not come up because
I think, I don't
know, because I
think it's mainly by
personal code space.
Probably will not
have, maybe you
can fork the code
and maybe just
host it in your
own code spaces.
I think Scott, you
were asking a question.
Yeah.
I forked as well when
I helped Mondweep.
So it's working
quite smoothly.
Oh, lovely.
And Mandweep and Ben
says, I was wondering
if I could talk to
you guys after about
if there's a
possibility of putting
this or into the Disco
member site. Disco,
yeah.
Because we have the
capability and we
can do badges and like
your content is the
missing piece, we
just don't have the
content for it. So
this is absolutely
incredible. I think
it would be really,
really useful for a
lot of members as both
a standalone
application and whatever
we can put into the
member sites. but
incredible job guys
thank you awesome thanks
yeah look looking
really really good
all right um we've
got a few minutes
left but what if you
guys have any questions
anything you want
to present a bit
of an open mic
opportunity uh this this
this is your this is
your chance greg i
have a quick question
as to um i was
poking around on the
agentics website the
other day and i see
there's a really
interesting sort of
agents area mocked up
I was curious if
anyone who's been
involved in anything
to do with that
might want to speak
to that a little.
We've got a new
version of the
site coming. So
that was, you know,
site's a little
aspirational.
You know, the early
concepts was essentially
a kind of agentic
inbox, you know, where
you'd have, we have
the ability to sort
of interact with agents
in a kind of Slack
-like way. um actually
brad and the crew
have been working on
a new version of the
site which i think
we're going to launch
pretty soon and which
will link from the the
main site here when
we when they tell me
to make the update um
awesome okay if you
want i can provide a
quick very quick two
minute or 30 second
update um yeah we're
we've got a great team
we're we're updating
the um the member side
portal so we're adding
all kinds of different
features all the
different committees
all the different
chapters on there, making
sure there's a link
for being able to
become an ambassador.
And one of the key
missing pieces is that we
want to add is all
this learning type
platforms like Mondeep
and Benz is doing. So we
have all kinds of
different courses. And then
we're also talking
about the accreditation
processes as well. So
what Mondeep and Benz
provided is exactly
what we want to have
available for all kinds
of different members.
Yeah. We'll be
updating the main site
here probably pretty
soon, right, Brad?
Yeah, I think
Matt's on the call.
The last missing
piece was really
just the onboarding
and making sure
that we have the
onboarding done.
And then from
there on, we'll
launch fast and
make sure that
everyone just starts
adding content.
So I'm going to speak
on behalf of the team
and say within the
next week, possibly a
couple of days later,
just to double check.