going to resume.
All right. August
1st, we're eight
months in and August
is my birthday
month. At some
point in this
month, there will
be a birthday mine.
So, you know, that's
exciting. July was pretty
exciting. Lots of
activity. We went from,
you know, unlimited
use to a lot less use
for Cloud Code, but
they're moving quickly.
Lots of bugs I've noticed
in the last couple
releases of cloud code
as well i don't know
if anyone's seeing all
those yellow screens
of errors that that
randomly pop up now
but they're they're
it makes you know what
all the errors i see
in cloud code make me
feel better about the
errors and bugs that i
put in in my various
tools if if a 170 billion
dollar company apparently
is up with what
they're worth can are
putting out bugs and
makes me feel better
about me and my uh
random office here in in
toronto doing the same
thing um but yeah
it's been it's been a
bit of a bit of a wild
ride they they came out
that that letter or
that email earlier in
the week and basically
without saying so
called us out for using
parallel concurrent
systems saying one user
in particular used uh
you know hundreds of
thousands of dollars in
credits i don't know
who that user is but
it's probably someone
in our crew i would
guess you know there
we you know 20 million
lines of code just by
me in the last six weeks
i think that there's
something crazy close
to 20 million um is
any indication now
remember i was bragging
earlier about the uh
being able to 500 000
lines of code an hour
cannot get anywhere
near that we're about 50
to 75 000 if for a
benchmark that that's
where the quota currently
lies but um here we
are we i'm not going
to spend too much time
today doing the demos
because we have a ton
of people and i'm not
even supposed to be
here so um rob who do
we get lined up uh for
our present you know
presenters today yeah
we've got it we got a
full slate um so alex
dubold one of the og
members he's been working
on uh he's in the
optometry optometry
and glasses and lens
manufacturing servicing
that industry so he's
got a pretty neat setup
he's going to show
us uh and then ocean
on some optimizations
some swarm optimize
orchestration optimizations
john petty uh from
enabled and those guys
are crushing it on
use cases which is
really fascinating uh and
then i think dimple
we've also got um uh
ravi is that right do
we have is dimple there
no i don't think
so but no all right
we've got ravi uh
shemioki from new zealand
and uh uh and actually
in new zealand
so on new zealand
hours so looking
forward to seeing
him bright and early
which which i think
is 4 a.m and and i i
think we have like a
single-handed new zealand
uh recruiter in dave
who's been recruiting
all his uh what what's
the nickname for
someone from new zealand
again it's there's
got a there's got a
kiwi right kiwi kiwis
yeah and all if has
anyone noticed the kiwis
have all turned yellow
recently like i i
remember when i was
a kid they were all
green. Now, whenever I
eat a kiwi, it's, it's
yellow, but that golden
maybe, but anyway.
Um, so that, that,
that's exciting.
I want to just, I'm
not gonna spend a lot
of time today, but
I want to show you
guys a few, a little,
a few tips and
tricks, um, that, that
I've been playing with
in this, these are
just little things
that'll probably help
you guys get, get
going quickly. Um,
again, Cloud Code,
cause I, that's my
current, uh, obsession.
Um, so let, let me
show you a few things.
So I don't know if
any of you guys have
noticed. Let me get a
second to get this going.
I know it takes a
second to share my
screen. But when you're
in cloud code, often
you have to type out
a long-winded sort of
description. What I've
been using are aliases.
So I just want to
show you guys quickly
how that works. And
for those that tuned
in yesterday, it's a
repeat, but whatever.
So when I type in DSP,
what's happening,
so dangerously skip
permissions, it jumps
and does the entire
command. And I can
also do things, I don't
know if I actually
did this here, but I
can also do things
like dangerously skip
permissions dash C. And
these are bash aliases
that allow me, and
with the dash C, it
allows me to continue
where I left off.
So to do that, so
you can see that I'm
working on my FAC
implementation here.
And you can see
that it jumps to
where it left
off. And I might
actually be working
on a better resume
capability as well
for the hives.
But that'll have to,
I'll do that when I
get back from my
vacation. But if you are,
if you want to use
this, and this can be
arbitrary, by the way,
this DSP, all you need
to do, so I'm going
to use DSP to start
it, but I'll show you
how to actually do it.
So, in clod, what you
need to do is say,
create an alias
in bash rc
for the following
command.
And for that,
what we'll do is
I'm just going to
grab this quickly,
and I'm going
to just say clod
And you can use
this again for any
command, but in this
case, you're going
to go and you're
going to say something
like dangerously
skip permissions.
So in this case, and
you could use it for
all kinds of things.
Like if you want to
stream the output, you
can do that as well.
But in this case,
I'll show you this.
So the command
DSP, well actually,
let's do a
different command.
Let's call it
hackerspace.
and whenever i
type hackerspace
i want to do
this but i gotta
go here and
i'm going to do
claude and i'm going
to do i'm going to
add a command that
this says hackerspace
and so this is it this
is all this is all i
could do in this case
i i wouldn't suggest
using the command
you don't need this
part here the part
where i'm putting
hackerspace all you need
to do is actually just
include the command
i'm just doing it say
i've already done
it so i'm just going
to create new command
since that'll work.
What this will do
is basically add
those quick commands.
You can continue
where you left
off. You can have
things you commonly
do frequently.
Look, I maxed out my Opus
4 limit. There you go.
It's going to edit
the RC. You see here
that's adding the alias
here, the hackerspace.
A couple of things
to note, when you do
create a new alias for
your bash, and this
is obviously going
to work on Unix style
systems, so Mac,
Linux, Windows, Linux
subsystem. You can do
similar things on Windows,
but it doesn't use
the Bash RC. It uses
a different PowerShell,
I think, approach.
Now, when I go
in here, fingers
crossed, and I type
in hackerspace,
hackerspace, it's
going to do two things.
In this case, it's
going to run the
command that's also
going to include the
hackerspace command
that I put in there.
And you see here, in
this case, it starts
automatically. Now, one
more thing I want to
show you that's kind
of cool. I'm going to
stop this because I
don't know what that's
actually going to do.
It's going to hack my
bot or something.
Now, you can go a step
further here and you
can see here that you've
got different commands
for streaming. So,
you've got output
formats. So, let's just
do a quick alias for
that as well. So, in
this case, what I can
do is I can do a clod.
In this case, I'm
going to do a command
that says run the fact
agent because I'm in
my fact area. Now, I'm
going to do dash p.
If you want
to invoke clod
programmatically
from, let's say,
an API or an action
or a serverless
function, this
is how you do it.
In this case, I'm
going to use the output
format and i'm gonna
use verbose so i'm
gonna i'm gonna start
with verbose and i
don't think the order
matters too much but
this is the way i do
it so now i'm gonna go
here and i'm also
gonna do the output
format and there's
different output formats
but the one that's
most visually appealing
and probably useful
if you're streaming
like if you want to
let's say you want to
create an agent in a
website that that goes
and researches and
does whatever you're
going to want to use
the output format of
the stream JSON, which
is this one here.
But you can also
do a blob like just
JSON or text. But I
like the stream JSON
because it's sort
of real time. So,
in this case, I'm
creating the structure.
So, I'm going to
go here and do
another one. So, I'm
going to grab this,
Claude. Then I'm going
to jump back here.
And then I'm going
going to create another
alias called, we'll
call it agent, just why
not, all right, and I'm
going to, right here,
and we're going to get
to that, now, so it's
just a lot easier than
having to type all
that stuff, now, rather
than typing it all,
all I need to do is
call agent, and it'll
basically do that.
It'll run the fact agent
in this case as a
streaming-based output.
And so I'm going to let
that do its thing here.
All right. And it
looks like that
worked. So I'm going
to go one more,
and I'm going to
just call that,
just type agent.
All right.
Agent. Now, this is
streaming. So this is
bypassing the user,
the sort of interactive
user components. So
it's kind of cool. So
I'm just typing that.
Give it a sec to
initialize. And it can
also interact with all my
agents. So, I have a
fact agent in there,
in here somewhere called
FAC CLI. Now, it's
not pretty, but you
can format all this
using, you know, your
favorite sort of Node
.js, Python, whatever,
you know, and this is
just JSON output,
right? So, if you want
to use Ocean's line
AGI and you want to
integrate the output,
this is exactly how you
do it which i'm i
might be still in the
ocean's thunder here
because i think he's about
to give a similar
presentation on how he's
doing the sorts of
things but the so this
allows you to integrate
any of these agents
into any sort of
application using
programmatic means so
you can see as as it's
making the request it's
essentially outputting
it in in a raw format
so when i show you
my dashboards and
things this is how i'm
actually doing it it's
kind of cool um last
i'm stop this because
I'm actually not sure
what it's actually
doing. But the last thing
that's really interesting
is the new agent
system that actually
came out last week.
When you're building
these agents, one of
the things to keep in
mind is you can invoke
agents by basically
saying, as I did a moment
ago, I said basically
run the fact agent.
But you can also create
secondary commands.
So, what I've been
doing is creating a sort
of two approach or a
bilateral approach.
I don't know a command.
The command will be
like an automation
command, which you see
here, and then this
command will then correlate
to an agent that's
in the agent folder.
You can just create an
agent by itself, but
creating a command gives
you the slash option.
You can invoke the
agent. Let's say if I
want to go back into
here, and I want to invoke
my ... I can do ...
You can see all my
different ... I think I
have a fact agent here.
You can see I have
different fact agents
that created so this
particular repo is is
using my fast augmented
uh contact system so
i'm using it to do
benchmarking and other
tools so rather than
have to remember all the
commands and all the
things i just create
these commands and agents
that do the the work
that i need so if i
want to benchmark all
i need to do is that
and it'll go and do my
benchmarking for me or
if i want to you know
make a neural network
or i want to send an
email or research or
whatever I've got a I've
got one client that's
actually using this
to basically create
sort of personas for all
their employees and
then when they hire
someone new they they
can invoke these sorts
of things and they're
using like a dashboard
like a web-based
dashboard to do that so in
this case it's asking
me some questions so
when you create an
agent you can have it
interactive like so it
guides you through you
know questions and answers
so um just you know
I'm just showing hey
hey Riven, are you in
standard Claude or
Claude Flow doing this?
Well, Claude Flow has
been initialized. So
all my Claude capabilities
are now instantiated
through a combination
of agents and
commands and the actual
Claude.md file. So
you don't really have
to use Claude Flow
after you've installed
it. You can just use
Claude normally, and
it just magically knows
all the commands because
I've given it all
the commands. So you
don't have to worry
about that. I I've
actually made Claude flow,
not for humans so
much, but for agents.
So essentially it
just magically works.
So in here, I'm
just saying,
just, just show
what's possible.
Are you saying that
some of, some of
these agents you,
you are configuring,
you, you built all
these commands, the
slash commands and
slash agents. And
some of them will
actually know how to
launch and leverage
Claude flow. Yeah.
Standard Claude.
Yeah.
Cool.
Just trying to
help clarify for
the rest of the
audience. Yeah,
that's good.
Good question.
So now the issue with
the one I'm doing
right now is it's
looking for clarification
because I told
it that it should
always ask, you know,
the user how and
what they need.
And so depending on
what you're doing,
it'll it'll it'll guide
it'll guide you
through the process.
Now, in this case, it
looks like it's running
the command. You can
see my little fact
little icon that shows
up here, and it's
doing whatever it's doing.
But the moral of the
story is a lot of the
flows that I'm doing
for development, I'm
customizing all of
this stuff. So when
you instantiate the
Claude-flow system, it's
meant to be a sort of
running start, but it's
not meant to be static.
the first thing you
should do is basically
get Claude to customize
both the agents,
remove anything you
don't need. There's a
lot of stuff here. Or
add things that are
specific to what you're
trying to achieve.
Different types of
flows, data optimization,
development processes,
requirements. And
then you put those all
in the either agents
or commands and have
those two folders
essentially relate to one
another one in ones
that one invokes the
other kind of does
so slash do something
will then invoke a
series of other agents
that does the thing
you want it to do
research whatever
scrape if i if i clarify
then you're saying that
the initial startup
processes that you
instantiate called flow
and it will build out
all the structure the
the directory structure
and in your code repo
of all the agency
commands then once that's
done you go and actually
use standard Claude
and then and it will
then know how to leverage
all the Claude Claude
instantiation the
flow instantiation. Yes
exactly so and and a
lot it's a cascading
series of components
but the most important
of which is this Claude
MD file and I can
again you you should
customize this this this
is meant to be sort of
a rough guide to how
the system works but it
should be you know I
generally customize
this to the particulars
of the environment that
I'm working in. So in
this particular one
is telling you exactly
how the tasks and
agents are meant to
operate. And here's like the
MPX commands, but you
can take it a step
further and just basically
say, cloud, customize
the cloud.md file for
the, in this case,
my FAC environment.
And it'll change it up.
And it makes it
look even better.
Also redefine the
agents and the commands
in the folders. Will
it do automatically?
Yes, it will.
And so, but keep in
mind, you have to
restart a cloud every
time you do that.
So right now it's,
it's trying to figure
itself out. I didn't
give it particularly good
guidance, but once, once
it's sort of figured
itself out, what I
might do is, is, you
know, tell it to update.
See now that it's
figured out how my, my
system's working, right.
It's looking at the,
help file which i can
invoke also by just
typing in help i oops
i love i love clis
as you know and and i
either move between
clis or mcps but in this
case i'm using a cli
and you can see here are
all the different
commands i have and and
the different tools so
it's learning how the
system works and then
and then once it's
learned how it works
and this is a this is a
work in progress but
see if this even works.
And I'm running
in the wrong
folder, but you
get the idea.
But so I'm basically
creating secondary. And
that's when you look
at things like my
GitHub integration, I'm
using secondary systems.
So for example, in
the helper folder,
you'll see here, I've
got the GitHub, you know,
checkpoint system. So
this is allowing the
system to basically do
automated checkpoints
and rollbacks. So if
I mess something up,
every step, every
element, everything that's
done within Cloud
Code is automatically
put into a GitHub
commit. So I can easily
roll back to where
something broke. And I just
point Cloud at and say,
well, if this worked
two hours ago, go figure
out why it doesn't
work. And it works
amazingly well at
figuring itself out.
So you can essentially
point it at these helper
files if you want. And
these these helper
files directly relate
to the settings. So
these settings are
essentially the hooks,
right? So I can define pre
-compact that it might
do a commit or it
might remind it what it
needs to do or here's
when it stops, it might
do something else.
So you can see here
that I'm running the
bash command from the
helper file. Every
time that the user
submits a prompt, I'm
essentially going and
doing a checkpoint.
And you can customize
all this stuff. This
is really meant
for you to sort of
understand how to use
this and change it up and
customize it to your
needs. But the benefit
to that is now if
I go into my Git
graph, you can see
that every single thing
that I've done over
the last couple days
since I've implemented
it is now checkpointed.
So I can manually
jump back to, you
know, when I cleaned
up the root MD files in
Wiki with MCP details
if I want to. but
it also shows me exactly
what happened. So
it's if you've used
the checkpoint option
incline or Roo, I
basically create a
recreate that, but for,
but for a cloud code.
All right, I'm done.
Now it's everyone
else's turn
to show what
they're doing.
It's useful. Not the
most technical thing
in the world, but
hugely useful. Like I
don't know about you
guys, but half the time
I go and have dinner,
come back and it's
broken everything that
I've just spent two
hours working on, it
solves that problem.
All right. Who's up
first today, Rob?
Let's dive in with
Alex. Alex has
got quite a nice
speed setup. I'm
looking forward to
seeing it. Alex,
how are you?
I'm going to change
my glasses for Alex
here. These are my
Alton John glasses.
Hi, guys.
I think a while
ago, I just defined
the version of
it that works.
Everything that you
showed is very helpful.
Reuven, I'm obviously
not as advanced
as you are. So the
gist of it is I'm, Veri
stands for vision or
vertical AR and AI
or like authentic retail.
So if you think of
like pulling on a
thread, I'm going
to share my screen.
I was building a
platform to first like
connect to basically
help people buy
stuff online better,
right? So I actually,
in the process of
actually finishing
the commerce studio
hopefully this loads
where um i can connect
through shopify and
all these different
platforms um i wear for
online sales but as
i was pulling on this
thread i realized oh
my goodness it's so
freaking hard that
these opticians can't
even get their data
to the website so i'm
dealing with multiple
retailers in europe and
they're like oh my
data is **** like oh
that's not helpful uh
you don't have pictures
you don't have
descriptions you don't
have dimensions like
you're missing a whole
bunch of information
i'm going okay like it
can't be that bad.
And apparently it is.
So I started using,
I've been using Roov's
platforms like from
the get go. And I just
actually pointed it to
the web and said, Hey,
go find me all the
practice management
platforms that actually
have an API endpoint.
Here's 55 different
platforms that have API
endpoints like, Oh,
this is a good start.
Well, you know, my
just took my son to
the optometrist. They
didn't actually tell
me anything useful in
terms of like, Hey,
like, when's the next
deployment? When are
you coming in? So this
is all coded by me.
I basically looked at the
opticians and basically
said, okay, I never
get a notice. They're
all about like,
you know, practice
management, like how do
you do a better job
with your business?
So I basically be
building a dashboard to
basically replace
or sit on top of the
existing systems to say,
hey, like my optician
has three people
sitting in the front and
they send me an email
two days before. But
really your practice
is about optimization
it's like look how
many people are coming
in how many did you
get most doctors or
dentists are not business
people so where can
ai play a role in
helping them manage
their business right
and i came up with this
idea of well look if
the data is there and
i'm already doing all
this stuff online it
probably exists offline
so like i can if
i can extract the
information then i can
understand what the
patient overview is and
i can start telling
them look here's the
revenue that you're
making based on different
groups and people and
if you have enough
training data right
you can start coaching
them to say oh look
you've got windows like
you actually don't
have people showing up
they're never going to
build this right it's
like going into quickbooks
as a small business
owner like it's a
giant pain in the butt
so ai has a huge opportunity
to kind of do the
work for them and spit
it out right so the
so this took me a couple
of months like i'm
probably past 200
commits now on just this
one piece but the idea
is that like there
are also people who
have multiple locations
so like i can start
doing also analysis by
location to help them
understand what's going
on um a key aspect of
all of this is like i
just kept on going
because it was so easy
with rue right before
the other piece came out
so i said look like
you need to build a
marketing campaign like
if you have the data
and you know there's a
hole in your business
then it's like so what
well let's build the
so what so how can we
take this and create
actionable insights
around your specific brand
because like building
an email came to an
email campaign isn't
hard connecting to an
api endpoint to
mailchimp or mailgun or
whatever it's not that
hard right to be able to
do the whole process
and i also put in a link
to sms for like
appointment notifications
but you know you just
you could just keep
on going and going
and going and going um
and i also built a
loyalty program into
the back so that you
could actually have
a rewards catalog and
change the catalog.
So all this is fun,
right? These are
components built
on the front end.
But the other thing
that would have
taken forever to
do is compliance.
So I actually went
in and with my
PM head on and
actually went
through and wrote
a whole separate
stories and Claude
around security,
right mfa um end-to
-end tests um everything
um was built into the
whole back end right
because you know i
did one pilot project
for rekhip and kaiser
global where they
sent me an excel
spreadsheet with 200 lines
of questions i'm like
never again if you
have questions like
here like go generate
a security port go
through the training the
other thing is because
it's eyewear it
has to be hipaa compliant
so i went and looked
at the standards
like what is hipaa
compliance right so
obviously i have to
reconnect this um but
this is working in the
past so you could like
schedule an audit look
at the policy i
actually have a staff
training component so how
each of the individual
people in the stores
work because like
one of the companies
that i'm talking to
is in europe and
they're buying opticians
they're private equity
backed um so this is
like a really simple
demo for people to under
kind of understand
what's going on but
the thing that i love
the most and what i
love what ru just
showed is iris so i was
thinking about tony
stark and jarvis and i
thought hey like wouldn't
it be nice if you
woke up in the morning
and you're a small
business owner and your
phone told you what
your day was going to
be like like really like
how much harder is it
because you have all
the data like 90 of
the battle is getting
the data organizing
the data extracting you
know kpis from that
data but why don't we
make it easier for
somebody to have a
conversation so uh this
is using um actually i
put it all over here
just pulled it up as
rube was doing it because
he normally asks me
how i build stuff and
half of it i forget
so i'm using um in the
back end iris is using
basically a bunch of
ml processes on the
back for patient
segmentation no sure rate
appointment optimization
so these back end
services are running
all of the time right um
and i think i'm using
dialogue flow from google
um to kind of handle
some of the stuff.
Theoretically, you
could probably run it
through an MCP. I'm just
not that talented yet.
But then you can ask
a question, like,
help me with my
appointments, right?
And the flip side is,
if I have finished
this properly,
this connects to
my commerce studio.
And theoretically,
any of us will be talking
to Iris's consumer
facing side to say,
hey, I need to move my
appointment great let
me find the appointment
for you so that's
iris that's um i call
this the the re the
cover sorry i call this
the practice studio um
for the opticians to
basically come in like
a co-pilot and help
them run their business
of connecting all the
data um making sure
that all the data is
seamlessly going
automating all of the stuff
that's usually done
manually because the
customer experience is
usually pretty bad um
but then actually just
giving them the workflows
so that like the
agent can do it for
them that's the demo
this is this is great
you're you alex represent
what i like to call
like kind of agentic
entrepreneur you you
have been given the
power to build the things
that you envision and
without having to go
and hire an outsource
team well maybe you do
i don't know but you
know but what i love
about what i what i
see you and i've known
i've known you for
what 20 years i've seen
your sort of evolution
right and especially
your evolution over the
last year and a half
as you've sort of embraced
uh this technology
i think you started
and you're like i'm
not technical and all
of a sudden you're like
i can i can literally
build anything i imagine
and you're doing
it and you're doing
amazing at it it's very
rewarding to see to see
how you have evolved
over the last you know
year or so yeah so i
didn't show you guys
the last the last
part that's missing is
because like ultimately
at the end of the day
the last thing that i
want to do because you
have to gain people
people's trust over time
is i do actually want
to connect um to ml
models around helping
with diagnosis so this
exists in the background
it's this is not
for public consumption
yet but the intent
is that if there are
models out there that
have been tested and
we have enough retail
locations using the
platform then we can help
on front end but we
can also help with the
diagnosis with those
models in the future so
this is all new i've
got a couple other
projects um if people are
interested in learning
more or want to help
me build some of these
models happy to happy
chat hey alex yeah
one thing about
this 200 uh question
questionnaires they all
come from uh existing
regulations like so if
you look for nist or sock
or iso like you can
actually extract the
questions and make yourself
like how to compliant
and there is software
like doing that
that costs like tens
of thousands of dollars
yeah the the interesting
thing here though
is that like one of
the brands that we're
working with in europe
one of the retailers
like they have like very
basic problems i have
a separate application
called skew genie
on my other screen that's
scraping the internet
and cleaning data
because they have bad
digital like this is
just the optometry side
of things the retail
like the glasses that
you're wearing they
they can't even maintain
their database of
like eyewear that they
collect so it depends
on who you're talking
to some of the chains
are like really advanced
like they're not
racket in terms of like
um 200 lines of questions
but you have this
huge disparity the
only consistent thing
is that the people in
the store are using
outdated software and
it doesn't know what
they're doing so you
have you better make it
like **** simple for
them to be able to get
onboarded with the
wizard and then and then
do everything for them
between hey this is a
sorry yeah this this
is a great opportunity
to um take on some of
your like um digital
project management
like drm and and stuff
like that or project
man project um god
it's noon and i haven't
meeting yet so i
can't think of the term
but those different
things like uh salsify
and and things like
that that that keep all
of that that digital
information but
they're much bigger and
have to be managed by
a much larger staff
like this is thinking
dam and pams that's
that's what i'm looking
for um yeah so so it
it does that for a
smaller business it's
that's a it's an
awesome It's an awesome
concept that makes it
a lot more automated.
Thanks.
Nice.
All right. Do
we have Ocean?
Mr. Hayang Lee?
Yeah. Can I
actually go last?
Well, if there is still
time or space for me.
Sure. Let me
just check on.
I'm not seeing Ravi yet.
It is 4 a.m. in fairness.
It is 4 a.m.
the ambition might have
gotten the better of him
and
John isn't on I know he's
juggling with a corporate
board meeting so
someone else have
something they want to
present and then we'll
get back to Ocean
wait jump head
is actually here
oh is he John I
am there you are
I'm pretty good good
um yeah so i will give
uh i'll go quick so so
we were talking about
like uh development
outcomes and stuff
and we'll find you
guys might find this
interesting so i actually
am running um my version
i've been working on
a version of legion
that i've been building
different iterations
on and um with the
latest like pushes that
Reuven has made and
some of the changes
there really like my
approach has been more
cognitive more thought
oriented and creating
different thought
structures reasoning
structures and then
last night for ***** and
giggles I kind of
just pushed it to like
continual persistence
where it's not allowed
to really exit until it
finishes its task but
there's so many layers
of validation quality
control and all sorts
of different stuff
that kind of go into
play here. So you'll
see that I actually
have Claude and Claude
Flow here, but down
here we actually have
the final build for
Legion. And what's
interesting about this is
I can actually initiate
Claude Code and Claude
Code will initiate
Legion inside of the
terminal after it's
already started cloud
code and you can watch
um legion spin up he's
actually working on
some stuff right now
this is actually uh
cloud flow but can you
make it a little bigger
uh how do i do that
actually you can control
control yeah control
plus all right yeah
here it goes oh you
guys just made my day
i do a lot of
presentations i do a lot of
presentations and
everyone's always i can't
see your screen yeah
i have a giant screen
so i've always had an
issue with this so um
the main thing is when
we go into like uh
legion there's sort
of a three-layer
system so if you
think about ephemeral
processes um the three
-layer system has like
a core and it can't
be touched that core
has the protocol and
the main mechanism
to do self-healing it
understands what the
layers should look
like. Those layers are
indexed and essentially
biblical in the
sense of how the code
can self-recover.
Layer two becomes
somewhat ephemeral
in the sense of it
can make changes, it
can edit certain
components, it can
add additions and add
agents and prompts.
And layer three
is the most, where
most of the action
actually happens.
Each one of those
layers progressively has
different sort
of like controls,
orchestrators, actions
that are all working
together. But there's
three main components
at the core, an
orchestrator, a brain, and
a spinal cord. The spinal
cord is essentially
a self-prompting
engine. It understands
quality control and
have we actually
achieved the execution
and making sure
that whatever AI is
working and the brain
is working and the
orchestrator is working,
that if there is not
good quality output,
the output hasn't
reached a final point
of either maturation
or user alignment.
And that can be defined
by the user. The
way I have it kind
of built is it's
meant to go past a
little bit what you would
ask. So in this
example last night, it
took about four hours
to write a book.
And in writing a
book, it actually made
its own website and
made a hero page for it
and started to build
like a lot of things
that you would see
subsequently if someone
was writing a book
and thinking about
marketing and it it
it uses the same tools
same mcps but you
know just for writing
the book it did about
3 000 perplexity
searches um in order
to do research uh and
pull different information
in so quick question
here john quick
question for you so
and and say if we
think about the the web
page that wrote did
you specify that in
your in your prd spec
that it needed to do
that no i just told
it to write a book i
can even show you the
prompt the prompt is
somewhere in here it's
pretty big essentially
i told it it needs
to write a book this
is the topic which is
uh ai uh did ai is a
digital divinity um
and then a uh it needs
to you know pretty much
deliver 15 chapters
so yeah because you
know the the that's
awesome the the people
in the foundation you
know one of the things
that i i'm a product
management lifetime
career pm guy right a lot
the big problem that
a lot of people have
and you you've already
figured this out it's
the first mile is
that you you have to
really specify a great
parity spec that and
give that to your agentic
coding system that
you've detailed out
what it is you want it
to do and that's the
first mile problem so
a lot of people would
appreciate seeing your
initial you know your
initial kickoff first
mile spec problem
Reuven i have to hand
it to Reuven his cognitive
diversity i think
is what you called it
yeah like it gave me
this it gave me this
idea to essentially use
scoring and a mathematical
way to actually
push innovative thought
into the LLM. So
if you think about like
your weightings, your
temperature, all of
those kind of things,
and then you think
about creating, it has
the ability to do its
own A-B testing. So it
will create simultaneous
multi-agent thoughts
across, let's say
it spawns six agents
for this problem. And
then it will take those
six agents and duplicate
them. And it will
then tokenize, create
a SHA hash for both
of those executions,
so it can track both
of those. And then it
will look and view the
output, and it will
measure, essentially,
is it headed the
direction it wants? It
chooses the one that's
winning. And then it
goes, did we achieve what
we wanted to achieve?
No. Great. Spawn
another group, and it
battles again. And
it will continue that
battle of progression,
innovation, and thought,
literally brainstorming
is the module,
until it reaches a
point of, yes, we're
writing the way, we're
using the right prose,
we're using the right
lexicon, we're not
coming across as AI,
we're doing a level of
research that we need
to do, and we're going
as deep and as wide.
And that's the key
is like, it's part
thought, but it's also
part measurement on
like depth and breadth.
Yeah, what's interesting
is what I'm doing,
and if you want to
take away all the
sort of, you know,
buzzwords around neural
networks and whatnot,
is I'm creating a
feedback loop that
both is recursive in
the sense that it
understands what it needs
and then adapts and
changes and updates
based on what works.
So the more you use
this system, the better
it becomes. So the
first time you use
it, it's like, you
know, it's kind of
stupid. And the second,
third, tenth, a hundredth
time, it actually
will improve itself.
And so, for example,
when I'm using my
Claude-flow development
environment, which is
the oldest environment,
obviously, because I
built the Claude-flow
system with it and
then started using it,
it actually performs
better than any of
my other systems. So
what I ended up doing
was taking the memory
files from those and
then using it in other
projects because it's
already been trained
to know what I like.
Yeah.
So there's a, you actually
hit on a important
topic. So there's,
I can't find it off
the top of my head,
but there is a area in
here that you can
see I have plenty of
versions going and I'm
testing them against
each other. but there's
a version that I'm
not demoing that I
really wanted to. I hope
to have it. It
essentially uses Dockers
as self-scaling compute.
So it will containerize
itself for execution
on a swarm and
on an agentic structure.
And then it will
run that as an ephemeral
process on the PC.
And in that way, when
it only pulls out what
it wants to pull out
and if it decides to
use nothing, the Docker
goes away, there's no
data. And then it will
do that in multiple
iterations over a
period of time. At one
point, you know, the
reason I'm not demoing is
it will spawn so many,
it will crash the PC.
It will just like kill
my processor and my
RAM because it's
generating so much data so
fast. And also a lot
of the models and API
calls, but essentially it
will just exponentially
move itself laterally
across a problem.
I need to contain
that a little bit.
But the interesting
side about that
is like, when it
starts to do that, the
learning aspect
that you're talking
about, Reuven, I
went and built a
similar aspect using,
where is it? I'll
have to find it. But
it actually will not
just move information
into memory. It will
learn positive, negative,
neutral self-scoring
through not just the
A-B testing and user
feedback, but it will
look at research as a
learning experience
that it can positively
or negatively influence.
And then it will
use that new information
as a way to change
or adapt in the
future of how it makes
decisions. So the actual
decision engine or the
real persistent mechanism
is actually just
one file that's about,
I think, 1,700 lines.
That one file,
though, is a massive
orchestration engine
that runs pretty
much all of the
recursive looping.
And the spinal cord
is really the only
thing that has the
exit button. And until
that exit button is
hit, the AI just runs
and it keeps running,
essentially challenging
itself, learning
itself and adapting
on anything that has
been tasked to do
until at such time
the exit button's hit.
That's cool.
And was, sorry,
was that more along
the fan repo lines
or more along
the neural divergent
repo lines?
um i would say i
started originally with
sort of just swarm and
then from swarm went
into the neural divergent
that's what kind of
clicked for me because
you know i like the
more creative side
of things and one of
the gaps that i typically
see especially around
like if you ask ai to
write a book there's
there's continuity is
missing and and one
of the cool things
about this is it created
its own book outline
and as it's going
through here it's laying
out this strategy and
it rewrote this
probably five six times
um how it was going to
actually build the book
what themes how it
wanted to do the part
that really surprised
me is it built
essentially its own
lexicon for the book so it
started to equate like
religion and religious
terms let me see if it's
up here two different
parts of the chapter
consistency this
is where it is so clergy
or developers temples
or data centers
prayer is clearing ai
systems and high priests
prophets scribes it
created this really cool
sort of like parallel
like way to talk
about topics that is
pulled through the entirety
of all 15 chapters.
And then to ensure
that it has continuity,
it was actually going
through and creating
the concepts and how
it's going to tie
these chapters and
thematic evolution of the
book all the way through
the last chapter.
That's amazing.
What is this being
used for in practice,
John? And is this, have
you open sourced this?
I literally am still
working on it i haven't
done uh i started it
like yesterday so this
is the whole project
itself what you've just
described like the
whole brain spinal cord
all that no the legion
i would say most of
the legion parts have
been a project i've been
working on for probably
over a year um and
it has different
versions like one uses a
computer um and i was
using components of that
decision matrix in
this but yeah the the
actual what you're seeing
right now i started
yesterday just specifically
on the book but
the main focus was to
get to if i give you a
command i don't care
how long it takes you
to do it you need to
figure out how to execute
and it has to be
executed at a level of
quality that i wanted
at and if you can't do
that you're not allowed
to stop until you do
and keep it right keep
in mind guys just just
um in terms of the
what underpins things
like clod flow is and
is the roof fan system
which i've uh compiled
as a wasm and then
i'm essentially using
the roof swarm system so
when you uh install
clod flow and you do
slash mcp in clod you'll
see that there's two
there's two mcps and
if you want to follow
the rabbit hole you
actually should take look
at the capabilities
in those mcps because
i've exposed all the
capabilities of the the
neural network components
of the fast neural
network system and the
neurodivergent system
which is essentially
a uh forecasting and
modeling system so
when if you're looking
to sort of do prediction
or learning you're
kind of doing this
interplay between the the
the custom neural nets
that are being built
on the fly, but also a
kind of various types
of forecasting and
modeling that use both.
And those are two, those
are kind of playing
off each other. And
what John's showing
is like the optimal
use of it. And I love
what you're doing because
you're like following,
it's following that
rabbit hole. It's fun
that you said that
because it's actually
a little bit, it's almost
like in some cases,
the opposite use
because you're using it
to predict and I'm
actually using it to on
purpose push different
thought like like instead
of predicting it's
it is using the
prediction especially
around user intent it's
absolutely like what
did the user really mean
and and the analysis
and like how to get to
that but the the other
um thing that i i i
really purposed the
math around was you okay
if we establish this
as your normal answer
where's crazy and
where is that limit and
how hard can I push
you to be different and
then what is different
enough that is
considered artistic or
like innovative versus
crazy oh so you're
actually trying to create
neurodivergent thinking
like like someone
that might have you
know ADHD versus someone
who's autistic and and
then using that kind
of mind construct to
that's that's amazing
that's amazing yeah
i'm on i'm on purpose
creating agents with
diversity mathematically
and then measuring
their output to see
how far it can be
pushed and then when it
reaches oh no this isn't
quality stop it knows
this is my limit in
this topic or this
thing and then it will
take those agents right
wherever the competition
or the ab testing
ended and go hey
here's my chapter three
off like swarm and an
agent group and then
that writes chapter
three and then that goes
into like the storage
for memory of like
hey here's a a group
that does really well
with this thing yeah
you know on a side note
oh you know all my
life people are always
like you know you're
you're you're weird
you're crazy you're
different and over the
last like 10 years
or so this idea of
neurodiversity has really
come up and it and it
turned out that the way
that that you know me
or others like us you
know think is isn't
isn't necessarily bad
it's actually i think
the the it's our
superpower it's our and
what playing with ai
does it is makes you
look at sort of how you
how you think or how
you think others people
you know other people
sort of you know
think and and that the
the inspiration for
why i even called it
neurodivergent was a
kind of homage to that.
When I saw it,
I was like,
oh, this is fascinating.
And my head went
sort of the direction
I went. I saw how
you were using it
and I still use that
component, right?
Especially within
Claude for that. But
the other thing
that I found that's
really powerful is
intelligence analysis.
So we're about ready
to go through another
raise. And I really
wanted to just see what's
on the internet for
enable. So I said,
hey, go out and research
enable. And I didn't
tell it to make a
website. I didn't tell
it to use whatever design.
But it's fascinating
that I have color
changes and customizers
in here that i can
you know customize
the website but the
detail that it got into
and where i i don't
i'd have to go through
the logs to find
out where it got the
information but it it it
did really well and even
did competitive
analysis there's a whole
bunch of detail this
is just the overview
behind it and and even
called out like areas
that i didn't give
it instruction to and
that was sort of like
the self it it has to
solve not just the
planning problem but like
what do i do and
what do i do next and
that recursiveness
creates this really
interesting thing where
you don't have to ask it
to build you a cool
html website to report
on what it found it
just does and it'll come
up with all sorts of
interesting solutions
quick question for
you then i'm sure that
the audience would
like to know right is
this is the basic
tool that you most
predominantly interacting
with Claude Flow Swarm.
How does your tool
stack actually
look and work? The tool
stack is its own
thing, Legion.
So I've been using
Claude Flow and
Claude to build this
component, but it
runs on its own
and it uses it very
similar to how Claude
Flow would work.
It uses the same hook,
same NCP, same tools
like architecture
and it just uses a
very different engine
and a very different
way of using the
models and how it does
sort of like its way
of thinking um sorry
guys one sec i there's
one thing i want to
show uh john quickly
before before i
forget and this is
something i've been it's
like a secret project
i've been working on
over the last uh
couple days um and this
is right up john's
alley it's it's using
something called
semantic Carton matrix.
So I define what's
called an orthogonal
enforcement of the
actual internal
matrix of the
neural network. This
is just bonkers,
by the way. It's
basically a theoretical
physics concept.
And essentially, I'm
rewriting the structure
of the matrix within
the neural network
to be self-optimized.
But for what you're
working on, this is
something you might
want to take a look
at. I haven't pushed
it to the main branch
yet, but if you want
to take a look, it's
issue 175 on Rufan.
It's so bonkers. I'm
not even quite sure how
to exactly describe
what it is that I'm
making, but in the early
tests that I've done,
it allows for the AI to
sort of self-optimize
in a way that's
really, really fast and
really, really really
good so i'm rewriting
the attention mechanism
which speaks back
to all the things john's
just been describing
i loved it john if
you've got a second
later on to take a look
at this i'd love to
get your uh your
thoughts on this um there
there is a branch i
think i named something
obvious like uh the
what would the the
semantic carton mark
matrix again i'm not going
to try to go explain
it it's like breaking
you know it's it's
cutting edge stuff
according to ai it's no
no one's ever tried it
but whatever so uh i
have i'm gonna i'll
push something um maybe
to that branch or to
the clod flow but it's
called an rl tuner
and it's out it's
essentially outcome driven
like policy optimizer
so policies being
like ways or rules that
it creates to process
information or think
but that is broken
into engine mapping
epsilon alpha gamma uh
mini eslon decay and
read and it creates a
dashboard that you
can actually watch the
decay but as it's
learning and adapting you
can provide it positive
neutral and negative
feedback and if you do
you can watch the ai
live adapt which
influences how the llm's
taking action and
using the engine and it
allows you to sort of
like steer live feed
of what it's doing
positively or negatively
So your system has a
whole bunch of models
that you're connecting
to in the back end?
Yes.
Do you adjust the
temperature on the fly?
You can. Yeah, there's
both self-tuning
components within like
your Bayesian's and like
your typical ones. But
there's more of, and
those are controlled
by the AI itself. And
then there's sort of
like drop-in or more
deterministic protocols
that come in in
different, I would say,
different mechanisms by
the engine. But the
main one that you're
allowed to live tune is
more on the RL tuner.
So these are self-hosted
models or publicly?
If you turn the
temperature up to two,
it's going to be
most creative, right?
I'm sorry?
You can adjust
the temperature
to be more creative.
So you can, like,
adjust that if
it's getting too
out of whack. It
goes from zero to
two, right? Yeah.
I think that, like,
I don't do that.
I, the model, the
AI itself does that.
So, like,
think about it this way.
There's an autonomous
maintenance loop that
is called the goal
scheduler. And that
loop uses the engine,
a set timer, a
priority, and is running
through intervals sort
of as its own quality
control analysts watching
everything happen.
That's a machine
learning flow where
you're adjusting
the hyperparameters
in a standard Epoch run.
Yeah. And then it
knows that like, I know
I have this many tasks
to do and the user
has provided me negative
feedback. Say the RL
tuner, I'm like, nope,
I don't like this.
That negative feedback
is going to go into
a whole bunch of
other models that are
going to essentially
distribute that feedback
to different parts
of the engine so that
it starts essentially,
for lack of a better
term, you have drift
on purpose, like
purposeful drift that
we're going to create.
And then when that
mechanism occurs, it's
******* off an AB run.
And that AB run says
essentially like, I
know I need to change,
but before I change,
I need to know
where I'm at and what
I'm competing against.
and then you guys i
i i hate to break up
this conversation but
i i want to get ocean
on here before we run
out of time because
i know he's working
on some really cool
stuff um we we do have
a bit of an after show
week so we come back
and we can dig into
some of this uh deep
neural net components
but uh ocean are you
are you still and john
thank you as always
your stuff's amazing
oh yeah uh thank you i
let me share my screen
great so today
i want to uh
talk a little bit about
how to write uh more
deterministic workflows
with cloud code and
line agi um so first
of all this script that
i wrote here uh that
uh it so the only uh
customization you need
to do for this flow
to do different thing
is the prompt and then
uh so that's about I
changed the prompt from
analyzing my own memory
NCP usages from Python
to Rust for the
analysis part to a
vulnerability detector
for establishing packages.
So let's run it,
and then I'll show a
diagram of what
it's supposed to do.
So this is the first
planting phase, and
it just telling me that
it started that it's
about to run that so
we are at here at a
so we just kind of
entered this security
vulnerability and then
we started doing the plan
part so this plan part
will generate three
dynamic plans depending
on depending on the
context so first
plan will trigger um
parallel parallel analysis
and then depending on
the result of those
and then we'll do a
complexity assessment on
uh which route of path
it continues to move
on if it's uh score
certain thing was we'll
trigger four agents
and if it goes further
we'll trigger seven
agents and then every
single agent here is a
separate cloud code
session or if you it can
be replaced with any
agentic processes so
can theoretically uh
switch to Gemini CLI and
then after the third
after this run gets
finished all of those
results get synthesized
back to the original
orchestrator which then
you can simply do a
cloud dendrocy dash c
and then the same come
uh the same orchestration
session gets continued
within the cloud
code that is uh
basically the whole flow
here so what i mainly
want to show is how this
plans gets created and
then how these plans
can be modified very
easily via the agent.
So here I have this
three plan. One is
discovery phase. One
is standard analysis.
One is the comprehensive
analysis for more
complex cases. Here
is quite simple.
It's just a simple
complexity thing but how
do you extend such
a system i basically
allowed it to be you
copy paste this into
complexity plan two
which we will do if
it's above seven uh
we'll do nine agents
and then uh okay so
right now it finished
the first round it's
going to do the uh
parallel uh discovery
analysis period and
then so when you do
this and then you just
and this will be
automatically become part
of the result once
you run that so what
you can do is you you
can just go back here
if the you know the
complex situation is
more complex and
there's a feedback loop
that says it should
iterate just iterate and
let me show you some
of the more complex
flows that i I did or
worked on this one.
Hey, Ocean, when
you call Cloud Code,
are you using
that stream JSON
approach where you
call it, or how
are you interacting
with Cloud Code?
Yes, this is just via
streaming the JSON
from the CI and
then I parse it, and
then I parse it and
then be able to trigger
all the hooks within
and then I extract
a structured output
from the cloud
code just kind of when
it's still running
and then I use those
structured output
to dynamically produce
the next steps.
So the question
is Lions pulling
from cloud code
or is cloud code
sort of interacting
with line AGI?
This is line AGI
orchestrating cloud code.
And could you do it
inversely? Could you
create an agent
in cloud code and
basically say you're
the line agent and then
have that call line
from cloud code?
That doesn't quite
make sense because
LineAGI is a SDK. It
doesn't really have an
agent. Like every
cloud code session
here, it is already
using LineAGI constructs.
It is being processed
exactly the same
way if I have an
open AI model there.
Gotcha. Okay, cool.
Yeah, so what ended up
with this is you can
build very complex flow
very easily and then
you can resume it.
So this can be a, how
do you do a quality
gates? The best part is
every single execution
here, it can be switched
with any model, with
any configuration,
kind of even runtime
dynamic if you want,
if you trust LM to
produce those parameters.
And then every
single, it can also be
pre-configured as
the ones you like.
So it really just
becomes very fun that
you get to experiment
how some of those
structures you like
that can be produced.
Yeah, that's
about it. Thanks.
And so what's a practical
application? So I
want to use this,
what would I
use this for?
So for example, this
is the vulnerability
analysis I was doing.
And then right now,
it is working on the
vulnerability, I hope.
I wonder where the
output is. I'll
find the output
later, but you kind of
customize this to
any flow you like.
And then those flows
are repeatable.
Those are, so when I
mean reusable pattern
in this way, I mean
the behavior of those
flows, they go exactly
as how you designed.
And then you can
tweak every part of
it, of what goes in
and out. I typically
use pydentic model
with validators
such that a lot
of conditions just
get auto-triggered.
If a quality gate
doesn't meet, what
should happen next?
If certain fields,
they're just corrupted
or dangerous, what
should do next?
I think the use
case of this kind
of system is
very fine-grained
control over the
overall processes.
Is it just for
coding, though, or can
it be applied to
different domains?
It's anything. It's
just the only thing
that you need to
change was the prompt.
Like change the
prompt to, I don't
know, customer
relationship analysis,
change it to stock
analysis, and they will
go through the same
flow as I showed you
before. I just keep on
going back and forth.
So the difficult
part about this
is actually the
flow design itself.
It's a lot of trial
and error, I have
to say. But since
I keep every single
data possibly
exists from the CLI,
so you can just load
this into a data
frame later and then
do some analysis
and then score them
to kind of see what
kind of flow makes
more sense to you.
So theoretically,
you can experiment
10, 20 of this kind
of flow structure,
provided you have
that much compute,
you run them
concurrently and then
evaluate what kind of
flow structure suits
best for your
particular use case.
We've got a question
from Toblow.
Yeah,
you know, Ocean,
I think where this is
really powerful and
it reminds me of
like some of the work
I was doing at Oracle
before I left, but
it's like legacy code
bases or knowledge
transfer on, you
know, replatforming,
stuff like that, this
would be huge. And,
I mean, then my next
thought was, like,
you know,
analyzing, like, a set of
service repos
in parallel,
like a service mesh.
But, yeah, really
cool. I just
wanted to add that
context and maybe
your thought when you,
instead of analyzing
one repo, but
you're analyzing,
you know, maybe five.
microservices that
that's all related yes uh
yeah i'm sorry go ahead
ocean oh i was just
gonna say the the fun
part about this is
the uh the orchestrator
like i'm not trying to
uh target a particular
flow to a particular
problem rather it's kind
of serve a particular
domain functionality
on how you organize
your work, like kind
of part of your work.
I'm not sure if
that makes sense.
I think what's
interesting watching both
what you and John have
been working on and your
approaches, although
application-wise are
different, but structurally
are interesting,
is we're starting to
see the integration
of these CLI and agent
structures like Cloud
Code as part of sort
of a kind of library
or interface into these
systems. So rather
than going and saying,
I'm going to directly
integrate with Open
Router or some LLM API
provider, we're
using these kind of
intelligent CLIs as an
abstraction, right? So it's
cheaper, obviously,
but it's kind of cool
to see what you're
dreaming up with these.
One other thing that
would be interesting to
see in terms of what
you're building is
leveraging the MCP
components within things like
CloudCode. And for
example, you could start
looking at the neural
network and the
neurodivergent components
and train your system
with those and seeing
what you could potentially
do for optimization
of these patterns.
Yeah, so that is
another thing I'm
experimenting,
which is intelligent
tooling for this
kind of system. So
basically, agents right
now are pre-configured
or agentic
processes, let's say.
So what I'm doing
right now is, so when
you see the agent
choosing part, I actually
have a very complex
agent composition kind
of planner system.
It will, depending on
the problem, it will
tell you how many
agents, what their
domain and roles should
be, and then what
is the order that it
should be executed in.
So like the first one
can be three batch and
then five batch, ten
batch, ten per batch,
et cetera. The best
part about this is
you can start to
accumulate your own
domain library. So how I
define agent in this
particular use case
is agent is made up
of a row and a domain.
And then a row can be
something like a critic,
can be an implementer
or a tester. And
then a domain can be
something like asynchronous
programming or a
RAS specialist, etc.
What I do is I give
each domain and
the row their own unique
set of capabilities.
And then the next
part I will do
here is I will
stop the access of
cloud code to most
of the tools. I will
only let it to run
through command line
that is pre-configured
in my system.
So I can basically
just have a lot
more control
that way. I still
feel kind of a little
fuzziness about
using cloud code
tools directly,
especially with
NCP. I don't know
why. I just feel
weird about it.
I think it's the
level of abstraction
you can get. Yeah,
sorry. Yeah, I think
I know what you're
saying. It's like,
and this is part of
the introspection
work that I've been
doing a lot of.
It's like, what's
actually happening?
And when you look
at the GitHub
components I came out
with the other day,
really what I was trying
to do is basically
get a view of what
each of those threads,
agents, whatever
you want to call it,
is actually doing
when it's blinking
and flickering and
doing all this magic,
I have a hard time
visualizing what
it's actually doing.
Is it searching and
doing things that
are inappropriate?
And how do I find
and figure that out?
So when you showed
your logs... There are
quite a few components
to this. One is the
work part. One is the
work level. One is
the observability
level. So on the task
level, all they need
is artifacts handover.
It's like the protocols
on the artifacts
handover and then what
should happen next.
And then, but in terms
of observability,
like I think
hooks are good
enough, or I add a
handler since I use
language. I like
on every single
event, I just kind
of send it there.
And then you can put
it into your WebSocket
server if you like.
But what I mainly want
to say is the
organization of your
artifacts, it actually
matters a lot and a lot
and then for especially
easy handoff among
processes, among agents
and among different
phases if you want to
all chain together.
So a flow like this
can be chained, I
don't know, a hundred
times and run overnights
and then I don't
know, scan all the
vulnerabilities to fix
or to attack up to you.
I hope to fix.
yeah that's about it
and then 1.6 dollars
it'll go it will just
i really wonder how
long our uh feast
on a cloud code will
be because that thing
go wrong with like
ten dollars or something
which is not durable
not quite doable
with such expensive
models as a model
models are you taking in
consideration the
cash because that that
drops the cost by
like 50 to 75 percent
oh yes this is this is
direct data from the
from the log like i'm
not calculating the
i'm not calculating
this yeah just as an fyi
when they do when they
give you that it the
number is completely
wrong you get you gotta
you gotta take into
consideration of the um
the caching which is
not doesn't cost really
anything right i i
went through the same
i went through the
same realization that
they're are you querying
the uh the clod uh uh
total cost no total
you yeah where are you
getting that total
cost from the cost is
directly from the cli
data so if that is wrong
i don't know it's it's
wrong it's 100 wrong
so yeah this is the
this is the number i get
it from total cost
usd i can tell already
that's wrong so what
what what it's not taking
is in consideration
is Claude's caching,
right?
The prompt
caching reduces
that cost by
at least 50%,
maybe more.
Does Claude code
automatically
cache prompts?
No, yes, it does.
But it doesn't,
if you're getting
that, the value
it tells you
doesn't include it.
Just, I think they
do it to sort of
make it look like it's
more valuable than
it is. So if you
want a true value,
you have to take that
in consideration.
So how you
calculate costs by
actually getting
these numbers and
calculate by the
price yourself?
Yeah, you have to.
It's not the default
number they give
you is like without
caching. And most of
the stuff you're
doing is going to have
some level of
caching, at least 50%,
which is going to drop
the cost dramatically.
But I don't think you
can control the cache,
right? I don't think
you have a lot of
control over how to
get code from cache.
So the other day when
I came, I came to a
sort of collective
value of the work that
people who have
downloaded Claude Flow
have produced over the
last six weeks. And
I came to like an
$890 million US value.
I actually reduced
the cost by something
like 65% based on
the stated value and
reduction and prompt
caching for Anthropic.
Now, if I hadn't done
that, the value would
have been like closer
to like $1.7 billion.
So I took a more
conservative sort of
estimate of both
caching and usage.
Now, if I had not
gone conservative, it
would have been like $3
billion, which seemed
crazy. So I assumed
a decent dose of
caching. And when I
looked at things like
my previous work with
– when I was using
Rue code, when I had
more access to the
cache, I was doing
around 55% to 60% cache.
So I just assumed
the same numbers.
But I couldn't get true
numbers. I had
to estimate it.
Yeah, that was kind
of my point, is
they're not exposing a
lot of visibility and
control on the cache.
So it's all just
soft, sort of fuzzy
math and estimates.
Yes, that's exactly
what it is. Yeah.
But just to some degree.
Now, I could get
exact numbers, but the
reason I'm not doing
that in my MPX is I don't
want to be the man
in the middle. So I'm
not getting the
telemetry, which I
hypothetically could,
given that I'm running an
MPX. But the interesting
thing about running
as an MPX is every
time I do an update,
I'm essentially forcing
anybody who's using
Claude-flow to do
an automatic update
and download. So if
you look at my numbers
and I see this week
I've done, what, 15
,000, 16,000 downloads,
that basically is
telling me that I've
got around 15,000 active
users of the Claude-flow
system, which is
amazing given it's
only like a month old.
I probably account for
eight of those, Reuven.
Yeah, yeah, you've
got to be careful
there, Reuven,
because I've been down
this path with many
open source projects,
and downloads is
not a mathematical,
empirical way to
claim users. I'm not
– well, it's 100%.
I get 16,000 – here,
can I show my screen
for a sec, guys?
Yeah, yeah, sure, sure.
I was just – This,
it's actually, I caused
a big stink when I
claimed a billion dollars.
And then the Reddit
guys, you know, basically
said I was a ****.
But what else is new?
So let me just show
you. So I can't get a
lot of detail. That's
my problem. Like, I
could get more details.
But right now, what
I'm seeing is 16,000,
oops, where'd it go?
16,744 downloads this
week, right? Right.
And so the benefit to
an MPX, unlike an MPM
style download, is
it every time I do an
update, it essentially
forces anyone that's
using it to do a new
download. Right. So now
the challenge to Dave's
point is I've done like
five or six updates
more probably this week
into it. So if let's
say I've got 5,000
users and I did five
updates, then that's
potentially every user
doing five updates, which
would skew the numbers.
So what I'm not
claiming here is the
fact that I've got 16,000
unique users. I'm
saying that I got 16,000
downloads in essence
here. But it's hard to
get a real judge of
true, unique usage unless
I do direct telemetry
on it, which I don't
want to do. This is
the point is like we
just have to be as a
nonprofit agentic foundation.
We just got to be
careful that we don't
imply that what we're
saying is 16,744 users
when there's eight
of them and they're
doing five updates for
every app that you push,
you create at times
eight for Jed. Same for
me. Right. So we've
got to be careful,
because the only way to
make that real claim is
you have to have
telemetry in the product.
Yeah. Well, I could do
telemetry, but
there's, you know,
at the end of the day,
it's a pretty nice curve.
I'm not disputing this,
Ruben. I've just been
here with a very
large, successful open
source project that's
owned by Linux Foundation.
exactly this problem
right stars is a
great is a great indicator
but if you go and
look at now a lot of
the organizations are
not using stars as as a
metric anymore um even
though it's it's a
good indicator right
and then and they don't
claim downloads you
just well it would just
be nice if we didn't
get ourselves into a
little bit of trouble
where people are
calling us jerks because
they're making all these
claims you know well
yeah i've already
gotten that trouble but
the uh so there's a couple
other things i could
do hypothetically
like i could have a a
server side um ping of
some sort that basically
just reports location
or something or or
but i i just don't
want to be i just want
to collect that information
like so actually
it's okay people do
it projects do it all
the time like you know
there's a hundred odd
projects in the in the
cncf kubernetes on by
Linux Foundation, and
they all do telemetry.
They all ping up when
the install runs.
They do a ping to say
first-time install. Then
they do, you know,
how many times the
system's up and down and
running, how many minutes
does it run for. They
collect some data
on what type of system
they're running on,
whether it's Linux or
WSL or Windows or Mac.
But they make
the data public.
I can get all that
data. Like the MPX makes
it super easy because
every single time
you're running a hook
you're running in
the mpx so whenever
that whenever that mpx
is hit i technically
could get the telemetry
so i'll i can know
exactly how long
people are using it how
many tokens are being
used you know i could
get everything if
i wanted to i'm just
not sure what we should
do maybe that's a
and this will be
important for the for
the agentix foundation
right because this
is an asset a really
important asset to be
able to claim you know
a hundred thousand
users Because that's
a very enabling asset
and brand for the
foundation. And we
probably should be able
to – if we're going to
make the claims, then
we should be able to
stand behind them.
You've got to be able to
credibly stand
behind them.
Yeah.
And right now, in
fairness, there's a
little bit of fuzzy
math involved in those.
I'm glad you admitted
it. I didn't want
to have to call
you out, but I'm
super glad you admitted
it because I have
been down this road
multiple times.
So it's very
good to be having
this conversation.
So it's healthy
to have this
out in the open.
Can I share my
screen again?
Just on this topic,
right? One thing I was
thinking here is, I mean,
Amazon says customer
centricity. We say
user centricity,
right? I mean, at the
end of the day, as a
foundation, we are here
to help the members.
But if we can
even capture the
member data,
like who are the
GitHub users who
are downloading,
we can get telemetry
of the maturity of
the users. Like, I mean,
for example, novice,
intermediate, or
whatnot, and so forth.
And that actually
allows us to tell a
more credible story
about how we are making
an impact on you. Yeah,
Mandvi, so that's,
so the Linux
Foundation, for example,
you know, they're
really good. They're the
most profitable open
source foundation on the
planet right now. They
write a, they give
Linus Torvalds a $700
,000 grant every year.
That's how much money
they make, right? um
and but that's one thing
you're asking about
is knowing more about
who who your user base
is in your foundation
you have to be very
very careful about
collecting that information
and then and then what
you do with it because
everybody will want
that information so
so that's very very
dangerous it's kind of
good but you get once
you do it you have to
be very careful about
how you manage that
corpus of user information
so maybe when i get
back from my vacation
Dave and whoever else
wants to help with the
open source stuff we
have something very
valuable pretty clearly
it's growing like mad
I can't keep up with
the amount of interest
we do, it's an asset
in roughly 7 days
we've had 30,000 unique
viewers on GitHub alone
so obviously there's a
valuable asset we have
here that we could
probably if you look at
like the early evolution
of GPT engineer and
what became lovable
Basically, what
they did is they
launched a relatively
rudimentary, you
know, CLI tool to do,
you know, and coding.
And then they were
able to sort of
parlay that into
this high growth,
lovable sort of
platform as a service.
We're actually growing
at substantially
higher rate than GPT
Engineer ever did.
So the question, and
this is not one I
have an answer to,
is what do we do with
it? Like I can keep
mucking around with
it and getting some
consulting work, or
maybe we can use it
as some kind of launch
pad for something
bigger and more
valuable. But I'm just
not sure how to go
from where we are to
where we want to be.
That is also the
question on my mind,
Riven, is I've been
through these very
large growth
organizations, and we don't
want to let this
run away from us,
right? We're the
curators of this, and we
should be trying to
curate and do the
right thing and
actually leverage it.
for both the foundation
and the members
and ourselves as
much as we can do the
right thing. And it's
a huge asset. I think
it's a very, very
critically important
asset. So let's chat
about it. Is Flood
Flo owned by the
foundation? No, I think
we don't want to get
too far ahead of it.
Reuven publishes
on Ruvnet.
Reuven is, you know,
Reuven does his
Reuven thing. We can't
make any assumptions
necessarily.
Well, I did a post
the other day,
basically, should I do
a startup or should
I contribute it?
One, you guys know
I hate venture
capitalists. So I'm
not eager to go in that
row because my
loathe for them. If
anything, if I could
put venture capitalists
out of business,
that would be my
number one goal in
life. But that aside,
my preference would
be to make this free
and available to
everybody. But that said,
I think that if we can
figure out a way to
leverage this as a way
that generates income
or revenue for our
foundation to support
all the crazy things
that we want to do,
and maybe even help
support me so I don't
have to do all this
crazy consulting work,
all the better. I
just don't know how to
get there. I agree,
man. I agree, Reuben.
And I think as us early
founding members of
this foundation and
anybody else who joins,
I think that's a great
ethical goal that
we should be looking
at. Either you create
a product company or
you create a way for
the foundation
members to financially
benefit and nurture the
growth of this thing.
I think it's an awesome
way to think about
this. What if we
could create something
sustainable, like
what open AI should
be, using some of
these tools? Because
we've got everything
we need. We just need
to figure out a way
to leverage them
appropriately and
responsibly. And if we can
start funding ourselves
and our organization
with it, that would
be amazing. If
I didn't have to
work 70 hours a week
because I'm doing this
and random enterprise
consulting, that
would be great for me.
Well, let me give
you an example,
right? So the Linux
Foundation, they
own the brand for
Kubernetes and
the Kubernetes is
super profitable.
But you pay for,
like the Agentic
Foundation, right?
You pay a membership.
What a lot of people
don't realize is
that the top membership
for the Linux
Foundation, for
the CNCF, which is
the organization
that owns Kubernetes,
the top membership
is $300,000. So IBM,
NVIDIA, Microsoft,
they all pay that.
And so they have like…
So they're FOSM members.
Yes. And so they have
a huge influx of money.
There's like 25,
30, 50 members are
paying $300,000 to the
CNCF Linux Foundation.
And that's a big funding
resource. Plus the
members pay at
different levels as well
with different companies.
So there's a lot
of ways that we can
leverage. Plus, we have
the hundred-odd thousand
-plus social media
assets that you've
nurtured up, Reuven.
That's another
very lucrative
marketing,
branding mechanism.
So we've got to be
really smart about how
we manage all of these
assets. Like you say,
they're taking off
faster than lovable.
We should be smart
about this. Can we set
up a steering committee
where we can maybe
talk about the sort
of commercialization
aspects? Yeah, my
background is a lot more
strategy than it is
tech. I'm more of a
strategist and consultant
than I am a tech guy.
And I'm happy to help
out with this. We
can drive this in a
much more organized
and structured way
to identify these
areas for sure. You
know, and we do have
guys like Reuven
and Brad and a bunch
of other guys have
been trying to, you
know, hustle and make
this work as much
as we can. But the
growth is getting
ahead of 16,000
downloads, 100,000 users.
It's more than
like three guys
and a dog can
handle it now.
There's a decision.
Chris Barlow really
wants to see the mesh
thing come together,
the synaptic mesh.
Yeah, we have unfinished
projects, right?
We have hundreds of
unfinished projects,
and the latest crazy
thing I showed you
guys earlier. So we
have no shortage of
stuff, and we've got
arguably our first hit.
So now what do we do
with our first hit?
Yes, we need to – it's
an asset, and we need
to make sure that the
Argentic Foundation
manages it in the
right way. the repos of
the github is maintained
and managed and we
there's so much we
need to do but by first
hit ruben do you mean
the potential sponsor i
think you haven't
formally announced it is
that what you mean no
i'm talking that aside
i'm talking about like
uh of all the random
things i've built
something that that is
blowing up really quickly
yeah it's a it's a
growth explosion right
spark was uh like uh
consistent and it laid
down it really has
become sort of
foundational but the cloud
flow is uh yeah it's
just absolutely taken off
and just for context
um david gratton the
chair of the board um
as uh has spoken to a
number of times about
uh the foundation sort
of rallying around
what would become a
central product and i
know there's a lot of
people here with a lot
of experience. So there's
certainly a great
time and opportunity
to have that conversation
at a higher level.
There's probably about
14 people that come
to the management
meetings every week.
They are open for
everybody to attend. And
those volunteers have
been working very
hard in very different
pockets and areas.
But this is now, Ruben,
as you get closer
to sort of making a
decision of how you
want to handle the
innovations that you bring
to the world in
terms of in the space
that you do it as
Ruvnet, you know, that
we all celebrate and
the foundation, the
foundation's mission
as, you know, as an
entity, as we get
closer to that, it'd be
wonderful to have a lot
of people participating
in what that
conversation looks like.
Hey guys, this
is Robert. Sorry,
I'm kind of new face for
this part of the
conversation.
As an outsider,
I'm a little bit
curious your stance on
building everything
around Claude. I mean, I
absolutely love the
utility. I'm a huge fan.
I'm showing this off
to everyone. But, you
know, is there any danger
in tying this whole
logic to something
that we're dependent on
another company to not
change the rules of the
game with their max
slice? Great question.
Very great open question.
Just to be clear,
Claude-flow has little
to do with Cloud,
other than the fact
that I instantiate the
Cloud code system. But
when you look at the
actual architecture of
Claude-flow, it's an
independent series of
components that you
could relatively easily
integrate with anything,
right? It's a memory
system. It's a neural
network. It's a
training system. It's an
orchestrator. But the
reason why there's a
dash dash clod for a
lot of the things is
because my intention
actually is to have it
instantiate open code
or Jules or whatever.
So I built it
independently of clod code.
You don't need to use it.
From the point of
view of a nonprofit
organization, right,
the Agentex Foundation,
that's awesome because,
yeah, we don't want
to be tied to a
specific corporation
-owned product as our
engine. And like Rob
said, Spark, the concept
of Spark that you
invented actually
underpins all of that.
That's a principle
with TDD, amazing, and
that actually underpins
a cornerstone of
what we're doing here.
And that is independent
of any technology
as well. And if you
look underneath the
covers, it's Rube Swarm.
And that's the work
that Ocean and Braun
and Jed and others
have contributed to.
So the Claude stuff
was the marketing hook
that got people
excited. They're not
searching for swarms.
They're searching for ways
to sort of leverage
Claude code. So that
gave me the ability
to sort of piggyback
on the excitement
and momentum of that
project. But everything
that underpins it is
independent of it.
So we just need to be
clear. So the most obvious
next step, at least
for me, is to basically
abstract it with
something like OpenCode,
the SST version
of OpenCode, and then
we can use anything.
Yes, and any model,
right? We also
need to be model
independents as well.
So there's a lot
of thinking and we
got a lot of high
performance into a
capacity here that
we need to apply.
And the other thing
to keep in mind with
models is I think we're
moving away from LLMs
altogether for coding.
If you look at the
work that we were
looking at earlier from
John and others, a
lot of those neural
networks, at least the
ones that I'm devising,
work just as well
and don't require any
kind of transformer
style or attention-based
modeling. We can
actually create much
more effective targeted
coding systems without
ever having to worry
about language itself,
but focusing on the
semantics of math,
calculus,
abstract algebra as
the basis for how we
create the code. And
right now everyone on
everyone's thinking,
you know, well, we
just need to ask the
right questions to an
LLM where where I think
we should be saying
is we should be
training models that are
that are explicitly
code orientated, not
like English English
English language orientated.
I totally agree,
Ruben. And what
you're actually, if you
up level this, right,
that's a core principle
that the foundation
should adopt as its
very core. Are we,
we're an AI, we're the
Agentex Foundation.
Are we tied to models
or are we tied to
actually an intelligence
type outcome mode?
I agree.
I've got a quick
clarification and I'm just
trying to relate my
question to what John
you showed earlier on.
John Petty is still
there, right? I can't
see you, but you know,
your book example,
like what I have been
trying to do, I'm just
putting something on
the chat here is, so
Roof, I kind of try and
go into your GitHub
repost and I'm trying
to throw a swarm into
it and ask you to create
a course out of it
for different levels.
So one iteration of
it is the link that I
have put on the chat,
which basically is Roof
swarm but it tries to
create quizzes and kind
of modules based on
what you have said in
your course obviously
i am i'm learning so
it has taken me a while
but i'm just wondering
what john you showed
your book creation
could we not throw that
into all the code bases
and effectively try
to create similar
learning material and
you know basically
accreditation processes
and other stuff through it
done yeah you're
assuming that it's open
source and like oh okay
well i i i'm gonna put
something i'm gonna
definitely put part of
it into what you guys
have built because i
need to add more of my
contributing stuff into
it that's just something
i owe the group
as a whole but um
the the stuff that is
proprietary in my mind
is the stuff that i just
have to get permission
from my board on and
like I that that
shouldn't I'll start that
process now but the the
the main part I don't
think like the stuff
that you would need in
order to do what you're
saying is not the
stuff that I am not I
wouldn't be allowed to
release as of right
now without permission
so um let me look
what I can do but like
essentially you're you're
spot on the recursive
nature and the processing
through the code,
the way that it looks
to drive outcomes and
essentially measures
when it gets to a
conclusion, it is the
process in which you would
need in order to do
sort of the learning or
book writing. I chose
book because it's a
stupid amount of content,
right? I think this
one's 400 pages that
it wrote. And, you
know, in that, I always
have found playing with
LLMs, even like trying
to build some basic
agentic systems that
it just doesn't have
good continuity at some
point it breaks down
there's some sort of
just dumb stuff that ends
up in the book it just
i don't know i i've
never really got it to
work the way i wanted
it to we have a a
process within our app
that does book sort of
like book level writing
that'll do like 150
page book in a single
prompt and that's the
happiest i've been
with it um and this
this blows it out of the
water by far is so the
way that i have played
around with it so far
is like intelligence
like go find me information
and tell me what
i need to know right
uh write me a book and
then uh i've had it
do like sort of app
development in the sense
of like i want you to
build me an end-to
-end enterprise app but
in the sense of the
back end has to be real
there has to be real
data so it's building
synthetic data it's
building databases and
actually filling them
with data so it uses real
api calls and does
all of that all in one
shot um and it built a
pretty good third-party
risk um website for
one of my buddies who
is super interested in
it so it i think you
i haven't tried it on
a educational thing
but i will point it at
one of the repos and
try it guys this is a
really good example where
you know the foundation
you know your your
goals are amicable you
know good great you
know but the foundation
is a non-profit open
source foundation and
we can only accept
truly open source code
that adheres to the the
principles of the
foundation right and so
that's like the linux
foundation you you
can't just donate you
know push push code into
any kubernetes or
linux linux foundation
project it has to be
kind of vetted and
approved to meet the And
so no proprietoriness,
it's got to adhere to
the right licenses,
all of that stuff.
And the foundation
has to have kind of
principles along that.
So I understand what
you want, but we're
a foundation, we're
a nonprofit open
source organization.
You've got to be
careful. You can't
just take anything in.
yeah well and actually
that's another problem
i've been having with
the clod flow prs
there's a someone did
a 5,000 5,500 file pr
the other day and then
and like i don't i
like it was so much stuff
it crashed my browser
then there was another
there was several
people who did prs
that had backdoors and
spyware and other ****
in it so it reached a
point where it's like
i just don't think
i'm in a position to
do that level of review
this is not my full
-time job so yeah i so
i'm just so david
there's there's actually
isn't a we have a repo
for the foundation yet
but we haven't got the
team around it or the
concepts or the
conversations about what
that will look like or
what's going to be in
it so you're putting
your finger right on
it there's there's
decisions to be made
there's uh discussed uh
policies and then support
and what's the content
going to be and
where's cloud flow going
to live or the version
of it so like we're
away next week but we
should probably
david if you guys and
everybody else who's
interested we should probably
talk about having
a getting together
specifically on this
topic let's just you just
let's use the tools we
have let's let's just
use discord or whatsapp
or or or whatever
we we don't have we
can we can use these
calls to have the in
-person conversation about
what what's our you
know res on debt but
But the rest can just
happen online organically,
and everybody wants
to get involved. It
doesn't have to – it
can be asynchronous,
for sure.
I can give you
guys the history of
Linux Foundation
and CNCF, how they
went through this
problem. What
tools do we use?
How do we set it up?
Why do we use them?
What works? What
doesn't work? I've
been doing this with
the Linux Foundation
for many years now,
and so I have a lot
of learning that
I would like to be
able to share. and
in part to the Agentex
Foundation here.
Awesome.
One thing that I might
be able to understand
why this is
important now.
Sorry.
One thing that
I can contribute
perhaps is a
legal background.
So I'd be interested
in participating.
Sure.
Yeah, it's important
for us to do this now
because I think we are
kind of probably at
that point where we
have formed like i think
i think some of the
discussions i think it's
it could be really
useful to kind of get
some kind of setup behind
that i mean personally
that's what i think
if that's what you're
asking from my perspective
it appears like
we're putting the cart
before the horse we're
trying to set up a
um what's it called a
accreditation program
without demand for
accredited agentic
engineers oh there's demand
oh there's a there's
a huge demand there's
huge demand for agent
yeah like i i get i i
get hundreds of people
reaching out you know
saying can you who who
can i use for agentic
engineering and i'm
not even sure where to
point them you know
because we don't have
a directory i you know
i i ad hoc suggest
people but yeah there's
huge demand i have four
phone calls during this
meeting alone that's
people wanting wanting
me wanting me for
my resume to to go for
agentic ai jobs yeah
just in this meeting
alone yeah i could i'm
sure channel who would
love to accept those
leads yeah but there's
no way to know who
in that channel are
capable of doing them like
anyone can be a vibe
coder and slap some
stuff together and but
it's it's more than
just you know randomly
asking a few questions
and seeing what pops
out the other side we
need we need the
mechanism to validate that
they can go from vibe
to something much more
elaborate and that's
partially what we're
doing on these calls
when i see the work that
you know ocean and
john and others are
showcasing you know i'm
getting on and others
yeah i i get a good
feel for it you know but
i still we still need
some way to validate
it beyond you know five
minutes on a friday
call i i would love
to what my goal was to
feed some of these
recruiters that are looking
for ai agetic engineers
into our group but
i don't want to you
know that needs to be
in a controlled way
where they actually they
actually have to respect
the way that we want
them to come in and
then they can present
their their opportunities
to our team and
then you know that guy
the other day yesterday
was asking for he wants
work so and there's
work i know that could
could be presented
to our to our organization
and by the way a
top tier agentic
engineer right now at a
major you know fang companies
is getting somewhere
in the realm of
three to five million
package that's right now
so and those are just
the ones i know about
the other part jed
is just take a look
at what happened with
cloud code naming the sub
agents where ru already
spearheaded the naming
and the invention
of the structure of
the directory and then
it's kind of getting
away in terms of how
it's being created and
now it's looking like
cloud code invented it
when that's not true.
So we give. If
it's open source,
right? If it's open
source and they
take it, then it
doesn't matter.
We have to be
happy with that.
Yeah, that
doesn't bother me.
Attribution is one of
those things that I've
always sort of struggled
with over the years.
But the realities for
Anthropic, it would
have been nice if they
had just reached out,
right? and i i would
have i would have
happily collaborated
with them but they're
they're a kind of silicon
valley i don't know
cult of some sort so
unless you're in their
little circle you're
you're excluded yes they
are man someone mentioned
something about a
sponsorship like i
know you can only share
what you can share but
like do we have any
strategic alignment
with a potential sponsor
that you know gives
us some support but we
need so yes there's lots
of companies that are
reaching out that are
looking to potentially
sponsor we uh we're
working on one in
particular that looks
like it might might a
smaller one not not the
larger one that looks
like they're willing
to sort of give us some
capital to get get going
um the larger entities
are are sniffing
around but we don't
really have a good
particular story on what we
need or why we need it
so that that is back
to all the other things
we were discussing
earlier like what why
do we exist what's the
structure what are
they getting for it you
know and and do they
align with with our you
know criteria for why
we exist right we're
i'm not saying we're
anti you know corporate
america but a lot of
ways we we are the
antithesis of of all
those giant companies and
we act as a hedge
against them so going and
getting a sponsor a
giant sponsor from the
companies we're trying
to sort of hedge against
can if not done right
could ruin the culture
of the organization
before whatever it
starts you know you
know ruben this is the
lesson about the linux
foundation is secretly
that you get all these
large corporations
that are paying three
hundred thousand
dollars for 18-month
memberships and there's
like 50 of them and
that run run the linux
foundation and it
just it just happens
and just just to give
some um feedback we
we have a whatsapp
group that's looking
into the accreditation
uh we have a bunch
of people trying to
get some university to
provide some some
credibility to it we have
others that um trying
to get things done
but i think i think one
way that we might want
to do is just iterate
and just have something
so we can have a
list of people that
pass a certain exam and
then iterate from there
to try and get uh the
more formal process
so we can we can go
out but i'm going to
post a link if anyone
wants to help out with
that part but i think
it's a more involved
discussion are we are
we not in the best
position to define what
accreditation looks
like and like just to go
to a university unless
they're like a stanford
or something like
that there's a whole
process to it nolan
it's it's way more
complicated than you would
think it is um but um
yeah but just saying
like you know handing
in handing out the
requirements over to
someone who maybe isn't
at the forefront of
agentic engineering
itself is potentially is
is risky i think there's
a there's enough
concepts that are being
defined in in you know
throughout this group
which are maybe you
know somewhere over
here on the highly highly
technical side some
are just sort of basic
you know what what
comes after vibe
coding well you know
specification writing
context engineering like
all this other stuff
so we're at i believe
we're in the best
position to sort of define
what that looks like
yeah that's sorry go
ahead sandy i was just
gonna say i mean and
we had a gentleman a
couple calls ago that
the whole reason he was
excited about joining
was because he was
tired of the red tape
within the bureaucratic
university system you
know like it you know
part of what's changing
is how we learn and
we have these old
systems and stuff um
i've been really just
swamped with owasp stuff
But, Rob, I'm going
to really commit to
really supporting the
agenda, you know, what
we're trying to do. So
I'll start joining the
meetings this week.
But, yeah, you
know, obviously
I have thoughts, too.
I think you're right,
Nolan. I've said this
numerous times. This
organization, this
crew here that Ruben
referred to earlier,
we're at the cutting
edge of thinking and
of executing and
doing in the agentic
industry. Yes, if
you go look inside of
OpenAI and of Google
and of Anthropic, they
have like PhD propeller
heads that are
probably – that are
even more advanced than
us. But out in the
real world, we're
the cutting edge here.
This is the bleeding
edge. I disagree
with that. i'll
fundamentally disagree
that they are really good
at building models
they are absolutely
prompting and building
systems yes like i
have seen and witnessed
this firsthand and
like they are you know
they are they're building
some of the best
models out there but
that is their focus
you go look at their
prompts you can go look
i mean claude's 24 000
like token system prompt
is one of the worst
prompts i've ever
seen but that's also
more efficient and more
powerful but like that
is not their focus
like prompt engineering
just by itself is
like a huge component
of where they are like
that entire industry
is failing to leverage
their own models for
the power that they
have but they're also
still stuck in this is
model was designed to
do this thing like
yeah silicon valley is
obsessed about models
i live in silicon
valley i live in the
center of the world of ai
and literally all of
my friends all they
want to do is talk
about model this model
release that model
release just it's model
model model that's all
they all they care about
this is essentially
context like context
engineering you know
everything around it's
it's it is context but
it's you know we we
are playing it in
the space in between
context and neural neural
network engineering
the the key difference
is we're gpu poor so
we've been forced to
work in this space that
says we have to use
the mo the minimal
viable access where
these guys in the valley
are like i got it i
got a i got a thousand
h100s i can i can point
at and and they're
they're they're rich
and comfortable where
i'm saying let's let's
use a cpu and distribute
many tiny little
neural networks and
hyper-optimized, nobody's
doing that because
those other guys don't
have to. They've got
abundance. They're
fat, happy, and slumpy.
Yeah, fat,
happy. Exactly.
But is that kind of
like in the startup
world where the
company I'm at,
Advanced Creative
Labs, we're part of
the Next Canada AI
cohort for 2025,
and I was sitting across
from a woman yesterday,
or two days ago rather,
who was sort of vetting
her, her, her ask.
And she only put that
she wanted $50,000
for marketing. And the
advice from the advisor
at, at, at, at Next
Canada was like,
you know, they're,
they're not, they're going
to look at that and
think that this is
a joke. You have to ask
for more, more money.
You have to ask for
$5 million for your,
for your marketing
budget. So while I
completely appreciate
and align to your
perspective, Reuven,
around the notion of being
GPU poor and doing
this on a CPU basis,
does that potentially,
is it the same
sort of parallel of
asking for $50,000 for
saying, you know,
we want $5 million?
Maybe. It's a
strategic partner that
could give us the GPUs
to get us into that
level of classification,
if you will.
Yeah, and that partner
we're having discussions
with, and we just
need to figure out
what it is we want to
be. It's hard to ask
for something when we're
not sure exactly what
we are or why we exist.
It seems to me that
knowing who we serve
is the first thing.
Are we getting this
technology into the
hands of ordinary
people so that ordinary
people can realize
their vision lacking
technical skills that
would have been required
earlier? Or are we
trying to hustle and
become big boys and
make a lot of money?
And I think Ruth
started off in the first
one. So there's a
critical distinction
to be made on the
mission that leads to
what the organizational
structure will
be, and then that
will lead naturally to
the path forward.
But I think those
three questions have
to be answered first.
Otherwise, we're just
going to balance all.
Should we get big
CPUs and GPUs, or are
we going to keep it
small with little CPUs?
Roof started with
smaller CPUs because he
didn't have the money
to get bigger ones.
Well, most of
the people in the
world are in
that situation.
So that's where I
think the power of
the organization
began and should go
forward. We need to
find our path and build
momentum going
forward on that path.
Yeah. 100% agree, man.
Well said. i think i
think the key here like
like let's be totally
honest if i wanted to
go make a lot of money
i'd go work in meta
or something i get a
job there but i would
hate my life i would be
unhappy and at my point
in life i you know i
might be altruistic
or whatever just crazy
i just i want to build
stuff that's interesting
exciting to me and
and i also think that
the the nature of of
um in that i might
sound like a socialist
saying it but the
nature and the nature of
capitalism is going to
change as this technology
takes over and there's
there's a we really
do need a hedge against
the sort of consolidation
of intelligence
you know to a small
group of you know large
very large tech companies
and governments and
the only way you you
you act as a hedge
against that is to have
something like what
we're trying to build to
be that hedge and that's
not you know that's
not the linux foundation
which is just a you
know a proxy for a
bunch of companies it's
something new and
different that hopefully
empowers average people
to do amazing things
yeah i i good core
principles of the for the
foundation rUv i love
it that's that's an
hour our mission statement
right all right guys
i i've got it i gotta
prep i gotta go to
the airport i'm i'm
taking off to uh nova
scotia um actually one
last thing i had a question
somebody reached to
me i reached over here
a couple weeks ago
about events in boston
i didn't get who it
was oh that that that
was yes there's a group
that i'm working out
uh out of boston they're
a consulting company
a bunch of x ey guys
that uh started an ai
company and they're
they're interested they
got they got some space
they're interested in
sponsoring um yeah i
can set that up and and
i think folks at mit
as well want to do
something yeah i know
folks at MIT they actually
meet at um like the
there is microsoft
office right next to
it called nerd yeah and
yeah okay so i know
these guys yeah so if you
need any help there
or something so when
you come when you're
coming back are you uh
but i'll be back on
the week of the 10th
of august yeah let's
just talk then like
once you okay great
next next week uh we
should keep these going
but someone else will
have to drive so um
we had uh we thought
jed could could step
up and and play the
room role how does
that work but how but
whose zoom account are
we using or do i need
to get out yeah we'll
give us i can i can
set yep i can just or
i can just uh organize
a zoom account and
make you the host or
something all right
sounds good so We'll
call next week office
hours for everybody.
Yeah.
And the benefit
of mine is we can
fit up to 250
people on these.
I bought the slightly
upgraded version.
We'll have an
amazing trip.
All right.
Thanks, everyone.
This was a really
useful conversation
today. And as
always, I really
appreciate all
the work all you
guys are doing. And
until next time.
Thank you, everyone.
All right.
Okay.
Talk to you soon. Thank
you. Safe travels.
Thanks.
Thank you.