Yeah, so I was attempting
to get this running.
So let's just show
you what it's supposed
to look like, but
I'm getting an error
and there's apparently
no documentation.
So it's basically,
I should try to vibe
code the result,
but I'm getting some
sort of no default
deployment found
error for the
supposed system.
So once you're logged in,
it basically
doesn't work.
Which is a shame
because it looks
promising, but now
we could try to debug
it. Let's see
what the heck this
is. So let's go
back here for a sec.
Well, for those that
aren't familiar,
there's a new project
that came out. But
like LangChan has a
tendency to half-***
their things. They're
like opposite of lana
index they they don't
necessarily do a
particularly good job
so for those who have
there's a few quirks
just even to get
it installed you
have to dissolve it
with legacy dependencies
which is weird
given it's a brand
new project like
who's going to use
legacy dependencies
and the installation
doesn't include any
real documentation
and how to you know
other than for
complete go to those
documents folders so
let's go there and see
what what the docs
folder looks like.
You aren't sharing
anything, actually.
Oh, let's try again.
Wait, I got to
stop sharing and re
-steer. I shared the
documentation as
well. In the chat,
the documentation
and the GitHub
repo, I shared it in
the... Oh, it's
built into the repo.
Let me try sharing
that again.
Hopefully this time
it works. Zoom, you're
letting me down today.
I couldn't get the
live broadcasting working
and it said it was
stream it was just
sharing but wasn't can
you guys see me now
yeah yeah all right all
right so in in the
folder here there there's
a there's a documentation
section um which
is totally completely
useless as far as i
can tell it just gives
you some you know
overview of like you
know architecture i think
they vibe coded the
whole **** thing Okay.
Now,
I think the
issue I'm running
into building
your own servers,
MCP server,
streamable HTTP.
Let's go here. Okay.
This is the part I
think I might be.
Why is it? Why can't? Oh,
it's an MPX. Okay. Okay,
we go here,
open is a first class
support for RAG,
open local host,
lane connect, set
up your local lane
connect, follow the
lane connect, read me.
They just need like
an install.sh, it just
does everything for
me, you know, so it's
the auth, I've set up
my auth, so this is
good. I've set up the
deploying agents I think
deploy your agents
and I think my problem
okay so here I'm gonna
I'm gonna go lazy all
right so once I get
this working hopefully
I'll get it working
and I'll just share
this for everyone to
get it looks it looks
actually pretty promising
now I'm gonna I'm
gonna use mine so I'm
gonna new terminal and
I'm going to go here
and I'm gonna install
I haven't given
up yet. I kind
of want to get
this to work.
You know, that post I
did last night, it's
got a whole ton of
views. So obviously
people are interested
in it. So if I figure
it out, then I'll
just share. If it
doesn't work, then
we'll be together in the
fact that it doesn't
work. All right.
So I'm just going to
click around and get
Roo, if you ask Roo
to find that, it
will find the modes.
If you just say
it in the chat to
find the new modes
in at Roo modes,
it will find it.
I just got to
click around a
little bit. Oh,
it goes in again.
Yeah. All right. So, help
me fix the
following error.
Review at docs.
I think it's
the docs folder.
Yeah, it's
probably set up.
and let me know
what I'm missing.
Looks like it might
be the MCP server.
All right, so back
to what, so I, you
didn't see it, but I
basically got, before
this, I was able to
get the login screen
working. I set up a
Supabase instance,
and I created a
user in my Supabase
instance by going into
Supabase and
generating a new user.
And then once I
logged in, I'm
basically getting
this error,
but no default
deployment found.
And I'm sure it's
one of these.
I'm not sure which
one it is. It
might be the RAG
server, possibly.
I signed up for a LANG.
I'm not sure if
it was LANGChain.
It's almost source
retrieval service.
It could be this.
I don't think
I set this up.
Next RAG app.
Lane Connect.
What's it decided
to do here?
So let's create a new
video with the next.
Of course it wants
to show an EMV.
This wouldn't be a
live coding session.
It didn't include
some kind of
environmental variable
I really want it to
show. I'm not even
sure what the heck
it's even doing.
Create new with the
acquire next public
deployment variable.
Okay.
I'm gonna, I guess
I'll save that.
Not really sure what
that exactly is doing.
restart the application
but it didn't include any
other any other variables
it's been simply
created all right
let's see what what that
I don't think
that's going to
solve the problem
but we'll see
employment found
Run the stack.
I think I'm getting
that same error missing.
It's not how you run it.
I was running dev.
I can only run it
in the subfolder.
That could be my problem.
Unless I'm
running dev. Yeah,
I was getting
the same error.
They certainly half-assed
this particular platform.
I'm not going to lie.
There's another
project that
I was working
on yesterday.
Let me show
you that while
I'm on. That was
kind of cool.
Similar idea. This is
like a genetic AI system.
This I was able to
get running in a few
minutes. I'm going
to let that bake a
little bit while it
figures itself out.
And I'm going to
show you the other
one, which
actually does work.
And maybe we'll
modify that instead.
All right. So
I'm going to
connect to my code space.
You know, I'll
also show you guys,
I've been modifying
the Rue core system
to do some agentic
stuff. I'll show
you that too when
I get a chance
here. Let me show
you that one first.
All right.
Connect.
It takes a second.
For whatever
reason, when I
share my screen, it
doesn't necessarily
work right away.
Something to do
with screen sharing
and Zoom slows
down VS code.
All right. Connect.
Let's try that again.
Do I have too many
things open? It's
like this is one
of those days
where nothing seems
to want to work.
The problem is I've
been mucking around
with the internal
workings of the VS Code
system and I probably
broke something.
All right, I'm going
to load Auto Analyst.
This is a cool little
project actually.
So let's go
back to this and
I'll show you
Auto Analyst.
While that loads, I'm
going to jump back
to the other one and
see if it's fixed it.
It's installing some
****, it would seem.
All right, it's
still figuring
itself out.
We'll go back.
So Auto Analyst is a
project. It's not fully
cooked either, but
it's kind of a cool
starting point for anyone
looking at the Vibe
code, a web-based agent
system. They've done
a pretty nice little
job. What I like about
this in particular,
if it ever loads, it
includes a canvas for
doing embedded code
editing and automated
code development. They
did a really nice
little job on the UI. So
you can kind of
bootstrap your own little
lovable style project
with it, which is cool.
And specifically,
it'll do the
data analysis
-related tooling.
Everything's moving
slow for some reason.
I'm just watching things
load at the moment.
And while I'm
doing this, I have
two other client
projects running
as well just to
make to push this.
I think I need to
get a new computer
with like 256 gigs
of RAM or something.
All right.
So are we loaded?
Come on, terminal.
You can do it.
Here we go.
All right. So I
don't remember. I
think that let's
just assume the npm
run dev is the
command it usually is.
This already works.
I've got to
work at least.
It worked yesterday.
We'll see if
it works today.
Done
yet?
Yeah, it looks like
this is running.
I'll come back to
that in a minute.
Oh, now what's going on?
Ah, of course.
Auto.
Analyst. front end.
And this one I
think if I remember
correctly has a
back end as well.
So let's run that
independently.
So we'll go into auto
analyst back end,
which I think
is a fast API.
I'm going to just
go lazy on that.
I'm going to get
rude to run that
because I can't be
bothered to figure
out what the
command is. I'll go
into my DevOps, run
the auto analyst
I'm running two
different things at the
same time all right
so this apparently you
need to run it using
yarn so it would
appear I'm gonna kill
that for a moment
because it's not and
I'm gonna go here cancel
that and I'm gonna
run it which folders
it looks like it's
running in the main
If this is confusing,
I'm literally
doing two different
projects at
the same time
just to multitask.
All right, so I'm
going to go and I'm
going to see if this
fixes the problem.
Oh, I actually
killed the other
one. I'm going
to go back.
I can tell it's
going to be an
issue, so I'm
going to kill this.
That's not right.
One of my million things
are running somewhere.
This is running.
I just want the
command to run it.
That's my problem
with port 3000.
I'm running two different
projects at the same
time and they're
getting conflicts
on both.
Let's refresh this.
Now that's one of
the challenges of
trying to run
different projects
at the same time. You'll
run none by
trying to run two.
It's using Next.js.
The problem with
Next.js is it has a
tendency to have
to compile, which I
don't like about
Next. Oh, here we go.
It compiled.
Now, I don't have
the back end running.
Go to chat.
So,
you notice that
it compiles.
Now, there's a way to
do fast compilation,
but they didn't
enable it to this
project. So I could
build it, I suppose.
But this is the
problem with Next.js.
All right. I'm just,
yeah, it looks like
that's running. Looks
like that's good.
All right. Hurry up.
Compiled. Perfect.
First time you run
something, it's always a
little slow. All right.
I got it working,
I think. All right. So
this is not the project
that I was originally
going to show you
but this works so we'll
go with what works
this is a new project
from the guys at fire
what the heck they call
themselves firebird
or something uh i don't
even know what the
name of their company
is i'm sure it's in
here somewhere but it
was reached yesterday
and what this does is
allows you to uh basically
do sort of agentic
visualizations and
it's pretty cool they
they've uh they've got
a bunch of code
implementation so you know
it'll do sort of lovable
style code, so now
I'll click this button,
which apparently
doesn't work at the
moment for some reason,
and preview default,
why doesn't that work?
Let's go to this one.
I'm not having
any luck today,
nothing seems to
want to work for me.
All right, let's
try this one,
let's see what
errors we're getting.
Nothing major.
Well, I guess
there's this.
it's amazing that
someone released
a brand new project with
this many errors
in the console
maybe I'm weird but
yeah it looks like
we're not getting
a network error it's
not picking up the
chat I don't think
it's going to work
it works on my machine
you're creating
a new chat
how did you get the
How do you get the
middleware working?
No, I mean the comment.
The actual
developer saying.
It's a Docker joke. It's
a Docker container joke.
You should be
running the container
instead of
trying to do all
this local is
what he's saying.
I want to modify
it though.
To be honest, this worked
just fine yesterday.
Looks like the
environment is mostly
Okay,
so let's just kill that.
Maybe it's running here.
So one more.
I'm going to go
here, and I'm
going to run
this like this.
And we'll see if we can
get it running directly.
This is a new, I'm
not sure what this
error is, it doesn't
look major, mind you.
So what I'm going to
do is I'm just going
to make sure that
the FastAPI works.
All right, looks
like that's
working, so I'm
going to go docs.
All right, that looks
like that works as well.
Give it a,
oh, it worked that time.
You can see the quirks
of these systems, right?
And, okay, so this is
a cool little system,
right? So this is their,
this is their little
data set that they're
giving you is it looks
like they're loading
some sort of preview,
you know, read
housing information or
something. I can, I can
click the auto generate
option if I want to
create a different housing
data, which is cool
for, for testing
different, you know,
concepts in this case, I
probably shouldn't have
done that since I had it
working, but let's see
what, what happens.
Let's go back here. I'm
going to have a second.
I'm going to have a
sec. So what appears
to be the issue was
the middleware needs
to run directly.
So I'm going to run
this right here.
I'm going to use the
default data set.
And I'm going to say
create a hello world
chart using the data.
All right.
Analyzing. Okay.
We're cooking now.
All right. So it's
processing the data.
It's a little
analytical planner.
It's creating a
visualization.
and you can view that
in the canvas looks
cool now we'll now the
visualization plays
a simple something or
other now i don't know
why it didn't run so
i'm going to run it
create the chart
hello world perfect
it's working auto
run i don't think
the auto run worked
but whatever.
Let's go back and create
a detailed analysis.
Now, what's cool about
this auto analyst
system, by the way,
they've already built in
payment system. So if
you're looking to like
bootstrap a startup
or something, you've
got a payment component
right here. So you
see that there is a
get more credits. Now
you can just, you know,
I'm logged into my
own. I can just
arbitrary to give myself
those credits. Oh, it
looks like it built the
visualization. Let's
check out what the
settings look like. I
can change the models.
I've got different
models and different
prices. So if you're
looking to like bootstrap
your own lovable
style service, this is
going to give you a
nice running start,
which is the theme of
my live coding today.
A lot of people
are like, want to
bootstrap some kind
of you know um bi
-coding or no code low
code sort of thing
what you don't want
to do is build it
from scratch you want
to give it something
to give it a running
start this sort
of thing is a perfect
way to do it so
in this case let's
choose a 03 mini and
with advanced options
temperature again
let's crank that
down save settings
failed update settings
there's some there's
definitely some
quirks in this system
let's go and see what
the heck is going on.
This is a minor
webpack compilation. I
don't know why they
would have released
something with
such a minor error,
but I guess maybe
they bi-coded it too.
But regardless, easy
to fix. So it looks
like the save doesn't
actually work.
That's weird. Let's look
at their payment system.
That doesn't,
okay, looks like
that goes to a
payment page.
How model credits
work. So yeah, they
got a credit
system. Now, some of
the things aren't
quite fully baked,
it would appear,
but that's okay.
Let's go, let's
see if we can muck
around with this
one a little bit.
Let's go back
here for a moment.
And I'm gonna
close this now
that we get that running.
I hope that made
sense, because there's
two parts you have
to get this running.
I mean, yes, I
could have used the
Docker version, but
who wants to do that?
Now there's a
backend and there's
a frontend. You
have to run both
independently
of one another.
So that's what I
did here. You have
to add your keys to
the environmental
variables. You'll
see, so you'll
rename the
environmental variables
file, the env, which
I did previously,
and the env here,
which I did as well.
And then that, and
there's a, I guess
there's a terraform. I
didn't bother looking
at that and some
docs. Now, what I'm
going to do is I'm
going to, let's update,
update the,
update, what was
that page called?
Pricing, the
pricing page,
which is
probably pricing,
yeah, pricing,
analyst app, where
would that be?
Page pricing, I guess.
It's, note to self,
bad idea to call
everything page.
It's just, why bother
calling, why naming
the folder and create
the name of the
actual file page and
everything's named
page? It's just stupid.
Call your page pricing,
not the folder,
and it's just a bad
way to name it, but
that's apparently
what these guys did.
I'm not, I think
these guys vibe
-coded this or, you
know, just throwing
it out there.
Not that that's a
problem. We're vibe
-coding ourselves.
Up to the pricing
page. Make the page,
or update the
content to be focused
on, let's call it
Vibe Data Explorer.
Explorer.
And I'm going to
switch from DevOps to,
I'm going to use the
autocoder mode here.
And let's see
what happens.
While that's
happening, I'm going
to jump to my
other project and
see what the heck's
going on here.
This one apparently
is running.
I'm going to restart
that for a moment.
In port 3000, again, it's
probably going
to be conflict.
So you notice it
auto selects. So this
other one I'm running,
this auto analyst
is also running in
port 3000. and so it
auto-selected port
3001. I'm trying to run
two different Next
.js apps at the same
time and in the same
demo. So, you know,
so again, what
you're seeing here,
this sort of slow
initial load is the
by-product of dev
mode on Next.js.
And to be honest, that's
why I hate Next.js.
I don't understand
why it has to
do a compile
every time. Like
who needs to
compile this stuff?
But, oh, yeah, it's
still giving me an error.
I'm not going to
worry about this error
right now. Let's focus
on auto analysts.
That's more interesting
anyway. And it works.
All right, the pricing
content in auto
X3 file has been
unsuccessfully updated.
We'll check here.
We're getting some
model errors, which
is interesting.
And, oh,
the reason it
wasn't saving
earlier is because
I didn't allow
it to use a
different model.
Just a poor, a poor
user experience.
It wants to
edit this file.
Okay. Let's go back here.
I don't, I don't
know what it changed.
Choose the, this
doesn't look like
it changed anything
in particular.
I should have been
paying closer attention.
Update the page
to include a
Vibe Dev Overview
at the top.
I
assume the page called
Pricing is the page
that the pricing is
on, but it might not be
the right assumption.
Who knows? We'll see
here in a sec if that
is the correct page.
Discover the Power of
Vibe Explorer, yeah,
it's not, it doesn't
seem to be updating,
which is a bad
sign, let's go here,
oh, I was in
the wrong one,
okay, fast refresh,
has to form a
full reload,
looks like there
was an error,
yeah,
all right, hi, bro,
At least I'm writing
the right file.
Where's the error here?
It's probably like an
extra quote or something.
Broke it worse.
So what you're seeing
here is the error I put.
Unexpected div. Yeah,
this made it even worse.
All right. I'm
going to cancel this
for a sec. Oh,
let's see. The issue
arises from the
incorrect placement.
I'm just seeing
if I can make
this into something
more useful.
Oh, yeah.
It's struggling with
this. Look at this.
It's made it. Just
broke the **** of it.
I'm going to cancel
this for a sec.
Yeah.
Let's go back. Boom,
boom, boom, boom.
Update the things.
Let's go here.
Restore.
Oh, no, that's
broken too.
Well,
you do notice that
this button right
here to restore
is pretty useful.
Sometimes it's
easier just to go
back to what was
previously working.
Try again without
the errors.
Yeah,
again, I don't
know. Is anyone the
call actually a
fan of Next.js?
Maybe I'm missing
something.
I kind of hate Next
.js. If someone loves
it, speak up because
what am I missing about
Next.js that makes
people want to use it?
It's not the
best runtime.
I think the Second
time is a charm.
Let's go back.
Here we go. Discover the
power of Vibe
Coding Explorer.
Okay, so you're
getting the
idea. What I'm
doing is I'm kind
of making this
my own, right?
And this is how you
build your own service,
right? And then I'd
probably integrate. Let's
see what happens when
I try to subscribe.
I don't think
I've got any
payment system in place.
Nothing happens.
Admin123, I think
is the password.
That doesn't work.
Let's go back.
It logged me out.
Minimal viable.
Apparently all
you need to do
is crank out the
most minimal
viable thing here.
What's going
on here? Okay.
Oops. I didn't want that.
Go to chat.
Alright, let's
just change the
auto analysts
let's go back here
the the welcome page
and uh auto analysts
in the sticky
header to vibe data
by data i don't
do that let
me pause for a sec
uh any questions
i literally took
a chat here any
questions for you
guys anything you guys
uh want to cover or
anything you want
to look at i'm
fool around here do
you hear i made a good
point like um you know
when we when there is
ai generated product
um there's a risk that
is going to be bad
in all sorts of ways
it'd be interesting to
come up with a checklist
of um things things
to look for that you
know that just because
it's a big thing it
doesn't mean that it's
any any good like at
least on github you
can tell whether it's
had updates it's not
just somebody this is
this is github this is
100 github so i cloned
the git this is what
i cloned from github
so no i'm looking at
another how about
looking at github didn't
tell me anything about
the quality it just
told me that it was i
can just clone it right
this is what you need
to look at see all
these errors so this
this is a pretty there's
a whole list of things
right does it have
cds does it have errors
on the front end does
it have errors in the
back And, you know,
did it use a
****** framework?
It'd be cool to have
something you could
just point at the Git
repo and go, okay,
tell me, is this
code quality good or
****, right? Maybe
that's ChatGPT now.
It is now. And that
was a new feature that
just came out, right,
that came out last
week. And that's exactly
what you should do.
So in this deep research
option, you can go
here. And what the
heck is that? What did
I call this repo? I
don't even remember. I
got to go back here
for a moment. But I can
tell you immediately
I hate Next.js for all
the reasons you guys
are seeing at the moment
But this is auto. I
guess I I called it
I guess it's the auto
analysts. I don't
think I cloned
that unfortunately
We'll see so it
probably won't show up
because it's not my
my repo, but we can
go here. Let's see
if it finds it auto
Now the problem with
with this feature, oh,
it does show up perfect.
Okay. Oh, that's
auto browser that's
a different thing I
created. No, it doesn't
show up. So the problem
with this feature is
it only does public
repos. So if you're
using this for your data,
it's not going to
work on anything other
than the things that
you share publicly. So
if you're doing something
privately, like any
customer facing
application, it's not going
to work. And two, it
doesn't work on other
people's repos. So if
I want to point this
towards the auto analyst
repo and say, tell
me about that, doesn't
work either so in
terms of functionality
it's somewhat limited
now if i want to go
took a look at my auto
survey ai that i built
last year i don't
remember building it
but i'm sure it was one
random day tell me
about the uh you know
framework and basically
it'll run the um deep
analysis against that
so it's could you please
tell me i don't know
tell me everything
now this will
take a while to
run now what i
could do here now
this this is this
is interesting
because i you know
it's it's got different
capabilities that i
like now i could say i'm
cancel this for a moment
and i'm going to go
back here for a moment
and say can i convert
this to vjs all right
why doesn't that
button work i i swear
nothing's working for me
today it's like it's
like a combination of
i accidentally discovered
this i this this
feature of the actions
in github where
it does when you when
you push something
in so i i created
branching strategy and i
push you security
custom workflows to see
front and back and
it does the checks
right every time the
code is pushed out i
guess someone raised
the question how do you
ensure that you know
all of the checks
and balances have been
performed maybe that's
a good practice to
follow or build it
in the prompt so every
time it automatically
does a git push it
will run the test
and basically the
within within in GitHub.
What? Well, we don't
run, like, as a
GitHub action? Is that
what you're suggesting?
Yeah, GitHub action.
So, I have this
thing. Yeah, I
mean, I can show you
what I mean, if I can
look at my project.
You can run those actions
locally, which
would probably be
easier than
running remotely.
Right? The problem
with remote
is you have to do a push.
Now, that looks like
I crashed the entire,
my entire code space,
so I don't know what's
going on with that.
But this is like the
day of nothing seems
to want to work for me.
All right, let's go back.
Sorry, did you want
to show something?
No, I'm just trying to
look at it. I'll show
you. I'm just unable
to. I did a few things
this week. So it's
one of those reports.
Once I find it,
I'll show you.
Okay.
Yeah, so I'm trying to
reload this whole thing.
I think I crashed
the, I don't
know why I'm having
so much trouble
at the moment,
but but apparently
I crashed the
entire code space.
That's what's going
on with the other one.
Now I shut that down.
All right, so, so far
the lane chain open
is gets a thumbs down.
I, unless
someone else was
able to get it working,
I'm having no luck.
The thing, the thing
doesn't work. I'm
sure I could get
it working, but I
like who's got
time to spend hours
trying to debug
someone else's garbage.
And the fact that it's
on Node.js doesn't
help the, or sorry next
.js doesn't help the
cause so good question
do you find yourself
now that there's so many
mcp servers out that
you even need any agent
framework like crew
ai or lane chain or pick
your poison of choice
because you can kind
of do that all with
an mcp well mcps are
don't handle orchestration
particularly well
right you could
hypothetically but there
it's it's unidirectional
so once you create a
request it waits for a
response so it's not
optimal for orchestration
of agents right it's
it's great for the
request of data and a
response and that in
that request could be
a multi-step agent at
the end of the mcp
request but you know that
could be a you know a
really long wait time
especially if you're
doing like deep research
i mean you can have
service side events and
you know a2a is also
works with mcp so well
you have to i haven't
seen any to orchestrate
agents that dramatically
right yeah like
lang graph is overkill
i think you've mentioned
that before yeah
well i i think what i
just showed you in
lang graph is is really
all you need to know
um let me show you what
i've been mucking
around with exactly what
you said within the
structure of rue itself to
modify it so i'm going
to show you how to
modify rue which just
to a guy's point here.
So I'm running
in dev mode, I
hit F5. So I
cloned the Roo repo
and I've created a
new set, a system
within Roo. I called
it, what'd I call it?
Inbox or something
like that, and tasks.
And what we're gonna
see here in a moment,
if it, once it loads,
all right, takes a
second. Hopefully,
okay, we're loading,
we're building.
and okay, takes a
second to build it. So
this is what I'm doing
is I'm doing a modified
version of Roo
specifically to integrate
things like A2A and
asynchronous tasking,
right? So when you use
Roo currently, it's
a synchronous based
system, right? It
means it does each
step and then waits for
response. And that's
great and all, but I'd
rather do a sort of
more asynchronous
approach, right so i can
do threads and concurrency
so i i've created
i'm going to add a
new tab here which
eventually this should
load and then that
should uh give give us
the option oh is it
right here uh no this
isn't it i don't want
that all right i guess
it's not going to
show for some reason.
Developer start
demo. Okay. Let's run
this. You said that
starts automatically.
So we'll see.
Nope.
That's not.
All right. Today
is not. Okay.
Nothing seems to
want to work for me
today. Let's try
it one more time.
Oh, second
time's the charm.
I bet you have an
OS patch coming.
Yeah.
You ever have one of
those days where nothing
seems i want to work
like today seems to
seems to be that day
for me i couldn't get
the the live stream
to work and so i guess
everyone on linkedin is
gonna be ****** about
that and i i uh you
know half the you know
the the things i've
tried i've been broken
this is all magic so
you're just running low
on mana exactly i actually
i've been speaking
of i i'm i got a uh
beginner's uh guide
to uh dungeons and
dragons for the kids at
the cottage this weekend
so uh let's see if
i can convert them to
be 90s style geeks i
would just have to watch
stranger things before
you do that yeah yeah
you know what i'm
gonna do i i've got a
whole plan i think what
i'm gonna do is i'm
gonna i'm gonna disable
the internet and pretend
like the internet's
broken because we're
in the country it's
like i don't know guys
the internet doesn't
work we're gonna have
to play board games
and they'll be forced
to hang out with
me at that point
because the internet
does go down frequently
at the cottage.
So that's my,
I'm just going
to manually
make it break.
All right, so this
takes a second
to build. So what
you're looking
at here is the
dev instance,
which again, it's
taken a while to build
because everything's
slow apparently.
It's building.
These don't look like
any major errors.
Okay, here we go.
So we go here
and now you see
here there's a
new inbox option.
So this is my dev
version, so I
click inbox.
So I called it
agentic inbox.
So this is a modified
version of Rue
code that I made
specifically to sort
of allow for
concurrent execution,
task hierarchy,
concurrent
context awareness,
progress monitoring
and other sort
of things. Then
we can go and I
did it sort of as
a Slack style UI.
So we can go in here
and I can modify that.
We can call it number
one or whatever,
you know, test. I
can create priorities
for how it executes,
high, low priorities.
I can define the
state completed
or whatever in
different modes.
I can create
tasks, step one.
And then I can, so
sequential would be the
typical way it works,
but now I've added
the opportunity to use
things like parallel
processing,
concurrent swarm-based
approaches. And this
was inspired, I think,
by Chris last week.
He's like, I created a
swarm system. Like,
well, he's got a good
idea. What if we could
update the actual
system to actually
be a swarm? So this
will allow you to do
that. And you can create
task dependencies
based on that swarm.
And then I create some
advanced options for
how long you need
it to run, you know,
like a recurrence policy,
like maybe it needs
to run every day or
week and stuff like
that. um i can enable
reminders i can i
can let it run for
extended periods like
let's say i want to run
all night and i want
it and sometimes i
have my processes stop
at two o'clock in
the morning which is
kind of bothers me a
little bit because i'm
sleeping and it could
have been running all
night but i didn't
have it uh you know i
wasn't awake to fix
it so this would allow
for to say well it
hasn't ran long enough
so i can say run for
for x amount of time
i i these are short
because I need to test
it. So I haven't
actually had it run for
12 hours, but I could
obviously set the
time to be more than
12 hours or whatever.
So then I can update
the task. We can
see the task here now
has relabeled number
one and, or I can
create it. I can go
in here and create
a new task either by
clicking this button,
same general idea,
or I can go
back and do the
same thing on
the UI, either
here or here,
get some filters.
I'm going to
add a new task.
We'll call it Swarm,
Swarm test, test.
We'll make this Swarm,
that looks good,
great task. We'll
see Swarm shows
up. Now we have
different options
available here. We see
that I've got the
option here to,
for completed tasks
or archive tasks.
Now it's executing
those. I have different
options here for
quick keys because
I'm lazy and I
don't want to type
things. I'll just
use my Alt plus keys.
I've got each of
these so we can
see the different
options available.
Active tasks, I can
set it. Now I've
got it auto executing
at the moment,
but we can define
different settings.
I haven't rendered
all the text yet.
I've got to work on
the rendering. This is
a work in progress.
I'm not going to lie.
But basically what
I've created is I've
modified Roo to be a
legitimate agentic system,
which is, and you
can see the costs and
I can get different
options available.
So, but basically
all I did to make
all what you're
looking at is I went
into this, I cloned
the core Roo system
and then I made
some modifications.
So you see here
that I've got in the
components folder,
I've got an inbox.
And so all the, this
is basically what
makes it all work.
You know, I've got my
plans. So you can
see, I started with a
persistence. The
persistence basically says,
how do I, you know,
understand what's
happening and save that
information. Then I
went and implemented
my sidebar updates,
which is basically
the nav components you
saw and created an
implementation plan.
And then I'm
working on the play
button, which makes
it basically run.
That's kind of where
I am right now.
But basically I created
my own version. Now,
if I want to take
this a step further,
I'm not going to do
this, but I could rebrand
this whole entire
thing to be, you know,
a, you know, RUV style
plugin if I wanted
to, but I still have
all the original
functionality. I can
close this. Now, if I want
to go back to the
original functionality
system, I can click new.
And this is essentially
the original sort
of system for using
RUV. But you can modify
Roo on the most core
level if you do it
this way. You can sync
it with the original
project. So if I want
to go in because I
created a separate
element, all I need to
do is initialize the
repository and get it
working. This is actually
the dev environment,
but let's go here.
This is the
actual part. So
you can see
all my changes.
There's an agentic
inbox branch.
Yeah, that's how
you modify Roo.
So I made this
available on my GitHub
for those that
are interested.
You can go to,
oh, looks like my
research is done here.
Let's go here
to GitHub slash
Roov. I guess Roov code.
You know the funny
thing about the Roo
code is a lot of my
friends call me Roo.
So, it's like
unknowingly calling
the thing after
me. But anyway.
Yeah. So, this is what
I did. So, basically,
you see here, I got
a couple branches.
So,
actually, I
included all the
branches, which is
a little confusing.
I think I called
it Ingentic Inbox.
Yeah. Here it is.
Ingentic Inbox.
Okay. and the guy
that created Ruko is
mRubens which is
also related somewhat
to Ruben I guess
anyway here you go this
is it if you want
to try it you can
literally just take
this branch and see
how I did it go into
the web view folder
now when you fork the Rue
system the
important part here
once you get it up
and running hit F5
So, the F5
command basically
runs this mode
right here,
the debugger, and
that'll automatically
instantiate the new
VS Code window that
I was just showing
you a moment ago.
And this window, you'll
see it says extension
development host, RUV
code test, and that's
how you get everything
working. You can
change it. You can,
again, you can create,
you can create, you
know, new, new scenes or
new sections. In this
case, I created a new
button here, but yeah,
you can do whatever
you want or just fork
the whole thing and
create your own new
extension if you want to.
So I think half
of vibe coding is
basically taking
someone else's
work and sort of
running with it.
All right. We've got
a few minutes left.
Anything you guys want to
cover, look at, discuss?
Well, on taking
someone else's work, I
think the LangChain
post you were referring
to, the OpenAgent
platform, is working in the
public demo, not from
GitHub. I believe
the GitHub is a
template. I made the joke
earlier about working
on my machine, and I was
like, well, why would
they post it if it
doesn't work? So I went
back to the LinkedIn
post, and I looked up
at the top. if you go to
the public demo link
and use Google. Yeah,
the problem with the
public demo link is,
like, who cares if they
can get it working?
If nobody else can,
what's the point?
Well, yeah.
It says, or fork and
customize it yourself.
Yeah, well, so I
forked it. And,
you know, here's
as far as I've
gotten in the
customization.
Yeah, right.
Right. Again, to
me, if it takes me
more than about 15
minutes, I'm done.
It doesn't work.
Now, could I get it
working? 100% I could
get this working. I
just don't want to
spend three hours
fixing their problems.
What they probably
needed to do is just
create a shell script
or a Docker file that
just basically made it
work, which apparently
they didn't do. Or
maybe I didn't find.
so you know i'm i'm
pretty competent so if
i'm struggling with
this i don't know some
of the it's i'm
someone smarter than me
is going to have to
you know figure it out
well or spend more
time on it well that
link works that i've
put into that works
yeah you know that
that's what i did the
video of yesterday
and i i mistakenly i
mistakenly thought that
that would just work
right so uh let's let's
take a look at your
looks you're talking
about this one yeah
all right yeah
this this is what i
tried yesterday
when i when i logged
in now let's look
at the console
the registration
isn't working
though i had
to do the i had
to sign it and
use google off
yeah the registration
the registration
didn't work work locally
for me by the way
I was able to
actually get
the registration working.
The problem was one step
after the registration.
All right. So you
got the Supabase.
They're just
using Supabase.
There we go. I'm in.
No.
All right.
It wasn't.
Looks like it's
just mock data.
All right.
Let's close that
for a moment.
Close my one.
I'm not sure why that's
not working. Just
added my things that
don't work today.
I'm going to refresh
that just quickly
because that thing
is bugging me.
All right.
So, hypothetically, this
is what should work.
I'm probably just
not running something
that is obvious
to them but not
obvious to anyone
else other than them.
yeah this is like
it's not it's
like hypothetically
it looks good
yeah so i asked to
connect to my calendar
and it brought up
authentication oh don't
given given the
quality of this thing
which is minimal i
wouldn't i wouldn't
suggest that yeah
yeah it looks this
looks like it was
vibed pretty quick
i i think out of the
options i've seen
currently the better
the better option i
i kind of like the
auto analyst better
fire crawl you were
referring to that
company uh no it's
some other company i've
never heard of fire
or something or other
fire fire eagle or
firebird or something
these guys don't even
promote themselves yeah
i'm not really sure
it looks like i looks
like it's not i'm
running anyway well
well that that is that
i think it's sorry
guys today was the day
of like basically
nothing working i don't
know i yeah mana is
low uh if you if you
believe in that i
don't know why why i've
had so much trouble
today but some Some days
things just don't
want to work, I guess.
So out of the two
projects, I'd say auto
analysts gets a sort
of thumb sideways.
I think they
lost some aura
because of their
use of Next.js.
Now, if someone wants
to convert that to
a decent platform
like Deno or VJS, then
that should be probably
done. I'd say for
me, if the platform
is built in Next.js,
I don't know.
I'm just not a big fan.
And if someone
gets that LaneChain
project working,
let me know.
I would be
interested to see
what you did to
get it working.
I'm not going to spend
any more time on it.
It's just nothing
that's particularly
something I want to
spend any cycles on. But
it looks promising,
just not fully baked.
all right now i'm
also going to have to
explore what the heck's
wrong with with zoom
i bet you when i try
zoom here in a minute
again it'll it'll uh
it'll work just fine
it's it's just just
a part of the day i
gotta go guys i get
another call i thanks for
thanks for everyone
who tuned in i i again
i i have no idea if
this is uh useful or
not um matt is that is
is what what kind of
guitar you got back
there that's a gretch
gretch oh yeah you're
like buddy holly or
i get the buddy my
glasses yeah yeah yeah
man yeah so gretchen
acoustic right there
so what's what's the
what's the acoustic uh
takamine takamine oh
takamine that's a good
guitar yeah yeah i like
takamines yeah nice
all right we'll
have to have a jam
session next time
oh absolutely man
let's do it let's
do it All right.
Thanks, everyone.
For those who are
interested, we do AI
Hackerspace Live on
Fridays. Hopefully,
I get my live session
working by then.
All right. I'll see you
tomorrow or next week.
Thanks, everyone.
Bye.