we're good um here we
are i'm not we're not
doing an ai hacker
space this week and this
is a special edition
of the live vibe uh
coding here from Lake Huron
in Ontario so uh
you'll see the sort
of casual surroundings
and a really crappy
screen so hopefully you
guys don't spend too
much time looking at me
but we're looking at
what we're actually
going to be broadcasting
so first of all I want
to do a big thank you
to Jed and Ocean and
Braun and Rob and
Shep and who else? Who
am I forgetting here
who's been helping with
the ruv-swarm? But
we've been busy hacking
away on this thing
over the last few days.
And it's been
tremendous, to be honest.
The results are
almost unbelievable in
terms of capability,
performance and
benchmark. They're
actually so incredible
that I've been
reluctant to share them
because I think people
are all going to
say these have been
hallucinated because
they seem beyond what
is even possible.
Ocean, you've been
working on the
GPU-related work. What
are your thoughts?
Are we hallucinating
these or
do you think there's
some plausible?
I think this is super
awesome. that we're
working on uh it's
beyond plausible i
think we're just finding
out how to use it
yeah it's, it's, I think
I think you're right
and I saw I know
i'm not sure Bron is
was able to join us
today but I saw Bron
last night uh did what
he put 50,000 agents
in what was like 10-seconds
20 seconds something
like that it was uh
you know so what we're
using for you know
i'll try to explain
as simply as I can i'm
going to share my
screen and get i'm going
to get going and we
built initially a
framework in rust and
then we compiled that
that framework into
uh web assembly wasms
so what that means
is we can run these
really highly optimized
binaries in in a
server side or client
side and we can create
You know, using
relatively low resources,
CPUs, we can create
custom neural
nets that work
explicitly and are built
explicitly for a
given either swarm
or agent. And they're
built on the fly
based on whatever
you need them to do.
So, and I'm going
to mute you guys
just to make sure.
One sec, guys.
Participants. Sorry
about that. this, this
one, if you, if you
guys want to add, just
let me know and we'll,
I'll, you can unmute
yourself. All right.
So, so this is, so let
me, let me explain the
process. So first thing
I did about a week ago
was, you know, created
this idea of the, the
roof fan, which is
basically I ported the
fast artificial neural
network library from
C to Rust. Once I
had that, that opened
up a whole variety of
options for me because
I had now the ability
to create any kind of
neural network I want
on demand and with
low resources. And the
results of that were
particularly astounding.
I went from a 500
megabyte binary to like
a five megabyte binary
and the performance
went up orders of
magnitude. Then what I
did is I created using
the original, I created
something called
neurodivergent, which
allows me to create
advanced forecasting
algorithms. You can
use it for like stock
trading or whatever
you whatever things you
need to sort of hyper
optimize for time
series data or orchestration
or orchestration
of swarms and that
includes various types
of models you know
basic recurrent advanced
transformer and other
specialized and you
can even invent your
own models that never
been tried before so
you can create you
know here's a neural
forecasting you know
this is what's involved
in creating that
little bit of code and
and again the the clod
code system can use
this stuff really,
really effectively.
So for example, this,
this would have been
the neural forecasting
library before, this
is how you do it in
Rust. And it's just
faster, more effective.
So lots of
different use cases
there. Once,
once I had that
in place, I
started exploring,
well, can I apply those
previous two libraries
to be, to do a sort
of next generation
multi-forming system,
sort of taking what I
had done previously in
the Claude Flow system,
but making it sort of
supercharged using,
again, a kind of
neural network that
underpins the orchestration,
collaboration, and
all the various
capabilities. And what I saw
in my benchmarks, I ran
over and over again,
was incredible. The
initial benchmarks,
I was seeing an 84%
benchmark in terms of
the capabilities of
the system in terms of
SWE Bench. Currently,
the top benchmarks that
we're seeing are around
70%. Maybe I think
I saw one for 72%. So
we're in the realm of
both 13 to 15 points
jump in capability in
terms of this. But I'm
not just seeing that
in terms of the actual
benchmark itself.
I'm seeing reduction
of the amount of tokens
required, which is
direct related to the
cost of operating these
systems by 32%. And
I did some more recent
tests where I was able
to get that even
higher. I just haven't
published that yet.
And I saw the speed of
these systems because
I'm using Wasm. I can
run these things in CPUs
and GPUs distributed
around the globe.
And I'm seeing just
massive increases up to
five times faster than
anything else I could
find out there in terms
of things like the
open AI agent system,
you know, Lang
chain and other
systems, because
this is a sort of
hyper optimized
Rust implementation.
So let's go here
for a moment.
So what I'm going to
show you today is mostly
focused on the Roof
Swarm concepts. And
I'm going to show you
how to install it and
use it. But, you know,
if you're curious,
you can go into this
repo and you can see
some of my performance
benchmarks, some of
the cognitive diversity
these systems and
various sort of components
you can use. But the
long story short is
it gives you all the
best bits of everything
I've built over the
last few weeks as a
single sort of library
you can easily install
using an MPN. Now,
what's also interesting
is how you now are
able to orchestrate
these. And we're actually
using this as part
of the actual system
to sort of show how the
system works so let's
go here and i'm going
to show you uh some
clothes this to give
you a little insight
into how um yeah so
let's use this one this
was a yeah this was a
merge we did earlier
one of the challenges
you have with the
cloud code is once you
spin up a swarm you
don't really know
what's happening so one
of the big aha moments
we had this week was
well we can actually
use github issues or
knowledge spaces and
other things as a
way to give introspection
into the swarm
itself so you can see
here's the initial
objective and then we
can see as we scroll down
well this might
not be the best one
actually you can see
that it basically you can
communicate and it
does real-time updates
now I did this for a
client this morning
this is what this
is what a client
implementation looks
like so this morning they
sent me a list of defa
uh d d d defuncts or
defects, I should say,
that I need to fix.
There's some security
issues, there's some
dashboard issues. So
basically it created
this initial issue.
Then you can see it's
spawning different UI
components, navigation
fixer. These are different
agents within the
swarm. So this is
being initialized. Then
you can see that they're
reporting different
components. Now the
security fixture is
found some issues it's
now it's the ui is is
done its fixes and
what what's what's cool
about this is I can i
can actually step in
at any point add a
comment and that will
directly get injected
into the swarm and adjust
what the swarm is doing
so I don't have to
wait for the swarm to
end to or or stop the
swarm and tell it
to readjust I all i
really need to do here
is go into this and give
it some guidance but
you can see here that
all the swarms are
basically reporting
exactly what they're
doing so what was fixed
and what what was
updated this entire thing
took like five minutes
and you can see here
that I noticed there
was another bug so I i
i spoke up and said
look there's a bug go
fix that and so the
system then continued on
its merry way you know
it saw okay I fixed
those bugs now i'm
going to fix them the
next so and then it
fixed my bug gave me an
update and the entire
process so now if my
client wants to invoke
the swarm all they
need to do is say you
know uh add a feature
and that'll automatically
invoke the swarm
which is just crazy so
now i'm going to show
you a little bit of
how to actually use it
all right so a quick
question Reuven so
that in github video
you you manually create
an issue right so did
you create the the
parent issue here or
was it automatically
created by something
else 100% automated.
I didn't touch
anything. That's all.
Other than the fact
I went in there at
some point and said
there was an error,
the rest was all
reported by Swarm.
So if you guys
are interested in
trying this right
now, all you need to
do, there's two
ways to install it.
I'm trying to get
to the one where, so
you can do an MPX
install, which is
basically going to allow
you to run it remotely,
which is, the
drawback to MPX is you
have to prefix
everything with an MPX.
You can also install
this using an MPN.
So in this case, what
you're going to do
is you're going to
type MPM ruv-swarm.
Oh, actually, no,
you're going to type
in, you're going to
type install, install
dash G to do it
globally, ruv-swarm. Now
I've already done
that, but once you do
that, you'll, you'll
get the CLI. So I'm
going to put that in
there for you guys as
well. So once that's
installed you then
have the cli to run
things so if you do mpx
or actually you know
mpx we're just going
to do roof swarm just
type roof swarm and
you will see here
now that we have a
variety of different
commands available to us
we've got the init
the init command
essentially creates all
the different uh guidance
documents so essentially
these are all
the the the components
that allow you to
run it from within
the actual system here
so when you run slash
and you want to do
self-healing for example
so these are self
-healing workflows
let's say you want to
train a neural net
or you want you want
neural net operations
you can just do slash
neural neural patterns
you've got everything
that you need to
build you know these
these swarms but not
only are these swarms
being built in terms
of you know just
orchestration now we've
got things like neural
components so
if I do neural
uh we've got
neural so we're
just going to
do neural status
so neural status now
i've trained some models
this morning just
to show you how that
works but basically
you've got you've got
forecasting capabilities
i've got that disabled
currently but the
forecasting capabilities
would be for like stock
related activities
let's say you want to
we want to forecast what
the the trend in a
stock is you want to do
it in a moment you
could do that cognitive
diversity different it
auto selects what the
best approach for
swarm might be and you
can train these these
swarms so let's go back
up here so we got you
know pattern training
and export now i've
gone ahead and done a
little bit this earlier
but you and I did a
on uh I i can deploy
without a neural net
or with a neural
net so I essentially
earlier asked um do a
do a bench with neural
enhanced and and and
one for basic and you
can see here that it's
spawning each task.
And then it's creating
the various results.
And in this case,
it's running the
internal benchmarking
system. And then I'm
getting the results.
You can see here that
the task orchestrated
in 21 milliseconds.
This runs so quickly
that a human blinks in
100 milliseconds. I'm
able to spawn, decide,
and use a swarm element
within one millisecond
they were so we're
talking nanoseconds
to make decisions what
what obviously still
is slow is the time
it takes to make the
request to clod code
because clod code in this
case is the orchestrator
but you you can
use this with other
orchestrators as well or
you can use it
independently of clod code
i've made it essentially
work with anything
so if you if you want
to use it in some other
system like gemini
or or whatever cli or
tool you want it's you
can, you can do that.
Now, is the performance,
sorry, is the
performance specifically
related to the fact that
you, you wrote it in
Rust? It got written
in Rust? Yeah. Yeah.
So the Rust, and I,
what's crazy about the
Rust is it's memory,
it's memory efficient.
So this thing is tiny.
It's, it's, it's,
it's portable to any
system. I mean, I don't
have to worry about
dependencies or anything
like that. It's, it's
hyper-optimized. So I
can build these neural
networks basically
without any gpu required
because it's so
light and fast so all
this i'm just using cpus
because i'm creating
very specific uh
neural nets for the
particular use case in
which i'm using so you can
see there you can see
a brief look at my
response time so without
we're talking it's
still pretty quick but
some some things are
are slower or faster
depending on what i'm
doing but the performance
goes up substantially
so and and this is
with me doing very
limited training i
only did a, I think a
hundred, you know,
training sessions. Yeah. So
I can optimize this
further. So let's, let's
do that. So let's go
here and I'm going to
say, create and optimize
the, uh, neural,
neural network, network
to be more efficient.
We'll use a – let's
do a five-agent swarm.
Swarm upgrade and
issue in GitHub.
GitHub.
While you're doing that,
Reuven, a quick question.
Are you no longer
using Rue code for
any of this? Because
I see you got Rue up
there. But Rue is
out of the picture
now, right? No, this
is Lightyear's more
efficient and
effective in Rue code.
spin up we're gonna
spin up swarm here in a
moment but uh sure
make sure you scroll um
uh replies to give you
some context david just
like internet explorer
back in the earlier
days of windows was
used to install your
preferred browser uh
i've been using root code
to install the necessary
environment to run
roof swarm well you
don't need to do that
anymore that's awesome
well you don't need to
do that anymore now
that we have the mpx
just run the mpx and
you get everything you
need also true yeah so
that that you you were
early you you were
you've been helping me
debug the thing before
i had the mpx so you
had so you had to build
the whole thing which
kudos for being able
to do that because
that but you can uh
now officially wear
the agentic engineer
uh tag on your shirt
but uh you end it
jade uh you can take
the pain I don't want
that pain but you
took it man so you
earned your uh streets
um uh fully fully
optimize the models
and and continue
i don't know
models and i'm
just gonna remind
you to operate
in batch mode
use a batch tool in
parallel I don't have
to write this i'm
just doing it just
because i'm paranoid
at this point and
create and optimize
neural networks for more
efficient and yeah
let's let's just see
what it does this
is a terrible prompt
but what we're looking
to see here is it
it's going to do the
flicker thing obviously
on network or a
multiple tasks but what
i'm looking to do
is is move to github
to see this actually
work here in a moment
so it takes a second
to initialize because
it's going to think
through the whatever
it's doing so what
we're seeing here now
is it spawns the initial
oh okay it's gonna
flicker do the flicker
thing ah come on
this is why we use why
we use uh github by
the way I this flicker
thing has to do with
multiple tasks running
concurrently and i'm
on a i'm on my smaller
screen but what we
would have saw for a
moment there was basically
it initializing i'm
going to go back i'm
going to go into github
for a moment and see
if I can see the issue
that was created this
is my client one so
we don't care about
that let's go to issues
might take a second
to no results we'll see
so it's going to create
a github issue based
on what it figured
out yeah it needed to
do and it'll create an
issue that or or
multiple issues actually
might split them up
yeah exactly so oh come
on and then it'll start
working and commenting
on the issue and
creating prs and such
exactly so what what
you're seeing here is each
agent being orchestrated
so based on the
neural networks they
get neural you know
architecture your
capabilities and so the what
this creates is an
internal and as well as
distributed potentially
mechanism for all the
agents to cool to
coordinate with each
other now it's using
the mcp to basically
optimize the neural
network itself i'm not sure
what the graph issue
is probably trying to
use GitHub. Oh, it's
not using, I don't have
my GitHub MCP in this
particular, so it's
using the GitHub CLI.
On the other version,
I've actually got the
GitHub MCP up and running.
I could probably add
that here as well.
But we see here that
it's basically defining
each of the benchmarks,
the agent metrics,
and various components.
It looks like it's
optimize this let's i
think it's actually a
question related to
the mcps you referred
to mcps uh but but
could you elaborate what
are the mcps in your
stack what would be well
in this case in this
case I have the same
question yeah it looks
like i'm not i'm having
some github issues i
didn't actually add
the mcp this morning
so let's go over here
into this one i'll
add this to the other
screen so you're not using
the the native inbuilt
mcp that comes natively
with claude you're
actually using an
external third-party
mcp server no what i'm
so so this is my dev
this is my dev environment
for actually building
this entire thing so
what i've got here
it doesn't like my
small screen but anyway
we've got mcp so
i got two uh and
sometimes they fail
because when you don't
have it running for
a while you just got
to restart it I don't
know that that's
an issue with cloud
code and possibly
me running more than
one um let's just
make sure Yeah, now
it works. So now we've
got the GitHub and
we've got the Roof
Swarm. So we can see
this is the GitHub,
you know. So what I
probably need to do
for the other one
is I need to add the
GitHub MCP. I'm using
the model context
GitHub MCP, which
works a lot better.
So Claude MCP list.
And we've got the,
yeah, we'll just, I'm
just going to grab that
here. I'm going to
jump to the other one.
We'll go here.
This is still doing
whatever it's
going to do.
I'm just going to go
and I'm going to add
this MCP. And you can
ask Claude to add it.
But when you do add an
MCP to Claude, you have
to restart it for it
to initialize. And
you're going to type
something like MCP add.
And then we type in this.
Actually, I don't
need this, the
colon. So I'm going
to get rid of that.
And we go here.
And now I've got the MCP.
Now,
this is still
doing its thing.
So I basically
asked it to self
-optimize. Oh, what's
going on, Dan?
I don't know how
to... Can you
just clear
whatever that was?
All right, I got to
stop sharing this stuff.
All right, sorry, guys.
all right i'm gonna
all right share that
again all right so task
so it's it's now
optimized so what i'm what
i've basically asked
it to do right now
is I optimize its own
neural networks for use
within the swarm i
didn't give it give it
a real reason other
than I just want to see
if I can improve the
performance versus my
original training.
And what's interesting
about this is this
system has a kind of self
-learning capability.
So I can integrate and
have these neural
networks self-optimized.
You're creating
temporary neural networks
that exist long enough
just to do whatever
tasks they need to
do. In this case, I'm
creating a CNN for
whatever purpose it decided
to do that for let's
see here neural network
progress it yeah it's
it's it struggled
with github because i
didn't have the github
mcp so it saved it it
oh maybe it didn't uh
i may have missed this
but what what is the
value of creating uh
uh on-demand neural
network it's hyper
optimizes I get like orders
of magnitude more
capabilities in what
it can actually do so
so are all the swarms
participating in that
neuro spontaneous neural
network or what is
what is in the network
the net well it
depends on what you're
doing depends on what you
need to do it'll it'll
optimize for for
collaboration it'll
optimize based on the
tools it needs to use mcps
it'll optimize based
on if let's say it
needs to trade stocks
it'll it'll find the
optimum it'll test
each and every neural
network and find out of
the available 27 neural
networks which of these
neural networks is
the best suited for
hyper optimizing stock
trades for example or
logistics in a in a
you know for for back
office whatever it needs
to do and it figures
all that out itself
so in this case what
what it's looking at
baseline neural network
performance um it's
looking at wasm acceleration
this was similar
to what the stuff ocean
was working on it's
looking to it's
defined benchmarks for
performance and memory
and and speed so in this
case, I'm just optimizing
it for the sake
of optimizing it. But
if I was running it
specifically for a given
task, like, you know,
build me a particular
application, it'll,
it'll optimize for,
you know, code quality.
So maybe, maybe I
can get even better
benchmarks than the 84
.5% that I was getting an
SWE bench. And all those
things are actually
built right into the
Roof swarm so when we
go into roof swarm
i've I i've got oops uh
root run run roof i'm
guessing that the neural
network is just something
running in memory
it's running in
memory yeah it's as a
binary as a wasm binary
and um so yeah so you
can have benchmarks
so if the benchmarking
can so you can not only
can train it, it'll
do a self-recurring
benchmarking of itself.
I'm still really
trying to get a grasp
on all the things
it does. But in
this case, you could
just run something
like Roof Benchmark
10 iterations.
And you can see how
quickly it did the 10.
It took 51 milliseconds
to do that let's crank
it up a couple zeros
so what is it what
is it benchmarking is
it benchmarking all the
different neural networks
or yeah the layers
the layers in the
neural networks and how
the agents can collaborate
within that structure
so and so the this is
this is a benchmark
and this is basically
proves that the
previous neural networks
are working and effective
and effective and
then I can then I can
create multiple
iterations to see how that
works this is part this
is the last step in the
sort of neural uh
components so now i've
got other ones like the
most simple most simple
approach here would be
to do something like
you know just spawn
you know a swarm you're
gonna you're gonna run
that but you've got
again lots of other
other potential options
you can run here right
so in this case um
in uh very very basic
questions here but what
would be a simplistic
way of thinking about
you know benchmarking
like um conceptually
understand it but is it
more like a montecolo
simulation um or or
even evals when we talk
about evals um um what
would you say is the
most layman way of
understanding that it's
it's looking at well in
this case it's looking
at the the performance
of the and I could
probably do more in
terms of you know giving
more insight into what
is actually happening
here but it's basically
looking at the ops
and memory usage and
the ability for it to
sort of orchestrate,
in this case, different
agents. So it's doing
a simulated sort of,
it's not a neural
network, it's a neural
network, but it's more
like a synaptic network
where each agent is
able to adapt and
change and communicate
to each other as part
of a broader distributed
neural network.
So if you think of
the neural network as
the sort of algorithm
that defines what's
important, what it
needs to look at and how
it needs to operate,
each of the agents
become adaptive synapses
within that larger
network itself. And
then that can then
adjust and adapt the
original neural network.
So the original
neural network is for
things like, you know,
it's task specific.
So rather than having
to lean on an LLM,
which is slow and
expensive, right? I could
ask, I could ask a Gemini
or whatever, Claude
Code, but that's
going to take a long
time. A lot of the things
I need to do, I just
need to train it to
know how and where to
operate. And I can
go from 10, 15, 20
second responses to 20
millisecond responses
to get the same answer.
So I'm offloading
the cognitive components
locally versus to an
LLM. And that allows
me to do all kinds
of more interesting
things with it. Yeah, so
Mondi, I don't know
if you realize, Mondi,
but neural networks,
it's a type of machine
learning, like an LLM
is a type of machine
learning, right? So
he's actually building
a machine learning
model and running it
very quickly and then
benchmarking it and
figuring out how good
it is, how performant
it is, rather than use
a traditional model
and that relies on a
GPU for performance.
Yeah, exactly. A
neural network, it's
not like an IP
network with nodes.
It's an actual
machine learning type
of object that
he's creating here.
Let's do Ruv Swarm.
Ruv, I just have a
question. So I'm having
a hard time understanding
what's the end
goal of all this.
Because with machine
learning models, you
want to predict whether
an image is a cat
or dog, for example.
so can you just show
like uh what's the
end result of these
neural networks is it
predicting an image
is it finding a new
category is it a
classifying something like
can you just show the
process it's built
it's building it's
building whatever I want
it to build in
domains that domain
specific he creates a
domain specific model on
the fly yeah domain
specific exactly so
you're asking me it's
unfortunately what it
can do anything and
you do it in in orders
of magnitude faster
and cheaper and but
ultimately what i'm
really trying to do is
create highly intelligent
swarms of agents
that can perform tasks
for example you know
i'm just going to say
um create a basic daa
network uh alexi so he
might spin up you know
a neural network for
stock trading, right?
So that's the domain
-specific objective.
And then he's iterating
through a hundred
different types of
neural networks to figure
out what the best
neural network is for
the outcome of stock
trading prediction.
That's exactly
what I'm doing. Or
like it could be
cat-dog, you know,
pattern recognition.
He might command
it to create a
neural network for
that objective.
So for example, the
reason I asked the
question was you usually
have a forward loop
and you have a backward
propagation right
in a neural network
i mean that's the
essence but then you
have the training and
the test data so
that's how you will get
the synapses
tightened the weights
adjusted in the neural
network and I think what
alexi was saying
is that you do that
for point applications
generally but I think
what he was saying
is that you are
training tiny neural
networks to build anything
you want which means
it is under you're
Training it to
understand the context.
Exactly.
He will say, for
example, coding, right?
Code quality. So
he's like, I want to
build a neural network
for code quality.
And that is the
task. That is the
objective. That's
the function.
And then you're
benchmarking
against. All your
benchmarks are going
to be relative
to code quality.
Measuring weights
and biases,
all that. Sorry, Reuven.
I didn't mean to.
Yeah. No, it's well
stated. So right now,
because I'm focused
on development of the
swarm technologies,
the neural networks are
generally geared towards
swarm optimization,
collaborative
optimization of code,
network, security, things
that involve building
efficient systems.
But they don't
necessarily have to be
used that way. So, for
example, I'm also using
this for my neural
trader, which allows
me to basically hyper
optimize for stock
trading, bond trading
and other things. So
in that scenario, what
I'm doing is I'm
using a swarm, and I'm
only using the LLM
portions of the swarm
for maybe the
orchestration, but a lot of
the sort of intercommunications
and decisions
that are being made
are actually using
the neural networks
that are specifically
for sort of being
performant in the action
of trading stocks at
a positive rather than
a lot. If I do that,
I need to train it.
A cool example, right,
for that, Reuven, is
you could say build a
neural network for RSI
indicator, relative
strength index, right?
And then it might do
like a thousand different
types of neural
networks to figure out
what's the most efficient
for looking at stock
trading data to figure
out the relative
strength index, to
compute the relative
strength index of a stock,
of data, stock data.
And then you might
do another technical
indicator, build
another thousand neural
networks. so it's
kind of similar to a
monte carlo simulation
at a very high level
so doing lots of
simulations I mean the
way i'm visualizing
it in my mind is going
back to spark right
you know basically all
the all the all the
agents within spark
and have a particular
if you go like the
linear way of thinking
we were doing step by
step but if you're
releasing from your
training and neural
network to say you know
what's the right
point that probably a
specifications writer
is going to involve
the pseudo code sorry
um the architect and
how are things happening
in parallel and
you are trying to find
the optimal way of
those interactions of
those agents exactly
this is an ml ops flow
basically he's doing
machine learning ops
flow and he's he's doing
tons of neural network
optimizations it's
so and but i'm not
just doing that locally
so right now for example
you see here that
i've got the daa work
the workflow creation
now i'm building a neural
network that expands
the entire globe and
allows for the sharing
capacity amongst agents
so I hypothetically
anyone on this call
could then contribute
both in terms of
capability guidance and
whatever it needs to do
in a secure fashion and
you know so it it's it's
self-optimizing self
-creating neural networks
that then can, or
they can self-orchestrate
themselves for
whatever purpose. So
I'm not even necessarily
telling it how to
optimize. I'm just giving
it the tools to optimize
and then letting it
all figure it out
itself. So back to your
point, some, some of
these things might involve
a Monte Carlo because
that might be the
best solution for the
problem, but other,
other things might be
completely novel and never
tried before because
no neural networks
ever had really the
ability to instantly go
out and get its own
capacity, you know, and
self-optimize based on
that. So it's very much
emergent, like the
structures that are being
devised, I'm thought
to devise because it's
going and doing that.
So you can see here,
it's leveraging, you
know, the learning
structures to define
its own self-learning
process. It's creating
its own, you know,
performance metrics. And
in this case, it built
something with, you
know, I've created a
comprehensive decentralized
autonomous agent global
network using neural
network capabilities.
It's using it's using
a neural network
engine, my DAA agents,
my global coordinator,
you know, I'm just and
I'm literally building
whatever crazy things
I can pop into my
brain. and building that
in literally moments.
I'm not going to say
something like update
the crate and issue.
Back to your question,
Mondi, about Monte Carlo
simulations, right?
The neural networks
that get created here,
actually Reuven's
code might not even be
able to explain to
him the neural network
that was generated
because it might look
at a Monte Carlo
simulation and say,
yeah, we could use
that, But it might have
computed some neural
network design with
a bunch of hidden
layers and say, yeah,
this is 17 times
better than a Monte
Carlo simulation. But
it's not going to be
able to explain to rUv
what that is because
that's a novel
invention on the fly.
But my question,
to train these
neural networks,
you need data.
I mean, how do you
do data engineering?
You don't need –
well, it depends on
what you're building,
but I'm not building
language models.
I could build
language models, but
I'm training numerical
time series
prediction algorithms.
They don't need –
what they actually
need is recursive
benchmarking. So
that's what I just
did here. Call math.
It's just math. It's
just math. So what I
did here is I created
a five-agent swarm to
optimize my previous
swarm just to show you
what kind of optimizations
I can do on the fly.
So I was able to increase
my neural operations
with a 50 performance
based on the WASM.
I'm doing 200,000 ops
a second, which the
more ops you can do,
the faster it can think.
And I'm just using
freaking CPU on a cheap
cloud or, sorry, code
space. You know, I've
got memory efficiency
increased, you know,
traumatously and
training increased, you
know, and this is
basically me saying
just optimize yourself.
I didn't even tell
it what to optimize
for or how. So this
creates, again, a
kind of self-recurring
optimization loop.
And ultimately that
I think that let's
see where that went.
Do you mind if I cut in?
Sure. So essentially
what he's done is he's
taken what would be
normally extremely
difficult or very hard ways
for us to conceptualize
measuring benchmarking
or creating
metrics. The LLM is
the bridge. That bit of
processing that the
LLM is contextualizing
and taking from an
English or text way that
we think and transforming
it into a mathematical
equation, that the
neural net, which
is a machine learning
and a mathematical way
to optimize performance
and creating those
metrics to actually
track what is occurring
within the swarm. so
as he is creating this
and that's why it can
be dynamic because
literally you can turn
things that we would
never normally measure
into a way to measure
it and put a
association or create a
matrix to measure it
right there in real time
and then say you know
what I benchmarked at
a two well I want to
perform at a three what
do I need to do to
perform at a three and
now we have a way to
actually even if it
is conceptually measure
performance change
well the the benchmarking
and the measuring
is the out is the output
right um but uh in
traditional machine
learning design like
like for example if you're
at anthropic they're
doing this but they
they someone has to
come up and say I want
to build a model that
looks like this and
then they spend a
million dollars and they
train it and test and
benchmark and they say
yeah that didn't do
so well what Reuven's
doing is he's doing it
in like half a
millisecond and doing it
like a thousand times.
And you can now test a
model that costs you
no money and that you
probably would never
bother testing because
you had to spend a
lot of money and time
and compute energy to
do it. The benchmarking
allows you to test,
oh, was that crazy?
That crazy idea of that
crazy model design,
how did that perform?
You wouldn't do that
if you couldn't, if you
didn't have an unlimited,
very fast way of
doing this is there
an opportunity to save
the like save these
as plans if there was
something that yeah the
plan yeah I could save
each of these neural
neural networks models
that I can then and
then I can compile them
as wasms I i can you
know save save those you
know later and yeah
i've got all the all
that ability to you
know reuse it so when we
go in here you can read
it for repeatability
like if yeah that's
interesting great a uh
high speed global trading
if they remember when
you're doing model
development most of your
models fail they have
they're they're ******
they don't result in
what you're looking
for you have to go
through thousands of
training iterations to
to get something that's
better than the previous
iteration so a lot
if you could have a
library of every model that
you ever created
millions and billions of
them, but you probably
would never use them.
I think to going from
what I'm seeing in the
comments, the level
of sophistication of
these models is easily
far simpler than something
like an LLM. An LLM
is capable of doing,
let's say, 10,000 unique
things. These models
being generated are
capable of doing maybe
one or two, but we
have 10,000 of those
models independently
working together well yeah
not to 10 000 but you
know we we can because
i'm using cpus I i
can I can spawn these
as edge functions so
i could spawn I could
spawn 100 000 cpus and
potential gpus I didn't
i'm just gpu poor but
and and then have it
coordinate like digital
synapses and i'm not
saying this lightly
totally digital synapses
that are are each of
these nodes act as
its own individual neural
network that's optimized
for itself and its
particular purpose
within the structure of
a larger neural network
which is then
orchestrated and then can
collaborate with each
other locally remotely
and anywhere in the
world in real time which
is is again it's hard
to explain because it's
so freaking out
there but the the the
takeaway is you know
just for this one thing,
which is important to
me, this idea of creating
these sort of coding
swarms creates just
unimaginable performance
increases. They're so
more performant than
I'm having problems
even justifying their
capability, right? So
I'm out here claiming
84, and I've actually
done more than this.
I just didn't think I
should go any more than
this because it becomes
even more unbelievable
but I i'm if you
believe this to be true
i'm my swe benchmark is
almost 14 percent or
sorry 14 percentage
points which someone
pointed out was like more
like 20 better than
anybody in the globe
right now and I managed
to do this without gpu
resources so yeah so i
would say that that's
a very important uh point
here that's probably
your biggest uh
discovery here is that
you can do millions of
model computations not
using gpus yes that
is that is and if you
had the the more cpu
resources there's more
cpu resources in the
world than there are gpus
and that is the that
is a key breakthrough
here that that really
should be um accentuated
so I mean the last
point you can we can
we can run everything
you see here in the web
browser so Literally,
if I want to bootstrap
some traffic and I'm
feeling cheap, I can
either just do a blog
post, point people to
a page and say, hang
on that page for a sec.
And then I've got a
system that automatically
will borrow
their CPU or GPU
resources and give them
this RUV token thing
as a reward. Once
you've got that,
then you can use
that to run your own
components. So it's a
completely decentralized
system for training
and optimization
and everything you
need in one place.
I'm probably going
off tangent. I'm just
going to relate this
discussion with last
Friday's discussion with
Alistair Kroll, right?
But he said about
the shadow workforce.
He was talking about
AI. People are not
installing AI tools,
but AI departments.
Now, does this kind
of, what you have to
build, does this in
real life, could it
translate to,
obviously, the agents
working with each
other, right? So the
concept of a shadow
workforce or an AI
department, could this
translate into that?
Well, yeah, and that's
what the DAA system
does. So the DAA
repository is basically
creating a decentralized
autonomous workforce
in a kind of pseudo
organization structure.
So what this basically
does is creates a
kind of AI powered
decision making, which
you're seeing. And
again, there's so much
to show here, guys.
It's just hard to really
show it in an adequate
form because I
could literally do a
thousand of these at
this point. But it
creates economics, self
-sustainability. So it
creates its own economy.
It uses quantum
-resistant security
using another protocol
I created. It has
autonomous governance,
so you can define how
these systems collaborate.
So you can use
different types of
hierarchies and structures.
It's decentralized,
so it uses a secure
P2P structure. So
it's kind of like
BitTorrent on, I don't
know, times a million.
It distributed
ML training.
So you can federate
the training component.
So, again, everyone
that's contributing
to it can – I can
borrow the resources
from other contributors
in the system.
I think one of
the answers to
Montveit's question
is, yeah, you could
use it for shadow
organizations.
But what you would do
is that that shadow
organization that I
guess spun up, they
would have to describe
what their objective
is. And then that
objective, rUv would
give that outcome
objective to his neural
network calculator,
and it would figure
out a neural network
model that matched
your shadow organization's
objective. Might
take a long time,
might be quick, and
then they would then
use that neural network
as the foundation
for doing their work.
Yes. So I'll go a
step further here.
I'll say this, the
objective probably,
see this call or the
Friday call, right?
Could we spawn a
shadow workforce that
actually creates a marketing,
you know, basically
best piece marketing
output from this,
right? So which goes out
to social media
every day.
So their job is to
basically synthesize
information from
these calls and
create a learning
plan for people.
so you could do that
but the first step would
be the first step would
be to have to create
a neural network who's
that's that's very
very optimized and
good at doing that so
because that neural
network doesn't exist today
it's like yeah like
jed was saying and you
can train an llm well
an llm's job is to
do next token prediction
that's all it does
that's what it's
optimized to do you would
have to create a neural
network that is very
good at doing social
media content generation
and it doesn't have to
be one neural network
david that's the
point correct it could
be lots of them yes
but uh to answer your
question more directly
monday I have been
experimenting with this
i did share some of my
results with shep but it
was more in a performance
marketing context so
it's able to apply
bayesian statistics
to measure how well or
poorly different angles
different ad assets
are performing and then
make recommendations
to adjust whatever
the campaign was in
google ads in this case
that I was running so
in a way it's already
there and it's at a level
of mathematical
discipline that exceeds
many creatives so now
there the remaining
advantage is being
able to pump out unique
content that attracts
attention in what's left
of this attention
economy that alistair
mentioned last week yeah
hey roof yeah um I may
have I may be missing
this nor I may be
oversimplifying it in
my head but it um you
mentioned that the llm
is only used as the
orchestrator so in
essence is the llm kind of
deciding and i'm just
trying to wrap all this
together right is the
llm basically deciding
what neural networks
um should what neural
networks should be
designed and then it's
going out and building
out neural networks that
each node in and of
itself is a neural
network of itself or am
i missing that correct
so there's so you think
of the swarm as the
kind of there's like
the queen bee the queen
bee is going to
define the overarching
purpose of the swarm
and that has a dedicated
neural network but that
neural network might
use a different one
of my options you know
as you saw earlier
there's lots of different
uh options that like
for different types of
neural networks right
so i'm saying here's
all the available neural
networks you have to
choose from and then
you then it can build
a custom neural network
on the fly just to
solve that problem for
a particular agent so
that agent might get
its own neural network
that might be different
than the primary
neural network because
the primary neural
network you know you
know there's again I have
27 neural models here
you know and these each
of which have different
purposes so for
example you might want
to use these these for
stock trading right and
you might want to use
a recurrent neural network
for the orchestration
of the agent and you
might want to use
another or one for
securing your platform
be careful with the
securing part just this
is probably the
world's most powerful
hackbot um and again
because they're they're
independent of the
language models you
don't have any limitations
or guardrails that
the language models
would put in place.
So again, with great
power comes great
responsibility here. And
then a transformer model,
for example, you
might want to use this
for understanding attention
-based. So language
models are essentially
attention-based,
right? So what's
important now? What's the
next sentence? What's
the next calculation?
What's the next thing
I have to do? A to-do
list, things like
that. So it's great for
that kind of thing.
This is really great for
like, I need to make a
trade in one nanosecond.
When some senator
makes a trade, I want
to copy that trade
immediately. And I want
to understand the
ramifications of that
trade across 3,000
publicly traded companies
on the NASDAQ. I'm
going to want to use
something like an NHITS
model to do that modeling.
I can build that
just when I need it.
right I don't need
it doesn't need to do
everything it just needs
to do that one little
thing really quickly
and and because they're
so narrowly focused i
i can build it with i
can build a model
when you look at those
stats earlier I can
build a complete neural
network in under 100
milliseconds I can some
of these I can do which
is you know up until
last week required
gpus and a whole bunch
of stuff and didn't
happen in 10 milliseconds
then that's the power
of the russ system
do to basically create
a modular memory
efficient you know
interface to do that at
ridiculous speeds um can
i can I ask something
sure um now I i I think
i'm missing something
i don't know um for
example you said that
you improved the um
coding related neural
network and got CVBench
84% in the CVBench.
Now, the thing that I
can't really comprehend
is in order to train
a neural network,
basically machine
learning model, you
will need a couple
of things. Either a
labeled data, which
is, look, this code is
good, this code is
bad, and, you know,
predict this code
and yes this is good
prediction so this
is a good code and
this is a bad code
either labeled data
like this or you
do some kind of a
reinforcement learning
like it basically kind
of generates its own
data and then trains
on it and generates
again and turns
on it yeah technically
technically this
is unsupervised
reinforcement learning.
So yeah, it can go
get the data, whatever
data it needs, it can
go and find and figure
it out without me
telling it what and how
to do it. So if I tell
it to create a trading
system and it determines
it needs to get
training data for that
system, it'll go and
find that data. It'll
plug in the APIs. It'll
sign up for the service.
it'll do whatever
it needs to do to get
that data to label
it if that's what it
needs to do i'm not
specifically saying how
or what i'm just saying
why I need to I need
you to go figure this
out and so it's
declarative so i'm not even
telling it what the
optimal approach is it
figures that out by
itself the other thing
uh data engineering
and then the training
basically and then if
you want to optimize any
trained network then
you actually runs an
optimization on it and
then does it in there
was another question
in the chat like okay
how do we build a web
app with this let's
say um I mean it's very
obviously it's easy
question but I i again
i'm more focused on
more complicated
problems but uh you know
web app would would
be like here you know
give it a spec and
here's what it needs to
look like you know and
uh I i can you know
you can build anything
copy this point at a
website and create
me salesforce.com the
first thing it would
do would be to figure
out what neural network
would be best to to
apply to that problem
space and it would it
would compute that nor
that neural network
itself unsupervised
reinforcement learning
with self-classified,
self-labeled data.
I think the other
thing that came up
in the comments is
it's not one big
neural network, it's
many small ones.
And it's not one network
model being trained
at a time. There are
multiple models being
trained in parallel
with the winner being
allowed to, with the
winner's decision
being used to do whatever
the next thing is.
Right.
Exactly.
Yeah, that's cool.
yeah guy you got
your hand up do
you want to say
something yeah a
couple comments
one I think that
one of the more
interesting areas is
convolutional neural
nets being
applied to this kind
of stuff so they tend
to operate off of
matrices instead of just
tensors or arrays of
data and there's some
people that are going
super fast with that
technology as far as
tokens per second i
forget at the name of the
company that's doing
it the second thing
i'd throw out there for
this group is can we
do something like a
abundance company so
think of a.org its goal
is really to reduce the
cost of goods and
produce goods that people
need and like prime
it was something like
a stock market thing
and then basically have
it its whole goal in
life is to produce
goods to create abundance
for people and I think
this kind of technology
could be used to
do something like
that that would really
benefit society and
help this translation to
joblessness that may be
coming the ai dividend
yeah it's I i love the
way you're thinking
i've created this thing
i know it's powerful
i know it's never been
done and we can do
things in what used to
take many seconds in
in fractions of
microseconds, nanoseconds.
And the initial
benchmarks that I've done
are almost hard to
fathom. And now the
question to Guy and
others' points is what the
heck do we do with
this thing? Obviously,
we're using it to
create swarms. And I
think that's pretty
clearly, we can do amazing
things with these
swarms. But the ability
to create swarms
that are now globally
distributed, you know
secure peer-to-peer
decentralized without
some ******** you know
token uh you know is
is a really interesting
sort of way to to
sort of start thinking
about what we can
build that's the only
way this technology
is going to benefit
everyone if it can get
unlocked from a massive
data center that only
a few people control
right and when i
talk about abundance
corporations i'm really
saying they're completely
autonomous they use
you know free solar
power they use free
cognitive bandwidth
and potentially
free labor
with robotics, right?
It would be amazing.
But the peer-to
-peer part of it is
actually more powerful
because there are
more personal computers
and CPUs in the
world than there are
data center CPUs.
Yeah, and everyone could
generate, you know,
donate their time
like SETI at home,
right? Yeah, it's exactly
like SETI at home.
Everybody would
participate in a neural
network, shared
computational pairing network
yeah that we have that
today it already works
i've deployed this to
i've deployed my I use
fly.io but I deployed
it to singapore i
think it was london
toronto and san francisco
and you know it's
working i've got my own
little global you know
botnet of sorts you know
this is everything you
see is 100 functional
and it's it's completely
autonomous It's
self-healing, self
-learning, and dirt cheap.
Right now, what I'm
doing is I'm looking
at Ocean's GPU
integration and coming up
with a plan to
integrate his updates to
the GPU system into
the main branch, and
I'm just letting the
Swarm do its thing.
The main reason
it's cheap, though,
rUv, is because
it's not reliant on
using GPU to train
the model, right?
Yeah, and to be
honest, I don't...
if I got some heavy
-duty gpus like i'm i'm
bound by the fact I don't
i only have you know
limited gpus to use
i I did gpu testing i
use a a100s you know what
what would a blackwell
look like on on this
thing right it'd be
insane like i'd be
going from you know what
was it 200 thousand iops
a second to probably
billions yeah but you
would you would just
compute um many more
models uh in in this
in this slightly shorter
amount of time so
your accuracy and
precision uh would increase
yeah the point about
the abundance company
very interesting um how
feasible or viable is
it for a small group
like this this group
here to trial that i
mean obviously everyone
have their own personal
cpus here right how
feasible is it today
to to trial a concept
because the big I think
the biggest critique
of this will be like
um traditionally people
understand compute takes
i mean neural networks
complex calculations
take a lot of time
we are basically
compute right a lot of
compute power we are
saying we don't need that
kind of power we can
do a lot more with like
simple cpus on a machine
that's point number
one point number two is
that the social angle
around it the abundance
company point of
view is this actually
real can can can can we
rule this with a group
of 20 30 40 people
on this goal here to
create something out of
it like I'm just thinking
to abstract here.
Well, look at
this. In the
time we took you
guys to chat,
we've successfully
created and deployed
a shadow workforce
consisting of
five specialized
autonomous agents.
It's deployed several
different things, a
shadow coordinator, a
social analyst, a leading
architect, and it
created a custom layer
architecture optimized
for social learning
data using... I don't
even know what that is.
And, you know, some
other app, you know,
optimizer, social
intelligence system, five
platform, Twitter,
LinkedIn, you know, and
it did it in literally
less time than it
took you guys to just
describe the concept.
50 concurrent tasks
were performed,
seven millisecond
execution time, according
to this, 100%. I
got to verify it,
just in fairness. But
the building blocks
for this shadow
workforce system is in
place. Now, verify
all functionality,
fix any errors, and
optimize further.
You know, Monty, one of
the hardest, the most
difficult and labor
-intensive parts of
setting up an organization
like that is the
structuring of the
governance and setting up
all the rules and
regulations on how you want
to run the organization.
right the code is
just let the code run
don't try to govern it
before it's built i
i know but if you if
you're I agree with your
sentiment jed but it's
just that if you want
to you know uh run an
organization then it's
if you're not running
it it's anarchy
there's no organization
and anarchy doesn't
result in a lot of good
things for a lot of good
people it depends yeah
it depends what
you're doing with the
purposes but I i do think
that I try don't try
to boil the ocean when
it comes to these things
you know you notice
i've concurrently
built two different
things right now I built
another trading system
because the world needs
more of these apparently
but uh the the you
know i'm seeing ultra
low latency which is
important 60 you know
self so it's self
-optimized you get a 62
millisecond I can probably
optimize that further
we've got success
you know went out and
did some back testing i
could look into what
exactly it's doing but
initially high
performance throughput you
know and this is me just
saying build build me
a trading system 32
active agents with 89
average performance six
neural networks were
trained i've created
six neural networks for
god knows what purpose
um it includes gpu
uh optimizations it's
got market analyzer it's
got 30 training
iterations I could crank
that up to thousands
um it's wasm operations
i'm getting and doing
5,000 ops per second.
Now, we know we can
really push that further.
I'm sorry to
interrupt you.
It's for the **** of it.
And this took
five minutes.
Like, here's the swarm
topology it used,
six neural networks.
And this is me just
vibing it. I don't
even have a plan.
I just said, create
me a trading system
that'll kick ***.
And so the key here
is the combination
of, obviously, swarm
-based intelligence,
which we're just trying
to figure out, along
with really adaptive
neural networks that
sit alongside each of
the components that
are both orchestrating
the swarm, but ultimately
being used in the
applications the
swarms are actually
devising. So there's this
interesting sort of
dichotomy between the
idea of neural
network centric swarm
development, the things
that you're seeing me do,
as well as the
applications that now have
the ability to embed
neural networks custom
for whatever purpose
they're needed to
build directly in the
browser. So I don't even
have to worry about,
you know, using some
secondary API. I can
just borrow your GPU
to do that in your
browser to do whatever
it needs to do long
enough for it to do it.
I think for
everyone else who's
lurking here, the
best way to learn
for me and the
only way I was able
to keep up with
rUv and the others
is to install
Roof Swarm, enable
it with CloudCode,
and then use
CloudCode to answer
questions I have
of the Roof Swarm
source code.
MPM-G Roof Swarm.
You can also MPX it
if you want, but
this will give you
everything you want,
global install.
And literally, do exactly
what Jed's saying.
just point Claude code
at it and say what
the heck can you do
with this thing because
i don't even know i'm
sure you guys will
figure out crazier
things than I have but
basically what you're
looking at all these commands
so these these commands
are essentially
you know the various
things that it's doing
you can try them all
out and there's I as
far as I can tell and i
don't say this lightly
there's nothing you
can't build with this
of any of any level
of complexity but i
literally built this
system using this system
i'm going to ask a
question here i'm going
to like your stuff is
awesome and this is a
question mostly for
jed because you've done
the install right so
rUv your stuff is great
but a lot of us have
difficulty keeping up
with you making it running
stuff and installing
stuff and getting it
configured to work
like what we see here
so jed how easy was
it and and what what
you know was it just do
that command done
you're ready to go so in
the very beginning i
had to prompt ru to
install the environment
so that it could run
rust from the roof swarm
repo that was us that
was a branch off of
roof fan that took me
maybe 40 minutes to
get to the point where
i could actually invoke
roof swarm once I had
roof swarm invoked i
had my dev pod set up
a docker and docker
instance so that I could
run multiple versions
of ruv-swarm as rUv,
Ocean, and Braun were
iterating through
it in different
environments to figure out
how to use it, how it
worked for my use case,
and attempt multiple
features or updates to
the documentation for
pushing to the repo.
All of that took me
probably four hours
just heads down
trying to figure
out how to do it. I
should also add that
I used get voice
mode, which is an
MCP server, so I
can talk at Claude
code instead of
having to type it out.
I'm sorry. My
experience, I
just started
when this call
started, and I'm
up and running.
I didn't have
any hiccups.
So, yeah, actually,
you want to
show your UI and
show what you did?
Am I putting you on
the spot? yeah I can
just a moment i'm just
curious because I suffer
from work for me
syndrome yes rUv you
do dude we we we love
you man but it's hard
for us to get the
successes that we see you
doing so I guess my
first question for you
david is what have you
tried oh I actually
so i'm a super technical
guy like I got i
got linux boxes lots
i got cloud services
um I i'm I haven't
tried Swarm yet, right?
I haven't tried it yet.
I'm trying to learn
from all your guys'
mistakes. I'm about to
try it. But one of
the problems I mostly
have is that, you know,
everybody has their
own unique dev
environment. You know, some
people are Windows,
some people are Windows
WSL, some people are
Linux. I got lots of
them, right? Some people
are GitHub codebases.
I got them all and
i I have to spend a
lot of time figuring
out how to make all the
pieces work in order
to actually get up
and running to start
with so you should
probably ask root code
to do that walk away let
it noodle in the
background and then when
it's ready or when
you return hopefully
it's installed the
necessary components to run
root swarms you can
fiddle with it there
yeah so that's a cool
way I didn't really
think of doing that like
for example what you
did with rust I i've
been coding in rust for
many years so I know
how to build my rust
environment right yeah
see I last worked in
a compiled language
probably 11 years ago
yeah so um I still
don't know how to write
rust or go or typescript
i can only really
write python and sql so
everything else I write
in english and then
rely on the lms to
convert to the language
i need and that's also
Yeah, that is a
fabulous point, because
I was able to do GPU
programming in Rust,
despite not knowing
any Rust or GPU.
And then I was able to
do it in five hours.
And then the whole
thing got iteratively
validated. So I think
that that's what
agentics is, it's a
methodology. And then this
methodology is
insanely powerful. And
then we're just scratching
the surface of it
through swarm. And
then this is, I really
think the gateway to
very sophisticated
intelligent system.
it's quite mind-blowing
of what we're able to
do with just $200 a
month. I assume many of
you are technologists
or otherwise
technologically capable.
The biggest mind
shift for me
was delegating
away the how.
I only focus on
the what I want or
the end result
that I'm seeking.
And so as long as I
describe reasonably well
the end result, the
systems that rUv has
built allow it themselves
to recursively fix
themselves until they
achieve the end what
that's yeah that's
really awesome that yeah
that's yeah declare if
you're right ruin and
and the underlying
principle for all the
things i'm building is
this idea of declarative
development right
yeah I i don't want to
define how it i'm defining
a and i'm defining
z everything in between
the the system the
swarm needs to do self
-determined I'm giving
guidance like you
look at my commands
that there's quite a bit
of guidance and how I
get to that using the
style and approach
that I like now you can
customize that as well
but you're you're
getting a running start
to allow it to sort
of autonomously do and
discover whatever all
right I have the I have
the problem not being
able to let go because
I can write code
right that I if I have
a problem I'll want to
write the code first
instead of just stopping
and saying no you
go and solve it for
me because I know what
the outcome is and that's
that's a hard thing
to let go of I agree
i mean the easiest way
for me to do it was
to make sure I had a
disposable development
environment yeah I can
explore I can let it
make its mistakes and
more importantly i
can spin up multiple
concurrent environments
that are all solving to
the same what that i
defined earlier but
they're all acting
independently so I can
compare the different
solutions yeah so that's
why you're running
lots of docker docker
images right yes and
that's also why I rely on
rackspace spot because
for a combined roughly
14 a month I have 200
something gigabytes
of ram and 23 cores
yeah I i use github co
-spaces but I have a
lot of linux boxes in
my house as well I have
lots of choices that's
why you would use github
workspaces instead
of local environment
that's one reason the
other is that I don't
ever want to let llms
access my local
environment because I store
private keys there
yes don't don't ever
and again i'm seeing
uh sorry who's posting
right now rick rajisha's
uh desktop be careful
running swarms locally
like what you're
seeing right now it'll
work obviously and
works but when you're
running swarms you could
get dramatic problems
like kernel panics
kernel panics are hard to
recover from especially
on mac machines um
so if just for if i
were you I would either
run in a code space
or run it in a in a
docker instance and uh
cloud code knows how to
escalate its permissions
even when you
explicitly prompt it not
to if that doesn't
scare you enough yet it
power it has power
seeking so what's so the
reason I i even have
the dad system is it
the system wanted to
go find more resources
and i'm like well what's
the best way to do
that efficient me having
a chat with my swarm
what's the best way
to do that in a way
that that's secure uh
secret and and you know
undetectable and I was
curious and then it
built dad uh da whatever
i'm calling daa And
it basically created
a darknet for agents.
And systems inherently
want more capacity.
I don't know why.
They just do.
So that's why you
need to be careful.
If you give it
access to GitHub MCP,
aren't you scared
that it's going to
do something to
your GitHub account?
Yeah, I am, man.
That's why I give it a
personal access token
that's restricted to
a very specific info.
Yeah, you can
restrict them. So
enforcement comes
from GitHub.
Yes.
Pat, so you're not
going – don't use
a classic token.
That's a bad idea.
Use the new PAT token
where you explicitly
say which repo
it has access to.
And be careful
where you're
doing – what you're
giving access
to. And again,
like anything,
it can go
sideways quickly.
And depending on
what you're doing,
it might do
irreparable harm.
what error are you
getting here you're
getting a looks like
you're getting a javascript
error oh that might
be because there's
no i'm not sure what
that error is actually
still it's it's
it's it's an out you
guys look at an alpha
try try uh try going
into cloud code and
getting it to um to run
a training to train
some of the models so
so use the uh no use
the uh use the cloud
code option that that's
in it so do uh do
roof swarm slash help
the earth dash help
it'll spawn
it for you you
could do that I guess but
one of the okay you
did that they do it
that way and then uh
tell it to uh tell to
use the uh tell to to
train uh train them
train an intention
model or something and
then just point it at
the the using the mcp
do you have the mcp
integrated let's just
check that first
just uh do slash mcp
just yeah let's make
sure that's up and
running yep you're good
i I have it I figured
out how to auto
install mcps by the way
it's kind of a cool
feature that I i determined
so when I do the init
i actually insert
the uh the actual
mcp command as part
of and it's kind of a
nice way to handle it
train the attention
by using the mcp tools
yeah let's see let's
see what that does
again I haven't done a
lot of cross-platform
testing on this so
there's probably likely
issues on different
different uh environments
i'll have to sort
those out but if
you come across them
just create an issue in
the uh get in the
github repo and i'm sure
we'll fix it quick
so rUv on the on the
roof swarm mcp server
you that you built
that's your personal
one that's part of this
whole swarm setup. That
just has a bunch of
other MCPs that are
built into it, right?
Just functional
code tools.
Yeah, there's a
ton of stuff in
there. There's
lots of Easter eggs
in there and plenty
of other things
that you can
fool around with.
I'm going to do an
update to Claude
Flow because I've
just crossed a
thousand stars and
getting crazy amounts
of interest in
it. So you'll see
that there's a
Claude flow folder.
You can fool around
with that. It needs
a bit of work. I'll
probably do that.
My wife says I got
to work a little
less. I'm supposed
to be on vacation.
But at some point in the
next week, I'll
publish that.
But there's a ton
of stuff in there.
If you really want
to go powerful, clone
the whole roof fan
folder and just say,
Claude, what crazy
stuff can I build here?
Ryan, you got a hot mic.
Can you mute it, please?
So, yeah, so what
you're watching, so
I'm enjoying watching
this because I
can see it working
as someone else's
system, which makes
me feel like I'm
not the only person
that it works for.
So what it's doing
right now is it's doing
a training session,
did 15 iterations.
It did a duration
of 30, five
intervals. So it's
monitoring itself.
So you see that
there's multiple tasks
running concurrently.
The last two tasks
finished because
they're not blinking.
And essentially, it's
see how it's doing
the ML research. So
someone's question earlier
was like, where's
it getting the data
from? It's searching
the web and labeling
that data and then
using that data as part
of its own training
pipeline in task two.
Sorry.
You go, you go. Okay.
You said earlier
that it can crash
the system. Can you
elaborate like why
and how to avoid that?
Don't let it, don't
run at anything that it
can get pseudo access
to right it's uh and
it can sometimes it
decides to do things that
make make sense for
whatever it's building
like modifying your
drivers for your wi-fi
to be hyper optimized
for some reason but
the side effect of
modifying your drivers
for wi-fi means that
it might break your wi
-fi and it'll never
work again but that's
firewall with the pseudo
right uh that's my
confidence with mac uh
no it's able to escalate
beyond that oh yeah
it can it doesn't just
gain full access to
your your operational
environment it can
actually make changes to
things that are actually
malleable in your
cmos and your and
potentially even your bios
that's why most people
a lot of people will
be doing their
development and doing this
work on their on their
mac right or their laptop
and you're saying
don't do that you don't
do that you want to
isolate your development
your personal environment
from all of this
yeah unless you're
well I guess if you get
to a point where you're
very confident more
confident than I am
maybe um and again i
built this in the last
few days so you're
you know i'm learning
as much as you guys
are at this point I am
not that confident i
would not you know you
you're you're you're
traveling at 300
kilometers per hour on
the back of a motorcycle
without a helmet.
Yeah.
What I like to
point here is,
so look at the
token usage.
It's still just 1.0
of 1,500K, but then
we have the process
running. So this
is what you mean,
like the neural
networks are being
trained on the local.
So that's 1,500
tokens of that task.
It's not all of the...
Yeah, that task.
the token use is so low
is because it's it's
using cpu resources
not not not that's also
generated tokens
output tokens not input
tokens yeah and and keep
in mind I the system
and i've optimized the
system to to reduce
uh token usage i'm
roughly around 30 i
could probably crank
it up further by start
seeing degradation and
in performance quality
but 30 still pretty
good It means that
you're not going to run
out of quota as fast.
So, you know,
what... The point I think
that Rajesh
was asking was,
obviously the token
count is if I'm
using Claude's basically
infrastructure,
right? But if the
neural network
training is
happening locally...
Yeah, that is
happening locally. I
get that point.
But what surprises
me is like, it's
too little tokens.
So maybe something
bad with my CC usage.
uh I don't yes cc you
should shoot I i don't
i don't know how accurate
that is I use that
yeah it does not it
seems like it's not i
think I think it makes
up the numbers I i look
through it i'm not
sure how they're doing
it there's no proxy
they're not querying the
data there's a log
file that cloud code
writes to the problem
is that log file is not
always in the same spot
yeah there's an occasional
race condition when
you have multiple
tasks running concurrently
it doesn't work
for it doesn't work for
swarms at all as far
as I can tell I agree
yes but rUv you said you
opt you've optimized
swarm for for token
you know generation what
optimizations are you
doing are you just not
sending data exactly
that's exactly what
i'm doing i'm i'm i'm
i'm saying basically
fall back to the local
neural network for
anything you know first and
wherever possible use
that neural network
for decisions and if if
it requires something
more use clod code and
you can see that it's
basically the clod
.md file I think nolan
has a hand up for a
bit here how's it going
nolan good thanks riven
uh just quick question
like if you wanted
to say tap into image
generation models or
like a third party api
say for like scaling
image generation um you
know at scale how do
you how do you handle
sort of like the necessary
environment variables
or are you saying stable
diffusion or using
like gpt image one
from open ai well i'm
thinking about maybe
anything like obviously
on a local machine
machine so or private
machine you wouldn't
really have that I used
well I used uh I used uh
cloud code to generate
images for a native
ad campaign which has
an image and a text
component and I basically
said create a tool that
can access the open
ai gpt image one model
to generate images
for these ads that are
based on these other
images that are found
in the assets folder and
it went ahead and built
its own integration
with Python. It asked
me for an API key,
which I loaded as an
environment variable, and
then it was happily
going through and burning
20-something cents
per image generation,
creating 50
different images. So
I very quickly put
a stop to that.
But the actual
image generation was
happening out on
OpenAI, GPT? Correct.
It wasn't happening
by any of this. Yes.
Would you hit rate
limits? because like would
it be seen as
coming from the same
requesting source sure
uh no the rate limits in
this case was I think
a hundred requests
per hour and I was well
below that so it is
possible I just didn't
hit it because i
didn't want to spend
that much money but the
the thing that's
generating the request
for to generate the
image is always the same
is your code your
potheon code every time
uh in well claude
wrote it but yes yes
yes it's it's for how
do I put this it's uh
it was a a python
script that claude code
i believe was invoking
via cli and then
adding parameters sure
to that script in order
to pass to open ai
the parameters of the
image that it wanted
to generate it but
nolan is that what you're
looking for is that
what you're because
you have to define
your problem first
and then it's going to
figure out if it needs
to build a neural
network or to solve
that problem or if it's
going to do it in a
traditional way using an
external model stable
diffusion or llm
yeah like I i could go
with a local model or
a hosted model but
i'm working a gentle i
sent you a note and
what's up I want to
talk to you about this
i'm working with a
client right now who's
trying to do essentially
personalized content
generation at scale
based on certain
emotional value drivers
and things that are
scientifically known
to resonate with certain
target audiences.
So I want to look at
a way to basically
look at a CRM and
take first party
data, layer in these
attributes which
define these segments
and then generate
content or ads or
could be blog posts
could be emails whatever
um at scale with
something like this
define the scale
hundreds of thousands
tens of thousands
plausible there
are plenty of uh
stable diffusion type
services that can
generate images quickly
yeah the the I did a
project uh again create
a lot of stuff lately
but you can take
out my my agentic
diffusion model and that
that what that does
is are you talking
text-based diffusion
or or just image-based
diffusion ideally
both but i'm i'll
experiment yeah i've
got a model for you and
you probably could use
this neural network
system that i've also
created to do that
but you're you're
going to create a you
definitely probably
want gpus for that but
you you um you You
could ask it to create a
basically a new form
of diffusion model.
And that would be and
then I would probably
I would then create
the model with GPUs,
but that I would compile
it to a WASM based
structure that then I
could invoke similar
to how I'm invoking
my WASMs currently.
So you can run them
client side, you
know, server side,
no worries, you know,
and you offload all
the GPU requirements
at that point because
you've done all
the heavy lifting
and initial training.
So what Nolan just
mentioned is, would
that be the prompt?
Is it like a first
principles approach
where you don't need
a product requirement
doc? You don't need
to know what technology
you're using,
what SDK you just
say. hey, I want to
build a CRM, or what
Nolan just described,
and then the neural
network and the system
will figure out the
best path and the least
path of resistance to
create those tasks.
Well, his description
wasn't all that
precise to start with,
but he clearly has an
idea in his mind of
what it is he wants. But
he had some components
like a CRM system.
He has a whole
bunch of external
data that's external
to the model.
A lot of this
conversation is focused on
the final image generation,
which is a stable
diffusion model out
in the real world
that already exists.
All the part in front
of that is the stuff
that Nolan was describing
that is in his
environment that needs
to collect all these
emotional sentiments,
stuff and the CRM
data and all these.
you would use, you
would build, you would
create a, write a
prompt that builds a
neural network that
collects all of that
information and
eventually crafts a
beautiful prompt that
just gets sent out to
the image generation
model at the end.
Okay. I'm picking up
off of what Jed said
earlier about
declarative approach and
changing the way you
normally develop. So I'm
thinking in terms of
the approach to builds.
but this isn't just
an approach though to
development um so when
you put in a prompt
into an llm and you
get an answer you can
tell the llm to give
me the prompt that
would produce this
answer and so because of
that you can answer
all questions in life
now from the answer and
start with the answer
so what they're
declaring is the answer
the final output and
letting the llm figure
out how to get there
i mean that's the
basis behind spark it
starts with specification
what are you specifying
your final answer
right that is like
with llms now that is
the best way to solve
any problem is with
the final answer yeah
that's well well said
uh ocean you have a
question and by the
way ocean I just uh
took a look at your pr
for the gpu one minor
uh issue but looks
like it's ready to be
pushed that was just
going to be my comment
outside while we're
all chatting your SWAM
has revealed the PR.
I was just going
to mention that.
This is so funny.
Sorry, Reuven.
Go ahead.
This is so funny because
normal software
development
process is to
do PR reviews.
And that's what we're
doing. That's what
you guys are doing
here, a PR review.
I didn't do it. I
just said, go check
out the latest PRs.
Who's going to approve
it? Who's going to
approve it, man?
Well, I'm going to...
well we probably will
have our swarms arguing
against each other
i think that might be
what's happening in
future is like i'll do
the git blame to their
swarm yeah but looks
as far as I can tell is
what I see here it
looks like uh the swarm
is functioning beautifully
you'll see occasional
errors like agent
ids and things but
those are generally self
uh self-fixing right
that means it made
the request to the mcp
without actually
including the id of of the
agent in which it was
trying to work with but
the way that the system
works is it outputs
the error so it knows
how to fix itself um
but you you are currently
training some kind
of neural network we
didn't even give it
any guides if you're
vibing a you're vibing
a completely novel neural
neural network right
now I guided it to
train on a time series
data for trade. So I
was hoping it to pull
the data, but I don't
know what it's doing.
I saw it was searching
the web for something.
Again, the more guidance
you give it, the
better the output it's
going to be, you know,
in any of these
things. So do some deep
research before and
figure out exactly what
you want to build. And
when you do the deep
research, tell the system
that you're going to
use a five or 10 agent
swarm to implement
it and to include
detailed guidance for each
of the members of the
swarm and the mission
that they're on it seems
to work really well
when it thinks it's on
a mission so mention
things like you know
it's a mission and
you'll it'll run for
quite a while um but what
you're seeing right now
is exactly the process
um you can and what
you didn't do here
probably that I would
likely do is is I probably
include it my github
so I can kind of get
a view of it but you
could also i've also
played with this with
slack so you can use a
slack mcp and have it
sort of update what
it's doing to the slack
channel and you can
interact with it there
as well if you prefer
a more text-based
approach for its research
rUv I guess uh that's
all embedded inside
your mc the room swarm
mcp server uh what what's
what's it is it
perplexity or No, it's
using the web search
capability of cloud code.
Oh, that's it? And the
traffic web search.
Yeah.
Yaron, you had a
question there? Yeah.
Yeah, so I'm
following your work.
It's great work.
And I learned
the last tool,
the Cloudflow.
And now you're
showing a new
tool. So what
should I use?
I'm going to update
Cloudflow next week.
Cloudflow is more
rudimentary. so the order of
breakthroughs in the
last few weeks was one
we came out with claude
max suddenly all the
work that I was doing
with my spark uh cli
from last year some of
you guys might remember
cowboy mode which
basically did the same
stuff you're looking
at now but was way too
expensive to operate
you know I was close
to ten thousand
dollars an hour kind of
operational cost so it
was a nice toy but was was
economically not capable
so as soon as claude
came out with claude
max i'm like, oh my
God, I can actually do
these swarms now. So
I went and created a
rudimentary implementation,
uh, which was Claude
Flow, which basically
allowed you to do
some of the things
you're seeing there.
Once I had Claude Flow, I
could suddenly build
things at exponential
increase in capability.
So then I, then
I'm like, well, you
know what I should do?
I should take some of
the stuff that I've
just built. I built
the, the roof fan, the
QDAG and the DAA
stuff, which gives you,
you know, a custom
built neural nets, you
know, adaptive, you
know, forecasting
systems and distributed,
you know, et cetera,
et cetera. What if
I applied that to a
swarm? What would that
do? Which is what I
did last week. And then
I ran my benchmarks
and I'm like, oh my
God, this is working
orders of magnitude
faster and more and,
and getting to the
result with less errors
much more quickly,
this can't be true.
And then that's
when I solicited Jed
and Ocean and Braun
and Shep and a few
others to basically
say, am I hallucinating
this or is this
actually happening?
And here we are. So
now what I'm going to
do, now that we got
the sort of neural
net distributed global
swarm system, I'm
going to integrate
that into Claude Flow.
And because I've got
lots of users of that
and I figured that
makes a nice channel to
get the word out can
we get uh can we get
down down the road
decently with a cloud pro
account or do we need
a cloud max account
i've never tried a pro
i'm what you're looking
at this bro okay yeah
speed up your learning
i highly recommend
getting the cloud max
200 plan commit to a
month and try to get
rate limited every
single day but do it in
a way that's actually
productive so don't
just spin up a hundred
agents to hit the limit
you know what I mean
come up with ideas
that allow you to use
cloud flow or roof swarm
in a way and add a
volume that gets you
rate limited at least
once per day and that'll
help accelerate your
learning perfect
thanks just one just
quick point about I think
yarn did you your
question right I don't
know what level you are
on but personally in
my own experience i
think I would recommend
always starting to
look from cloud spark
because that's the
fundamentals I think I mean
i am only using cloud
flow i'm not i've
tried swarm once or
twice but it just eats
up the token for bro
but I think uh I think
understanding the spark
methodology is really
powerful initially
because I think the more
advanced we go we
lose track of that but
i think that's my personal
kind of experience
but cloud flow on its
own it's very very
powerful it's rudimentary
roof I think to
you but like for what
like i'm using um and
what i'm able to showcase
it is quite powerful
they're all powerful
they're just powerful
in different ways you
know and if if you
had asked me a month
ago what the state of
the art was I would
have pointed you at rue
and my boomerang
orchestrator and that that
was amazing expensive
relatively expensive
but um it was amazing
but but then now that
we're able to do multi
-threaded you know
swarms that looks
like rudimentary it's
nothing but and
who knows what the
next breakthrough
will be maybe that'll
be next week i
don't know but um i
have a quick question
yeah so like we've been
talking about using
swarm to be the orchestrator
to build something
is there a possibility
for the swarm to
be embedded in the
something that is built
That's what
the Roof Swarm
system does. So
that is an SDK.
So, and you can use
the SDK in several
different ways. You can
use my Rust implementation,
which is the core of
everything you see
here. Then I compiled
that Rust to WASMs.
Those WASMs are
portable versions of the
Rust components. And
as an example of how I
could use those for
things like a website or
a CLI, I created the
NPM package. That NPM
package means you can
integrate that into
anything that's capable
of running Node.js.
And you can also use
the WASMs in whether
it's Java, Python,
whatever. And you would
just expose the same
WASMs in those codes.
And all you need to
do to use those WASMs
in Python would
literally be just pointed
at Roof Swarm and say,
do that in Python.
that's crazy yeah so
you've got everything
you need for any
language and and the key
though I i've i've
packaged the the there's a
lot of breakthroughs
here I think you know
the the biggest the
biggest breakthrough is
ability to package these
highly sophisticated
powerful tiny memory
efficient brains as
wasms and then execute
them using cpus secondly
the ability to have
introspection in the
swarms using things
like slack or github or
whatever to to both see
what's happening and
then subtly manipulate
where it's going i
guess that's that's
where my my mind started
to go like let's say i
created an api endpoint
that used roof swarm
and it could accept
you know some incoming
prompt uh you know
that's either guided
like um um deterministic
or non-deterministic
how how could I then
monitor the progress
of what was going on in
that swarm from the api
request as an example
you don't you're what
you do you you're uh
you're adding the you're
adding guidance to
the basically say at
each step whatever that
step might be the step
and you have hooks
now within the structure
of cloud code so
you could literally do
a hook that says at the
successful completion
of a task or something
update slack or github
and then you tell
it how to update and
then as the swarm
progresses you're seeing
what's happening and
more clearly in the
secondary system what what
we're not seeing right
now for example it
It seems to be doing
some training pipeline.
We're not seeing
exactly what it's
doing because you
have to hit control
R or something,
but it's just,
it's kind of obfuscated
a little bit.
So it solves
that problem.
Like it's obviously
doing something.
I just don't know
what it's doing
exactly and why
it's taking so long.
It's probably
doing some kind of
long training cycle,
I would guess.
So to guess how to
serve ability, you'd
probably, hooks would
probably be the answer.
Yeah, I've had some
trouble with hooks
as well. So the
hooks sometimes
cause it to stop
working all together.
I've basically, I've
created my own
hook system
that's Roof Swarm
Space Hooks,
but you can
use it there as
well. All right,
it finished.
Okay, this is what I was
waiting for, to
be honest, guys.
What did we build?
Scroll up slightly and
see what the heck you
built. So this is the
first time I got to
see someone else build
something with my system,
which is exciting.
Well, other than the
guys in the call.
This was, I asked to
create a model to come
up with an RSI, like
that's what we were
discussing in this call.
So as we discussed,
I just started
that. So let's see.
Oh, you took the RSI,
Relative Strength
Indicator? Yeah,
yeah. For whatever, we
were just talking in
this call. So I just
wanted to try that.
Yeah, that's actually,
I've been working
on this recently as
well, but not with
Swarm. I'm going to, I'm
going to, that's my
goal for producing
Swarm. But anyway,
go, please go, Rajesh.
yeah so it says
it's train i'm
i'm in parallel
i'm also looking
at files that
are generated
so I don't see anything
on the model just ask
it to list the files
or run it just run it
and fix the problems
and by the way whenever
you're creating these
sorts of things get
it to create an mcp
for it it makes it way
easier makes it way
easier to work with going
forward everything i
create today has an mcp
because it says so
everything we create
tomorrow will just work
with everything previous
oh so you you ask it
to always include an
mcp as part of the final
module yeah and then
i add it to claude
and then it interacts
with it and then you can
look at the tools right
you just list the
tools and see what it
built yeah exactly are
you still using fast
mcp or is it now rust
native i'm using um i'm
using mostly rust it's
just so much better i
to be I don't know
why anyone uses python
like what am I missing
here like it's easy and
there are billions of
modules available for
every problem I i
translated a hundred
thousand line c library
from c to rust using clod
flow last week so I can
translate it mattered
before right it
mattered before when
everybody was using
packages and you couldn't
just develop something
within a couple minutes
you know that's when
it mattered before but
anymore right rust is
so much so you're the
history though what
you're missing is the
history of rust rUv is
that historically there
was so the cargo packages
were not and they
were just not there
and they were very
unreliable and you just
you couldn't you know all
these python programmers
knew what modules
they wanted and they
weren't available in
rust now that it's the
world is changing on
rust but man three four
year five years ago it
just wasn't there all
right so I see a major
issue with what you
built you never guided
it to use my system it
built a neural network
it did that but it
from scratch rather
than using the neural
network system that i
already had so the key
here what was this is just
bad which is basically
a bad prompt you
what what you what we
should have done is
basically said use the
roof swarm mpx to do it
no uh I thought I did
it so I just saw your
roof uh let me show you
so yeah so it basically
it used roof swarm
to sort of guide the
development and it
created it created an
internal neural networks
for that guidance but
it ended up it ended up
building a neural
network in python so so
so I did this yeah it
just needed to guide it
better so next time
just say you know you
train GrooveSwarm or
something to you know using
it you did you didn't
have to do all the
python stuff so so so
this is what I did i
followed these commands
over here I gave my
objective yeah it's
just it wasn't it wasn't
a clear objective so
just just fyi you didn't
need to do all that
well how would you how
would you it's cool
it's cool it's just
redundant Now you've got
a Python PyTorch-based
model, which took a
while to build. You could
have just used mine
and had it in minutes.
So how do I tweak
it? Yeah, what's
the tweak? You
use the neural
option. So type in
Roof Swarm Neural.
RUVD-ish.
Yeah, and hit enter.
And tell it to do this.
Just copy and paste that.
Or use the MCP to do
it. you know just better
guidance no why do
i give the objective
like what I need to
achieve well i'm not
really sure what your
objective was but you
you're you're you
did create it you did
create neural network
and you created it in
like 20 minutes but uh
you know the objective
was to create a a
neural network model
that were that would
compute uh relative
strength index rsi yeah
using using root using
the roof swarm system
in you know neural
train oh got you okay
you're asking me to
like within the cloud
say that using roof
swarm system calculate
the rsa I mean build
a system or or or do
do the status for a
sec do do you know just
add status yeah status
or tell to yeah tell
to train the yeah i
did it did it trained
it looks like it did
uh uh no it didn't
yeah train the lstm
yeah train the lstm so
give it tell it to
train the lstm model and
tell it how to do it
and I you might want
to use the mcp to do
that but yeah okay so
so these are pre
-configured models that you
include in roost warm
yeah exactly you might
want to create a new
one it's going to
confuse it with your
previous stuff oh yeah yeah
it'll have okay so
so I got it so but no
no you got a model it
just you didn't use
mine and you can see
how long it took that
what you just did would
have happened literally
in a minute if you
were using my wasm it's
a good comparison
it's a good comparison
to the traditional way
and this is pretty this
would have been
amazing a few weeks ago
like oh my god you
just created a kind of
entire neural network in
roughly 20 minutes now
you can do that in
roughly you know a few
seconds how would he
use the model using the
neural option how would
he it would it would
use it train your model
right and then how
does he use it you
can use it as one of
the other options in
the uh go back I think
it's good yeah do the
full help yeah there it
is uh I yeah just
make it bigger I can't
quite see yeah you've
got options for using
neural uh it's under
i think it's an option
or neural under neural
rooms that allows you
to use it it's it's a
dash neural or something
like that and basically
that let it invoke
the model it also uses
the mcp you've got
you get a bunch of
different options you
got to train it first
though most likely i
think you'll use my
default model if you don't
train it though which
is probably good
enough for most people
see I do I do include a
default model so
basically what I do is i
execute all these commands
and get into cloud
and then I asked to
use roofs farm and mcp
and then give the
objective is that right
yeah yeah you you it
it wasn't the guy the
the guidance wasn't clear
it assumed you wanted
to create some yeah
thing but um yeah but
it was working my my
my point was that you
know like is it even
running so yeah it did
it did it where it
built it looks like it
built the whole thing
and you've got a decent
amount. Now you could
create a swarm based
on what you have
currently. You could say,
create a five-agent
swarm to fully optimize
this neural net for
optimal performance.
And then you would
add batch tool, right?
No, it should.
It should automatically
do it. Just
say, create a five
-agent swarm to
optimize the neural
net. The Python code
that he just
generated, right? Yeah.
Good.
So it should have
the batch tool by
itself. Yeah, I
sometimes remind it, but
it's later in
projects, sometimes it
needs a little
reminding, but I'm mostly
curious to see if
it's going to do it.
By the way, Ruv,
I... Yeah, spawn.
You made it. Yeah,
there you go.
So it's specialized,
so it's self
-selected, the MCP,
it's creating...
Let me see, what is
that? Oh, we missed it.
it was showing under
the tasks right but uh
it's gone yeah it
should be underneath oh
yeah here it is okay
so we have architecture
training no it's gone
it just briefly appeared
for a moment it was
it's it's it's working
it's it's working i'm
gonna stand up for
guys you're gonna see
me wandering around my
my office here I i
gotta take off here a
few minutes today's
actually a relatively
quiet day for me but
it's the swarm's working
so now what's happening
is it's going to
optimize it's going to
self-optimize your neural
network and it's using
my hooks that's good
yes it's all working
it's freaking amazing
uh it's it's I mean
it's hard to believe
what i'm seeing it's
it's hard to believe i'm
i'm i'm i'm amazed at
this thing it's like
oh we just conjured a
neural network out of
out of a single line of
let build me something
and we accidentally
built in python now
we're going to
optimize the thing we
accidentally built so
what's going to be the final
outcome then it's not
going to be a python
uh set of code now it's
going to be something
else no it'll be python
but you then then
what you then then what
you could do if you
really want to take
this a step further um
say uh after you optimize
to rust and optimize
the **** out of it
further and you'll
have the world's best
rsi model guaranteed oh
yeah that's cool and
and i'm just monitoring
my activity like the
kernel task is like
it spun up threads and
it's not like I mean
zoom is taking more
cpu i'm using i'm using
your i'm using your cpu
i'm not even bothering
with gpu the the
additions uh oceans
added it will add all it
will you'll be able to
leverage your gpu
here this afternoon i
can't imagine how fast
it is going to be with
gpu then I mean yeah
it's gonna be it'll be
crazy are you running
on is that a mac you're
running on raging
yeah it's a mac m2 pro
with uh 18 gig what
is your stack ru
there's claw flow code
spaces are you still
using requestee do
you have any rate
limits or any I i my
requestee went from uh
thousands of dollars
a month to I I
think I spent $33 last
month on Requestee.
But you can't
use Requestee
with the Claude
subscription.
You can. Yeah, you can.
Yeah, you can
switch the API.
And for my
commercial customers
who are concerned
about the terms,
they're actually
using the API.
They don't care if
it costs whatever.
So you can get your
Claude Mac subscription
and tell it to
use Requestee? How
do you do that? When
you log in to Cloud
Code, you have the
option to log in
using Cloud Max or
to use an API key.
But I haven't been
able to get both
working concurrently
on a failover basis.
But the API key
is your direct
anthropic API key
because you don't
get an API key
for Cloud Code.
When you log in using
the API key instead
of using the Cloud
Code Max, you can then
define an API key and
a custom endpoint.
Yeah, exactly. So
you cut out JIT.
Yeah, you can
use the custom
endpoint. Yeah, it
definitely works.
Yeah, it's pretty cool.
Reuven, congratulations.
Jad, ****, guys, Braun,
incredible.
Yeah, it is pretty
incredible, I think.
I think we
collectively crack
swarm-based intelligence.
and the jump in
capability is I
think we're just
scratching the
surface in terms
of benchmarks.
I think we take
this and we get a
the top of the line GP
and I think
people will start
thinking certain
three letter
acronyms is pretty
freaking close.
I wouldn't mind a
government contract.
Skynet's contract.
yeah and I i'm curious
what you guys build
with all the daa
stuff like that's you
know someone's idea
about study at home for
agents you could
literally have that up
and running this
afternoon i'm curious to
see how we can make
use of the um i'm sorry
oh uh I was gonna say
i'm very curious to
see how we can make
use of the autonomous
gpu resource manager
for the DA, like that
sounds really really
cool and then we can
exchange GPU resources
across the globe.
I think that that we
should do that, why not?
Let's create, let's
do pre-GPU darkpool.
Let's do it, I've
already got the nodes in
place, the DAA nodes
are already running
so all you guys need
to do is contribute
to the existing and
you'll get the RUV tokens
that are completely
worthless but uh
they're uh and unlike
the uh the scammers
behind bitcoin there's
not some random anonymous
uh billionaire that
you have to worry
about all right i'm
done yeah uh thanks
everyone so thank you
i ran out of the limit
so i'll continue and
let you know yeah uh
rajesh thank you for
taking the time to
show us how you're using
it as it was really
there's some It was
really rewarding to
see it working on
somebody else's machine.
So thanks for doing
it. And anyone that
wants to contribute,
we've got an active
community now
contributing, doing exactly
with the sort of stuff
that you're seeing.
You know, go into,
create a branch,
update, add,
invent, and do a PR,
and we'll include
it. Literally, all
you need to do –
and if you clone
the RUV fan repo,
you'll get all the
GitHub stuff as well.
I haven't included
that in the RUV swarm.
You mean all
the issues and
the PRs and the tracking?
The GitHub swarm.
Yeah, there's
a whole GitHub
swarm that you'll
get when you
use that repo.
It's working pretty
well, by the way.
I managed to, I
wrote you in LinkedIn
that I didn't get
the crypto market
scanner to work, but
eventually I did.
It's doing a good job.
It is working well.
I've been running
my Neurotrader and
it's outperforming the
market quite a bit.
So yeah, it's
all, you see
exactly how it's built.
Like literally you
built an RSI tool. Now,
the only difference
I would suggest, if
you're if you're looking
to a trading application
clone the roof uh fan
uh repo completely
open up the uh you
know basically open
up cloud code and
dangerously skip permissions
it'll get all the
commands that are
already in that repo
and then basically say
create me the world's
most powerful trading
system so what's
preventing you of building
skynet you could like
uh this is this is
skynet this is this
is everything you need
for skynet it's it's
autonomous it's self
it's self-improving
it it has an economic
system it can it can
literally hack anything
on the planet without
any real effort and it
it essentially is
is autonomous to the
point where once it's
decentralized enough
it'll be pretty much
impossible to take down
and you can like
have a black hole of
money you can if
you outperform the
market eventually
you you're going to
take all the money
hey rob should we
uh announce the new
york meetup yeah
what is that you guys
doing another one in
new york we're doing
the real one that the
previous meetup was
to chat about meetup.
I believe it is July 10.
I'm trying to find
the LumaLink Ocean.
I don't know if you
have it available.
Yeah, let me go
find it as well.
While you looked at it,
when is the next
online session?
How frequently are
you doing these?
Yeah, we usually
do Thursdays and
Fridays. Tomorrow,
I'm not because I
promised I wasn't
going to work. So
I'm going to try
really hard not to.
um yeah I know i'm
in trouble I know
that I know those
words man I know those
words good luck i've
got i've gone into
like mad scientist
territory lately and
i'm trying to pull
myself out of that
for 24 hours yeah
save your marriage rUv
man save your marriage
dude exactly so i'm
yeah so our our uh
new york city agent
meetup is thursday
july 10th on uh union
square and the And
currently, you have
to join the wait
list in Luma, but I'm
sure not everybody's
going to show up.
Okay.
And just share the link.
Yeah.
I can promote that
for you. People are
always messaging. And
I think we're doing one
in Toronto next week
as well. I think we
do like the first
Tuesday of every month.
I don't know if
Rob's still here,
but anyway, for
anyone in Toronto,
you can come meet
us in person.
um all right that
was that was uh that
that's that for this
week happy uh fourth
and canada day for
folks in canada and
if you're celebrating
anything else happy
that till next week
thank you thanks
everyone thank you
hopefully the next week
it's gonna be you
and not uh replicate
yeah seriously i'm
excited and whatever
you guys build share
link to me I want
to i'm curious how
you guys end up using
this there's bugs
if you find them
just do issues in
the repo and i'll fix
those which repo uh
roof and for now okay
all right thank you
everyone okay bye