okay well last set
lots of lots of uh
activity this week
for sure guys and uh
appreciate everyone
to join yesterday was
absolutely uh bonkers
for sure um we did the
live a live coding
session and had an
unusually large amount
of people show up
to take a look at
what's being built in
the sort of Claude
code area that I've
personally been super
excited by this week.
I've been trying to
get this to go live
today, but apparently
it's not going to
happen. So we're doing
this old school. We're
recording it. So
that'll be what it is.
Rob, how's it going?
Great. Great, great,
great. Yeah, it
was a monster week,
eh? Claude Spark.
Claude Flow. that was
last week we're right
we're we're already
we're already past that
that that that was
popular also that that
was the underlying
premise but yeah yeah yeah
boy has that taken
off there was a there
was a lot of folks that
showed up yesterday
and uh yep that'll
push the us pushing the
calf up that's for sure
we've got it we got a
great lineup today
ruben um we've got three
folks here Let me just
pull up my notes. So
first off, Everett
Clevin, and he comes to
us by way of David Young's
blood. And Everett,
he's the founder of
Evangelist Technologies.
They're an AI-driven
studio, or native
product studio. And
he's going to be giving
us a quick demo on an
ECS, Entity Component
System, that is a
simulation engine. So
that should be pretty
cool. And then Chris
Phillips, he's a member.
He's going to be talking
about improving MCP's
identity layer, and
he's going to be
sharing the work on the
first OIDC Federation
sign-in to MCP. So that
should be neat, too.
And then we've got
****** V3, and ******
V3 is back from New York
City, the Big Apple,
and he's the co-founder
of Human Frontier Labs,
a long-term member,
and he's going to
be doing a demo on a
Next.js app that uses
Sonic Pi, uses AI to
write compositions. So
it's an evolution of the
music platform that
he's been working on.
So it should
be pretty fun.
Yeah, so we've been
having a little
technical difficulties
with this and we're
thinking about
potentially putting
together a production
team to sort of help
with some of the
logistics of getting
the show off in a
more structured way?
Anything you want to
tell the community
or solicit or share?
Yeah, absolutely.
So, you know, as
every new sort of tool
comes along and we see
the impact of drops
like Cloudflow and
the audience expands,
and then we have all
of the chapters that
are opening up around
the world and the events
that are taking place.
The need for us to
elevate across technical
scalability and
production value and
managing that growth,
those growth vectors,
is really apparent now.
So, yeah, Ruben, you've
correctly identified
that we need to put
together production
team and uh we'll be
putting the signals
out and starting the
yeah the the calm
channel on that for folks
that have experience
in that space uh
on the distribution
side restreaming
everything along those
lines um and also
how it supports the
marketing team the
marketing group and how we
work together with
that so uh looking
forward to it's going
to be an an exciting
area of focus over
the coming months. So
if there's folks out
there with experience
in this space, feel
free to reach out,
touch in. We're putting
the team together.
Yeah, I like to
say it's kind of
like community
television, you
know, production
value currently.
We've kind of grown
organically and, you
know, it does well.
But today's a perfect
example. I haven't been
able to get the live
version to work for some
unknown reason. So we
don't have a live
broadcast, you know, so
having a team that can
help with logistics.
So I'm not trying to
do it while, you know,
ad-libbing is probably
going to make it a
little easier. So that,
which is exactly what
I'm currently doing.
I'm trying to get the
live version up and
running while I'm talking
to you guys in the
hopes of sharing it on
LinkedIn. So fingers
crossed, I'm clicking
the button. I saw a
live stream thing start.
Let's see. So, yeah,
this week for me has
been all about clock
code and clock flow in
particular. So, I've
been busy on lots of
things. Let me show you.
Let me show you guys.
Clock code does
rule for sure.
All right. So, clock
code, for those that
aren't familiar, is a
system that came out,
well, I think it was
March at this point,
that it essentially
allows you to use Claude
as a command line
tool. It's very similar
to things like Ader
and other sort of CLI
-based tools. So it
allows you to sort of
interact with it.
So on the weekend, I
thought, hey, why not
create a kind of Claude
-based, or last week,
I created a mechanism
using sort of the Claude
MD file to essentially
interact with various
parts of it. And
then it occurred to
me, well, I should
actually create a library
script to do that.
So I launched
that on Monday.
And what do you know,
several thousand
downloads later,
the system was
swarmed with interest.
And we did a live
cast yesterday and a
thousand people showed
up. but it's, I, we
can go from idea to
product in moments.
So I went from Monday,
I should create, I
should create this,
uh, orchestration
system to getting
Claude code to build it,
launching it on Tuesday,
something like 50,000
downloads by Wednesday.
It's amazing that you
can go from idea to
50 freaking thousand
downloads in, in less
than like a day and a
half. Like It's just
it's that in itself is
mind blowing. So anyway,
I'm on V43 and I noticed
there was a quick
bug. So I'm going to
show you guys first,
I'm solving the bug.
And secondly, I'm going
to show you how some
of this stuff works.
But from a high level,
what this does is
allows you to have
multiple agents that can
kind of, you know,
collaborate with each
other. So right now,
while I'm talking to you
guys, I have this system
building. So we can
go here. I basically
said update it to be
45 and that and then
i'm i can in this case
i'm going to launch it
but before i do check
this out this is the
amount of code i've
developed since since
the scroll back up
there we go so this i've
created 77 000 lines
of typescript for
this project so far
complexity level is pretty
good and that if you
believe ss or scc
that's worth 10 million
dollars and would
take 22 months with 41
people working on it
that's just since monday
on this one project
and keep in mind i'm
actually working on a
bunch of different things
so look at all these
other tabs these are
all working on different
things i'm i've
got going on concurrent
things and this is
just a hobby i'm just
doing this for just for
the fun of it like i
got no real plan here
other than i thought
it'd be cool to build
something. So the fact
that I could build a
project, if you believe
this, even if it's
a fraction of that,
even if it's $100,000,
that's still
amazing. I could put
out something
worth $100,000 in a
week, even if it's
not $10 million.
So it's probably
worth somewhere
between nothing
and $10 million.
And the fact that it's
got 50,000 downloads
probably indicates
it's probably worth
close to $10 million,
I would say. So this
is a glimpse into
the future of sort of
the development process
and the way that
you can develop things
quickly and iteratively
just from idea of
thought. So right
this morning, what
I've been working on
is I've been working
on a sort of Bruce
code style extension
kind of like this, but
for the cloud flow
system. So I'm not,
I haven't launched
that yet, but you can
see here that we've
got, you know, tons.
And this is, this
SCC ran before
I even built that.
So this number
is probably
even higher now.
So you can see all
the commands and
all the structure.
So I'm building that
out right now. But
what does it do?
Let's just jump in here
and I'll clear this.
So I'm running
right now in my dev
environment
because I noticed
there was a bug.
So when you clone
the system, you
get a bin folder.
The bin folder
basically is a kind of
wrapper that allows
you to execute
things. So in this
case, but if you're
running it locally
using the MPX command,
you'd run, let's go
back to the set for a
sec. you're gonna
run the, first you're
gonna install it. So
you're gonna install
cloud code and then
once that's installed,
you're gonna go and
you're gonna run something
like this to get it
running. And then
you can run different
other commands. And I
actually added a UI
as well, which I'll
show you here in a moment.
But basically you've
got the ability to
run commands like
start my project and
I'll show you some of
this stuff. So back to
getting this running,
I'll go back here and
I'm gonna run bin.
so ignore the
bin unless you're
cloning the
thing directly
cloud flow and
then we run help
help gives you a little
help dialogue lots
of different options
keep in mind this is
this is optimized for
the cloud code system
to basically work with
the clods code system
as a kind of swarm of
different coding agents
that can collaborate
and build collectively
so when you think
about root code root
code essentially had
this idea that you could
you could get this thing
to automate through
these various features,
right? You've got
the Spark Orchestrator,
but it was essentially
sequential and task
-based, meaning I
couldn't get this thing
to really work beyond
the context of a
single sort of threaded
environment. It would
build, it would create
subtasks, it would come
back to the regular
task, and it would
build. It could build
for hours. I think I
had the longest run was
36 hours straight. But
this is different in
the sense that it's
multi-threaded. It means
I can run these in
various threads. So in
terms of I can run
agents, I have memory,
I've got coordination
systems that allows the
system to understand
the context of all
the other systems that
are actually running.
So in this case, if I
want to run different
modes, I can do
Spark, I can do Mode.
And these are
all versions.
If I want to do Swarms,
I can do Swarm, and
I can do Help on that
as well. And this will
show me different
modes. so i've got modes
that allow it to to
have auto you know to
automatically determine
the best approach which
is kind of what i
use by default it can
research it can do
software development and in
this scenario it
orchestrates different
agents so it so if it
took 36 hours to build
you know something
previously now i can spawn
10 of these and it'll
take three and a half
hours and and what's
more interesting is
because clod max is
basically all you can eat
it doesn't cost really
anything other than a
couple hundred bucks
that it cost me for the
service. So it's orders
of magnitude less.
So my requestee bill
went from like hundreds
of dollars per week
to basically nothing
this week. I think
it was like 30 or 40
bucks. And I use that
mostly for MCPs at
this point. So in this
case, if I want to
do, you know, if I want
to execute something,
I'll go here and
I'll execute a swarm.
You know, I can just
go here. I got to do
bin. I forgot I'm not,
i'm running my local
and it will be bin and
you'll see here that
i i've got the various
you know components
being executed i might
clean this up a little
bit but basically i'm
creating a swarm and
then it's gonna it's
gonna do it whatever
it's gonna do i'm gonna
actually cancel after
now and show you more
a prettier version of
this which is basically
the spark mode so
spark test now i get
different modes so i
could run for example
tdd if i wanted to run
the test driven
development mode or DevOps.
In this case, I'm just
going to run
Spark normally.
And then we see here
that we're executing
the different
commands. And then it's
going to start doing
various things. I'm
going to cancel
it because I don't
actually want to do it.
But what I'm essentially
doing is I'm injecting
a combination
of complex sort of
task allocation. So
it's saying, here's
all the things it
needs to do. Here's how
you need to operate.
and it'll essentially
build forever.
Now the other
thing I did this
morning, which
is kind of cool,
again, I'm going
really fast, hopefully
it just makes
sense. But the
other thing you can
do is I added the
slash command
option. So if you're
more comfortable
using clod directly,
you can just head clod.
And when you
use clod, now
you've got the ability,
oh, I don't have the
commands. So let's
invoke those. So if I
go clod, I can go bin,
clo init spark force
this is going to create
a clod folder here
right here called
clod these give it
different commands so the
these these commands
are essentially giving
it the ability to run
no I did it didn't
run come I didn't run
for whatever reason
so I'm gonna jump
to another tab the
demo gods aren't aren't
aren't smiling on me,
so let's go here,
and I'll run it here.
That was a dev
environment, probably the
reason. But anyway, when
you slash, now you've
got these slash
commands. So these slash
commands allow you
to invoke each of the
commands directly from
within Clot itself.
So for example, the
tutorial mode or MCP
modes, and you can
customize all this yourself
as well, using the
command structure.
So basically just MDs.
And similar to the
root structure, these
provide guidance for
each of the commands. And
if you wanna add your
own command, all you
need to do is basically
go in here and add
a folder or file name
and you've got different
options. So these
are basically telling
you how to operate the
swarm modes and things
like that. So tons
and tons of options.
So let's go back
here for a moment
and see what
else we got here.
So I mean, this is a
remote environment.
So in this remote
environment, I can just
run flow. yeah I think
I need to do UI it's
UI oops no I can
remember what my command
is maybe it's devil
slash UI mmm I gotta
I gotta remember
there's too many things
for me to remember
let's see here start
all right let's do start
UI. So now I've got
a, I have an entire UI
system. Well, it's,
it's a command line
UI anyway, that allows
you to have an event
bus, the orchestrator,
and this, this
gives you idea of, of
what's, what's happening.
And I'm just going
to start all those.
And then you're,
you're able to run the
different minutes. So
now, now the MCP server is
running, the memory
management system is
running and, and I can,
I can interact with
those. I've got different
options as well for
like orchestration
so if i want to go to
number three i can see
like what's in progress
so it provides a kind
of what all those
agents are doing because
when you're running
dozens of agents it's
hard to visualize that
so this provides the
ability to see what each
of the agents is
actually doing in this
case you've got a research
agent a coding agent
development analyst
thing things like that
so this this is it's
i'm not gonna lie it's
a work in progress like
one one guy juggling
multiple projects and
clients if there's
bugs feel free to use
clod code to fix my
bugs and do a do a pr
on it you know i based
on the amount of interest
we're seeing this
is this could be big
i'm getting tons and
tons of interest um
and i'm showing you i'm
just scratching the
surface on all the
capabilities of the system
like let's just go let
right back here you can
see that i built i'm
i took a vibe approach
this i you know there
was an image going
around what a vibe coder
looks like where it's
like a car with like
a billion things
attached to it this is
totally that but that's
okay um so we got the
memory systems we got
monitoring we've got
we've got all kinds of
different things the
moral of the story
all you need to do is
point clod at clod flow
and it'll orchestrate
everything for you
that's the the simplest
way to think about it
and if you run the bugs
there's probably bugs
there's a lot of i've
got a ton of stuff
let me know or just or
just fork the repo and
point plot at it and
say go fix that and
and you should be in a
good spot i've also got
ru modes integration
for those who are sort
of switching between
there's a lot of work
i need to do on the
mcp side of things
so i it does have mcp
integration i typically
right now i'm using clis
i find them more secure
and easy to use but
again you can build
pretty much anything
you want with this thing
i i i'm building all
kinds of crazy stuff and
my next major release
other than some minor
bug fixes is going
to be a uh the actual
vs code extension so
you'll i push the
fork out it go you can
probably go to what is
it the uv or 44 ui and
you'll see that there's
a ui folder still
some work to do but
this this will give us a
VS Code style interface,
so that'll be cool.
Let me pause for
a moment. Any
questions from
the crew here?
You guys quite a bunch
today? Or did I... I
think everyone's just
trying to take it in.
Yeah.
One quick question.
How much of,
how would you say it,
these capabilities
that you're seeing here
are already kind of
built into um the cloud
code with and you're
just adding kind
of a nice layer or
accessibility how much of
them none of it so clock
clock code essentially
allows you to invoke
coding and so what
i've done is i've given
it the ability to
do swarms memory and
orchestration none of
that exists within clock
code so so you you
you can you can try
to using the approach
that i did last week
if you guys remember
the cloud spark files
you can kind of fake it
a little bit and using
md files and get it
and then you can create
additional um terminal
sessions and kind
of get it to a
rudimentary version what i
did i took this to
like a whole new level
i i've got memory i've
got orchestration i
got swarming so you
can see here the the
memory folders and
various other components
that it's it's substantial
it's substantial
you know so i've got
eight asian orchestration
systems and sessioning
and you know lots
and lots of features
none none of the
coordination features
exist within the structure
of um a cloud code
it should now it does
i have a
question with the
cloud code and
your uh code flow
sure uh what plan is
it recommended for
it like there's max 5x
max 20x or it depends
on the project size
i think i think for
you don't need to
spend 100 bucks first
and foremost like i'm
i'm a crazy developer
doing 50 things at
once i just showed
you i did apparently
10 million dollars
just in this one
project but if you're
getting started the 20
plan will work now you
might not get a lot
and you might max it
out quickly if you're
doing the swarms.
So if you're using
the $20 plan, maybe
start with a little
more targeted.
Maybe use the spark
option slash spark
and start with
a single thread.
Maybe try two threads,
but don't go to
like three or four.
You're probably
gonna max out your
plan too quickly.
The $100.
My project is 200K tokens
around that.
That's the size.
Yeah, that's nothing.
Yeah, so you
should be good.
with a $20 plan for that.
The reason I'm
maxing it out is I'm
running concurrently
dozens of agents,
right? And I'm
maxing out the $200
plan by running like
15 concurrent agents
across multiple
BS code instances.
So if you're not
me, you're probably
gonna be okay with the
$100 or $20 to start.
And if you max it
out, just upgrade.
But it's substantially
cheaper than Roo.
like if i'm paying
100 bucks a day
for rue i'm now paying
200 bucks a month
so it's the cost is
you is is substantially
less everett uh nice
to meet you i see
you get your hand up
yeah yeah it's great
it's great to meet
you honestly you are
working on like the exact
same space that i've
been like focusing
on but it's amazing
to see this particularly
applied to like
the most cutting edge,
like instantiation of
an agent that we've
seen so far. Um, so
it's really cool. Um,
my question on cloud
flow particularly
is on, you know, the
communication side,
what, what medium are you
using to, to enable the
agents to communicate?
Are you using
particular protocols?
Um,
you know, there's
just, there's so many
different options
out there and maybe
you vibe coded that,
but like, I mean,
there's nothing wrong
with that either.
the so this is a
question i get a lot and
what you're really
asking me is am i using
a2a adp or mcp and no
you know no actually no
oh i'm i'm what i'm
actually asking is like
in terms of the so i
guess if you are using
mcp that i guess
that would answer my
question the uh communication
maybe like schema
is also what i was
kind of thinking about
and then if everything's
just happening over
the network and like
the memory buffers are
just like maybe JSON
files are just running
over the network.
That's something else.
I've got two
implementations. So one
is a, it is just a J
a JSON style memory
and coordination
buffer. And you'll
see that in the, the
memory folder. And
it's essentially
that that is giving
it, you know, a
structured memory.
It's, it's nothing
too, too complicated.
The other, and this
is, you'll need to dig
through the various
settings and a lot of them
is I'm using SQL light
and the SQL light
is information in a
pseudo vector style. Not,
it isn't actually
vector, but I'm, I'm
mimicking the structure
of a similarity search
and structure within SQL
light and then saving
it in, in that, in
basically a, a sort of
more structured SQL
versus JSON structure.
Now I you look at like
work that i've done
my spark 2 i've actually
implemented a true
vector implementation
using fast f-i-a-s-s
implementation of vector
which is amazing if
you're going to use
vector that's probably
the way to go i didn't
go with that because
i built this on monday
but you know just
to throw it out there
but if i was like if if
i was like going to
build this as like a
startup which i'm not
i would um i would
probably go with something
like that and if you
look at my fact
implementation from a few
weeks ago that actually
uses the fias approach
so what but i built
that in python this
is built in typescript
there this is like a
a jigsaw puzzle of all
the crazy **** i've
built over the last
month yeah that's great
and i love the cli so
um amazing yeah it's
it's it's a little
bonkers uh quick question
on the on the mcp
reuven uh if you install
claude flow does it
automatically set up a
bunch of mcp for you
no but i'm thinking
manually do that because
i find that setting
up mcps in claude is
basic claude is a pain
you you're not alone
so the the takeaway
from claude code mcps
is this it only works
locally currently
as far as i can tell
so if your mcp is a
remote like you're using
composio or one of
those mcp run type
services it isn't
going to work so if you
want if you want to
use those services you
have to create an mcp
abstraction there's
lots of them around
now but basically
allows you to run a
local version that then
goes out to the remote
version it's i don't
know why they did
it that way so they
changed the schema
roof uh david i'll post
an example mcp
configuration in the chat
yeah i've looked
everywhere man it's just
it's just a it's like
it's so easy and ruined
klein but it's so
painful it's the most
weakly done part of
clawed code yeah so the so
what i did because
i 100 agree with you
it's it's a little bit
awful i'm using clis
you can create a cli
sub clis in literally a
second if if i need to
interact with superbase
i just use the
superbase cli if i need
to interact with aws i
use bodo or something
so i'm using the clis
and then as part of
the orchestration layer,
I'm basically saying,
use those CLIs. And
that works amazing.
Now, the one part
that you have to be
very careful about
in this is I'm using
the dangerously
whatever parameter.
And if you're using
this against a
production environment,
well, don't.
It's a bad idea.
This is beta. Did
I mention I built
this on Monday?
You probably want to
test the **** out of
it before you point
this to anything near
a real production
environment. The second
thing you're going
to notice, this thing
is power hungry.
I pointed at my
Hugging Face system
for the SAP desk thing
I've been working
on for my machine
model. And the
first thing it
did is it went and
bought the most
expensive possible GPU.
And I told it, never
use that GPU. And
then three iterations
in, it did it again.
It seems it's going
to want to use the
most powerful tools
available to it. And I
can't get it to stop
doing that. I don't
know, you know, no
matter what, how I try.
So the only way to
get around that is
to do is to put in
secondary limitations.
So you're going to get
the proxy it basically.
Oh yeah.
Good to know. Alex,
you got a, you
got a question?
Yeah, I do. So Roof,
like, let's say
we had a, an idea
to build like just
something brand new
right now. Like how
would you, are you
changing your approach
now with cloud
flow or with cloud
flow versus is what
you've been doing in
the past when it
came to using Spark?
Like, are you now
just typing in the
idea? Are you
doing deep research
inside of open, you
know, using open AI
and kind of using
that process still?
Well, Cloud
Code has the web
search capability
built right
in, so I don't
need perplexing.
And so all I need
to do in the sort of
research phase is it
basically says, use the web
search capability in
Cloud Code. And it
goes out, finds it, it
iterates and creates
the deep research all
directly in the system.
Now, I have a tendency
to want to do my deep
research using like
either the cloud desktop
or the mobile app or
chat gpt mobile apps
i'm just you know
sitting chilling thinking
about why i want to
build and then i'll
use deep research there
and then i copy the
file in that that's
what i did for the uh vs
code extension that
i've been working on
so i i basically used
the deep research uh
capability in chat gpt
connected it to this,
give me a plan to
build a, uh, cursor
style UI as a VS
code extension.
Okay, cool. So, but
you know, in the
past you had like a
pretty robust prompt
that you were using
to kind of like
start the project
and say, I want a
full implementation
plan, PhD level.
You know, you, you
kind of talk about, do
you know, you bring
up all these things.
Are you now just
simply describing your
idea or are you still
defining kind of
how you want to approach
the project as part
of your initialization
of the project?
That's all built in.
So that's built in.
So if you look at
the primary clod dot
md prompt that gets
created in the root
directory, that's kind
of the overarching
guidance system, and
then the dot clod
folder are the sort of
subcommands. So I've
recreated the entire
root code system
in clod, but with the
additional ability
for multi-threading,
swarms and other sort
of orchestration that
that Rude doesn't do.
Okay, so you're just
starting a project
by saying, here's
my idea, go make it.
That's like, you're
literally just describing
it now. Well, yeah,
so when I showed
you guys that project,
which seems like
ages ago now, that
I did the sort of
ultrasonic system that
basically embeds secret
commands encrypted
in the 18 to 20
kilohertz range for
audio, I used this system
to basically say, what's
the most complicated
thing you can
possibly build that's
never been built?
That was my guidance.
And then I pointed at
that and i let it run
for about 20 hours
and it popped out the
ultrasonic system just
and and you know if
you guys saw the other
day it totally works
it's a lot of people
think think that it
was it was crazy and
might infringe on
people's privacy or
whatever but that's a
secondary problem it
totally works so um so
did you say so that the
the difference between
you what the root
code setup and this
is that there's no
native extension for vs
code at the moment
so you're interacting
with Claude within VS
Code at the terminal.
Correct.
And then I spawn
multiple terminals
and I can have a swarm
on top of a swarm
on top of a swarm.
And then I've got
different models
for the swarms based
on sort of, oh, one
thing I learned.
You can't do evolutionary
AI processes with
Claude Code. It stops
it. I have not been
able to get around
evolutionary structures.
if anyone figures out a
way to do that it it's
um it basically stops
it i get a big giant
error it says no which
is interesting what
do you mean by evolution
alignment issue
alignment issue it's
100% aligned so i built
this i built but i
built a secondary system
to handle evolution
independent of it which
i'll maybe roll out
next week but if you're
trying to do uh like
an evolutionary swarm
it'll stop you you
have to call it like
unsupervised learning or
something but it doesn't
let you go down the
the sort of modular as
self-evolving source
code structures which
is unfortunate uh yeah
yeah hi how are you
guys um yeah interesting
i think someone said
there on on linkedin
the other day that uh
ai will will come from
a product not from an
llm um but i uh i
have a question just a
basic one because i work
with uh teams and um
uh how do you manage
uh multiple people
uh working uh uh with
um claude flow when
so so the way i'm
thinking about this
is that you know you'd
have a jira board
with tickets on it
and an ai could pick
out uh pick a ticket
or uh or a person
could take out a ticket
so to integrate um
ai directly into teams
and managed solve
that that part of the
problem uh how does uh
because you talked
about mcp there uh
and not being really
great you talked
about cli being
your your tool of
choice what's the
process for um cloudflow
pulling tickets
off at your board
jira is easy so jira
basically all i did
there is um i did a test
on jira actually i was
curious and i i created
dot env and then i
basically said you use
the uh the token for
jira and this api
endpoint and go do it
that's it that's all
i said and it went and
figured it out so you
used the api i used the
api and did it in like
seconds like it literally
just figured it out
and it was it was so
easy i didn't even
think about it um so for
a lot of things all
you really need to do
And because it has the
web search capability
built in, it goes and
just figures it out.
And because I have
multi-threading, one of
those agents is just
going and doing that while
the other agents are
doing other things.
So you just create your
ENV, put in the API,
and then you said, go
do it. Just go fetch
it. Can you say, like,
go fetch a ticket?
I just said, go
use the JIRA API to
get the latest
tickets and fix them.
Nice.
Okay. and then and
then and then and then
i didn't what one thing
to watch out for i
didn't tell it to do
the the commit it went
and just did that
without me asking so you
have to be you have
to be really careful
it it has a tendency
to go and do things
that it thinks you want
even if you don't want
it to do that like
it's it you notice
that i've got version
10.043 or 44 now of this
uh system it's because
it kept publishing
the **** mpm and it
did it dozens of times
and i wasn't paying
attention so i came
back yeah and suddenly
i'm like on version
22 of of the mpm because
it's published it
to the mpm 20 freaking
times then i had to
go say it never published
the freaking mpm
so that's funny oh yeah
they make them they
make them helpful too
helpful like i don't
want you to publish
it until i tell you to
publish it so yeah
there's definitely some
guidance uh things
that we need to work
through there it's a
little it wants to be
too helpful um i know
we're on we're at time
here uh thank you i
know this is so i know
we get some great uh
guests lined up here
uh rob yep i just
want to do a quick
check in a ***** v3
had to hop off a little
early and so let
me just see if he's
still with us or not
***** you still here
uh i don't no i think
you had to run all
right so everett nice
to meet you and welcome
yeah thanks so much
um honored to be here
and to demo some
more cool tech and um
honestly just it's great
to be here with a bunch
of other vibe cutters
a bunch of other
folks looking to push
the envelope and you
know um i think
particularly throughout the
last two years you know
there's just been a
lot of pain knowing
what these technologies
can do but like not
quite getting there and
in these last two
months it's really it's
really different it's
really different clad
4 and gemini 2.5 pro
i i genuinely think
we've seen a big
difference in fact um the
project i'm to show
you would not have been
completed if Cloud4
Opus had not come out.
So even simple things
like setting up
your debug environment,
I think are huge.
But without further ado,
I'm just going to
go ahead and jump
into my project here,
if you don't mind.
Yeah.
okay so hi everybody
i'm everett and uh i've
been working on this
fever dream that i've
had uh since chat tbt
came out in 2023 and
um i have to say it's
taken a long time it
took me probably about
a year and a half if
not almost two years
to figure out that i i
wanted to build this
simulation engine, but
Archetype is effectively
a simulation engine
purpose-built for multi
-agent orchestration.
Context provisioning
at scale is hard.
Right now, honestly,
our biggest limitations
are rate limits from
closed-source providers,
and I've got a
solution for that, but
that's actually not a
part of this project.
There's some other
great tools that
I'd love to talk
more about, but
I don't have a ton
of time. So I'm
just going to dive
right into this.
So Archetype
is very similarly
architected after other
game engines. Game
engines like Unity employ
the entity component
system architecture
to decouple state from
all of your different
processors and
schema definitions in
your components. And
this is essentially the
diagram of what the
code base looks like.
The point of Archetype,
like I said, is to
enable support for
large-scale simulations.
That's not intended for
real-time use cases,
which is great because
we don't necessarily
need to run at like
full real like 100 i
don't know 100 hertz
timing for running agents
um but the uh beauty
of how this ended up
working is that the
combination of the
technologies that i've
used and the way that this
ended up being
architected enables me to
run multiple worlds
in parallel running on
thread safe like
transactions on um individual
archetype tables and
so you're able to run
multiple uh archetypes
in parallel which
are like classes of what
you could call maybe
like a player or an
enemy um and you could
run those worlds in
parallel as well the
goal being something very
similar to what cloud
flow has which is
like recursive agent
simulation so i want a
personal agent that's
better than everybody
else's right then i
want my agent to go
and and simulate the uh
potential outcomes and
even run simulations
themselves recursively
um i had a few uh key
references in prior art
i think that's critical
for any vibe coded
project that you
reference something
that's kind of canonical
and has a lot of robust,
like, thought that
went into it. And so I
referenced that here.
And as much as
there's, like, all this
complexity on the back
end, the scripting side
is really what I've
been focused on, because
I've been trying to
limit the complexity
by which a large
language model needs to,
like, the amount of
context that it really
needs to know to be
able to write good
simulation scripts and
so we have a like kind
of a traditional user
usage pattern for
where you define
components you define a
processor and i'm using
daft data frames which
are uh lazily
evaluated and uh which
enables query optimization
um and it's backed
by rust so um the team
behind daft set the
rec the world record
for s3 reads and
writes and the in-memory
format is Apache Arrow,
so you get zero copy
reads and writes.
So these are a
bunch of big data
technologies. That's
my background,
and the whole goal
is that it makes
data processing
super efficient.
We support sync and
async, and right
now I've got just
toy examples,
but the next
integration is adding
OpenAI client and
chat completions,
which the same
DAF team has
demonstrated to
be able to...
They scraped like all
of GitHub to go and
try to find the most
cracked like Rust
developers and they saw
massive like 80 completions
per second on VLM
on a GPU that they
were running. I think
it was a 8 by A100.
So there's no rate
limits if you're
running your whole
stack on open source.
I'm just going to
dive into the code
here. and show you a
couple of moments and
so if we just run
this really quickly,
our simple simulation
here is just
updating a position
based on the velocity
and see that
those positions
do end up updating here.
It's nice that you
got those data frame
visualizations um but
you can see what your
data looks like but i
think i'm out of time
and that's everything
i've got for you
no i think i so explain
explain the practical
applications of
what you're uh what
you're doing here so uh
my goal is to ensemble
um llm responses
to explore multiple
perspectives in parallel
um the most powerful
prompting technique
that i found especially
initially when I was
working with ChatGPT
was exploring
different perspectives,
like orthogonal
or inverted
or just different ideas.
And the whole purpose
of this is to give
LLMs really a kind of
constrained scripting
primitives for them
to go and script
their own
simulations. And then
the goal for
that is to enable
like super intelligence
utilization
because currently I
believe a majority of
us as humans are the
ones that are really
holding these systems
back as opposed to
you know kind of the
other way around so
really how do you
want to use it
Everett like do you
want to like give
it a task or be
like hey like help
me make like how
are you actually
you used a positional
one here is this like
a military use case,
where it's like, I
want to know where
this tank's going to be
in 20 minutes. And
you're simulating that?
It certainly could.
The system is
generalized for a lot
of different use
cases, real time,
like I mentioned,
probably wouldn't
work as well. But
it's intended to
support mostly code
generation initially,
and then particularly
act as like a personal
agent engine um so uh
long term this has the
scalability potential
to serve entire
enterprises um it scales
on ray as well so it um
it should be able to
scale to petabyte scale
without a ton of um
extra features just
given the technologies
that it has so
enterprise knowledge
management enterprise
agents running a bunch
of agents in parallel
um and then using
a bunch of big data
engineering best
practices. The whole
purpose for that is
just enabling a better,
you know, a more
constrained or a scalable
agent ecosystem
without rate limits.
So you're using a
multi-step process
to do sort of
introspection in
the problems and
data analysis?
Yes, that's kind
of the hard part,
is that this is
still very general.
One thing I'd like
to do here this
weekend is take the
Tencent Persona Hub
that has 350,000
personas and have
those simulate to
potentially do like
synthetic customer
discovery with them.
So I should be able
to ask effectively
like 350,000 AI agent
personalities, whether
they would be interested
in some product,
maybe even enrich
the context by which
they're viewing this
product from that
perspective and say,
who's interested in
this? And that would
provide some value.
The other side of this
is also being able to run
subprocesses
like CloudCode.
I think there's still
some gaps here that
would, I think, take it
to actually integrating
CloudCode directly
into the processors.
But the goal is to
just let the LMs
discover emergent
patterns themselves
and enable an
expressive cognitive
architecture
scripting system.
I love it. I think
you're building
some really cool
stuff here. So
could I use a GPU
to sort of create
some parallel
processes using this?
Yeah, absolutely.
GPUs would accelerate
this tremendously.
Um,
the great thing is
that, uh, this works
locally as well as on
distributed systems, um,
with, I still need to
test this, but, um,
that's on the roadmap
here to work soon. Like
all of these technologies
that I'm using
are already built for
distributed systems.
Yeah, this is really
cool. I'm going to have
to take a deeper dive
into this. So, uh,
you and I have a like
mind here, because
I think this is some
of the stuff that I'm
working on is very
similar conceptually your
implementation looks
a little a little
more elegant i would
say but it's uh it's
cool lots lots of
interesting opportunities
here for this kind
of recursive thought
processes that go into
these like is it true
you know what what do
i need to do and sort
of you you could
probably create a really
cool swarm algo here
as well yeah well and
so here's what i
struggle with the most
painful experience of
prompting for me is that
feeling like every
response is arbitrary to
some extent like most
of these models are
like giving us a piece
of truth um and at
least based on the
training data that they're
seeing so long as you're
not like prompting
bias in it i think
it's really hard to to
not prompt your own
biases in it and so i
think scale is actually
how you get out of
that you say like you
can just be as biased
as you possibly need
to be you don't have
to worry about how
you're prompting it but
if it's going and
exploring like orthogonal
perspectives different
perspectives that you
just have this big
enum on like you're now
adopting a statistical
um methodology for
evaluating responses
and i think that's a
much better approach
that's fundamentally
how how llms and models
are built and operate
they're statistically
indeterministic so
you can't make them
deterministic they are
fundamentally statistically
indeterministic
yeah i think we should
we have to lean into
that the more that we
rely on these models
so the um like for us
to continue to make a
bunch of decisions
based on one response
from one model i think
is kind of insane uh
considering you know
this is why i've been
wanting to work on this
is because if if it's
low cost to get a
bunch of different
perspectives on a single
prompt then like by all
means we should at least
have an understanding
what that distribution
of that response
should look like yeah
there's different
ways that you can
structure responses right
like anyway i didn't
determine how many
simulations you run like
i mean you give it a
general idea i want
to simulate how many
customers i'm going to
get next december like
hey there's some sort
of i mean like process
you're running i mean
how do you determine
how many simulations
it's going to require
it's a and then also
the accuracy of that
you know is it just
are we just playing
like a game here
to see like kind
of what the
system thinks like
ultimately when the
rubber hits the road
and you get in
december rolls around
does it actually you
know does it actually
pencil out so i'm just
trying to figure out
like what's the where
do you see like the
main value of running
the simulations and how
do you know that it's
actually going to get
you closer to true it's
it's risk mitigation
for the most part it's
saying it's not over
investing in a
particular approach and
making sure that you're
exploring the solution
space um and i think
more than anything this
will probably end
up being used for
evaluations more often
insurance um right and and
on top of just like
you know you've got uh
yeah i mean we're
we're we're looking to
delegate more and more
of our cognition to
these types of systems
right and um it's really
difficult to operate
as a human without
bias um and to me this
is a means of us being
able to interact with
these systems without
like um overly
introducing our biases
because it's able to
go and explore those
different possibilities
and again like when
you talk about simulations
like that's just
like the way that the
system is built this
is a state machine
where you have unified
context and the first
agent i'm going to build
is going to have
the same querying
capabilities as these data
frames so they're going
to be able to query
data at scale just as
well um and be able to
process that data at
scale so so i think
that i mean bias is
obviously top of mind
for many or all of us
and certainly something
we need to mitigate
and like take out
of our ****, right?
Protect us from
ourselves kind of thing.
And I think AI
obviously and LLMs have
shown a potential
path forward to help
with overall bias
considerations. But I
think oftentimes,
at least from what I
hear and observe, we
tend to discredit or
forget about intuition,
which is, in my
opinion, like the opposite
of bias. And if we
can engineer and or
recreate systems of
synthetic intuition
systems, which is, you know,
more or less a
different word for bias,
in favor of the intended
outcomes of the use
case scenario. And so
I see this as being
potentially complementary
to both sides of
that coin in our usage.
And I also wanted
to point out while
at the mic there was
another comment earlier
that was a good question
max had uh so based
on um is this based
on or does it utilize
any tree searching
algorithms characteristic
search algorithms or
monicalo etc and i
know that like that's
right up your alley
out everett so i wanted
to yeah that's a that's
a primary goal for
the platform um and
um i would that's a
probably one of the
very first features i'm
looking to build as soon
as i get to an agent
but i have to get
ellen i have to get
open ai client
calls inside uds
with semaphore
concurrency and there's
a couple of things
i have to figure
out um but like
you said uv um like
if anything my
goal is to empower
the actual like
the the kind of the
then this nascent like
pure experience of
vibe coding where you
just lean into intuition
and you're leaning
into like that the
present moment of what
you want to explore um
and hopefully this
is like going to be
helping you do that homework
um and open yourself
up to the not just
the limits of your
own like creativity
but beyond that yeah no
it's it's we're we're
in an interesting and
what are you using
to build this stuff
like what's what's
your dev flow look life
yeah so um i'm usually
using cloud code at
this point um like i'm
not even really gonna
pay for my like cursor
subscription as much
anymore especially
because the tab completion
kind of already works
um cloud code but
i'm pretty much
consistently just using the
latest models uh and
attaching myself to
that because they end
up being the best um
i do a lot of manual
inspecting and, like,
I have a much harder
time, like, trusting,
like, generated code
bases if I don't
know that the LLM is
using primitives that
I trust. And so,
like, a majority of
my coding workflows
take some sort of
authoritative reference,
whether that's a
large code base or
some script or even an
article. And I ask it
to build off of that
because I know that
there's I feel like
it's less likely to
kind of collapse on
itself and introduce
a bunch of errors.
Yeah.
This particular...
Oh, go ahead.
Are you developing in
Rust or Python or what?
Python. This is all
Python for right
now, the back end,
almost the majority
of the back end,
like the actual
technologies that I'm
using are using Rust.
And I would love
to build in Rust.
I'm just not as
familiar with Rust yet.
Rust is awesome.
It is amazing.
The biggest issue
with Rust, I find with
the sort of automated
development, and
Cloud Code actually
proves this a bit,
is the compilation
process. So, you have
to do it as like
a sub-thread that
doesn't block in timeout
within CloudCode,
right? You got that two
-minute timeout issue
with CloudCode, which
is a bit of a pain.
And maybe someone else
has figured out how
to make that go longer
in two minutes, but
I've yet to figure
that out. And so, if
you're constantly doing
compiles, and as we
know, Rust is not
known for doing fast
compilation. there's
techniques i guess to do a
pastor but for the
stuff i'm doing two
minutes doesn't generally
cut it right and then
for your guys we've
got uh we still have
chris phillips up if
we want to give him
the last few minutes
sure sorry so yeah sorry
guys we we've been
uh super chatty today
uh really really neat
stuff brilliant everett
yeah yeah feel free
to reach out to me
If you have questions.
Hello, Rope.
I have a quick question.
Did you have a face?
We don't have time
for that right at the
moment. We'll push
up to the after show.
Chris, take it away.
So my name is
Chris Phillips. I'm
an identity architect.
And Everett,
if you could stop
sharing the screen,
I can start
sharing your money.
Awesome.
Thank you.
uh so
so just a couple flies
there is going to
be a demo uh so what
pause for a second
take a breath we were
talking about lms
and all these kinds of
things and i'm going
to ask you all to
shift a little bit
and let's talk about
multi-context protocol
and about some of
the things on how
they get configured
and stuff um so some of
the challenges that
we were talking about
today about how tokens
end at a certain
time, or it's just
a pain in the butt.
We're absolutely
right. There's
a lot going on in
that space right now.
And the MCP layer
has got a challenge
with identity specifically.
Now, of course,
the identity guy says
there's a challenge,
but I think everyone
else is experiencing
it as well, because
the security model is
dealing a lot stuff
with localhost and a no
auth endpoint and one
of the things in my
background for the last
two decades is operating
a saml federation
or a multilateral
federation where you
could sign in with your
institution's credentials
into other services
so single sign on at
scale globally and
right now in the mcp
side of things it's
pretty challenged in the
sense that i can only
either run things on
localhost or i have
to do this and we heard
today that there was
a comment it was like
yeah that mcp is not
starting up or i have
to run on local host
or how does the
authorization happen and
to me this is the
world in the federated
space i'm trying to bring
it into the mcp side
this where this has
value is that we can
start dealing with
more single sign-on and
a lot more certainty
because right now when
you sign in or use one
of the authorizations
you don't know that
MCP service doesn't
really know who you
are. And that knowing
who you are in that
deterministic statement
that we heard a few
minutes ago from Everett
about that non
-deterministic versus
deterministic, identity
things need to be
deterministic because
that's how you deal with
access permissions and
those kinds of things.
And what I've been doing
is I've been working on
enhancing the MCP
side of things
with existing
protocol called
OpenID Connect
Federation.
And the OpenID Connect
Federation is the
standard from the OpenID
Foundation, same one
where OpenID Connect
is built on OAuth 2. So
this goes together
like peanut butter and
jelly in a sandwich.
So you can use the same
MCP libraries, you
could use the same
authorizations and use
the same JWT bearer token
with the federation
stuff to sign in. and one
of the things that
a lot of people are
commenting on is it's
easy to sign into things
within your own institution
when you have an
identity provider of
one but what happens is
this moment you get
out of your own domain
is the moment that
how do you sign into
there how does how how
do i get authorized
into agentix.org from
some other organization
i would have to have
an account there and
that's that's a that's
a not a great identity
and access management
story so this is
about cross-domain
token sharing in a safe
and secure fashion
and it's tamper-proof
because it has cryptographic
groundings on it
and you can use it
anywhere in the circle
of the trust now time
check here i'm not
going to be able to
get into all the things
so i want to
jump into what
does it actually
look like
and so i have a
repo that's private
right now that's
publishing a library
and the what you're
going to see is just
an example of me
having a sign in with
github or github i
built an oauth app or i
have an application
registered in github
on the oid feds test
i've created that and
i've registered this
one on localhost
you'll notice that the
redirection url is on
localhost so i'm signing
in with my github
credential into the
local application.
This is running in a
Docker Compose right
now in my VS code on
my machine, actually.
So when I tap sign in,
what happens is you
get this JWT over the
wire. And then here
in the federation, the
app or the MCP for
the federation is it's
now building and adding
in the OpenID connect
federation so what
has happened is my
docker composed when
it became instantiated
said i'm a federation
here's my signing key
for my token and this
mcp that we're going
to be signing into
will also be in that
federation so you can
have any number of those
in there so if you
think about how someone
has to use mcp to sign
in each individually
to each mcp this gives
you an opportunity
to use the same token
to sign into any of
the mcps that are part
of the federation so
when i go to test the
mcp server you'll see
that it's part of has
the token it has my
identity from github
and this is a web
interface but really
what we want is we want
to see this in the real
MCP side of things.
So what I have
is I have, I've
already signed in
and I have a bearer
token in my MCP
inside VS Code
in my local federation,
so local host here.
And now I can actually
interact in with VS
Code and say who, let's
go up a little bit,
just check on the who
am I. so now this is
a pure mcp call and
it has the information
about the federation
so the federation in
this case is the
issuer of localhost but
this could be businessname
.com and they say
oh i'm going to allow
others into this
federation or if i want
to have an mcp in my
fleet of things at my
organization you only
need this one jwt to
be able to be in there
and then you can do
interesting things like
compare, is this
person the same as the
person who authored
this code, for instance?
So what we're doing
is we're bringing
that information into
the JWTs and the MCP
space, so you can
evaluate, is this
person truly who
they say they are? Is
this the person that
you think it is? As
opposed to having
anyone do that or have
your token change.
The other thing is
about demonstration
proof of possession.
That's one of the
pieces where the token
would be bound to
your device so that
you can have certainty
that no one can
lift the token and
use it somewhere else.
What I've been
doing with this is
building an open
source library.
And one of the things
I'm working on is,
Reuven, I've
been inspired by
your MPM or MPX
installation
uh to be able to do
the delivery of the
packages and those kinds
of things so i'm building
base mpm packages
for this as well as a
boilerplate for the mcp
elements uh i have a
long form demo on this
but about 15 minutes
long and i welcome
questions and i'm just
going to glance at the
meeting chat i'm really
mindful of time so and
i'm really appreciate
the time here today
it's a Yeah. And I
apologize for not giving
you a lot of time.
That was probably my
fault for blabbing on too
much. But what you're
doing is really useful
and important for
anyone using MCPs. And I
think we discussed this
a little bit earlier,
where some of the MCP
concerns, especially
with remote MCPs, are
particularly vulnerable
to, you know,
interception of data, data
leakage issues, you
know, especially when
using untrusted third
-party streamable HTTP,
right? And you're
addressing
those concerns.
Exactly. And I'm a
member of the OpenID
Foundation and on the
working group that
actually is part of the
OpenID Connect Federation
space. I've been part
of it for the last
couple of years.
And we have a really
awesome opportunity here
to have this kind of
technology into the
space and be adopted.
Because if you're
going to try to do MCP
at scale, like if I
were to use an example
of, say, Spotify, if
I want to have an MCP
for me, my agent, to
go and say, what was
Chris's listening history
and do some really
interesting things
and then say, is my
billing up to date? Or
if Spotify says, I'm
going to use a third
party and I'm going
to say, hey, you do
this for my customers.
I'll add you into my
Spotify federation.
So it's that federation
around the service.
then you can say that
token that I used to
sign in, which by the
way, you sign into
Spotify, typically with
Facebook or Google or
something else, right?
What happens is you
can decorate the token
and then say stamp
of approval. Aha, that
is the person. And
that is unchangeable
and unmodifiable because
what happens is you
have the token being
able to be issued by
central author the ca
and signed there so i'm
looking for interested
parties my information
is on the last
screen here and if you
have uh interesting use
cases and i know people
are suffering from
mcpi dis on signing
into things and tokens
rolling off and all
those kinds of things
so i know this is a
problem and if you have
a problem in any of
your projects hit me up
and um and if you have
insider and say, Hey,
what if, can I do
this? That'd be great.
It's, it's, it's pretty
cool. I think that
if you're doing this
in an enterprise
context or, or even
integrating secondary
systems like MCPs as
part of your workflow,
the idea of, of auth
is, is essential.
And so you,
you're, you, you've
got MPX installed,
which I love,
or you're, you've
implemented
that or is that
coming soon?
it's implemented and
so the the there's a
the docker composed
demo is using its own
libraries to be able to
do things so it would
be an mpx install so
there's the federation
management part and
then there's the the mcp
core which would you
you would be integrating
with and my intent is
i'm looking at meta
mcp maybe because
what you'll see in any
of the uh any air quotes
agentics people that
are saying hey sign
in one place they're
using basically a proxy
and what you see here
is a proxy and it's
the mcp server has got
some extra pieces on
it to have uh just
decode this the the
token with the extra
elements to it so there's
more here and um yeah
yeah so that yeah
love it i love i love
what you're doing
really really cool
stuff this is uh And
I, again, apologize.
You probably needed
15 minutes to really
get into what you're
doing. This is really
useful. This is really,
really useful stuff.
So take a look.
There's a video
for this with
the long form.
Basically, you
got the super,
the expresso
form of this.
And, yeah.
This is huge.
That is, especially
for OIDC,
that's critically
important
for Cloud Federation.
of identity management
and access controls
you have to set
that up anytime that
you're integrating
with a cloud provider
amen i have a question
yeah can i ask you
yes hello sorry yeah
go go for it so as you
know uh cloud max is
not unlimited token they
not provide so did you
ever face any token
issue like out of limit
uh issues do you have
a phase i do um two
i'm using a 200 one so
it happens when i'm
running concurrent
processes i i run a i i
time out and says come
back in a few hours or
whatever um yeah yeah
it's there i i i started
with 100 because i
was seeing how far i
could push that one i i
ended up being
frequently running out on
that one but again i'm
i'm using a ton of of of
you know concurrent
processes and and things
so uh you know that
that's probably my my
issue um yeah so i would
i would uh you know
it depends it depends
what you're doing like
if if you're if
you're a developer and
you're spending as much
time as as i am which
is all day you know
running things and 200
bucks is just the the
cost of doing business if
you win a business
expense it right and if
if you're independent
like me uh use it as
a tax deduction or
something you know so that's
it's it's just uh
it's it's part of your
tool set but i don't
think there's any better
value you know a lot
of people are saying
well why don't you use
like a local model like
like debt dev stroll
or coach stroll and
stuff like that i just
don't find them as
capable uh at least the
things that i'm doing
not as far as the state
of the art goes i don't
think anything comes
close to in terms of
capacity capability
and cost nothing this
is the best okay um
unless you know i mean
open other people's
opinions and by the way this
is the open mic
portion so if there's
something someone wants
to show or tell or discuss
this this is your uh
this is your chance
all right yeah it's
been it's been it's
been an interesting
week to say the least
i i love i love working
in ai like i know
everyone there's
like a lot of haters
out there whatever
but we get we get to
create stuff but it's
literally this this
the line between idea
and creation is non
-existent like i like
i say this every
week and i think i've
proven it by this
point but there's
nothing we can't create
like in this the the
more the more complex
the problems and when
you look at like we've
been doing these ai
hacker spaces for a
little over a year now
and you look at the
things that that we were
building a year ago,
like I went back and
looked at some of the
first episodes or whatever
we call these things,
like from a year
ago, it's like, it's
almost laughable at how
impressed we were with
the simplistic things
that we were creating.
We're like, oh my
God, I just created a
website or something.
And I can do that in
like 10 minutes now.
And, you know, so you
don't realize where you
are in the exponential
curve when you're in
that exponential curve.
And, you know it's it's
like i i i remember
one i was watching
the video and i was
bragging i just created
10 000 lines in a week
well now i create
10 000 lines in like
five minutes two minutes
right it's yeah we
don't even think anything
other than 10 000
lines is incredible that's
crazy i think that's
kind of yeah it's
also hard to review
sorry ever sorry chris
i think i'm already too
much of your time chris
you go ahead i think
i think that that
self-awareness on that
that knee of the curve
absolutely and this
is such a leading edge
on it the trailing edge
is so far back that
bringing that forward
is that's the that's
the heavy lift right
now because people are
it will become second
nature oh yeah i can
make that website or
those 10 000 lines
like all the work that
goes into that is um is
kind of lost on people
and then it's you know
it's a function in
excel then or something
you know it turned
it that they only encounter
it in those contexts
uh like some of the
federation stuff
they're not mcp is still
you know what's that
the further curve the
more you're going to
give them an existential
crisis once you tell
them what's going on
it and i i've explained
some things to people
they're like that's
not that's not you can't
do that and i'm like
no it's going on it's
happening and they
have no they don't believe
it i gave a presentation
to a very large tech
company yesterday
and this is senior
leadership and these guys
are supposed to be like
the the top ai guys
in the world and and
they're they're the
the response to when i
showed them like building
their app in real time
while i was giving
the presentation i
literally loaded my
powerpoint in vs code
and then said what do you
want to build and
while i was giving my
presentation it built it
and then by the end of
it they're like you
know *** like i you're
you're like us collectively
we're so far beyond
what a lot of the
industry is even thinking
or doing it's amazing
right so it was kind
of for them it was
like a glimpse into the
near future and again
for us we kind of take
it for granted a little
bit right we're we're
building these crazy
things we're like yeah
this is how it works
but the rest the idea
like you hear about this
and you hear pushback
like no you know
programmers aren't going
away anytime soon i'm
like well the traditional
programmer is
definitely going away
that's right the the
agentic engineers coming in
i think and i think
the takeaway from this
this particular
presentation was every major
team within a large
corporation probably is
going to need an agentic
engineer to be part
of it which is which
i think is true right
because we're like you
know magicians almost
it's crazy like wave
our hands around for
a minute and build and
just magically builds
um revive a question
for you real fast um
what are you finding
in your coaching
sessions or in these
interactions like where
are people getting
stuck the most when it
comes to being able
to even get close to
some of the stuff that
you're you're building
i mean you're
obviously on like a
unique level i know
there's other people in
this community that are
are probably similar
but you know there's
projects that were
also you know in my
own world where i feel
like we just kind
of get stopped and
stuck a lot which is
coding right in its own
right but i just want
to figure out like
um it seems so
effortless for you uh i
know you're putting in
a ton of sweat behind
your screen but
Like, where are you
finding most people,
most developers are
being blocked? And how
are you coaching them
on overcoming some
of those challenges?
The biggest blockage
is the disconnect
between the things that
I take for granted after
building things for
30 years versus this
idea that I can just
kind of magically wave
my hands and it's going
to build it without
me having to understand
the technical
nuance, structure,
architecture, whatever of
what I'm building. and
it you know it's hard
to articulate the
things you just
instinctively know because
you've been doing it
all your life and that
that's the i know it
sounds kind of obvious
but that that's the
that's the challenge
that that i think i'm
i'm having a little
bit you know there's
this expectation that
it's just i make it look
easy and then you're
just going to imagine
being able to do it
it's an engineering
process like any like
any you know field it
takes time and practice
to hone your skills
you know i i've been
doing this particular
form of engineering
for about four years
now and you're seeing
where i am after four
years of becoming an
agentic engineer but
that's already on top
of the 20 something
years i had started
right so it's it's not
it's not magic it's
it's It's skill, right?
Yes, definitely.
I ran into all sorts
of moments throughout
the day, especially
after I eat lunch or I
crash off of dopamine
being depleted from having
an awesome day. And
I'm just in bed,
comatose, because I just
vibe-coded something.
And, like, honestly,
I genuinely feel like
the major limitation
is me at this point for
so many different
projects. And that, like,
I get existential dread
probably at least a
couple times a week
just thinking about the,
like, the fact that I
don't have 50 agents
running 24-7. um so i
i definitely like vibe
with you know um it
it's difficult i think
for anyone with biological
cognition to really
like comprehend what
uh like any of us are
really capable of now
uh and i think you
know cloud flow is a
perfect example of that
uh yeah built built
on a whim just
because on top
of all the other
stuff and yeah
those are the best
projects yeah you know
what's crazy i just
i i put my uh my
booking link out there
people book my time
and i never know what
my next call is going
to be my my the most
interesting calls i
get are like these
random vcs that are
paying for my time
which i kind of love
because you know i kind
of loathe vcs but
they're they're they're
they're booking my
time and paying my
hourly rate and then
try and convince me to
create some ********
startup. And it's
like, why would I create
that? I'm like, I'm,
I'm, you know, by
the time I build the
company, drive the
funding, get the product
out the door, it's
already antiquated.
And that's, that's
the challenge we have
with any startup that's
being formed right
now. Like I see some
******** startup from
like Y Combinator
and it's like, well,
I can just literally
point my bot at that
startup's product
and have a verbatim
version of it because
it's probably some
wrapper anyway in in
literally a an hour right
and and then the the
question is the is
is the opportunity
isn't technical anymore
it's it's momentum
or or the ability you
for it's like a
distribution problem right
it's ability for you
to get get access
particular customer
base that you're trying
to sell to and that's
that's obviously
relationship or some kind
of you know reddit sub
group or something
but it's certainly not
a technical problem
yeah and that means the
uh the uh the space is
ripe for joint ventures
between agentic
engineering firms and a
sea of opportunities
out there where that
distribution is already
in place probably and
and even distribution
is shallow because
the fact is like if the
technology gets to a
point where people can
prompt their way into
product development
all the way i mean we
fast forward 10 years
from now i mean now
all of a sudden the
distribution channel is
the creator right and so
and or or the customer
is now the creator
and you don't need
to distribute anything
because you're just
building it yourself
remote is speed development
speed if you can
continuously ship and
ship and ship new
features then duplicating
you people are always
going to be one step
behind you know that's
honestly one of the
only ways that i think
ai native companies
are going to survive
is by adopting a vibe
coding approach and so
like i i tend to see it
like in terms of some
of these big like ai
tools players um the
evaluations uh companies
being the big
winners here because
evaluations and you know
the testing that goes
around like providing
repeatable agentic
experiences is orders of
magnitude you know more
than just like the
initial creating of the
product um so like i
really would like to
see continued investment
on like the evaluation
side that has the
same like vibe coding
aspects to it right
like um there's i think
i remember i think you
continue to see some
of these major the
major cloud players you
know partnering with
evaluation frameworks
and things like that
um but i think honestly
even them they it's
it's difficult for them
to iterate quickly
particularly if they
have an existing business
model if you're not
adopting a new business
model you're going
to get replaced within
the next five years
unfortunately you're
right generous man
five years is generous
and it's it's it's
like a i call it a
cognitive dissonance
I feel terrible in a
sense that the work
that we're doing is
going to be highly
disruptive to a large
portion of the industry.
And when I say
industry, I mean
specifically the technical
programming development
industry that I'm
obviously part of.
But I don't have
a solution to it.
Like I know that I
can relatively easily
replace entire
teams in moments.
and that sort of
bothers me in the sense
that i i want those
people to do well i don't
want them to be
unemployed i don't want
to be the destroyer of
people's livelihoods
but i also have this
this immense capability
to build stuff so
i'm just not sure
you know i don't know
if i the only real way
we have this to solve
that at least in my
opinion is why we
created the agentix
foundation Maybe
there's a way for us to
facilitate that
transformation in a way that's
more friendly, human,
and not devastating.
And maybe I'm just
kidding myself. Maybe
that's just not possible
and this is going to
be what it's going to
be. I think that's a
great topic, Reuven.
I mean it's that this
foundation, like someone
was saying earlier, I
think it might have
been Chris, is that the
tail, the long tail
behind the knee is so
very, very long. they
are all the people that
are not us that we are
at the bleeding bleeding
edge of what is what
what is possible with
this technology and
we we have basically
cast aside all of our
doubts and preconceptions
and just said yeah
let's let's embrace it
and adapt and change
all those and we're
we're running at light
speed and and we accept
that **** this is all
really radically radical
stuff that makes us,
you know, you imagine
something, you write
a spec, you kick it
off in your dev
environment, and it starts
building, and seven
hours later, you're done.
All those, that long
knee, behind the knee,
that long tail, those
people aren't there,
right? And so they
actually have to, you
know, they have, they
haven't accepted, and
they're actually resisting
that this radical
stuff is actually
possible now. And I think
this foundation we have
here is potentially
a great team of people
that could actually
help people understand
that it's actually
okay. It's safe. We
can show you that it's
okay. You can adapt.
You can change. Maybe
that's the value of what
this organization is.
And you can help
teams and companies
actually adapt to
what is coming.
Like Jed said, it's
not five years.
It's actually way
less than that.
And what Alexander
was saying was like,
what's the blocker
here? Why are teams
blocked? Well, the
teams are blocked
because they are
resisting the fact that
there's a monumental
fundamental shift
that's happened, and
this team of people,
this foundation of
people has actually
realized that, and
everybody else is kind of
resisting. I sit down
with teams of people,
engineers and PMs that
are like, yeah, we're
going to just continue
the way we code,
and we'll do some
agentic coding. And then
I come here, and
everybody's like blitzing
10,000 lines of code
every seven minutes.
Yeah.
So this organization
is potentially at
the most highest leading
edge organization
of people that could
potentially help
people to actually
become okay with that and
understand that this
is what's coming.
um i'm not sure i'm
not sure if um people
are familiar with the
uh unsupervised learning
podcast um but there's
a the host for that
show tends to grab folks
from the um leading
ai labs quite
frequently um and one of
the key researchers for
cloud four uh hopped
on right before cloud
four was released or
right around that time
um and he kind of went
through what they're
seeing and internally
um i would highly
recommend anybody to go
and check that out
and i'll try to drop a
link here um one of
the things that really
stuck out is how
confident he was that agi
would be here by 2027
um and particularly how
uh each time he talked
about how much progress
they were making and
how like each of the
trend lines they're
not bending they're
staying consistent
we're continuing to see
exponential growth in
cognitive ability even
on alignment research
and mechanistic
interpretability
which is potentially
more important
um at this stage um
but the the incentives
for you know all of
these large labs is
to become the monopoly
or the big player in
the space um and i tend
to hear the conversation
go from we're seeing
all of this progress
we know AGI is coming
we and then the
they it's in the same
tone but they say but I
hope that people are
working on the these
like critical pieces
where AI is actually
being implemented to
like realize some social
good or collective and
important problem like
you know there are
definitely teams leveraging
AI to you know solve
can cure cancer
and things like that
but even just some of
these like other issues
that we see and maybe
experience every day
like um there's not
actually like vc money
for that because the
vcs are more incentivized
to invest in like
capital focused
ventures so um if you're
working on a really
difficult problem like chris
is like and i think
this foundation is
then you guys are actually
on the leading edge
of impact uh as much
as all these other
people have billions
of dollars they're only
kind of pushing the
they're pushing the
frontier out uh we're the
ones actually delivering
the value um and i
think that's a really
important distinction
to keep in mind um
especially you know if
you're you're broke and
the labor market's
as trash as it is um
like that's i think it's
critical to keep that
into perspective yeah
that's good that's a
really good point we
gotta wrap up i think
thanks you know we
really enjoyed having you
guys on today everett
and the whole crew
here uh so and chris
as well and i feel bad
with chris we kind of
took all this time and
so and again that
was mine i was i was
really excited this
week about the whole uh
swarm stuff and whatever
um yeah so the question
is when are we going
to build next week?
It's like Monday
seems like a year ago.
I think this is
great. I really
appreciate it.
We're putting
together a
production team.
I've nominated Rob as
our executive producer.
So Rob, thanks for
taking on that role.
We're going to try
to put together,
what I want to do is up
the production value.
So we're probably going
to maybe move away
from Zoom. But I
like the part of Zoom
where we can kind of
collaborate and chat. um
maybe there's other
tools that allow us to
do that i don't know
i'm gonna let rob figure
that up that part out
um and i just love
doing these as you
know and it's it's just
it's the way to sort of
articulate and you know
percolating in my
brain throughout the
week and it always is
the best way to end the
week right because
it gives me all these
ideas from you i was
like seeing whatever it
worked on in the in and
the auth system from
from chris now i'm
gonna i want to combine
those two and do
something new with it so
well that's what i'm
eager for an integration
i'm eager for an
integration i'm telling you
right now yeah awesome
no i'm we're we're
your crew if you want
if you like the tinkers
we we love that all
right so um hopefully
all the live casting
stuff worked and my
record button works and
if it didn't whatever
this was a good
discussion regardless so
thanks thanks thanks
again um and if you're
looking to support us
you know we've we're
working on a new site
brad's up gonna be
launching a new agentix
.org which is a little
gonna be more organized
we've got a sponsor
in disco and tribal
scale who are gonna
sponsor the new website
for us i know you've
you you're paying money
and it's not obviously
what you're paying
it for you're paying
to sort of help us
figure it all out not
we're all volunteers
by the way none of us
make any money on this
on the agentics.org
we're just doing it
because we can it should
kind of be the the
antithesis of open ai we
want to be open
agentics or something um
that's it another
another uh another great
week thank thanks
everyone awesome bye all
thanks guys thanks
everyone thanks everybody