All right. Yeah. Well,
well, congratulations.
It sounds
like it was a
great template
for us to follow
other locations.
You know, one of
the things that,
you know, I do
for these types of
events, just as
an FYI, I overbook
them by like 60%
or more sometimes.
So if it's free,
so, you know, the
amount of people that
show up is greatly
reduced for some
reason. I guess
people just like to
put their name on
things and not show.
So what kind of no
-show did you see?
We, I think apart
from our core group,
there were in the
room 35 new people,
right? So all
those 60 signed up.
I mean, someone can,
someone from the team,
if you were here,
correct me with the
numbers, but when I
manually counted, like at
one point I saw 35
to 40 people broadly
speaking, which is I
think a fair turnout.
And the room was quite
big, which is actually
good. And I think
Tim Walton and others
really made a lot of
arrangements actually
a lot of food a lot
of drinks so you would
always see a bottle I
mean a beer in my hand
wherever I was watching
at my pictures I
was saying I always
had a beer in my hand
so okay great awesome
thank you to uh to
requesting Google too
for hosting it and Google
didn't lock down the
premise too much I
know they're famous
for that sort of thing
they're fine they
were quite quite
good actually and
everyone I think
uh yeah they
played their part.
Oh, great. Well, that
sounds like a good time.
Today, I was going to do
something a
little different.
Next week, I'm
doing what they
call a GenEye
SuperStream with
O'Reilly, the
book publisher.
So I thought maybe you
guys could watch as
I prepare my presentation
and the online
portion of it, which is
basically a data. It's
focused on data
analysis, data analytics
so i mean what i need
to come up with today
is a the the live
demo portion of that
presentation so i'm
gonna i'm gonna try to
figure that out on this
call i know generally
what i'm going to
present and i only get 35
minutes so i need to
need a combination of
both a um a presentation
that introduces
the concepts of generative
ai and vibe coding
and agentics and then
i need i'm going to
jump in and probably
do like a uh an intro
to actually doing that
for data analytics
so i gotta figure
all that out you know
they give me a topic
right so it's and it has
to be data analytics
related so that that's
what i'm going to try
to figure out today
so if you're not if
you're not into data
analytics or vibe vibing
with data analytics
and this might not be
your your session um
you guys are literally
watching me do my
work today like i needed
to do that I figured
I'd just share. And
that's actually why
I'm not live broadcasting
this because, in
fairness to O'Reilly,
I figured I'd maybe not
share that more publicly
until the actual
live event. And that
live event is on the
29th, which I think
is like next Thursday.
But it's 22 plus seven,
I think, next Thursday.
So here we go. So
I'm going to...
You guys have a
little sneak peek.
Again, like always,
if you guys have any
questions, feel free
to jump in and let
me know what you're
thinking. Happy to
share my opinion here.
All right, so I'm
building my little
presentation. I like
the retro futuristic
look. It's kind of
the thing I go for.
I like bluish greens
and turquoise, so this
is the Rube brand.
Here's the subject
matter. I still need to
format this a little
bit. You're looking at a
fairly rough version.
I'm gonna send this
out a little later.
this font's a little too
big get that a little
smaller there we go um
so i yeah this is
their text not mine i
wouldn't call myself a
leading ai consultant but
whatever um you guys
know me whatever this
is this is my approach
to uh generative ai
and agentics proactive
autonomous collaborative
and targeted i love
acronyms it's just my
thing what can i say
if there's an acronym
that needs to be created,
I will create it.
So Pact, I saw
in some sci-fi
movie recently
with Pact with
the bad guys,
but that's okay.
So Vibe Coding, it
was actually quite
difficult to come
up with a definition
for Vibe Coding.
So I decided to
sort of dream up
my own definition.
Crafting code by feel,
balancing functionality
with readability style
and project mood.
That's 100% me
dreaming that up.
Basically, I kind of
thought something similar
like surfing, and I
wanted to create a
separation between the
idea of vibe coding and
agentic engineering
as kind of a spectrum.
So describing it,
I'm like rapid
iteration versus
ideation. So the
ability to be
guided by intuition,
the ability to sort
of follow where
the path leads without
actually knowing
where that endpoint
is. and for
faster prototyping
and code the field's
approachable, you
know, basically
surfing the vibe, if
you will, for code.
And then on the other
side of the spectrum,
I figured I needed to
sort of have a correlation
here for agentic
engineering itself and
the sort of idea of
having a plan or a
process. So where vibe
coding is flow, you know,
you're in the zone,
you're using your
intuition, you don't really
have a process, you're
kind of trying to figure
out where the where
the path leads
agentic is kind of the
opposite it's structured
it's process driven it
involves large amounts
of planning and testing
and and the iteration
and refinement so
one side is ideation
the idea the other part
side is iteration the
refinement of the idea
now let me pause does
that make sense or
am i just making **** up
here as i go no that's
perfect you may want
to distinguish the
presence or absence of
a feedback in the drive
building reduces agentic
engineering sorry
say a little say again
i had a bit you may
want to emphasize the
presence or absence of
a feedback on between
invite coding and
agentic engineering by
building a human is the
feedback group for
agentic engineering tries
to reflect or do it's
clearly through fact
before we put the
feedback loops and you're
saying I like that and
you're saying that on
energy the human human
is the feedback when
via coding yeah self
vibe code self yeah
what's it called reflex
or self feedbacks exactly
the machine machine
is the feedback loop
the reflection is
within the machine
and the reflection
is with the human
but yes that's
the distinction
that I think should
be emphasized
I like that I mean
there is a commonality
right I mean one of
the rabbit holes then
how to avoid I think
wipe coding can be
very powerful but
wipe coding can lead
to rabbit holes but
the whole point about
yeah probably that's
a bit of structure
but the point about
the test-driven
approach, the research,
right? The initial
research. I think
whether we are vibe
coding or we are doing
agentic engineering
because I've played
around with Cursor,
Windsurf everywhere
in different ways.
Research is key.
Even if you do a
simple deep research
using Gemini,
right?
And asking the system
to adopt a test-driven
approach. So feature
by feature. I think
that is the one way
you can really follow
the vibe because
otherwise if it is random,
then you know we
can't guard the system
we can't get the system
good on a guard from
guard rails so i think
having that research
first before we code
anything like just
think through it and
do even like use ai
just to research i think
that is very powerful
for me methodology
driven like you've
established a methodology
and now you're
following that method
yeah the research to
generate the methodology
and the methodology
then creates that
framework of containment.
I think
Rue of yourself,
you said I think it
was last week, where
before you initiate
Spark, you want to
give it a framework
for it to follow,
right? Whereas
on the other side,
you have nothing.
So you're specifying
the guardrails
and the framework.
So guardrails
and framework
on the identity side,
whereas VibeCone
is like, I'm going to
do whatever I want.
okay i think i i
don't want to i don't
want to make a mountain
of text either like
this is i got 35
minutes so i figured at
bullet points i can
i like what you guys
are saying one is
free form the other
structure and that's
kind of the story i'm
trying to say here
and and it's kind of
the this the the
spectrum it very much
reminds me actually of
brookman's um integrated
thinking methodology
because that is
a lot about going
back and refining the
methodology itself
as a process of deep
integration across the
entire value chain.
So what's that
called? It's called
integrated
thinking. It was
actually part of
Roger Martin's
big bring to Rotman
back in like 2010s.
And that's integrated
thinking. So you
could call it an
integrated methodology.
Essentially, you visit
the whole value chain
and and refine the
methods at each step.
So, what I feel about
Spark is that, you know,
it is a framework
of methods
and the iterative
process will deepen
each method and
then you string them
together to go to
create a value chain.
Okay, yeah, I like that.
To me, the difference is,
is the difference
between fun and
work that encapsulates
it. Vibe coding
is fun. It's kind
of the hobbyist.
Agentic engineering
is work. You're
trying to really
get in there
and create
something that has a
method and will
endear, hopefully.
Okay.
Yeah. So one is learning,
the other is doing.
And all right, again,
I don't want to
make this too, I don't
want to put too much
in here because I
got to actually speak
to it a little bit.
But let's see if I
can make that a little
somewhere subtle.
Nope, too subtle.
I think on the agentic
side of things,
it's really embodying,
if you could be
the best software
engineer all the time,
every time, these
are the aspects of
that. Because those
who aspire to be that
great engineer,
they concede I don't
have enough time for
docs I don't have
enough time for
good architecture or
something but the
rigor that the agentic
engineering offers
is it's consistency
there's a price
on the tokens
but if you can
be consistent
and agentics is just
that great consistent
engineer and if you're
weak on your product
requirements document
it's hard to be
consistent yeah those
are all really good
points And I got to
spell methodology, right?
All right,
there we go.
Okay, so I'm going to
go from the spectrum,
if you will, to the
actual methodology
that Martin was mentioning.
And for me, this
is obviously one of
many methodologies, but
this is the easiest
methodology to get up
and running. So then
I'll explain what the
Spark is, is a kind
of comprehensive
mechanism to both define
a structure to both
the free form vibe
where you need some
structure, but you can
use it to sort of guide.
And then the, then
the idea, and I've
got another one
too, I guess I could
probably include
here, but I get, I
don't, I should
be, I get the AIGI
spec, which is better
for vibe coding,
but I'm going to
stick with the Spark
because I think
it's easier for
the types of projects
that I guess the
O'Reilly guys would
probably want.
Then I'm going to
explain best I can what
the heck the model
context protocol is and
every day someone's
calling me out saying
that the mcp is
******** but uh you know
whatever i i think
i've come around to it
i think i went through
that phase myself
for a while but
basically i think there's
someone that mentioned
this a while back and
maybe on one of these
calls the idea of
the usbc for a for ai
kind of a universal
interface for plugging
things in tools and
whatnot. So this is
gonna be the sort of
core of the presentation.
I'll explain what
the MCP is, plug and
play, zero friction.
Now this is me and
my interpretation
and I guess it's
arguable at best for
the Unix style
composable components.
Built-in guardrails,
it allows you to
understand the
structure of how an LLM
should interact with
secondary systems.
One of the biggest
issues I have, and I see
this on my list every
day, people showing
up and creating an
MCP abstraction for an
LLM. That completely
defeats the purpose.
If your MCP is just an
abstraction to another
AI, it's pointless,
to be honest. That's
the whole point of
the system is for the
AI, the LLM itself, to
interact with things
that aren't necessarily
LLMs. If it's just
an AI talking to another
AI, I don't think
there's a **** of a
lot of value there.
What is the value
going across
model paradigm, model, I
guess, families,
so Grok to GPT?
Do you need MCP for that?
Is there a better
way in lieu of MCP?
Yeah, well, that's a
really good question.
So when you look at
like, let's go in here,
and actually, right
now, I'm going to jump
in and in my presentation,
I'll jump in and
do a live demo, which
for the folks, hopefully
on O'Reilly, they've
never seen this
before. So we're opening
up a whole new crew
to people sort of to
introduce what we're
doing here. So then I'm
going to pop this in.
Before we go there, on
that slide about MCP,
I think for my person,
where I kind of best
see MCP, it's one of
the best guardrails
around data. I mean, people
would argue otherwise,
but security and
control because you are
able to expose access
to data source in a
very controlled manner
so the tools you know
for example if you're
building an ai app you
want to make sure
you're doing it securely
safely trustworthily
right so what an
organization wants to
expose they then have it in
their control through
the tools that they
define so yeah it's a
universal usbc but it's
that much more than
that which goes to this
point about responsible
trustworthy ai yeah
but you can't you you
can't use mcp by default
as a guardrail it's
actually the opposite
it's completely open
but if i want to expose
my data but if i'm a
corporate organization
i want to expose my
data and i will only
do it through the mcp
tools that i have i have
control on what i'm
exposing to the like
open banking or others
right the way they did
it's like apis you open
up the access to the
data but you're opening
up to ai applications
and agents but then
you are applying
controls about you can
only do so through these
tools and these tools
do only these things
which i know what it
does so i have based on
the what you coded in
the server and what
the server is advertising
up to the client if
you don't have all
those controls in the
server it's a it's
completely open people can
just add prompts and
ask the mcp to do stuff
and and if it they
can they can ***** and
coerce then you could
the same can be argued
for any api website
whatever right if you
don't put a password on
your website they can
just access your website
if you don't put a
if you don't put a token
on your api they can
just actually access
your api i think that
that that is in some
ways just an inherent
part of any information
technology system it's
not it's not like mcp
is inherently more
or less secure it's
up to you to secure it
yes it is um But I
wouldn't use the word
guardrail by default in
a conversation with MCP.
Well, I'm using it
in a sense that you
should think about the
guardrail by default.
Yeah, you should do.
All right. So back
to the question, the
comment about the
use of, what was it,
multiple models. Like
for me to use multiple
models, so you can
see here I'm using
GPT 4.1 for my MCP
integration because
it has a really large
context window. But
when we go here to
different modes that
I've got set up here,
for example, Tester,
I'm using a different
model again.
So I'm using Sonnet
3.7, hopefully Sonnet
4, if it comes out
in 10 minutes. And by
the way, if anyone's
watching that separately,
let me know what
they come up with.
That's announced
in like 10 minutes.
So I'm actually switching
between models
here, depending.
And then there's this
new when to use option.
so what i want so now
what i can figure out
exactly is what so what
do i what i want to
do with this oh let's
go back to read me so
i i'm i've got this
presentation and this
is a super stream or
whatever what and i've
got basically 15 minutes
to show them something
i think the most
valuable thing i could
show someone would
be some kind of i'm
thinking out loud here
maybe you guys gave me
some ideas that some
sort of rudimentary data
science um application
that combines maybe
the perplexity mcp which
is really great data
collection save it
to maybe some kind of
like sqlite data what's
he doing what are you
doing hey oh what are
you doing uh what's
going on here you guys
are throwing me off
sorry somebody's
somebody's vibe coding yeah
they made a major
breakthrough there all
right sorry that that
totally threw off my
chain of thought i'm
thinking out loud here by
the way um and just
unmute yourself if you
actually want to say
something i just muted
everybody um so back to
my my chain of thought
i'm i'm want to create
some some sort of
data science system
that does an analysis.
So I'm gonna use
the system to do
that right now.
So I'm gonna go in
here and I'm gonna
switch to my MCP
and I'm gonna say,
give me some ideas
on a basic
using a uh sql light
bb for the collection
for the collection and
understanding of like
what data should we
collect any ideas we
can do anything um what
kind of audience are
you anticipating to be
role you guys all these
enthusiasts professionals
something else
yeah yeah it's i'm
guessing professionals i
i don't really know
uh for advanced data
analytics from introductions
to more automated
and by the way the
o'reilly guys came up
with with this do an
analysis of the tariffs
i already did that
the tariffs are so
political i know i'm
just gonna just use
the yeah please uh
health data so yeah it
has to be you can do
housing data you can
do housing data
that's one that we we
use today to set up
one of our golden data
sets was housing
data you could do um
consultancy rates you
know job jobs jobs
uh the latest uh
jobs data from the uk
maybe let's It's still
clear for the U.S.
Too political in
the U.S. Every
time I post
anything about the
U.S., everyone
flips out at me.
Apparently, my A
-flip... How the layoffs
are affecting all the
AI transformation.
Jobjita.
Change.
Relating...
It might give us
the wrong thing
we're looking for,
but relating to
AI
affecting
technical...
jobs from the UK. I'm
going to do the UK.
No one ever got mad
about the UK, right?
Everyone loves the
UK. No one thinks
I'm going to do the
UK, can you say?
Oh, they should.
Yeah.
Somehow that post
about my post this
morning gave like
15 people they said
I'm a woke libertard.
I don't even
know what the ****
that even means.
I'm just pointing
out that it's
dangerous to not
have regulations
but apparently
that makes me woke.
uh but regardless here
we are um so okay i'm
gonna use that so i'm
gonna use use the at
mcp so if you
guys are curious
about how i do
this i've got
my mcp instructions
and use the
So that's just a
mockdown file with
some instructions
that you wrote?
Yeah,
I copy and pasted
them directly from
it. So I did those
instructions.
So it just basically
says how to use the MCP.
And otherwise, it
kind of messes around
trying to figure out
how to use the MCP. so
what i do is i went
into here and i i chose
the perplexity and
literally just copy and
pasted this oh got it
and then copy paste that
over here and then
when i refer to it it
doesn't have to spend
10 minutes and two
dollars trying to figure
out how to use it save
to a you know it would
be really smart if
it actually read its own
instructions that you
just it's supposed to
but it never does i
i don't know why this
there's a slash tool
and slash discovery
option it but there's no
consistency in the
specification so everyone
implements it differently
uh so it'd save
the day the data
to sqlite db
in slash db uh
data db do you
have a sqlite
instance running
uh no i'm gonna
i'm gonna create
it so we're
going to we're
going to do that
right now um
use subtasks the
uh underscore task
let's do a little
light uh db creation
all right so now
we're gonna practice
what we preach i'm
i'm researching
the data. I'm
going to use sky
kit, side kit.
So now it's going to
create a structure.
I'm vibing this
as you guys can
tell. I'm just
kind of winging it.
I'll refine it
here in a minute.
This is a live vibe
session anyway, so
why not live vibe it?
So what this is doing
is creating a SQLite.
SQLite's by far
the easiest way to store
dynamic information.
It's light, it's
easy, it's text, it's,
you know, for these
sorts of things,
you don't need a vector
or anything crazy.
All right, so. You
should try .db sometime.
Yeah, I like .db for
the same reasons.
We could do .db.
Hey, why don't
we do that then?
Okay, stop.
All right, you
convinced me.
It's an analytics
effort, so should
be good enough.
Yeah, exactly.
It's a little heavier
though, right?
Heavier on the RAM,
but easier on the I.O.
Okay. All right.
You convinced me.
We're going to go back.
We're going to delete
that momentarily.
All right.
And we're going
to start again,
because I like the
idea of DuckDB.
and you know it's a great
start by researching
duck b and duck db
yeah duck db is tuned
for olab workloads so
it's yeah technically
it's technically a
good fit for what
you're doing here yeah
you know you're right
it's a great and to
be honest that was one
of the things I was
considering the other
day as well. So that
was a good call out.
All right. So start
by researching JEPTB.
Let's see.
All right.
I always feel
like I'm starting
the boat motor
on this thing.
Give it a
couple of pulls.
And by the way,
if anyone asks, I
did get an electric
starter for my
boat. So I'm moving
up in the world.
It's nice.
it's it's i think they
call it a rib it's
like one of those boats
you like storm the
beach on it it's i
also have this heart of
this little heartless
uh little cove on lake
huron so if i ever
need a smuggle i mean
go across the lake
i've got a nice little
way to do it i'm only
i'm about 80 kilometers
from the uh from
michigan straight across
the lake i probably
do you need to carry
your passport when you
do that trip oh i if
i i i don't go to
stage right now i think
if i showed up at the
border i'd probably be
smuggled out to el
salvador at this point
let's just say
calling calling my
uh friday the ai
hacker space might
have not been
the best branding
anyway i i get the
special room it's all
good special room
yeah they uh they
take my laptop and then
they get my password
and they ask me
questions about ai
Last time they
asked me about what
does AI stand for
as an acronym? I'm
like, I think it's
Adobe Illustrator.
They didn't appreciate
that joke as
much as I did.
All right, so what's
it doing? It's
creating an
initialization of DuckDB.
I assume DuckDB
needs to be installed
through a pip, I'm
going to guess. It's a
runtime, so you just
add it to your path.
Okay.
Let's see if it
figures that all out.
Roof, how close
do you need to get
when you are
prompting? Because I
think they're calling
it AI turnover.
So how close do
you need to get in
vernacular terms
to find what you
want when you're
prompting like this?
Well, you're seeing
what I'm doing. So
right now, it didn't
find the module, which
is obvious, it needs
to install it. But
right now, I'm just
vibing it, right? I'm
not giving it
particularly a lot of
guidance. You know, I'm
using the orchestrator,
but I actually
manually invoke the
orchestrator by basically
telling it to do
the subtasks in the
new underscore task.
So you'll see that the
autocoder currently
is a subtask,
right? So I'm kind
of vibe orchestrating
it a little bit.
Now I've created
the DB. So I'm
guiding it, I think,
is the answer.
You're being
of a conductor,
right? Yeah,
exactly.
Here's the thing, though,
Matt, is that I'm
currently defining a
product that I'm coding.
I haven't started
to code the product,
but I've actually
written a 40-page PRD
that's a very technical
architectural PRD,
not a normal PRD that
a PM should write.
Because if you write
that sort of PRD and give
it to the engineering
team, they will,
like, attack you
because you're telling
them how to build it.
But for VibeCoding,
you need to do both the
PRD, the use cases,
the personas, and the
architecture. So your
VibeCode PRDs are huge.
You need to get really
detailed. And in
some cases, you need
to say, this piece of
it needs to be running
Neo4j in a Docker
container and needs to
be connectable through
using specific types
of technologies.
Just because
you're opinionated
as an integrated
role across all
those steps in
the methodology.
Yeah,
that's absolutely
true. I'm a product
guy around management
PM teams, and I
wouldn't do that if I
was giving a POD to a
Figma designer or
an engineering team.
But because I am both
the PM, the designer,
and the engineering
coder, I've got
to put all that in
one POD, and I've got
to write it in kind
of prompt language,
prompt vibe
language, so that
I can actually
give it to Roo
to say, start
building this.
Yeah, and this is the
integrated methodology,
right? And, you
know, the power of
that is concentrated
in yourself rather
than dependent on
this chain of other
individuals across
the organization.
And that's why I do
it, yeah. And that's
what I think. To me,
that's the future
of product management
is that I'll be
an extension of
engineering and of design
as well as I do
all the front-end
stuff, the competitive
analysis, the
marketing, you know,
all that ****. Right.
So I'm a one-person,
five-man team.
Right. But whereas
before, you then get all
these knowledge gaps
and these collaboration
issues, now with it
being you can do it
all in your head,
the coherence and the
speed, because you can
do this excellence all
the way down the value
chain, is immense.
That's the problem.
Absolutely. And that's
exactly where
PM is going.
As a PM, we already
know most of that
anyway, but there's
always this tension
between design and
engineering. and you're
supposed to not tell
engineering how to
build it right but
if you're the one-man
team you've got all
that in your head i'm
a i'm a super technical
pm i can write code
and like python rust
and go so i know
how to do all this
anyway i usually break
it out david and break
it out specifically
into technical
specifications functional
specifications uh
mostly following in
sort of my exposure to
Reuven's process earlier.
But I guess as long as
you're covering
that ground,
it doesn't matter if
it's in a singular
document or broken
out separately. Yeah,
you're right, Rob. And
the key thing that is
really catching me, and
this is one for you,
Reuven, is the test
-driven development.
The theory that you
have sort of proposed
here and we work with
is that you should do
your test first right
you need to build out
your test first so
that it knows what to
code against what to
test against so that's
kind of that's the
tricky part for a product
management whatever
you're defining a pod
is like how to how to
get your test built
out first before you
start writing any code
yeah that that point
hands-offs sorry just
to finish your point
that hands-off or rather
handing off right
was because it's only
fair that you build it
you run it right and
you're asking someone
else to build it they
have to have a say but
right they don't exist
anymore so yeah they
don't yeah it's like
it's in one person's
mind now um and so you're
my prds are like 40
pages plus i have some
some supporting prds
or our specs and docs
um but you know it's
all in this sort of
different language now
which is well you're
what we're doing here
but david i mean you
touched upon the future
of pm right so you are
you obviously know your
stuff you are actually
a developer in
disguise as a pm right
in fact that's a yes
people who are not who
have lost like in my
personal case right i
mean the first version
from a discussion anyone
can create right i
mean the way to do the
you talked about the
detailed you know
customer journey now if
you kind of would have
found the deep research
mode that you know
that rose prom does that
actually creates most
of the guardrails
anyways for the bill so
for me like even someone
who's starting off
new i mean basically
getting the groove of
this the first iteration
is relatively pretty
easier that probably
is the spec to the
engineering team to say
here is what and now
you guys you do it so
it's no longer like a
prd but that's the
that's the specification
yeah so that's what
you should be aware of
is that if you use
perplexity or open AI deep
research to say, draft
me a POD for this
particular problem space
and this particular
application, it'll do
it. It'll do a really
good job of it. But
I always find that it
does an 80% job and it
misses one of the big
ticket items. So you've
got to read it and
you've got to know
what the application is
and the problem space
and the use cases are.
But that POD will
reflect a traditional POD
that you would normally
give to the engineering
team to architect it
and design it, build
it. You can't give that
POD to Roo and say,
now build it. It's not
good enough to vibe
code from that. You've
got to elaborate on
that as an engineer,
as an architect, as a
designer, and as a vibe
coder. You've got to
build out that POD.
That's why the normal
process now is to give
a five-page POD to an
engineering team you
would never i've built
100 page prds in the old
days i would never do
that today but with
vibe coding i i have to
do that you've got to
be able to build the
depth david do you have
a outline or framework
of a prd that uh you
are comfortable with
like uh like for a for
an example so um us
starting with the PRD
process could
get an idea of
how much needs
to be there
and where it
starts and stops.
I could, yeah,
I could actually
show you some of
my PRDs. Like the
one I'm working on
now is actually,
I'll share it with
you. It's actually a,
what I call a vibe
quant, stock quant. So
I'm building all of the
knowledge of a stock
trading quantitative
analysis guy and um and
and but as as a vibe
so you can anybody can
be a quant basically
anybody can be a stock
traded quant do all
the deep analysis that
they do over months
in like the space of
like three minutes which
is kind of what um you
know do all this analysis
and stuff i could
show you guys my prd
uh for that it's not
it's a filled out prd
not a template but um
i could do it i'll
have a look for it and
ruben i'll hijack ruben's
presentation i don't
want to do that man
sorry david i think
you could join us
tomorrow you guys can do
whatever you want i'm
just building my my
presentation for next
week but you guys you guys
saw quickly i created
myself a data science
system like you know 20
minutes so apparently
it ***** to be a data
scientist yeah it
does i know uh so and
by the way i i i was
embedded into a few data
science teams recently
i'm not the most
popular guy when it when
i show up i you know
like sometimes when
people can't hide their
disdain on their face
when they have that
sort of uh ****-eating
grin i know i know i
i show up i see that
sort of look and like
oh great this is this is
going to be one of
those uh one of those
engagements but the uh
i don't this explains
why look i what it is
did you know this this
job cluster visualization
i literally just
asked chat you know
perplexity to go build
me this thing tell me
review the jobs in uk
and then create a data
structure for it you
know literally in a
second i buy the whole
**** thing um yeah
this is awesome this is
one of the first use
cases that came out like
two years ago was
conversational analytics
and that's basically
what you've done that's
exactly what i'm
doing so now now that
i've done it now i need
to figure out how to
present it um let's
see so i'm going to
jump i'm going to jump
back and push it into
into gamma well i'm going
to get a presentation
i'm going to Joe
something to read me
to I discovered something
yesterday unless
you've got something
you know Gemini after
the releases they have
an export option of
when you do deep
research they have got
these used to be export
to docs only now they
have said export a
lot of other options
and then it gives
something else so I said
game so I was working on
a use case so basically
based on what I
have, they created a
kind of a gamification
or a website option.
So like if you have
this output and
present it as a like
a website, interactive
website, it just
creates it for you.
That was quite, quite,
quite interesting.
Well, I'm the presenter.
I don't, I don't
need it. I only
have 20, I've got 35
minutes to give me my
entire presentation.
And what's going on
here? I mean, you
just said it took you
20 minutes to run it
in the background.
you could either show
them at the beginning
by the way this is
me i'm going to run
this in the background
while we talk and
at the end come back
and show them that
it's actually done
yeah maybe instead of
line bars you could uh
actually have
representations of the teams
in 20 i don't know 2019
there was eight people
in 2024 now it's
one one to three and
actually use the icons
of the people possibly
instead of the bars
because you have to figure
out how to read that
all the data scientists
if a data scientist
can't read a bar chart
then yeah they're
definitely going to be
automated you know i
these two are the most
basic form of data
visualization right i yeah
i i'm going to assume
that the these people
are are at least somewhat
capable Maybe that's
the wrong assumption,
but all right. So
I've got the O'Reilly
SuperStream. I'm going
to put that into another
folder, we'll call
that presentation and
then what I'm going to
do, rename that something
a little better.
GenAI
Super
Stream
And now what I'm going
to do I do like the
idea of starting
something At the beginning
But it might be
disjointed to start Before
you know what the
**** it is But I
don't know, we'll
figure that out in a sec
We're going to
go back here And
I'm going to
update the region
Using the At
Presentation stream
and the current
implementation as a
tutorial step by step.
Include the Spark
specification as
outlined in at through
modes and I know
this is interesting
you guys to see how
I put together a
presentation I'm doing
next week. You
can tune into the
presentation and see
how bad I massacre it.
Roo,
I'm basically introducing
sort of my approach.
And then I'm just
gonna go here.
We'll go to the
document writer.
This would be a high
level introduction
to how I,
Roo,
do this.
Use agentic
development and imbibe
coding for data
of the science.
Great. Let's
go over here.
Look at this.
Where's my readme?
Let's see all this.
All right.
Include. Advance.
Get. All right.
I think this should
be good. Good,
right, let's see
what it does.
Remember when we
had to do all this
by hand and scratch
and this would
have been like a
two day project
just to do the
stupid presentation?
Oh yeah, God, man,
more than that dude.
Presentations
for these things
take like a week
to get right.
And I even, I
exported my entire
presentation
as a text file.
I could probably format
that up a
little bit more.
So now it's going to
review all the stuff I
created and then create
a little tutorial.
I might try to
integrate some
more this side
kit components.
I really like side
kit for like basic
data science stuff
because it's easy.
You know, it mimics a
lot of the structure
of PyTorch without
having to wait
20 minutes for
everything to install.
Yeah, yeah, it's
a great module,
Python module. Yeah,
you can see how quickly
I was able to do it here.
I guess I probably
need the extension.
It's one of
the originals,
man, scikit-learn.
Yeah, it's still
one of my favorites.
Yeah, it's up there
on the leaderboard.
Let's show it.
I got it.
All right, let's see
what it's doing now.
It's just reviewing
everything, I guess.
Let's see. Let's
make a closer
look at what the
heck it built.
And so, job
analytics example.
I use the database with
scikit-learn
for analytics.
It uses learn.
Looks like it's
generating sample data.
This is the data I
scraped from using
complexity. Oh, here
we go. Screen tutorial.
SuperStream is a
product demonstrating
agentic engineering and
Vibe Coding Principles
by me gives you
my definition it's
creating a regurgitated
version of the
presentation which is
kind of what i wanted
spec model mcp i
didn't add an mcp
but i'm using the
mcp from ru's point
of view uh because
i first it's often
described as sqlite
for analytics
suggestion thanks guys
for for that um all
right let's say that's
done let's render
that and see what that
looks like something
funny about mcp i was
writing my prd and open
ai interpreted mcp as
master control program
yeah it does it all
the time so i have
to actually tell it
what what mcp meant was
mcp a thing back in
like june 2024 came out
no no november october
november yeah Yeah,
that's the cutoff for
the open AI models.
All right. The
project consists
of several
Python scripts to
demonstrate aspects
of the system.
Right.
Tutorial setting
up the database.
That's good.
Populating it with
data jobs. Oh, yeah.
Let's update that.
the AI MCP within
root code for
the populating
of data jobs.
Review the mcp
.givson and mcp
instructions and
update the tutorial.
All right, so that's
because I statically
inserted the data,
but I got the data by
doing the query. The
idea is to use RuneCode
MCP capabilities to
research and then
pop you late the DuckDB
and related data.
We probably
should use a CSV,
but we'll worry
about that later.
Leave the rest as is.
We have title engineer,
we can filter by,
that's kind of cool,
we can filter by jobs.
We got advanced uses,
create a custom
advanced analytics, but
combine depth to be
SQL capabilities.
This is actually
kind of a
cool little thing
I built here.
Extending the database,
we can add new
structures,
integrate with
other systems.
Okay, what's
it adding now?
here we go.
Hopefully I didn't
actually add my key.
Where is it?
Yes, the GitHub
is correct.
That's technically
correct.
Your
key or whatever.
All right.
I need to give it a
little more guidance.
What it did is it
gave it the actual XML
that Roo needs to
use to invoke it,
which is not quite right.
This is technically
true. This is how it
does the argument,
but it's not actually
how you set it
up, which would be,
I think, confusing.
So it's like
telling it basically
how Rue does it,
not how you do
it. It's the
wrong perspective.
There we go. Now we're,
that's the way
we want it.
All right.
Configure and
close it, yeah.
Within Rue, use the
perfection, yeah.
Yeah, that's better.
Rue. Okay.
Let's cancel that. Number
two or number
two I think one
of the things that
people don't necessarily
see as often is just
the magnitude of
documentation and
backstory you can offer in
this and I think
that's part of the vibe
coding benefit if you can
put all the information
here because this
is this is all the
stuff people do after
and they and they and
it never gets done and
it and this is such
a good it's such a good
backstory these are
angel fire ancient
news processes i don't
think a five corner
is going yeah it's uh
yeah and you're right
it's it's not just set
and forget and you
know sometimes i brag
about oh i can let it
run for 36 hours we
know we touching it
that's more like like a
marathon just to show
that you can do it
but most of the stuff
really it's i'm running
for a couple hours i'm
iterating i'm fixing
i'm adjusting you know
it's not too often
i let something run
for for 36 hours other
than just to prove
that i could are you
discussing sessions
it's an approach for
excellence right because
you've got these deep
methodologies and you
can say what excellence
looks like and then
say go do that thing
do it the best you
could possibly do it
You know what I want
to do? I'm thinking.
I'm already
vibing here, so
let's vibe this
a little further.
An advanced
version of the, um,
of the, uh,
uh,
tutorial, no, I'm, I'm
not sure I'll
describe it,
of the analytics,
Java analytics,
yeah, this one,
Java analytics DB.
create and what i don't
want to do i don't
want to hit an llm i
want room to be the
llm i don't want it to
go and make a separate
separate so what i
want to do is i want to
create another version
create an advanced
version of the uh
you know in slash you
know in a sub folder
advanced that uses the
perplex perplexity
what complexity is the
worst freaking name for
something perplexity
mcp as part of the data
gathering component
similar similar to
the attach an example.
Let's go here,
where's my picture?
We'll use this.
And remove the
Gemini requirement
and just Just use
the raw JSON response
and update the
db, advanced db,
and create all
the files going
to be, you know,
init, import,
CLI, et cetera,
and a re, me,
that's going
to be in a subfolder.
All right. I think
that makes sense. Now
I'm going to switch
to, back to my, there,
and I'm going to
say, use sub pass via
new underscore task.
Now I see what I'm
doing, I'm spawning
subtasks from the original.
The original has
the context that I
want, but I don't want
it to get confused
with all the other ****
I just did. I wanted
to orchestrate sub.
Now I could do this
also by switching to
just orchestrator,
which is, let's
do that, why not?
And I'm gonna copy this,
hopefully that
makes sense.
So where did you come
into the thing? You
are using perplexity
for data gathering. oh
yeah yeah so what i did
so it's a good question
when you if you look
really closely it's
probably too small to
see this image is a
is how to create a
sort of mcp driven sort
of tooling but but i
used a gemini api to
do this yesterday it
was like a linkedin post
i did just for the
**** of it but i don't
want to include gemini
in this case i just
want to be able to
request the mcp and then
i i want to be able
to then get the data
so and it already knows
i use the perplexity
hopefully so i'm just
going to take the
perplexity and do that
so now you see it created
a subtask and it's
going to use it's
going to create an
advanced version it's going
to initialize the duck
db and i'm going to
create a new duck db
db here and then i'm
going to create a readme
and some other stuff
for it let's see under
what circumstances
do you completely
start a new task versus
just add chat context
to an existing task?
When I'm actually
building a project
that's meaningful and
guided, and I'm probably
not going to do
that, but I'm vibing.
Like right now, I'm
just vibing. So if
you think of it like
a tree, this is a
branch from the
original vibing session.
The original trunk
gives it all the
context to the thing
I was building. This
branch is a sub sort
of vibe from that.
So I'm vibing in a kind
of orchestrated mode.
Subtasks, main tasks,
research. So now
I'm using the perplexity
components here.
And by the way, the
integration of MCP
as part of your vibing
process, as you can
see, is spectacular,
right? I can integrate
all kinds of
different MCPs based
on what I'm vibing.
And like if I'm doing
like a agent using
Mastra or something,
I'll use the the
Mastra MCP, which tells
me all about Mastra.
So it's a really
cool way to sort of
vibe. And now there
might be a DuckDB MCP
that I could go find
somewhere and I could
start using that.
That's actually
an interesting
thing that, maybe
I'll do that next.
All right, so let's
create a new folder.
So while that's
happening,
what I might go do
a quick search here.
I'm gonna go to ChatGPT.
There's got to be a
DuckDB MCP somewhere.
Give me a list
of DuckDB MCPs.
Let that cook
for a minute.
So now it's creating an
advanced job-related,
better error handle,
advanced methods for app,
leveraging AI-related
metrics, better data
extraction, integration
of the perplexity
MCP for data gathering.
So now what I'm doing
is I'm putting a pipeline
that actually uses
an MCP directly in
the code itself, where
before I was abstracting
the perplexity MCP
through root code,
I actually wanted to
integrate that directly
in the system itself.
You can see here, it's,
this might be,
so it's going to
extract the data.
That's a good way
to do it. So this is
the data structure,
the DB structure,
a schema, I
guess you'd say,
creates the index.
Now what I probably
wanna do at the
very end is add a
environmental variable
so I don't give
everyone my
complexity. I'll do
that here in a minute.
After it works,
I'll worry about
the environmental
variable.
Oh, this happens
sometimes on longer
writes. I don't know
why it does that.
And also ChatGPT
doesn't like me sharing
the screen anymore,
it locks it all up.
It only happens
when I'm using Zoom.
Everything broke.
All right, I'm going
to cancel this for
a moment. This is
something that happens
frequently. use a
more modular file yeah
it's it for whatever
reason when you reach
around 700 to a
thousand lines it's
root truncates I don't
know why but let's
let's go with a more
modular structure to
check my calendar
make sure I'm
not skipping
someone's meeting I'm
a smarter I extended
this call so
I people kind of
tendency to book
me right at the
end, and I was
late for every
single one of these.
Does this make
sense so far
what I'm showing
you guys?
Yes.
You mentioned about
using MCP within
the code. I did
see the code was
actually writing a
lot of SQL statement.
Could you elaborate
that a little bit?
I'm not sure I fully
followed that bit.
i'm i'm basically
using perplexity mcp to
search for different
topics in this case job
you know doing the
analytics on jobs and
jobs impacted by ai then
i'm then i'm setting
up the uh sql structure
using duck db and
saving the the response
output from the mcp
directly to the database.
Then I'm running
a rudimentary data
analytics model using
scikit or scilearn or
whatever they call it.
And then running the
whole thing as a CLI.
I like CLIs for data
science in particular
because of what
you see right here.
when you in uh in
ru you've got the
execution mode i find
most things you know i
i can run especially
for local types of
things that i don't
need studio studio mcp
as a cli is actually
more than adequate
because you can run
those commands directly
in here and then it
can self-optimize
and test and do
everything it needs to do
what you also show on
your slide deck ru uh
the impact of a genic
engineering where
you talk about how you're
able to do the tasks
of three people and
it saves ** dollars
for what it would normally
cost and development
time and cost savings
which you also
want to include something
like that on this
day well i could but
again i got 35 minutes
it's it's one
of those things
like maybe i
should speak to it
yeah I'm not I'm
not like a big
fan of like walls
of text this is a
wall of text right
yeah yeah but
yeah I don't even
like putting in my
own like consult
I I don't like the
self-promotion part
either but everyone
tells me I have to
put that in there.
And then at the very
end I've got this,
maybe this is
what you're you're
talking about
something like this.
So a lot of posts you
have often you talk
about the end result
where you say it ran
for X amount of time,
and what it would
normally cost is $100
,000 in development time.
That's what I was
trying to talk about.
Basically, the whole
overall system and the
ROI of the system and
what you're able to
do as one person
would normally in the
enterprise take a DevOps
team and six months
and costs
80K, 100K.
That means SCC
command, basically.
So, Rup, the bit that
you do, maybe it's just
the running the SCC
command on your code.
I think that's what
you refer, Matt, right?
Oh, yeah. I
could do that.
Let's go to Klein.
Client just got an update
today, looking
pretty good.
Act, install the
Go SCC library
and run against
the, what the
heck's the name
of that folder?
I guess,
db and advanced.
I'm not trying
to do too much.
db, now
I'm running Client and
Rue at the same time.
I don't know which
I like better, you
know, the way that,
you know, the way
that Roo integrates
the command, you
know, terminal
directly in the session
or the way these
guys sort of, you
know, force it to the
existing terminal.
But for installs, it
definitely, sometimes
you just want to
go to the terminal.
Clients, you
know, for this
sort of thing, I like it.
So it's installing
the SCC. Let's go see
what Roo is doing
while it's happening.
All right, let's
go back here
and see what
it dreamt up.
Oh, there we go.
AI engineers ROI
multipliers. So
they give it an
increase in data
analysis productivity
is expected.
I don't know
about that text.
That's just ********.
Let's see what else
it comes up with.
I might have to
actually write that one.
that's like
text to me it's
meaningless text
where is that
so start the
slide deck you
are showing
where is that coming
from is it coming
from here from the
from the this one
is it auto updating
no right I haven't
inserted it yet but
I'm using Gemini's
you know slide
creator so AID assigns
a similar increase
in data I don't
like the image but
the text is better
yeah
All right. Let's
use that. Let's
lose this cheesy,
cheesy image.
Sometimes you don't
need it. You don't
need a cheesy text.
You just got to
say what you mean
and leave it at that.
Significant increase
in data analysis
productivity for
sure. Reduction in
traditional data science
hiring costs. Yep.
Enhanced scalability
with automated
workflows. Yeah.
Faster insights
leading to quicker
business decision
potential substantial
return investment
doing doing more
with less sorry
to step off and come
back are you trying to
figure out what the
value props are for doing
this yeah it was a
suggestion i i sort of
finished with a value
prop the one thing
with conversational
analytics because it was
a very early use case
uh sort of two years
ago, is that, as you
know, data scientists
are really expensive,
and it turns out that
only certain large
companies can have them.
So, by having
conversational analytics
tools, it democratizes
data science and lets
the average person
be a data scientist.
Everybody can be
a data scientist.
That's the real
reason for doing
conversational
analytics tools.
Yeah.
so like like a like
a 75 000 person
salary person can be
can act like a 350
000 data scientist
that that's the real
value everybody can
be a data scientist
now and you don't
need special you know
charities non-for
-profits anyone could
do it and which is
great for society
yeah that's the real
reason why these
tools are good
from my one bedroom
apartment i can be a
data scientists and
so can you yeah it
sounds like an info
commercial from
like the 90s it does
what's the ronco set
it and forget it the
oven put the chicken
there you go uh exactly
i i need i i need
like a like a one of
those sweaters that
guy used to wear oh
my god you know the
guy i'm talking about
yeah sweater guy all
right so apparently if
you believe sec estimated
costs to develop
uh 44 000 44 000
months four months oh
that's silly required
i'll break that one
they want to put an
asterisk there in case
someone takes you
to task board maybe.
Well I could
do a screenshot
I like that tool
actually I installed
that tool last
week and played
with it it's got a
weird name though
What's that tool?
The ACC tool
There we go so
you're saying maybe
let's do a
screenshot of this
Yeah yeah
i think you meant to
exclude some directories
i think it's probably
taking all the
directories yeah it
takes them all in the
plus 20 specified
specific directories
subdirectories right
oh yeah yeah it's two
hundred and thousand
dollars right okay
cancel that you're
right Okay, good catch.
Only include the advance,
advance and the
folders and nothing.
Yeah, you know what?
I'm like, oh, I did
$300,000 in 20 minutes.
That's a bit much.
Go.
It's going to
run it directly.
I'm not sure why
it keeps doing it.
I'm running multiple
things at the
same time. It's
probably what's,
yeah, it seems to
disappear after a second.
all right stop doing
that looks like
it yeah it's just
closing the terminal
after it's done
which i don't want
it to do what's
the value in this
one is this a more
reasonable number
what does it say
it doesn't have the
dollar number here
SCC, my file sort code.
I don't know why
it keeps closing.
All right, it's
taking the terminal
output and then
closing it when it's
done, which is
kind of annoying.
This should be a usual
thing to add to Spark.
Oh, you don't
need a spark.
This is just a terminal.
Yeah, I know. But
what I'm saying is
that, you know, it's
an output, right? so
it assesses the value
yeah it's it's it's
a console command so
you know you'd have
to install it i i'm
i'm only doing i'm
only doing prompts
uh all right 66 000
it's skill building
that's why it's higher
do we know how it gets
to the dollar number
like does it take any
particular average
salary details like do
you know the details
of now yeah it's all
it's all configurable
you could change it
and tweak it you could
do the alley rate um
it's all configurable
and they use a standard
database what's the
hourly rate is
considering at the moment
that's a good question
man we get lines of
code is it one api
usage is it sixty six
thousand dollars you
could probably back it
out that way yeah
always ask it you know i
don't know this is the
default output right
i'm just i'm just gonna
go here and and i'm
gonna use this view
because it looks more
clock clock code is
the what is the name
is a weird name for
that for that tool
construction
cost object or
something like
that i saw okay
it's a collection
i think of three
estimating libraries
or methodologies
Let's make that
rounded and
make it look a
little better,
there we go.
That looks more
believable.
Maybe put a
hashtag science.
This person.
Constructive cost model
following the parameters.
All right,
we'll copy that.
There we go.
Math in there for
those who like math.
I think, let's see where,
let's see where Rue is.
Still building.
Well, you guys
also saw that
you can use
multiple, you know,
clients at the same
time. So while Rue
was building this
uh what did the
heck did it build
let's go to advanced
do
you know how sec gets
the value of the the
overall value 72 000
is it lines of code is
it api it just it just
said it right here
uses the basic como a
constructor cost model
Kokomo Kokomo
calculations
yeah
that might be
an interesting
post for me
to do actually
if I can customize
SCC what I
should do is
some kind of like
the more code you
can produce the less
value of the code and
the time and the amount
of effort I should
do some kind of like
reductive algorithm
that basically says
you know i can create
10 million lines of
code a year but that
doesn't mean the 10
million lines of code
is actually worth
200 million dollars
it actually means that
10 million lines of
code is worth some you
know order of
magnitude less based on
some kind of uh
mathematical equation that
i determined because
it uses three models
So it uses three
models, organic, semi
-detached, and
embedded, but you can
also customize the
model that it uses
as well, highly
customizable for
calculating the financials
of its estimate.
so one on that point
building on that point
one of the criticisms
i think general i
mean against like coding
or agentic is people
like traditional
software engineering
will say well but it
doesn't mean that you
write so many lines of
code so it is you know
it's about tech debt
etc you know so this
point about reductive
cost modeling how
can we showcase the
quality of the code and
thereby what therefore
is the value of it
like i'm thinking
more like so that that
point of criticism that
people come about to
say okay but this is
not as good as what a
human could produce
etc etc sure it doesn't
well the debt is a
massive thing you think
you've got progress
but actually you've
accumulated debt if
you can show you have
built excellence across
the methodology and
it's robust then
surely that's a great
starting point take an
existing application
not to find features
and then you reproduce
the features but it's
been produced sorry
and here you're all the
way jet you take the
also if you take an
existing application
and its features and
then you compare that
against something that's
reproduced without
reproducing the actual
problem so that's how
you can assess quality
you benchmark of that
and then whatever your
new cost versus the
perceived old cost is
what you're comparing
it's super hard to do
quality man to assess
code quality it's no
it's it well it's it's
subjective like yeah
totally subjective everyone
that and the pushback
i get from almost
everyone when i show
up in a business is you
know you're cranking
out so much code it has
to be bad yeah low
quality right yeah it
has to be low quality
which is subjective and
it's almost impossibly
for me to basically
say no it's not bad it's
actually it's actually
pretty good and here's
why because it's
subjective right and
and And any developer
worth their salt is
going to go into my code
and they're going to
find problems 100%. Of
course. Because there
is no such thing as
perfect code. It's
like perfect, you know,
written words. It just
doesn't exist, you know?
The difference between
Shakespeare and,
you know, some other
writer is purely
subjective. I like this
more than I like the
other. It doesn't make
it better or worse
as long as it's
grammatically correct.
Same general idea.
one of the one of the
biggest things that
points that vibe coding
gets hammered on is
supportability in
production right because
the code that it generates
is supposedly like
like elaborate or
overly complicated which
makes it very difficult
in order to support
it in production an
engineer has sit down
and read the code and
figure out what the
**** the the the system
was actually thinking
when it wrote the code
which you lose all
the now you have to
spend all this time
learning code that you
didn't spend writing the
code and that that's
that's one of the biggest
problems that vibe
coding comes up against
is so it's fast
prototyping awesome but
to support in production
you end up spending
all that time to learn
the code and nobody
wants to learn somebody
else's code right
so to build on that
point david the solution
i would think is to
keep everything modular
and if something's
broken rewrite it and
don't try to understand
how it used to it
don't buy absolutely
find the feature and then
rebuild it yeah i agree
i you know the the
rule of keeping
everything under below 500
lines and then also
doing highly modularized
code i bel i actually
believe that's that's
the a way forward for
for combating that
that uh objection
around don't using vibe
code because it can't
support it in production
yeah and you've built
you've built all these
test harnesses around
it so it should be
because the test harness
was requires that
modularity um you should
be able to establish
quickly what the
issue is yes it should
be modular enough to
be able to chop it out.
I totally agree. That's
why I was
talking earlier.
Ruben's thesis is
you get it to write
your codes first,
to tests first, then
write your code
against the tests.
And so if you get
your test harness and
all your test cases
done and built out,
then the code's modular,
then it's awesome.
That's great.
Anybody can
support your code.
And in fairness,
that's not my
thesis. That's
called the London
School of Test
-Driven Development.
Now, there's
also the Detroit
School. I don't
know who names
this stuff, but
it wasn't me.
And the Detroit
School of Test-Driven
Development is essentially
Waterfall. I'm building
a function, I build a
test, and then I run
the test against the
function that I'm
currently building. And
that's how 99% of test
-driven development is
done today because nobody
really wants to build
entire scaffolding
and do the job literally
three times to solve
the same problem. But
AI doesn't complain.
So the fact that AI
is doing four times
the work to get to
the same result is
a feature, not a bug
in this scenario.
So the London School of
Test-Driven Development
is suddenly really
practical because
it creates a roadmap
of what needs to be
developed before it
actually develops it in
multiple steps. A mock
step, which is faking
it before you make
it. it then makes it
once it's made then you
can go and say implement
a more detroit style
implementation of
the test against real
endpoints and mcps or
whatever and again
you've now done two
different implementations
of a test-driven
development process to
get to a single output
yeah yeah i i
would rather have
yeah i would rather
have it have my system
designed and built and
run through like 19
times than once god
knows how many products
i've had built that
like you know took 18
months to build and
and were like you know
7 million lines of code
and were like almost
failures i'd rather
break it down into
like small iterations
and and iterate over
them like 100 times
way better way to do it
yeah yeah and if you
look at what i'm doing
right now i did the
opposite i did the let's
call it the Detroit
vibe school. I created
an initial, just to
recap what we've built
today, I created an
initial implementation
of a DuckDB sort of
analytical system. It
worked great. Then I
said, okay, let's go
and build this in a
more modular, scalable,
extensible way.
It did that.
Then I didn't test
it. Then I said,
go. I noticed that
it didn't include,
it forgot to include
the actual perplexity
MCP implementation.
So I said,
you know, to create an
ENV, which basically
allows me to
define where the
perplexity MCP is running,
which is apparently
localhost, which
I'll fix later.
And then lastly, I
told it to go create a
unit testing framework
based on everything
that's in here, and then
run it until I get 100
% coverage. So that
would be a top-down
approach because I vibed
it. I wasn't sure what
I wanted to build. You
guys kind of watched
me discover that I was
going to build something
based on which jobs
get replaced. So now
it's going and it's
going to create the
missing parts to parse
the various components.
Now I'm still going to
have to do a few other
things to get to the
end point, but I vibed
myself an MCP-driven
data analytics system
which is with with
no need for having an
llm to interpret it
which is cheaper yeah
conversation on analytics
tool yeah and this
will integrate really
nicely into ru so now
if i wanted to create
a data analytics system
which i do directly
in ru to enact and
have ru act as the
orchestrator of the analytics
all i need to do is
point ru at this code
and say go do your
thing now Now this is
going to be problematic,
I already know it,
but that's okay, I'll
get it to replace this
with the actual
endpoint for Composio or
whatever I'm using as
a remote instantiation
of it, but I'm going
to worry about that
later because I want
the tests to pass first.
Once all the tests
pass, then I'll go back
and say update any
mentions of localhost with
the actual live
perplexity MCP endpoint,
which inevitably will
result in a few errors
because the response
will be different.
I'll fix those, and then
we'll be good to go.
Great.
And that – this is – as
far as vibe coding goes,
we've hit, like,
a new tier of
vibe coding
today, I think.
This is a really
good approach.
What do you say
new tier? What
did we do that
was different?
Well, we've integrated
a sort of MCP
-driven data collection
process as part of
the Vibe coding, right?
So we essentially
use the Perplexity
MCP to do the research
and then implement
it as part of it,
where normally I would
have gone and went
to the ChatGPT or
Perplexity directly
and said, do deep
research, create a
strategy. I did that
more iteratively today.
Got it.
I don't know. I'm using
hyperbole, whatever.
Ruben, just
pasted my comment
back at the bottom
of the chat.
Regarding one of your
early slides, you say
that your framework is
a methodology. I don't
think it is. I think
it's an approach for
excellence, for incorporating
deep methodologies
into the automation
of a value chain.
And Spark is just one
of those value chains.
So you think I should
call it framework?
What the heck do I call
it? i think i think
you do have a framework
but i think the
framework is for
pulling in methodologies
all right so i think
spark spark like what
the heck well i think
your approach um
your approach can
pull in methodologies
and spark is one of
the methodologies
so maybe it's
fine now maybe
it's a conversation
for later
I don't think
it's, yeah, I don't
know how much value
that adds to this
presentation. Yeah.
You know, I think
it would make it
complicated now,
but I think it is
worth a discussion.
Yeah, you're
probably right.
I'm not really sure.
I've debated
whether or not to
call it a framework,
a methodology,
prompt engineering.
I don't know.
I would go a step
further to say, is
it a catalyst, like
chemical reaction?
You put a catalyst
in and all
the different elements
behave better.
Pseudocode, specification,
writing. yeah just
visualizing it perhaps
a catalyst yeah i
was bouncing around
thoughts i wanted to get
your opinion opinion
on the thought of vibe
coding because i think
it really doesn't do
what ruko complete
justice to ruko because
and as i'm thinking
through the process you
you um to properly
evangelize ruko in my
opinion i think what
you're what you are
currently doing is very
much in line with test
-driven development,
trunk-based development,
DevOps,
things that
enterprise developers
have gone through the
transformation for
the last two years.
So, and technically,
under the
hood, it's all of
that. It's not just
the vibe coding
part. It's more
what an enterprise
is doing now.
Yeah, so I call
that a convergence,
right? You're converging
like five roles.
so the roles but also
the uh the methodology
like development we
need to have this we
need to make this a a
focused discussion i
think this is yeah
it's really powerful
right yeah yeah super
powerful of what you're
doing rude so just
but i think the way to
meet the developers
where they are and what
they understand you
know so all right well
i'm uh i'm out of time
and uh you know next
week i'll be doing this
and i think there's
a free link somewhere
that i got for the
if you guys want to
tune into the o'reilly
uh presentation
there's a whole morning
afternoon if anywhere
you are i guess of uh
of similar presentations
uh from the o'reilly
team on data analytics
and i'm covering
the agentics part of
it um you guys will see
you guys get a sneak
peek at how i came up
with the whole thing
on the presenting next
week that's cool
thanks all right thanks
everyone so and for
anyone that wants to to
uh show anything
tomorrow we've always got
spots for you to show
on the friday sessions
awesome thanks all
right thank you okay