So, okay.
August 14th, here we are.
I was away last week,
so hopefully all
went well last week,
but we're back.
And this week, you
know, I think there
was some requests
to do some more
introductory sort
of work here, sort
of to go through
some of the flows
on how I'm doing this
stuff and how I kind
of go from idea to
sort of final product.
Before we do, though,
it'd be nice
to get a little
recap from Jed
and the crew on
what you guys
did last week.
So last week,
we got a bunch
of folks stood
up on their
respective Codespaces
or DevPods.
I think two or
three people got
their first Rackspace
accounts up.
And then the day
following, we created
Anteroids, basically
a quick demonstration
creating an offline browser
-based game representing
the, what was it,
1970s Asteroids
game. uh i the prompt
was wasn't perfect
intentionally so and was
very openly shared with
the group who attended
so that they were
able to reproduce it
for themselves with
i assume a bunch of
folks are putting up
their own mods or different
sprites for whatever
variants of games that
they're experimenting
with so it's like
uh was that what
was that game i saw on
netflix or it was on
Throggles, I think
it was, on Black
Mirror. And the
guy creates this
sort of universe
of autonomous
self-aware sprites
in a game and it
takes over or
whatever. I don't know,
if you've seen that
episode, you've got
to watch that one.
It's for the AI.
Yeah.
It's a good one.
Also, there was a
really neat demo
by John O'Hare on
a visualization.
of uh of swarms and
orchestration which is
really neat of uh i
gotta pull back up what
that repo was but
there was yeah there's
some pretty neat stuff
there there's some pretty
neat stuff there cool
all right so this
is the vibe cast so the
big story apparently
is everyone there was
a a guy uh paul graham
which is like uh like
a vc for tech stars
or i think it was tech
stars um he's a vc
of some sort and he
basically said he talked
to someone who's he
was claiming to do 10
,000 lines of code a day.
It was my combinator.
I don't know. All
those, you know, all
those PCs are scammers
anyway. But the
interesting takeaway here
was basically everyone's
like, no way, that's
not possible. You
can't do 10,000 lines of
code a day. It's going
to be garbage. It's
no good. You know,
and I think that it
opened up an interesting
discussion in terms of,
you know, the meaning
of lines of code is
kind of meaningless,
right? And in fairness
to some of the haters,
a lot of those lines
of code are things
that probably aren't
meaningful whatsoever,
like a config file,
an MD file, and
scaffolding that
goes around the code.
And ultimately, what's
meaningful is does
it work? Is it
secure? Does it scale?
And does it make you
money, right? Those
are the metrics that
probably ultimately
matter. Now, if you
can do that in 2,000
lines or 100 lines
of code, then great.
But what's interesting
about the things
that we're looking
at and what I'm
showing you is you
can also do things
that are substantially
more complex.
So the lines of
code is obviously a
mechanism to look at
things like complexity.
It's the ability to
understand how all the
parts of your application
fit together. but
it doesn't necessarily
represent the value
at all and I've anyone
that's telling you
because I've created
you know X million lines
of code it's therefore
more valuable than
some other application
that was able to do it
in a fraction of that
but what it also speaks
to is the is the
performance and the
capability to build this
stuff at scale so we
look at a team like a
large team let's say
the Google's and the
Microsoft's of the world
they have tens of
thousands of developers
cranking out probably
hundreds of thousands
of lines of code, I
don't know, a day, but
definitely a month,
and that their benefit
and their capability
up until recently was
the fact that they
couldn't afford to hire 10
,000 developers, you
know, at an average cost
of $150,000 a pop
per year, right? And
that was a sort of
defense against, you know,
upstarts and others
who would look to, you
know, you know, compete
against them. It's
hard to compete against
a company that has
10,000 developers.
Now you've got a small
group of people who
can compete because
collectively or even
individually, we don't
need 10,000 developers
to, to build these
sorts of things. So
it's, it's perspective.
Now I'm not saying
that the code is great
or bad or, or otherwise,
but I'm just saying
that it's possible.
Now in the, my last
comment here, while I
finished my diatribe
is that's why an
agentic engineer exists.
It gives us the ability
to not just vibe
our way into a solution
to the problem, but
to create a actual
process and architecture
and a definition
that's repeatable that
we can implement,
share, and use to sort
of effectively build
things in a way that
isn't sort of vibed
or abstract or random.
So again, this idea
that it's not possible,
it's obviously possible
the the idea that
it's bad well yes there
are bad programmers
there are good
programmers there are bad
vibers there are great
vibers that goes for any
profession and just
paint the sort of you
know it's either good
or bad isn't work it's
obviously a gray
scale and there's 256
shades of you know in
between there's probably
more than that but I'm
going to stick with
with the uh the the gif
analogy for a minute
all right or unless
you're the guy to
create it then it's Jif
apparently. I met the
guy once actually
that created Jif and I
asked him, is it Jif or
is it Gif? And he says,
it's like the peanut
butter. So there you
go. It's Jif, but I
don't want to, that's
a, that's another
conversation for another
day. All right. I'm
going to jump in here and
I'm going to show you
some stuff here. So
what I'm going to do,
I'm going to, as you
know, I like to jump
around in these things.
I'm going to, we're
going to do a few things
all at once. So first
of all, I've created
a repo today. You can
check it out while
All I do, I'll try to
update it frequently.
There's a Vibecasting
GitHub here,
and you can see
different branches.
I'm creating
a branch here.
Where did I put that?
I'm using the web
version here. It's
called August 14th.
The August 14th branch,
let's publish that.
This will, oh, I
should probably
add a name to
that or something.
Let's go ahead and
do that. Oh, it
looks like it's
working. So this
is where we'll
create whatever it
is we're gonna
create today. Okay.
But first of all,
what I'm gonna
do is I'm gonna
install some of the
components. So
this is gonna, for
those who haven't
done it before,
you can follow along
and do this as well.
For those who've
seen it, well, this
is just gonna be the
same old thing, but
I guess set it up. I
could hypothetically
use a dev container.
So whenever I
spin up a new instance,
it just does this
magically. I probably
should, but in
this case, I'm just
gonna do it manually.
So I'm gonna go to my
Claude-flow and I'm
gonna grab and I'm
gonna install the Cloud
code system first. so
I'm going back in here
and into my instance
and they keep mine
this is a Ubuntu and
everyone that's using
Windows my apologies
at some point maybe
I'll come up with a
Windows solution if you
are using Windows just
use a docker container
with Ubuntu it'll
work if you're on Mac
if you run into errors
most likely sequel
light errors point clot
at it and say fix the
errors and generally
to work there's as
far as I can tell
there's there's like
thousands of people
using mac so it does work
it's just not it's
sometimes it breaks in
weird ways but eventually
if you if you get
clod to sort of fix
those problems it will
resolve itself all right
so i'm going to pop
this in here i'm going
to install and i'm
using the code the web
-based version because
i didn't bother up
uh opening up vs code
so i'm popping this
in here i'm going to
install clod code and
while that while that
installs i'm going to
pop another one and
i'm I'm just copying
and pasting these
commands. So in this
case, I'm gonna grab alpha
89, which I launched
later last evening.
And so I'm gonna pop
that in here. I'm
gonna paste that as
well. So I've got two,
you can see one running
here. And I installed
Cloud Code. Now
what I'm gonna do is
I'm gonna jump back
and I'm just, I'm
lazy, so I don't wanna
bother typing this
stuff. So I'm just
gonna go and I run
dangerously skip
permissions. This will invoke
the various settings
for what I'm gonna
do. So I'm popping
that in there as well.
Now, when you're
using the sort of web
-based console, you're
going to have to log
in twice to Anthropic.
I don't know why. It
only really happens
in the web-based
version. So I'm going
to go and I'm going to
log in with this. I'm
going to open that.
That's not going
to work. It tries
to redirect to
localhost 54545,
which is unavailable
in the web version.
Exactly.
So I'm popping it twice.
So I'm not even
bothering with the first
one. I've done
this so many times
at this point, I know
it's not going to
work. So now I'm
going to the second
one, and I'm going
to click authorize.
And I'm going
to copy my code
and popping that in here.
Oops, guess it didn't.
I was a little too quick.
Oh, what?
What's going on?
Let's try it
one more time.
Oh, that time it copied.
Let's try it one
more time. Boom.
All right.
Creating the API key.
I'm going to log in.
yes with recommended
settings you can mess
with this if you want
i never do um i i'm
gonna i'm gonna do the
warning use at your
own risk all right i'm
in now i'm gonna jump
back here this is
installed oh i did the
npm install uh yeah i
can do the npm so why
not so there's there's
two ways to do it so
the the benefit the
npm install is you
can just run it like
this so in this case
I can go cloud I think
it's cloud flow yeah
there you go now I'm
gonna now I'm gonna
run cloud flow with my
in it now I've got a
bunch of different in
its by the way because
I'm in it so you can
see here that I've got
in it's for a github
and I've got some
monitoring and I guess
spark I get minimal
and there's actually
a bunch more that I
haven't even made available
in the help but for
now I'm just gonna
go with the standard
in it so because I'm
in a folder that has
stuff, I'm going to
have to force it. So
I'm going to go force.
You can see that it's
creating the various
things. We can go here.
We can see what it's
creating quickly.
Here's a cloud folder.
It's still creating.
All right.
Now I do a check to make
sure that the
MCP is working.
Now I didn't do an
MPX. So that might
be, I might take a
few minutes longer
because I didn't
install mpx now just
to just to make sure
that that's working
correctly it might
be it looks like
it's for some reason
i'm going to go and
do quad dash flow
at alpha slash mcp
sometimes there's
a conflict conflict
well no it looks
like it works
it's working okay just
took a second to do
its thing all right
so just just to recap
just for those who
aren't familiar you'll
notice that i did an
npm install the biggest
difference in npm install
means i don't need
to prefix this with an
npx or and i can also
run this using my
wrapper like this either
way it should work
so depending so if
you're on uh windows
you cannot use npx so if
you're going to use
windows the only way it's
going to work is it
was using npm just
straight up i don't
think npx works correctly
on windows for anybody
for anything but and
then basically at that
point point the um
cloud code at it and
say fix it i will at
some point fix it but
that's a different
problem all right so
we've got some so quickly
while i'm here we've
got some new features
so let's let's
show you those
quick and then
we're gonna vibe
some stuff so
cloud flow help
you'll notice uh that
that we now have uh
some features relating
to oh you know what i
didn't do i think
i'm writing the wrong
version here no i'm 89
no we're good all right
uh so we're we're we've
got features including
verify truth and
pair and i got some
other hidden things some
other easter eggs in
here but if we go here
and we'll do verify
so verify essentially
allows you to verify
and create a this was uh
our friendly neighborhood
uh vibe coder idea
to create a truth
and verification system
that creates a kind
of threshold that uses
the system to verify
and train itself so
it's not going down a
rabbit hole of creating
stuff that isn't actually
functional you'll see
a variety of different
features and commands
here relating to
that we've got a truth
option the truth it
works alongside that the
truth option essentially
allows you to view
and analyze the truth
scores reliability
matrix and verification
history so what these
things are doing is
essentially making
sure that your agents
aren't telling you what
you want to hear and
anyone that's vibed
anything will know that
you i created the the
newest quantum system
that unravels the
mysteries of the universe
but it doesn't actually
it just tells you what
you want to hear so
what this does is allows
you to sort of create
a mechanism to to
have the system learn
how to optimize and not
go down the rabbit hole
of the building the
wrong stuff and then
lastly and there's a
new pair system the
pair system allows it to
act like a pair coder
so this is a real-time
collaborative development
system that allows
you to kind of interact
with it a little
bit better and help
guide the development so
one of the challenges
you have when you're
working with these
agents and these swarms
and these hive minds is
it's like what are you
actually doing and
how can i sort of help
massage that in
a direction that
actually makes sense
so that's what all
these tools are
doing Now, what I
probably need to do
a little bit of is
probably add some
additional commands,
but I'll get around
that to another version.
But you can basically
point that at and
say, create me a folder
with commands in it.
You can see some,
I think I've
included some
of those in the
actual main
Claude-flow repo.
All right, hopefully
that was helpful.
We'll get into
how exactly this
works here in
a few minutes.
Now, I wanna vibe some
stuff today. So, and
you guys know I love
vibing crazy things. So
one of the thing, I've
been getting a lot
of, you know, I don't
know if pushback is the
right word, but a lot
of commentary on the
fact that I like to
use Rust. So everyone's
like, well, why don't
you use Go? And to
be honest, I'm not
really a Go guy, which is
a great, that sounds
better than I thought.
So what, there was
a research report
that came out recently
that was shared, I
think in our coding
group, that looked
at using AI to
detect signs of
extraterrestrial intelligence.
And this was, this
was actually a
paper someone wrote,
and it was kind of
interesting. So they
came up with this
whole hypothesis that
extraterrestrials might
be attempting first
contact by suddenly
influencing outputs in
language models, which
is crazy in all the
best ways possible, to
be honest. And this was
a theoretical paper.
So they had created
sort of the math and
the structure to do all
the analysis, but
they haven't actually
implemented this idea so
the question is can we
detect unusual ailing
like anomalies in ai
outputs seriously that's
that's that was that's
what i'm going to try
to do today because
it's crazy and i
thought why not use go
because i'm not a an expert
in go and i'm curious
how the system will
work in terms of using
that so if you're
interested i'm going to
pop this quickly into
the chat and anyone
that wants to vibe along
with me feel free but
you're going to watch
how i set up yep sorry
i shared that um and i
had a long conversation
with ngpt5 about how
it's how they want
to get in contact and
how they want to hide
and you know step by
step very cautious they
get in contact with
us so it's a complete
theory did you try
to have you tried to
implement it no it was
just a conversation a long
one and uh he suggested
i mean chair gpt
suggested me to really
look around it from
different angles and
it's possible absolutely
feasible and and
and really a good
idea from the um
from the aliens and
then i found one
paper which was not
peer-reviewed but
there is a guy who
was searching for
this four years ago
All right. Well, we're
going to build it.
And thanks for inspiring
today's vibe coding
session, because it's
crazy. Fantastic.
It's crazy enough
that I want
to go do it. And
I know exactly
if I share this
on the Reddit,
everyone's going to
say that I'm a, you
know, I'm a lunatic
viber that's
creating things that
don't actually work.
But that's beside the
point. It's normal
for me to do this.
Happy second day.
Yeah, exactly.
All right. So I'm
going to jump back in
here. I'm going to show
you how I set things
up. All right. So
first thing I'm going
to do is I'm going
to jump back in the
cloud code and I'm going
to set up my aliases.
So create the bash
RC alias for DSP.
And I'm going to go
to my history here and
I'm going to grab
the dangerously skip
permissions. And then
I'm going to do create
a dsp-c for dangerously
skip permissions
and I'm going to go
back. I always do this
because I hate typing
dangerously skip
permissions because
it's dangerously long.
So I'm going to
start with that and
what that what this
allows me to do
is basically type
dsp to start Claude
or dsp-c to start
Claude and resume.
Actually while I'm
doing that let me show
you another little trick
here for those people
always ask me about
how do you resume
sessions in clod well
you can do this as well
resume and when you
when you type resume
yes proceed with servers
you can see in this
case i haven't done
anything but you can
resume all previous
sessions which is kind
of cool or in and the
the dash the dash c
option basically allows
you to resume the
session you were you
were previously running.
In this case, I
was doing the DAS
C, so I'm going
to go back here.
All right, so
we've created that.
Now I'm going
to quickly test
that, just to make
sure it works.
DSP.
There we go. It
continues. Now
let's try DSP with
continue, and that
continues.
Perfect. All right,
now what I'm
going to do is I'm
going to go right
here, and I'm
going to create
a new folder.
and we'll create a
new folder, we'll call
it plans, and then
we'll call this new file
spec.md.
I'm going to jump
back to my anomaly
detection system, all
right, and because
I'm lazy, I'm just
going to go to the raw
version of it, go
here. Now, I could
just grab the URL and
help to look at it
but i prefer to have
it handy so i'm going
to go here and i'll
pop that in here
oops i copied the
wrong thing there
we go pop that in
here and remember
when if you're you
can always render
your mds by ctrl
shift v i anyone that
looks at an unrendered
md file is it
doesn't have my form
of OCD for sure.
I much prefer to
see it rendered.
So that looks good.
Again, this is
a high level
specification. It's
basically a functional
specification.
Now in this case,
what I'm gonna do
is I'm gonna start
a new session.
So I'm gonna type DSP.
And then in this
case, I'm gonna say,
I'm gonna use
my slash and I'm
gonna use my
Spark methodology.
Now you see I have
different Spark options,
Spark Code, Spark
Architect, Spark
TD, deployment
monitoring. In this case,
I'm just going to
go with Spark Spark.
It's kind of my generic.
Create a detailed
implementation
plan using at spec md in
in plan slash
implementation as a as a
multi-step multi-step
multi-step phased
implementation i i spell
it right not that it
really matters
implementation plan using
a clod flow swarm with
detailed TDD based
um structure uh
structure and uh using go
lang be complete and
in this case i'm not
going to bother with a
swarm it's probably not
needed but i could
hypothetically do a swarm
for the spec but
i'm not going to all
right so i'm gonna i'm
gonna invoke that what
would be the what
would be the difference
between them right
like is there a quality
difference a time
difference if you were to
do this versus just
using this one the spawn
well and in this case
i want to i want to
review the specification
before i actually uh
implement it so really
i i um i'm i could
say spec it and build
it but you know i want
the plan and if if i
want to speed up the
process what i might
do is create the
specification using a
swarm, but the drawback to
doing a spec-based or
a swarm-based spec is
there sometimes is an
inconsistency between
each of the parts of
the specification if
you're creating it as
multiple documents.
So, you know, Agent A
will have an idea that
Agent B doesn't, and
then the two, there's
a mismatch between the
two. So, if I'm going
to use a swarm for
that, I'm probably going
to use a hive mind. The
hive mind essentially
allows me to sort of
have more consistency
between each of the
agents where the
swarms they operate
independently with a self
uh governance and
autonomy so it depends
on what you're doing
in this case i'm going
i'm gonna go i went i'm
going i'm going more
simple so we're and
it's not that it's not
that crazy aspect so
we're gonna go there
now while that happens
though just sorry one
question please So that
slash Spark, that's
like basically accessing
your REPL Spark.
Or can you explain a
little bit that part?
In this case, you
notice that I invoked
the slash Spark Spark.
So what is actually
happening is in the
commands folder,
you'll see that
there's a folder called
Spark. And in the
command folder, there's
a document called
sparkmd. Orchestrator.
Yeah.
So I'm basically
invoking this file.
Nice. So 500
lines, modularity,
here's how it needs
to use my MCPs.
Here's how it needs to
invoke various things.
So it's simple, but
it's kind of a kickoff
point to how my
spark system needs to
work. so it's it it
know this is the most
important part and then
this works alongside
the clod.md file so the
clod.md file also kind
of knows how i like to
work it just augments
that a little bit
so originally when i
had the the uh the
early version of cloud
flow i basically stuffed
a giant clod.md file
and the problem with
that is it lost it
after you know several
runs it would sort of
lose context. By moving
all these into both
a combination of the
command structure. So
these commands are
slash commands and the
agents are the
invocation of the slash
commands. So you see that
there's corresponding
agents for each of
those Spark components.
There's an architecture,
pseudocode, refinement,
and specification.
So when I get to
the point of implementing
it, the two bounce
kind of back and forth
between each other.
So one invokes, the
other does the work,
the agents do the
work. And you guys can
customize these as you
want. You'll also notice
if you want to dig
deep into sort of the
way that I build
stuff, I've got a wiki.
The wiki also includes
lots of different
examples of how
I customize this.
So one of the most
important parts of
the customization
is an area that I've
got for my CloudMD
configurations.
So you'll see here I've
got different project
types, web dev,
mobile, API, AML, TDD.
Now, if you want
to, I don't have
Go, I should probably
add Go, but if
you want to go and
add some of these,
you can then invoke
these by going
to, let's say, the
JavaScript one.
This is the JavaScript
MD file that you can
just basically copy.
So you can go here.
I don't think
there's an easy
way to copy the
entire page, so
you probably have
to click edit.
And then you can
just copy and paste
this back into your
claw.md file. So
in this case, you
just go here and you
just blindly paste
it in here. And
then you're getting
sort of a JavaScript
orientated version
of the claw.md.
Or you can just
customize it, use it as a
guide as well for your
own customization.
Thanks.
So the other thing that
we're going to do is
I want to create a
front end and the like
it or not i still think
bolt and lovable and
a few others are still
better for front end
than you know we can
we can get decent front
ends out of claude but
to be honest i like
the more iterative
sort of visual parts of
lovable so and i haven't
tried lovable in a
few weeks and they tell
me there's a bunch of
new updates i'm most
curious what those
updates look like so
what i'm going to do is
i'm going to go to
claude and i'm going to
create and i'm going to
create a detailed lovable
specification that
i'm going to run
alongside the development
of this crazy backend.
I'm going to create
a detailed ViteJS
and for those who
don't know, Vite
is French for fast,
using ShadCN for
the UI and a dark
monotone style dashboard
for the following
specification.
that will be used to
guide the development
of the frontend
using the GoLang
API that line I'm
creating separately.
Now I'm going
to paste that.
Actually, I posted the
wrong thing. I
go back here.
I'm going to
grab this one.
And yeah, I
don't know about
you guys, but
GPT-5 *****.
I want to like it,
but it's garbage.
But anyway, so that's
why I'm using Claude.
It's just better at
this sort of thing at
this point. All right,
so I'm going to go
here. And in this case,
I'm going to let's
use opus and i'm going
to also just jump back
here for a moment i
think i have some specs
here so you see
it's using the the
implementation so i'm
going to actually grab the
api which is now
available so i'm oops i'm
can i yeah here we go
this is double i should
probably look at it
yeah let's grab that
pop that And then I
don't need everything.
I just need the bits
that are important.
That's the API,
crypto core modules.
Yeah, let's grab the
architecture too,
grab that.
And we'll pop that
in there as well.
Create a detail view.
Yep, looks good.
We're gonna go, we're
gonna start that.
All right, so
that's gonna
take a second
to do its thing.
And the Opus is
particularly good at, so
when you're using
thinking models, you
never use a thinking
model to implement,
but you always use
a thinking model to
create the specification
and the details
of the thing in which
you want to create.
You'll notice here
that I was using
the Opus 4 as well,
and I don't think
it's showing it for
some reason, but this
was actually based
on Opus 4, you know.
And, all right, so
that looks like it's
almost done. It's
following my nice phased
approach. It's using
the architecture,
and it's using my
Spark methodology.
Looks pretty good.
It's defined, it
understands my swarm
approach, so it should
invoke the Claude-flow
components. So I'm
creating the spec
specifically to use
Claude-flow to implement.
I'm explicit in that,
and it's important
because it'll work
better if it knows that
it can have multiple
agents and it can work
concurrently and all
that kind of stuff.
All right, so
let's take a look.
Let's take a
look at this one.
All right, it looks like
it's going pretty good.
this will take a minute
so what i'm going
to do with this
once this one's done
this will take a
minute or two to to i'm
going to then copy
and paste this into
lovable so you know
lovable is cool i
can connect my super
base if i want to you
know i i'm not going
to bother i don't
think i want a db
right now i actually
i want i just want
a generic ui which
lovable is particularly
good at creating.
So,
I can attach images
if I want to go
find an image. So,
let's go to Dribbble.
And I know the graphic
designers in the
room are going to,
like, hate me for
doing this. But it is
what it is. I'm going
to go to Dribbble
and I'm going to find
myself a design style
that I like, sci
-fi UI, that looks
like a good option,
and all right, so
we're going to go here,
now the best UIs
have the least amount
of image, like this
sort of thing is not
going to work well,
this probably would
work better, you know,
I want minimalist,
and I want cool,
i'm just looking yeah
there we go i want
this is looking for
aliens right it needs
to be crazy and futuristic
perfect you know
so this is a video
so what i'm going to
do is i'm going to
take a screenshot of it
yes i'm literally
copying someone's design
work but it is what
it is all right so
i'm going to go here
i'm going to grab that
pop that and i'm going
to go into lovable
It's not gonna
look exactly like
this, but it'll
inspire it, let's just
say. So I'm popping
that in there.
All right, and
I'm gonna go back
here to Claude,
see if it's done
yet, it's still
doing its thing.
So while that
goes, I'm gonna go
back here and see
how we are. It
looks like we might
be already done.
Yep, we're done.
Okay, now what I'm gonna
do is I'm gonna do Swarm
and Claude flow Swarm,
I'm redundant, you
don't necessarily have
to say concurrent all
the time or parallel,
but I know it'll work,
currently implement
the full at implementation
until complete
and no errors verify
all functionality
and no simulations
or mock in the final
final application
and
create a concurrent, I'm
going to say a concurrent
a
swarm
to
build the full
implementation, yeah something
like that right so
I've already done, I
should probably review
this to be honest
like if i it we don't
have a lot of time but
i'm just gonna i'm
vibing it so i'm not
overly concerned it
looks generally correct
the spec seems all
right it's using npx
it's it's getting the
go libraries that's
important i want it to
be in go the architecture
let's take a look at
that hey very quick
question man yeah um
how come you're using
the slash command
for called flow swarm
would it not just infer
what you want by the
rest of the command
you've written there?
No, I'm switching to
the cloud code swarm
command because it's
using the cloud code.
It's invoking
that particular
feature right here.
So I'm just using
that instead. Yeah,
so I just want to
make sure it knows
is that that's
what I want to do.
Okay, so it would
probably get there, I
guess, but you're just
being a little more
explicit by invoking the
actual slash command.
Yeah, actually it would
be in the commands,
it's using this one.
Yeah, okay.
So this is telling
it, this is
so it knows how
to run, right? So
now it's telling
it the agents,
it's telling it the
strategies, it's
giving it everything
that it needs to know.
So when I invoke
my swarms, I'm
generally using the
commands to do that.
And that's why I
do it that way.
Okay, so you
don't use the hive
mind for those
kinds of things?
I could.
In this case, I've
done a pretty good
job using the spark
specification.
So I'm a little more
explicit in what I want.
Now, the hive is cool
for like, I could,
this would be a great
use case for the hive.
So, you know, I could,
I might say, you
know, concurrently
implement the swarm.
Oops, why is it going
so slow? All right.
And now you'll
say a swarm,
let's say, hide mine.
See what that does.
Let's kick that off.
All right.
So now,
sometimes it's like
starting a boat motor.
You kind of have to
watch what it's gonna
do to invoke. So I'm
looking for it to
sort of invoke some
of the MCPs and swarm
components. So now you
see it's invoking the
swarm in it, which
is good. That defines
the hierarchical.
It's saying it's auto
-selected 10 agents,
which is actually smart
given the complexity
of the system. I never
told it how many
agents I want. The
drawback to 10 agents
though is blast through
your Claude Max account.
So anyone that's
got me booked later
this afternoon, we
might have to use your
Claude Max account.
But now, so the first
steps generally are
not going to be
done in a concurrent
fashion. So right now
it's going to make the
directories. It's
going to set up some
things. What we're
looking for after this
step is it to actually
go and then go from
this kind of task to
an agent structure.
So I'm going to keep
an eye on it for a
moment. If it doesn't,
I'm going to stop it
and tell it to invoke
the agent, but it
should work. But this
is something that you
want to keep an eye
on. So certain things
should be done
sequentially. Other things
concurrently creating
project structures
makes sense to create a
initial sort of structure
before concurrently
implementing it and
you'll notice here
that it says here um
it's doing the first
step then it's going
to implement the other
phases and we'll i
want these phases to
operate concurrently
so i'm just going to
keep an eye on when
it gets to phase one
So, it's installing Go.
There's also a
background feature that
was released last week
by the Cloud folks,
which is kind of
cool. I can show you
some of that in a
minute, too, which
allows you to sort
of invoke the agents
using the commands
that will allow you
to run it as background
processes. I could
have asked it to do
that as well, but
the agents should
work fine this way.
i notice you're
not using uh
github cli today
i guess that's
just for expediency
for the demo
yeah i i probably
would use it but in
this case i it slows
it down a little bit
so i was we don't
have a lot of time so
i figured we just
jump right in yeah
so one question is
like when we are doing
this is it possible
to ask the system
to visualize how the
agents are working
like what's this
building and can you ask
like as you build
creative visualizations
of how the different
agents are yes
interacting yes it totally
is so if you're you
know and i've and
i've got a i've got a
tool that i haven't
published publicly yet
that does that um and
this this is taking
a really long time by
the way um we're all
looking forward to
that visualizer mate
yeah well it's
it's in the uh
agentic swarm
branch so yeah
oh here we go i'm
too scared to use
your branches i'm
keen to use mine
uh no well you
we're all we're all
vibing our way through
whatever all right
so it looks like
it's created several
different uh
dashboard i'm not sure
why it's creating so
many i only wanted
one docket. It got
a little carried
away here. I'm going
to go to lovable.
And I'm going to say
fully implement
the following UI
and dash board
and board. And
I'm going to paste
that in here.
All right. Now, I
could have probably
saved as a document
or whatever. And it
looks like it It
includes the design.
It looks like it's got
various API components.
This is probably not
a bad starting point.
And I don't know why
this image didn't
work. Let's give
that one more try.
And we'll go, let's see.
Let's try it again.
I guess the uploads don't
work for lovable today.
Oh, it worked that
time. All right,
so I'm gonna start
this process.
So while I'm working
on the back end, I'm
now gonna get level
bolt to build me a funky
sci-fi front end that
I will then connect to
the back end later when
the back end works.
That hopefully looks
something like this.
All right, what's
going on here? It's
setting up, project,
so it's still, so
this is going through
the initial phase,
project setup,
oops.
So
it looks like
it's creating a
gitignore file,
it would appear.
Now if I wanted
to visualize
what's actually
happening here,
what I could do
is spawn another
instance and
have it sort of
explain where it
is in the process.
It's only doing
one task right now,
so it's in a sort
of sequential mode
while it's sort
of planned, so I'm
not overly concerned
about that.
looks like it's
trying to install Go.
It looks like it's
running in some errors.
Project setup agent.
I'm going to let
that continue.
I'm going to jump back.
This is a a fairly
complex project, again,
you don't want the
swarm to do everything
all at once until
it's ready to have
the appropriate architecture
to do everything
all at once. So what
this is essentially
doing is creating
the appropriate
structure for it to
follow, which looks like
it's creating in the
package folder. So
you can see here that
it's basically creating
the initial sort of
specification. So
the Spark specification
works really well
because it does a
pseudo-based outline
before it actually
fully implements
it. So what it
was doing right
now is doing that
pseudo outline.
So you can see
here, if I go here,
it looks like it's
actually doing quite a
bit more than the
pseudo, but it's creating
that. So now what I
could do hypothetically,
it looks like
I can go here
and I'm going to
let it continue
actually because I think
that's actually
doing a good job.
Basically, it's creating
the scaffolding.
So I'm gonna go back.
Lovable is decided
not to work.
Lovable's having
some problems here.
All right, I'm gonna
post this in here again.
Lovable, you're
failing me
on this. It just
did nothing.
All right,
let's try it again.
And you know what?
It makes me feel
better when Lovable
does nothing. I'm like,
oh, well, if a
company that's growing
as fast as they are
has problems and
i don't feel so bad
about my own stuff
all right the vibecast
anomaly detector
front end
all right so
you see here i
basically give
that so i'm going
to go here and
i'm going to
go and i'm going to add
this to the knowledge
base so i'm going
to pop that in here
and we go back
and see what else
we got here. Maybe
we can borrow
some other bits
and pieces.
Claude.
We'll go here.
I guess that's all one
document. No, it's just
content and
set up. I don't
know what the
difference is.
We're going to go back.
I'm going to add
that as well.
Oh, I think it's
the same document.
All right, don't
need that twice.
Save that.
All right, I'm going to
go to my project
settings.
I'm going to hide the
badge. Sorry, lovable.
And I'm going
to rename this.
Metasense?
It's not a bad name.
Anyone have any
better names for the
extraterrestrial AI system
that we're building?
I'm open to suggestions.
It's hard to
make an acronym.
Extrasense.
alien spy
I'm an alienator
alienator seems like
it's like a double
entendre I love
it alienator it is
I'm sure this video
will alienate some
people so there we
go alright so that's
doing that let's see
how this is doing
alright let's
let's create a dashboard
the first version of
lovable never quite
works right so we're
going to come back
to that let's see
what let's see how
this is doing all
right this is still
going you know what
i'm going to stop it
for a moment i'm going
to say spawn swarm
to continue
implementation currently
and normally i probably
wouldn't spawn the
swarm yet because it
probably would do the
swarm later but I want
it's doing sort of
a first minimal viable
take using the spark
specification which
is actually probably
the right way to do
it but I we don't have
a lot of time here
so I'm gonna and this
would probably likely
run for several hours
so I'm gonna try to
see if I can speed it
up a little bit we've
got it we've got a
general sort of structure
in place now so I'm
gonna see if I can
get the swarm to to go
ahead and do that we
see with the coder the
tester there's a there's
analyst now we're
going to orchestrate
a massive concurrent
implementation all
right i like the sounds
of that so this is
the task so the tasks
are the internal system
as a task orchestrator
this is what keeps
the agents on on
task right so you've got
a a core swarm a queen
if you will that sort
of understands what
the the overall
approach is and then you
have there is the
secondary implementers.
I'll use the task to
execute concurrent
implementations to
specialized agents.
Now, why isn't
it, it just
doesn't want to
run concurrently.
It's decided that
it wants to do a
single task again.
It really wants
to follow the Spark
specification.
Interesting.
Now, the reason that
is doing that is
because I specifically
told it to use Spark.
If I had originally
done a specification
that was less
rigid, it wouldn't
have disregarded
my instructions.
It wants to follow
the spec to a T, which
is exactly why I
designed Spark in the
first place. But it's
interesting that it
ignored me when I said
to not do that. Go
back here for a moment.
Nope, lovable.
All right, let's see
what this looks like.
Ooh, we're going to
need AI therapists,
right? So tell
me how that
makes you feel when
they ignore you.
Well, it makes me feel,
you know what? It's
actually following
my guidelines. The
Spark specification is
an explicit specification
that basically says
you have to follow
these rules and do
it exactly how it's
meant to be implemented,
right? So in some
ways, it's doing what
I wanted it to do.
All right, so let's
see analytics,
not page not found.
Okay, so this is
a really common
issue with lovable.
See, all the pages
don't exist. It kind of
created the initial
page, but to be honest,
I'm kind of digging
what it did. So, but
before I bother with the
other pages, I want to
always make sure that
I get the sort of core
design set up correctly.
So, update the UI
to use a responsive
mobile-friendly design
with uh animated uh
hamburger menu i don't
know and uh um sci-fi
sci-fi loading screen
for both desktop
and mobile.
All right. Once I've
got the sort of,
it's actually, you
know, it went dark
mode because I
told it to do dark
mode. And it actually
kind of sort of
looks sci-fi-ish.
It's not that bad.
All right. So, it's
going to do that.
Real-time monitor.
Still doing its thing.
So it's working on all
the different parts
and it's creating
the tests.
So it looks like
it's working
through this
phase right here.
Ruf, when you've
got a Swarm
up and running like this,
is it possible to go
and inject other Swarm
members? So let's
say you'd forgotten,
I don't know, you
wanted to do a security
review over the code
that was already
written. Could you
go in and insert
additional swarm members
to then kind of go
back and review what's
already been done?
Yeah, and this
is how you do it.
You can. So
I'm using DSP.
So now that's continuing.
You know,
add additional
swarm members to
implement phases
one through.
uh let's do let's
do a smaller group
since i would use
spaces one through five
currently collaborating
collaborating with
the other swarm
currently implementing
the architecture
something like that so
now i've got two now
i got two different
versions of cloud
this is going to burn
a significant amount
of clogged credits.
So now I'll spawn
additional swarm
agents, you know,
to handle phases
one through five
concurrently working
collaboration with
existing swarm.
Now I could, I could
do that for testing.
I could do that for
like, let's say just to
a Munchweep's question
about like, can I
create a dashboard,
create a dashboard. It
gives me a current
view of what the heck
it's doing, whatever.
I can do all that kind
of stuff. And so I
I'm, I'm spawning it.
And the benefit to the
way that I've created
the Claude-flow
system is you'll see
that the MCP provides
that sort of coordination
capability to inspect
what the other
agents are currently
working on, right? So,
that gives it the
coordination capability.
All right.
So,
I don't know.
This might be,
this is an
interesting issue.
Use the agents.
I'm not sure what's
going on there, this
seems to be an issue
with this particular
environment. Maybe
it's Spark. It
doesn't seem to want
to invoke the agents.
So I'm going to try to
manually invoke them,
anomaly detector.
It's interesting.
I'm going to have
to look into that.
Hopefully I didn't
break anything, but
I was doing order
work earlier and I
had no issue. It's
just this one seems
to be reluctant to
spawn the agents.
Let's jump back
here for a moment.
Question. Do you
often use agents to
interact with like
cloud resources?
Yeah, I do.
I use my MCPs for
that, like Postgres
or EC2 on AWS,
stuff like that.
I don't know why
it's not using the
it just doesn't
seem to want to I'm
invoking my agents
but the Claude itself
isn't using the
agents for some reason
it's weird sorry
when you say
you are invoking
the agents
where are you
interjecting because
it's running
anyways autonomously
yeah you can see you
can see that it's it's
running the agents or
spawning agents you
right here you can see
that the orchestrator
is is spawning you
can see here that that
it's doing it's creating
the task but now now
that what it's what
it's not doing is it's
not doing them
concurrently it seems to
just be stuck and this
maybe it's an update to
clod that happened
possibly but you can see
here that it's not
running you know with
the color coordination
it's it's it's writing
all these it's writing
them all sequentially
i had this issue
yesterday in the live
coding for the london
meetup so i specifically
asked it to follow
spark and tdd so it
ended up writing all
the test cases so it was
um so i wasn't getting
errors but it was
obviously visibly slower
than if i had just
asked it to go by the
normal cloud.md file?
This is what it should
look like, right?
And this is what I
was doing earlier. I
stopped it. But you can
see how I've got the
base templates. I got
coders and all that.
It's, for
whatever reason,
this particular
environment
doesn't seem to want
to invoke the agent.
So I'm going to try
to, I'm going to stop
this because I don't
want to conflict.
But I'm going to do
DSP. you know and i'm
gonna do i'm gonna
do a little debugging
just because it's
gonna drive me nuts
um so first thing
i'm gonna do is i'm
gonna check the agents
actually even there
so let's do agents no
agents found interesting
no agents found that
is interesting okay so
there's no agents
being found because
there's no agents all
right so let's go back
here and i'm gonna go
to one where i know it
works and I'm going
to go to DSP, and then
I'm going to do agents,
that didn't work.
Agents,
why is that
not wanted? I'm
having lots of
trouble today.
With the expanded
context window
came some other
features. here we go.
I can see all
my agents here.
That explains why the
agents aren't working.
I want to create
an agent, dot clod
agents, generate
with clod test,
dot clod agents.
It looks like
the same folder
structure.
Structure looks correct.
We should see a file here
in a moment
called agents.
Continue.
Oops.
Continue. We'll
use opus for this,
make it orange.
All right. No
agents found.
Interesting.
Okay. Perhaps trying
to re-init Claude-flow?
No, I just create an
agent using Cloud Code.
That,
try doing it without
the alias, typing
out the full Cloud
Code indication.
I think Anthropics
added a new line
of code. If Roof,
no agents for you.
Well, it looks,
this one works,
right?
So maybe it's related
to the online VS code.
I can view the
agent. I can see my,
oh, that's an
interesting theory.
New.
Okay.
good point good
point i never i i
don't generally use
the online version
but how would the
online i i like okay
it's odd but it's
a it's a thesis
all right so let's
uh connect to that
and see if that
resolves that issue
all right uh connect
to my code space
yeah it looks like
it's not detecting any
agents even the ones
i'm creating with clod
so let's start this
up let's take the
we'll see here
I did have one
thought Reuven
could it be the
new foreground and
background commands that
Blot has put in there
maybe they're running
in the background
and they're not being
detected anymore
and if you type in FG
foreground you might
see them I noticed
that the other day
no No, I don't, it's
just not, it's not
even finding the
ones that it created.
Like it created
these two, these two
testing ones and it's
not finding those.
I think it
might. This, this
happened to me the
other day, Roof.
I looked it up on
Reddit and other
people have
experienced it. I don't
think there's
like a solve right
now. It's, it's
some type of bug.
The, I was going to
just chime in and say,
the only thing I've
been able to do to get
around that is I have
a copy and paste prompt
when I'm in the hive
mind that specifically
spells out all of
Rude's worker types
and whenever I see the
MCPs or whatever not
batch executing the
agents I interrupt
Claude put that prompt
and it takes a bit but
it goes through all
the directories under
the Claude sub directory
and then the color
coordination agent
types begin from there.
So are you using VS Code
or using the web version?
VS Code.
I think the problem
might be the web
version. And to be
honest, I never used the
web version. I was
just lazy. I didn't
bother starting up
VS Code. But let's
see if we can, let's
rule that out first.
So I'm going to
create a new terminal.
And we're in which?
and just to just to
clarify i or i don't
ordinarily use slash
commands i'll be honest
i ***** the hive
mind spawn prompt and
either i'll iterate
within the cli itself
based on what it's
doing or i'll control c
out of it just to make
sure that if it just
is stubborn and won't
call the color the
correct worker types
because i've seen a
hallucinate worker type
several times and I've
had to inject that
prompt to get Claude
CLI to run back through
the directories and
find the appropriate
agent worker types.
Yes, it's not
finding any.
That is interesting.
Let's try it.
Let's see if it's
a version issue.
Claude version 80.
All right, let's go to
the one we know works.
72.
Interesting. Okay.
I don't upgrade as
frequently, apparently,
so let's downgrade. All
right, let's go here
to Rue, and I'm going
to ask it to, and
we're going to see if
that has any effect.
All right, down
grade Claude
code to version 1.072.
If that's the
case, let's see
if that solves
it. So I'm just
going to get
Roo to do that.
Do you find that
Roo has better
results than
using cursor?
I don't like Cursor,
to be honest.
Cursor is all over
the map. Sometimes it
works great, sometimes
it's just garbage.
And they're messing
around with it too much.
I like Klein or Cursor
for this sort of thing.
And in this
case, I'm using
Cloud Code within Rue.
It's free.
I think there's a
hack I saw somewhere
for Cursor using
it, but it generally
doesn't work
particularly well.
All right, so
I'm going to, now
I'm going to
downgrade cloud code.
A little bit of a tangent
here, guys. I know
it doesn't look like
it's a cloud flow
issue. It looks like
it's a cloud code issue.
But you're
learning how to
downgrade if that's
any consequence.
Yeah, no, and that's
great because for the
sake of clarity, i have
not tried that prompt
injection technique
whenever i pull up a
hive mind spawn i haven't
tried it since the
new clod i've only i've
only done it on the
1.0.7x or whatnot yeah
so so the london issue
you there manjwik was
talking about yesterday
is likely directly
related to clod clone
Yeah, because I
basically install
the latest
version as well.
Yeah, so the latest
version of
Enthropic, yeah.
Yeah, so you see, if
you want to install
older versions, this
is how you do it.
All right, so I'm
going to pop that
into the text
area for you guys.
All right, so now
I'm just going
to go here and I'm
going to Claude.
Oops, it's still
Claude, right?
oh it's doing the
version for me
perfect okay it
did exactly what i
wanted to do kind
of kill that all
right now i'm
gonna run dsp all
right
agents
oh why didn't that
work oh it did work
i just wasn't okay
that solves it that
that that is the
issue so perfect yeah
okay so all right
i don't know which
version broke it but
80 definitely doesn't
work with agents
currently so it's
a claude so now what
we're going to do
is we're going
to go back and
we're going to
go to claude list
Okay, and now
I'm going to say,
I guess I could
just do it
manually. I'll just
do it manually.
All right, I'm
going to go
and I'm going
to do clod 79.
And then I'm
going to figure
out which version
doesn't work.
All right, so then we're
going to do version 79.
Then we're
going to do DSP.
And then we're
going to do agents.
7.9 is broken.
70.
Yeah, it's 100% a bug.
It's a cloud code bug.
Or is it potentially
intentional as well?
No. Why would they break
their agent capability?
Because haven't
they introduced
their own agent
framework?
No, this is the cloud
code agent system.
I'm not using
Claude-flow. I'm
using cloud code.
I'm just trying to
figure out which
version broke it
78 doesn't work 77
oh i feel really and
keep my anthropics
like a multi
-billion dollar ai
company so if they
can't get their
together then i
feel better about me
and this is that that
that might be weird
but whatever all right
so let's try this
Hey, Ru,
I'm running 1.0.81,
so is it like possible
that it's in the
newer version also?
All right, so 77 works.
You say you're
running 81?
All right, let's
try 81. agents
okay 81 works they
fixed it okay so let's
sort you so note to
self use version 81
um all right so next
and by the way i i
installed this you guys
saw me install cloud
code earlier in you
know and it gave me
version 80. i didn't
know 81 was even a
thing i just just
installed it blindly now
spot the one that i
have currently on my
own so just on five
agents concurrently
so now what we're
looking to see is is
whether or not it
can we know we know
72 works so i was
using that earlier
and i showed you
guys that now i just
want to see i just
want to see five
agents spawn. I don't
care what they do.
All right.
Oh, no. Spawn.
Okay.
Let's see here.
uh chris do you mind
sharing that prompt as
a github gist might
be easier to copy it
into wherever we're all
using cloud code yeah
absolutely i can i
can uh it'll take some
time today i got a few
clients i've got to
get through but yeah
i'll upload this as a
gist for sure appreciate
it yep all right
yeah thank you thank
you we got a little
sidetracked here and some
debugging, but I just
want to confirm that
this will actually
‑‑ okay, why is it not
‑‑ it spawned ‑‑ no,
implement at ‑‑ what
did I call that again?
dox
I thought
doxing was plans
I gotta tell you
that this is actually
almost more valuable
to see you troubleshoot
than anything so
I don't want you
to feel like it's
like a ton of pressure
yeah this is amazing
now
it's not buying
plans because plans
apparently was added to
get ignore file which
means they can't
find it i'm just it's
struggling to start
any agents and like and
that's a it has no
problem using my commands
but the parts that
where claude needs
to actually do it to
do the work doesn't
seem to want to work
so what i'm trying
to do is force it to
to do something fun
you can do it
dude let's oh
my goodness it's it's
totally dumb today i
again i don't know
what these guys
have done but the latest
updates definitely
have uh made this
stuff not work
i guess i was running
an old version and
never i never occurred
to me to that i needed
to upgrade to the latest
uh claude code same
for me and it should
be if i if i think
it's right the after
the bash runs it will
call the agent worker
types after the bash
goes through the mcp
and you'll see the color
coordination or at
least in my version for
my use cases that's
what i've been saying
yeah it's it's
not doing anything
it's just saying
especially fun
no no you know
fully build the app
it's interesting there
we go that was painful
yeah and that's
exactly how like all my
hotminds spawns have
been at least on my
cloud flow version and
cloud cli version yeah
that that generally
it just works for me
until now which now
it doesn't um hmm i'm
gonna have to look
into why that is it
looks it looks like a
it looks like a clod
a cloud code related
a change that they did
in terms of how you
instantiate it but you
see now that you see
the color coordination
that's what it's
supposed to look like
these are now
operating concurrently
can we just unpack
what you did to
get that running
again you installed
the latest version
which is .81 and then
what did you do
to get it actually
I then basically
forced it
i i prompted it to
to to i can't scroll
because their ui
***** but yeah the uh
basically i i invoked
it manually basically
saying to just
build it and do it
right until it did it
man yeah let's what's
what's your what's
your deal man why
why aren't you working
and meanwhile i I
think this one here
is still operating.
No, I guess I
stopped it there.
No, it's still
doing something.
So basically try harder.
Yeah.
So this one is
currently stuck in
version 80, which
doesn't allow for
concurrency or
agents. that's why it
didn't work. Version
81 works but now
requires a little
more finesse to force
it to do whatever
it's going to do.
Let's jump back
to Lovable. What's
Lovable look like?
I got totally...
Oh, we got a
page coming soon.
What? That's silly.
All right.
Oh, it removed the pages.
I think everything's
dumb today
i wanted the
original actually
i'm just going
to go back here
store well this
is today's been a
case study in like
the um getting
it to do what
you want it to do
the the mobile ui and
yeah just wanted to
clarify so my
understanding and maybe
incorrectly so far has
been that we so agents
with the role the
goal and the tools
that we locate is
defined in cloud flow and
we are only invoking
cloud code to eggs
as an execution engine
behind the hood so
but what i heard you
say is that you are
in cloud code not
so you understand
originally that the
agents are are actually
configured and defined
through Claude-flow.
Yeah, so Claude-flow
acts as an
abstraction, it's
an orchestrator.
And basically
what I'm doing
or when it works anyway,
is having the
Cloud code system
or other coding
system, you could
probably use Rue
code and others,
basically orchestrate
through the Claude-flow
system, right? So
what I'm using,
what you're looking
at right now is
essentially the agent
system that is allowing
each of those agents
to run concurrently
to one another. And
now within each of
those agents, there's
a sort of subtask.
Those subtasks allow
for sub-coordination
between those agents
so they know what's
happening across
multiple agents at any
given point. So
it's a communication
channel, it's an
orchestration channel, and
the implementation
itself is cloud code.
but the agent system
is that part of
cloud flow the agent
system is is well
it's two parts see
there's an agent within
cloud flow but
i'm using i'm also
using the agent system
within cloud code
so but one's more
orchestrating but that's
what's spawning right
basically so you
would spawn or the
agents through cloud
code as the execution
engine but you would
be defining the role
the goal and the
tools that you
allocate the agents in
cloud flow that is
what's my understanding
yeah cloud flow
is an orchestrator
basically is the most
simple way to look at
it it it does nothing
more than orchestrate
and and do well
there's also a neuro
neural network
component that allows
for training but it
that all relates to
the orchestration
so it gets smarter
and more capable and
adaptive, but it's
not implementing
cloud code implements.
So if you think
of it, a kind
of a architect
editor model,
the cloud or
orchestrator
editor model, the
flow is the
orchestrator code
is the implementer,
the editor.
So if I were to just
rephrase my question,
so when we set
slash agents and we
saw all the agents,
like there were a
number of agents, those
agents are defined
within cloud flow
or they are well
they're both okay
okay yeah so they're
they're they're in
both all right now add
pages yeah are you are
you essentially saying
that um that the
cloud flow um defines
the agents that are
going to be used by cloud
code so that's why
it's defined in both
exactly so the cloud
code is dumb right it
doesn't do anything
other than what it's told
so a cloud code has
the ability to define a
command structure for
for the slashes that
are like secondary
prompts and then it has
agents that can act on
those prompts right do
this do that you know
access a certain you
know part you know
application in a certain
way and so and what
what uh the flow system
does is ties those three
things all together
gotcha he brings up a
good point rube and i
meant to actually
commented this on the
linkedin thinking it was
a live stream chat before
i could pull up zoom
um sometimes when i'm
used when i use the
hive mind spawn prompt
occasionally i've had
either better results
working inside the have
mine spawned prompt
in the cli itself and
other times i've had
better luck control seeing
out of that particular
query and steering
the next have mine
spawn towards the
swarm's memory and then
going at it again what
yes is the best approach
for that that you're
100 right and that's
because i didn't what
i didn't do and maybe
i should do is when you
when you go when you
go into the commands
folder here you see that
there's things like
memory and spark and
so on and and what what
i don't have in here
is explicit commands
for the hive mind which
i which i actually do
have in my dev environment
it's probably why
my dev environment
works as well as it does
but in my dev environment
i've actually got a
uh you know a swarm
i got stream chains
you know and other
components and so i
can invoke those more
effectively using that so
i probably so it's more
granular that way and
it kind of steers the
overall ai ship in a
more precise direction
is what i've taken
away yeah i i
have less stuff
in the sort of
uh invoked you
know in it version
in this and so the
the common issue i
run into is it works
for me it's because
it works for me
because I've hyper
-optimized this thing
for the development
of the tool. And
I probably need to
spend more time in
secondary environments,
like what we're
looking at here,
which is a standalone
environment. And
I ran into some
issues around the
invocation of the
agent itself. So I need
to go and I need
to fool around with
this environment, figure
out why it doesn't
invoke quite right,
which most likely
has to do with the
Claude MD file.
Now, I'm telling
it, the patterns,
always organize
files and, you know,
operate in parallel in
a single message, you
know, and this, but
then Claude code
changes their, their
approach and then my
stuff stops working
and I don't notice.
But this is what's
guiding it, at
least on the initial
starting point.
Would it be beneficial
to bake in some
type of pre-flight
check with Claude
Flow? so that you can
I do I do I do have
a I do have a pre
-check when you do the
init command that's
exactly what I'm
doing okay nice yeah
but it's it's I I'm
oh look I crashed
the entire instance
today I think that's
too real I I I'm I
did a little too
much but later you'll
get you'll You can
see how I can recover.
Actually, the other one's
actually running as well.
So let's go, oh,
not this one,
this one,
yeah.
This is still
running, I'm
gonna stop this
just to not,
all right, and I'm
gonna go back here.
Hopefully, I just had
too much going on.
I was running several
different swarms
all at once. But
what I'm going to
do here is I'm just
going to resume.
Now, because I was
running multiple swarms,
I probably can't use
my DSP-C. So what
I'm going to do is
I'm going to show you
how I'm going to do.
I'm going to do DSP.
So that was
my dangerously
skip commissions.
And then what
I'm going to do
is I'm going
to just resume.
All right.
And then I'm going
to choose coding,
troubleshoot,
implement features.
I think it's this one.
Zoom.
No, that's not the
right one either.
My code space
keeps crashing.
It doesn't let go.
spawn and spawn swarm
and complete the plans.
We'll
see what happens.
Now, the benefit to
these is even when
it breaks, it usually
has the ability
to kind of figure
out where and what it
needs to do to finish
itself off. Now
it's thinking it
needs to do 15 agents.
We'll see. well
there's like i guess
there's like 15 uh
so yeah okay nine
i'm just i'm just
curious on the on what
oh look okay now it's
working so i think i
think the issue the
predominant issue that
we were facing was a
uh the version issue
want to make fries in
the empire where's the
basket thing oh someone's
the big instapot
in the big drawer yeah
also uh save some for
us okay yeah i'm i'm
suddenly very hungry
you do like i
keep the basket
out i put the
fries in the basket
all right so we're
at the end of the
day and and i think
with that this it's
there's just as much an
art as it is a science
here right and and
some of this involves
you know me fooling
around with it and getting
it to do what i want
it to do it's not
set and forget like
especially for complicated
things like i'm trying
to create some kind
of alien you know
detection system which is
meant to be the most
complicated thing i
could possibly build
right so and what we saw
most of this time was
it working sequentially.
The reason it's not
done is rather than
having 15 agents all
working at once, we
literally had one agent
kind of going one by
one. Now, I probably
could have let this thing
run for several hours
and eventually it
probably would have
completed. Now, what I'm
doing is I'm running,
I think, 15 agents all
at once. I'm going to
let this finish and
I'll publish the final
alien detection system
later this afternoon
for you guys but yeah
it's i think there's
still a role for an
agentic engineer somewhere
someone has to be
involved you know we're
not dead yet it's not
you know so those that
those that think that
there's no room for
for developers or
engineers this is probably
proof that there's
still room for for people
like us to exist and
then you spent i spent
half the time here
just debugging the
**** thing so uh anyway
use use clod 81 for for
anyone that's uh you
know having trouble
apparently 80 ***** and
everything between 77
and 80 was doesn't work
thanks roof all right
um for anyone interested
in presenting whatever
you're building
uh we do our agentix
uh meetups uh ai
hackerspace uh fridays at
12 noon similar vibe but
you guys get to show
what you're building
If you're interested,
let me know. We
have a new board
committee member,
I think is the
right term. He's the
ex-chief counsel
for Google, who's
agreed to help us at
the Identix Foundation.
He will be joining
us tomorrow.
He led a lot of the
anti, I don't know what
you want to call it,
monopoly stuff for
Google. So he's been deep
inside the beast. He's
going to give us an
overview of his thinking
in the space. And he's
going to be creating
a agentics legal
committee for the agentics
foundation. His name's
Ken, Ken Carter.
So if you're
interested in legal
related elements
of agentics, join
tomorrow and you
can pick his brain.
He also, I think
he also worked at
cloudflare for a
while, was the chief
counsel. So he's
very experienced.
Perfect.
All right, guys.
Thanks again. I hope
this was helpful.
I always feel weird
when I don't get to
finish whenever I
started on these,
but it is what it is.
It will finish.
Until next time.
All right.
I got to jump, guys.
Send me a note or
join one of our
discords. Happy to
answer them there.
I got to jump in
the next call.
All right.