Vermont,
I
think? Yep. Good. Vermont. Good,
good to see
ya.
Good to see ya. Did you guys get the snow that we got here
in
Ontario? We did. And our local Killington Mountain is open as of
yesterday.
Oh, nice. I'll have to come visit you sometime.
I love skiing in
Vermont. Yeah, it's awesome.
Anytime, but
why don't I like him? Actually, I want to offer a way to do
a meetup or hackathon or something like that.
We have a, a 20 bedroom hotel here,
uh, right by Killington Ski Resort.
So it'd be a really fun thing for us all to get together.
So, you know, longer than I should, uh,
a meetup. We could do a little, little
overnight thing. And yeah, uh,
uh, extended getaway. All right. It's top of the hour,
so I'm going to, I'm going to jump. I'll get back to that in
one second, uh, Mark. Okay. So I'm just going to hit the record buttons.
All right, here we go. We're getting moving here.
Recording to the cloud. Okay,
top of the hour, and it's the 13th of November.
So, uh,
nothing lasts forever, and, uh, actually I'm not that going to the,
to the, and, anyway. Alright,
good, good, good to see you. Lots to cover this week.
You know, last week was kind of a wacky,
weird, and wonderful,
you know, sort of, episode. Examination of what we could do this
week is it hopefully is a little bit more practical.
I'm not going to I'm not going to dig into so many bugs.
Hopefully, maybe we'll, we'll build,
build some more interesting things. A few things I've been working on as well
is in the new update to my neuro trading.
And when I say new update, I mean a complete rewriting of the entire
platform from the ground up in rust and in.
MPX, and I think I'm going to open source the thing,
because why not? Why? I'm just going to make that available to everyone,
so I'll show you a little. Sneak peek of what I'm doing there and
how I'm going to go about open sourcing that maybe in the next week
or so when I when I do some more debugging and some other various
various other approaches and tools.
That I've been building on. But before I do,
let's see. Let's see what everyone's up to. I see Jed.
Hey Jed, how's it going? Any crazy?
I don't know about
crazy, but I've been experimenting with maybe a third,
third party, uh, web search. Providers,
so we've all heard of perplexity. We know that open AI and eutrophic have
their web search capabilities, but now there's this.
Company called Exxon, and it's interesting having my swarms
using Exxon alongside. Uh,
it's interesting. They want to explore from yet another perspective,
especially now that the likes of. Thanks.
Bye. Bye. They're starting to add barriers for agentic access.
Okay, this is especially problematic
for documentation.
And that's exa.ai, is that X-A-I,
or X-A,
Okay.
So, uhm, yeah, it's worth, worth taking a look at,
for sure. Uh, what, what else we got going on here?
I, I just, let's see, uh, I see Nick.
Nick, uh, you, he's, I, I, I think you've gotten over the,
the loss of your, your Blue Jays.
Good to see you on, on Tuesday at the Toronto meetup.
That, that was fun. What, what have you been creating here?
Yeah, that, that was a good time. I'm,
uh, just, just following the rabbit hole.
I started with this rewrite of a popular,
uhm, program. that helps you find leaked keys in your project,
and I converted it to Rust. So,
it's, like, way faster and stuff like that. And then, and then,
really, Reuven's, like, okay, now what you should do is build something that's related
to that. Or, you know, what's, what's next?
And then, I started to understand better,
like, about building in stacks, you know.
So, I just go into, like, ChachiBT, I'm building something,
I'm like, what's related to that? What's the next thing?
And I'm just, like, following that rabbit hole, and it brought me to some
sort of LLM DevOps, and,
you know, I'm building all these footings. So,
yeah, it's been pretty cool, you know, getting some downloads on NPM and
crates, and, you know, it's, it's pretty sweet.
Yeah. So that's, that's what I'm
doing. Nice. Yeah. The, uh,
there's, there's this bump you get when you first post a crate or an
MPM or MPX where you get a bunch of downloads because I think it
lists it on the recent downloads section.
Um, and of their website. Um, earlier this week,
I did my, uh, what I call it, the agentic jiu jitsu,
which is a sort of, reimagination of
the version control system, which I'll show you guys here in a few minutes
as well. And that ended up doing,
uh, I think, 11 or 12 hundred downloads in the first day almost entirely
because of the MPM sort of discovery tool.
So, the, the trick is to see if you can do and keep that
momentum going, right?
Yeah, most of mine are dipping pretty hard after the first week.
I was, I was pretty hyped and then, you know,
a little late. Less, a little less excitement in the following week.
I actually took that specification that you showed me,
remember? And I, uh, the,
um, the, uh,
lang chain RS, uh,
uh, specification, and I did my best.
I did my best Reuben, you know, to, to,
uh, to build it and I used the,
uh, clod web for that one and I,
I did put the E2B,
I did put the E2B, and. You know,
a clod key and I think one other something.
Oh, open router, cause there's like a routing component to that.
Uhm, so I, I did also put my open router key.
It's not, it's not done, but, you know,
I, I, it builds. What,
what it built and then I, you know, it was a few things that
it said it wasn't, hadn't completed. I turned on before I went to bed.
I haven't actually looked at it yet. But, uhm.
Yeah. That was the, that was the laying
graph, uh, for. Yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah. For those who are interested,
I, I'm po- you I'm hosting my PRDs on my JIST,
and there's a bunch of interesting ones, uhm,
but the one in particular is- You
just
close. We'll
see. So, uh,
oops, did I share my wrong screen? It's hard to
tell sometimes. Oh, we lost audio for, like,
just about 20
seconds. Oh, you did. Oh,
oh.
I'm back. Um, yeah. I was just sharing the,
uh, the lane graph,
uh, eh. Uh, PRD here, if you guys are interested on just,
um, you can see sort of how I go about building this stuff.
And basically, I think when Nick was saying- Thanks. This is just kind of
blindly took this. And that's all you need to do.
You copy this URL, and you go into cloud code,
and you basic so, and then you say, imp- We're going to go to
implement. And this is something I did was doing with Martin the other day.
So Martin asked me in regards to like how can you build you
know, the robotic system. So, and then this was like before we were doing
a meet up in Toronto. So basically we.
We created this, uh, Ross three,
which is a robotic operating system three ground,
you know, rewrite for the next 20 years. So a lot of times.
When I do these things, I'm like, what does it look like in 20
years from now? And, and this actually ran for,
Uh, quite a while, uh,
in terms of the deep research. So,
let me just show you that quick, which was interesting.
So, here, here it is. Ross, too.
So, this is it. Give me a complete specification using Spark,
which is my, uh, spec- application. And what's cool now is,
uh, blood actually knows about my spec.
It actually, it doesn't tell me it's a Sun Microsystem- Uh,
chip anymore, which is cool. And robotic operating system.
But here's the important part here. You'll,
you'll notice when I go to it, it says, ask me. It's it.
A bunch of questions. Now I said I want to,
I, I want SDK and I want a Ross 3 that would exist
20 years from now. That 20 years from now actually seems to make a,
a big difference in terms of when you're,
uh, building this stuff. It, it, it,
it literally creates. It creates the future. And then you'll,
what's interesting here, that this one ran for 58 minutes,
but some of these run for like two hours.
And at the end of it, it. Gave me this is really,
so I can look at, I can see two things. So here's all the
research it did. And I can see here all the things that looked up
and all the sources. So this is the. Grounding 574
and then what what I did and is,
I ended up with this, but what I like about. I hope this is,
I can easily copy it, right? So I can copy the,
the markup, and so I can copy his markdown,
which, uhh, par- Here. I really chat,
GPT used to do, but got rid of, for some reason.
And then I popped it in here. Now I could probably just publish it
and do it the same way, but I- more people follow me on- on
g- on GitHub, so I- I have a better following there,
so that's how I post it there. But you see it's- does- it's- it's
like hundreds of pages. They do. Long. And then what- once I did that,
I just said basically fully implement. And we can see I did this about
a day ago, and it did a- We'll see you in the next thing,
blah, blah, blah. I'm gonna go the end,
and it built the whole thing. Now, I haven't had a chance to verify,
and to be honest, when Martin told me that it might be you- I
used to create an army of evil robots.
It kind of gave me some cold feet. So,
uh, I, uh,
I built it- and I'm probably going to publish it.
All I need to do is click this create PR button. And that'll- that'll
create the PR on my vibecast.
But for those who are interested in this before I actually go ahead and
do that, I-I create a lot of my experience on the Vibecast,
uhh,
GitHub.
You can- You can go to my- or what's going on here.
It seems to have been locked up for some reason.
Oh, there we go. So we- Did we go to the branches?
I'm not sure why it's- what's going on here.
Am I- am I still coming to come through, okay? Brand new computer.
Period. I think- think the thing would work
okay.
All right. Come back to
life.
Yeah, we just have, uh, a hot mic.
Joe Stills, Mike. like. Oh, right,
right, right, right. Lemme fix that.
What I'm gonna do quick and, uh, just unmute yourself,
guys, when I do this, I'm just gonna- unmute all, and then you can
just unmute yourself if you want to talk to me.
Yeah, this Zoom, for whatever reason, doesn't automatically mute.
I-I'm when I originally- I'm usually crying. I hated it like months and months
ago. I didn't turn that button on, I guess.
Alright, this came back to like 22 branches.
So now what we gotta look at here is which branch. And it. This
is, this is the cloud implementation.
I don't even, I can't see it all. Let's see what that says.
It's got this funny name. So we're gonna go back.
Back here. And we'll find that.
Okay, here it is. So if there anyone that's interested in trying it here,
I'm gonna pop this in the chat.
and you can give that a spin.
You still have 972 credits.
It's,
Yes, seriously. I built,
I'm built in the crate. I don't think this works.
It hasn't moved in several days. And it was 976.
It was credits, like, 3 days ago when I was given the presentation at
the Toronto meetup. I think it's broke.
It definitely doesn't seem to have any- real bearing.
Like, I'm building all kinds of stuff with it every day.
Mine's at 972 as well.
So I don't know if- That's a magic number or
what.
I think they're probably just letting you run, uh,
since you're doing all their dev work for them there, if- Perfect.
Apparently, apparently. Uhm,
oh, but before we jump- into the vivecast,
though, I wan to come back to Mark Allen,
our-our friend in Vermont for a moment.
Mark has-has just offered- to do a-a-gentic weekend
retreat at his hotel. Mark,
you-you still there? Okay. I might-uh,
I might have
lost him. I'm muted, Mark.
Oh, I'm fine.
I got remuted. Here
we are. . . .
Oh, yeah, yeah. So let me, uh, let me share.
So we are in Killington, Vermont.
Uh, so it's, it's,
uh, easy to- Next. Test from New York,
from Boston, uh, from Toronto.
And so I think it's just picking a date that works for folks and,
you know, we could come out here. I think we got a,
uh, a 20 bedroom place. We got a big working space.
So we could do a hackathon slash.
Hiking slash snowshoeing, hiking,
whatever, uh, depending upon the weather conditions.
Uh, but it's a, it's a beautiful little slice of.
The heaven that would, uh, I'd love to,
to host, uh, some kind of,
of meet up here.
Yeah, well, I love. Skiing,
I, I, I attempted to learn how to snowboard,
but realized I was too old to learn new things and went back to
skiing. But, uh, yeah,
it's. It's, there's some nice hills there too, right?
No, mountains. I'm from Ontario.
There's no mountains here.
Yeah, this is all over here. Can I? I jump in real quick.
Mark, I was just at Killington.
Just at Killington. I, I keynoteed at Vermont Fest.
Uh, so I was there just three days ago.
Uh, and I talked about agentics with superintendents and teachers and all of that.
So sorry, I just wanted to jump in there and say
that,
that was
amazing. Yeah, I was just there three days ago.
Yeah.
And, and hi, this is Stu,
first time meeting most of you, but I've actually been up at Mark's place.
And spent the weekend coding with him.
And it is sensational there. You should definitely find a way to get there
if you can.
So the mountains open. And so I think if people want to try to
do something, uh, you know,
maybe even this month or early next month.
You know, we probably need, like, maybe a month out for a lot of
people to travel. But, uh, you know,
let me propose some, some dates. Uhh, uhh, that I'll look at our calendar
and, and, you know, let's make it happen. The question is,
do we do it, try to do it over a weekend? Do we try
to do it during the weekday? What, what works best?
I don't know about you guys but my schedule is like ridiculous
so if, for me, it would have to be over a weekend but I
know my, my, my kids would love to go and ski in a new,
on a new hill somewhere so they would,
they would, well, they, they all snow. I did convince my daughter to ski
though, so I'm not alone on the hill.
They, they all ditch me on, on their snowboards,
but, uh, I, I still have. I have some, uh,
accompaniment with, with her for now anyway.
Okay. Let's, let's do it.
Let's
on, let's do it on a weekend. So, um,
I, I will get. Let's get back with, uh, some proposed dates.
I'm going to talk to my wife about it, figure out when we can
do it, and, uh, let's make it happen.
Yeah. There's also been some. discussion next year in regards to a broader
global meetup. And, uh, in,
in Toronto. Well, I'm proposing somewhere in Ontario.
Thank you. Because I'm lazy, mostly. Um,
but the, and, and, uh, potentially,
I was thinking maybe we could do something similar, like,
find ourselves. Some kind of, like,
uh, resort in the middle of the,
uh, sort of lake, lake area of Ontario,
where we can chill. Thank you. So on a, on a,
on a nice dock with our laptops and build stuff,
I don't know. Something like that. There's,
there's a lot of interest in, in that. And. And, uh,
you know, it's probably a little more accessible for,
for some of the Georgian Bay area is gorgeous.
Yeah. Yeah, for sure. Exactly. Georgia.
That would be the, that's the area. Sometimes referred to as Muskoka.
Yeah. So that'd be cool. That'd be fun. Uh,
and actually. action. . . Actually, speaking of, we got Rob on Rob Ranson.
You live in that area. Don't, don't, don't you, Rob?
I think. Oh. Oh. Hey.
Uh, you see there? I think he's there. Anyway,
I put him on the spot.
Alright.
Alright. So, uh, one last. Looks
like he tried it off. more. But we're not hearing.
Yep. It's, I'm, I'm, I'm,
I'm, I'm improvising here. What can I say? Uh. Bye.
Actually, side note, you, you guys will see my,
my, my dad on this, on this today and I just wanna give it
a, a little story because when I was like. Around 10 years old,
my, uh, my dad hosted a local community television talk show
called Round Town with Malcolm. I'll come. And I was the gaffer.
I think they called it the guy that went around and, and bundled up
all the chords and learned how to do the sound.
now. on mixing and was like Johnny on the spot for whatever problems they,
they had. So anyway, 30 years later,
here I am in this. This is my community access channel,
uh, get, get together.
So anyway, a long, a long history.
history. of, uh, of nerdy activities.
Um, I, I come by it naturally.
So, so thanks for tuning in, dad. Alright.
Um. That, let's, let's get into some of the stuff I'm building.
And again, if you guys have any questions or whatever,
I'm gonna, I'm vibing it. I'm showing what I'm doing.
We're kind of. I'm kind of ad, ad,
ad, and it all replaced. Yep. Thumbs up,
Dad. Alright, so, uh, here,
here we go. I'm gonna share my screen and, uh.
you know, we'll take it away. Lots to show this week,
actually. Alright, so I'm gonna start with,
uh, I'm gonna get back here to,
clog code. So, clog code something is,
is my, well, it's free, so I've been a little bit obsessed with it,
and this is actually, this is the example. I was showing you briefly earlier,
in regards to what Martin and I were sort of discussing.
And this is essentially, I took a project.
Right, so I took the project that exists originally as,
I apparently wanted a more popular,
uh, robotic platform. I'm not going to for a second.
I think it's essentially, actually, I'm not even sure what it's originally built in.
I probably should have. You took a closer look at that,
but the robotics. Thanks for and I'll video. Uh,
system 2, let's go to the github and see what,
what I converted. I, I, that's blind cut,
you know, blindly sort of, uhh, rea- writing the system.
So, where's the repose?
Let's see what the most popular is, uhh,
robotic 2. Uhh,
there's- A
lot. Quick question, move on.
Sure.
Around research. Uh, how do you know when you- the output that you get
back is- comprehensive enough or you need the prompt?
Are you taking what you get and trusting?
Are you-
I no, I certainly don't trust it.
Uhm,
I haven't gotten to the point of actually doing verification.
Perfect key. Umm, but I set,
I, when I'm, when I'm really curious right now is what it's built in,
uh, originally built in because I, to be honest this,
this was about. Viving as you get, I didn't even really pay much,
much attention to, uh. You what it was built in.
I think it's Python. I would guess it's Python.
Hey, Martin, what, what is, yeah, what is this originally built in Python?
Looks like, Python. See. I
think it's It's like, mishmash, actually. Like,
he's been around a long time. And that's one of the reasons why I
said, you know, it would be a good target. Umm.
But with that, also maybe some requirements.
Perhaps, um, different,
you know, it doesn't, it's not sp- So it will be written in the
same thing. Maybe it needs to interface with various languages.
Uhm, I, I don't have the details on those answers.
So I think, you know, unless we actually put a
P.R.D. in front of the expert, we don't know whether it's way off.
So
I think
bringing physical AI and vision language action models into this space would
be awesome. There. I've used Ross quite a bit in my robotics.
For Ross to is the latest,
really. And, um.
Yeah, they're getting
trouble. They're definitely not. Not
integrated. upgraded. With AI yet.
Yeah, so calling it Ross three is probably not where I'm going to go
with it. Cause I don't piss. Like we, I learned my experience from doing.
Drupal.js last year where the entire Drupal community thought it was the worst thing
that ever happened. Which, I don't know why they got so upset about that.
But anyway, less. So,
I'll give it a different name here before if I decide to publish it.
But basically, what this, what this does is.
Is essentially, I took all my various components that I've built
over the last, uh, couple of months. And I've essentially applied.
So, again, to get an idea of what exactly it's doing,
we've got to look at the PRD. Now,
unfortunately, the PRD is- is is quite in depth,
right? So, this is a comprehensive or technical specification,
defines Ross 3, a complete roundup, rewrite of- Right.
Now, one of the big changes that
I've- been doing over literally the last couple weeks is
the idea of the NAPI-RS.
And what that allows me to do- uuuh, is essentially compile rust
components on the installation of an MPM.
MPM or MPX. Okay. So,
traditionally what you'd do when you take these systems is you'd have to do,
uh, a wasm, which doesn't have direct access to,
the file system and has limited access to networking and other things,
which is great for, like, algorithmic components,
so if I want to do something complicated, that is beyond the capabilities of
TypeScript, I compile it as a wasm.
What, where it falls down, is it doesn't allow me to- I there directly
interact with the CPU, and GPU,
and other, sort of, hardware-enabled environments.
So, knowing this, I knew that I needed to compile it as it in
a way that will allow me to, to get all the benefits of my
AI systems that I've built in both Wasm and now in the MP8.
You know, an, an API structure and then rebuild it within this Ross 2
technical architecture. So what I,
and then what I want to do is say, well, I've got all these
different libraries that are available in terms of,
uh, learning. So for example,
a, agent, uuuh, The agent DB,
which is my, my vector, my vector system,
which allows the system to learn. I've got my agent booster,
which. It provides a speed up for, for transformations of code.
And I've got multi routing and so all in my quick system.
So all these, I've got all these. Various libraries and tools that are hyper
optimized for, you know,
essentially a multi part robotic system.
them. 7 So when you think about robotics,
there's a tendency to make a robotic system.
Again, I love the term monolithic, but monolithic.
You've got all these parts you've got,
you know, the arms, the legs,
the vision, the accelerators,
the, you know. with it. And, and the various parts. So rather than saying,
I'm going to create one central command and control unit,
what I want to do is say each of the- Different parts of the
robotic entity have the ability to interact with separate threads or agents
that are capable of, uuh, uuh,
hm. And really quickly communicating with each other,
right? So you've got, again, a swam,
if you will, of different parts of a robot.
Bye that do different parts that are hyper-targeted on those robotic components.
Now you'll see here that says the zero RTT connections.
What this is. Zero RTT connection does,
is allows for zero latency between the request and the agent.
Now, a lot of the traditional systems that you'll see,
including the Ross 2 system, basically use.
Use traditional HTTP sort of transactional components,
which requires a 300, roughly around a 300 millisecond delay.
late. between the request and the action.
Now, for certain things, that's fine. But for other things,
you know, when you're trying to be as capable as.
As a human, 300 milliseconds is about 100 to 150 milliseconds
slower than a human can react.
So the. the best. That's baseball player is capable of reacting within something like
50 to 100 milliseconds to a pitch.
And then the reason why a. . . A champion home run hitter can
hit a home run is the fact that they can perceive that information more
quickly than me. Some. When throws a 90 mile per hour fastball at me,
it's just going to be blasted by me. I'm like, what's happening right now?
A professional is going to be. Is capable of sort of slowing down
time and understanding that I can, I can sort of preemptively see where that
ball is going to be and. . Hit it. That means that I'm able
to perceive in less than essentially 100 milliseconds and be able to hit in
that right spot. So conceptually,
what, what these types of platforms are doing are trying to mimic the speed
and efficiency that you get in a human sub.
200 sub 100 milliseconds as part of the overall flow of information
between all the parts. So the part that decides I'm gonna hit the,
this ball and then swings that entire process between where
and how, what and doing needs to be faster.
master Or at least as fast as a human.
That's what these, that's what this system is essentially attending to do.
So when you see things like Agent D. . b,
this takes it a step further. The Agent,
so you can see here, this is basically measuring the speed in which the
computational overhead. Versus intelligence,
um, basically, uh,
allows you to perceive and, I call it bullet time frequently,
but basically. Slow down time to be able to make the decision quickly and
effectively. And that's why it's so important for these,
uh, robotic systems. Secondly,
the, the, one of the things you see in a lot of these robots,
the, uh, the humanoid robot you see from like,
uhh, like Tesla and others, is they're still heavily dependent on essentially remote
sort of embodiment. So often, there's actually a person It's controlling it somewhere else.
It's kind of like, fireflies in their pizza post the other day.
And the or, or they have GPU.
Now, the problem with the GPU approach is GPUs run hot.
They use tons of electric.
electric electricity. So a battery doesn't last that long and essentially
they're slow. Like, they're trying to compute everything.
thing. All at once to determine what the optimal solution is to whatever in
which it's doing at any given point. None of that works particularly well for
a robotic. I couldn't believe it. Now,
in my scenario, I'm using something called on X.
On X allows you to embed these,
the, the, the neural. family. I think you for things like language and vision
and other components directly in the model using,
again, that WASM that I was talking about earlier. It's lighter,
more optimized, uses a lot less computational resources.
And ultimately, when I say, uses a lot of- .
Less computational resources, it uses a lot less energy.
So, that's what this thing's trying to do.
Now, I've added
the
idea. I have an MCP protocol because I want to use things like my
agentic flow and other MCP-enabled systems to more efficiently in
a- interact with these- the- the components of the robotic environment.
So all this stuff's happening within this,
right? So this is the- this is the- general spec,
next generation features. This is saying, what- based on all the things I just
told you, what does the next 20 years look like?
So what does a robot in 2045 look like versus what
does a robot in 2025 look like? So it, it, it, uhh, hmmm, came
up with, and some of the stuff that came up with is actually pretty
cool. So it came up with this idea of vision language action model.
So you see 200. Hurts, the hurts represent speed,
sort of the timing. Gemini robotics,
and, you know, again, a lot of the stuff is- But,
is- is based on control frequency.
So, back to the- the sort of idea of speed and time,
and the- and the time it takes you to think. Thank you.
And the- versus the time it takes you to do,
it's actually taking all those things into consideration.
Then it's looking at the energy There's the effect. The efficiency,
the 140 times less energy than the DNNs.
What's cool about this, this stuff?
Back. To the original, the,
sort of the original PRD.
When I requested this thing, I said none of those things.
I. Bye. I basically said, at the beginning, give me a complete specification using
Spark. But what's interesting is a combination that clos- What
seems to be getting to know me, like the memory or whatever it is,
it knows this stuff that I'm telling you.
Cause I have a tendency to have conversations with- ehm,
expressing exactly what I just said.
So it sort of inherently knows this stuff and I gave it my various-
my various projects like Agenic Flow, Agent DB,
and other things. So it sort of defines that as part of it.
So when I said, you know, uuuh, this, tell me what the future looks
like using my own tools. It kind of just magically knew that that's kind
of what I was thinking without me even artic- speculating those thoughts.
Alright, so then I have that popped in here,
let this- this ran for- I think I started- Bye bye.
Before the meetup at 6.30 on Tuesday,
and it literally ran until I was on the train back home around 11
o'clock at night. So it- It ran for close to four hours.
Nonstop doing all this stuff, testing.
You know, so now, I'm- I'm,
You know, say something like, guy thinks this is BS.
Uh,
this is- This is a elaborate,
elaborate, uh, simulation.
Let's- convince, uhh,
him that it's real.
Haha, something like that. Alright. All right. I'm going to fix my spelling.
Eh, the, the, it's real.
Uh,
it's real. Great. Great. A detailed
benchmark, benchmark,
and optimization. Um. Um,
ehm, to prove this isn't total,
total BS. Yes. I don't know.
Something like that. Let's, let's go with that. Alright.
That's, that's it. That's all I'm doing, right?
And, and this is going to run for a while. So I'm, I will.
It's come back to this in, in a, in a few minutes and see
what, what it comes up with. Alright.
And the next thing I was working on here,
some of you might know what to do. I I've got an MPM library
called Ruby, which is what leads to call me when I was ten years
old. But, so I said review,
and. Yeah, it's Ruby. So this is a library that I've been working on,
and it's, you can see here that I've chose a particular,
uh, repo, which is my, my. So repo I use for managing my Rube.io
website. So I've combined the MPX for Ruby into the,
uh, when you go to, like, the. Rube.io site that basically they use the
same repo and you'll see it here, right? All right. So,
this, this site is both a website and an MPa,
an MCP server. So,
it's- easy to combine the two. But anyway,
uhh, so then I went here doing the review.
It's looking at all the various parts. It's doing its thing.
It's giving me a report. Here's the report.
Now, what I really want to do here is I want to make my-my-my-my-my-my-my-my-my-my-my
rugby- uhh, MCP and M-and CLI into a-basically
a place where I could list all my various,
uh, um. M-P-M experiments. So what,
cause everyone's always like, what have you built recently?
How do I find out what you built? So I kinda want the crate
I kind of, uhh, uh. where you could just go and download my,
m-my whatever. Right? So if you go, if you go to,
like, m-p-m-p-m-p-m-j-s. uhm,
Yes. And let's see, look here if I can find where I'm at.
We go here. here. Like, I basically just want to show,
I've got 40 packages now, which is lots and lots and lots of stuff.
I just wanted to wait for you to be able to grab and, and
explore. Or, and find all the stuff I build quickly and easily.
It's basically what I was thinking there. So it went and built that.
So. So all the, you'll see here that basically,
you know, it will scroll up to where, where I can find where it
did it. I gave it a, you know.
I'm to test and ensure all the MPS work.
Let's go even further up here.
Uh, where is it? it. Uhh,
I gotta find it. You can see it does a lot here.
Here it is. This is what I asked it.
Can I update my MPX Ruby to enable- my users to easily list,
search, and install my various MPM libraries and MCP services.
And yeah, it went- Letting go. Tilt it. Built the whole thing.
I haven't published it yet, so before you go and say it doesn't- doesn't
work. I haven't- I'm- I'm gonna- I'm- I have to review this stuff.
There's not enough time in the day to- review it, but this is the
sort of stuff you can do. It's- it's- it's pretty cool.
Umm, yeah, lots and lots- of- of,
uh, opportunities here to use this system.
You can see I'm- I'm creating different, uh,
you know, different ideas, different components.
and You know, here's- let's go take a look back here at the robotic
system. So now it's this convincing guy that this isn't being- s.
It might still be s. Just throwing it out there.
You never know. But if I convince guy,
I'm one step- Yep. Closer. Uhm,
so yeah, you can see it so you can all, you can see this.
So one of the things I want to show you also.
Is how to quickly use some of my tools within,
you know, in this environment. So in this case,
a couple things to note. Okay. You've got environmental variables.
These are particularly important. And by, I'm not going to show you these because
I, you know, I don't want to go change all my environmental variables because
I, Accidentally leak them, but I'm going to show you default because there's no
variables other than what you need to set up in the in the default
environment. This is a really important part.
You see this network access. By default,
it's set to trusted. Trusted means that you can only download from package that.
Go ahead. That, uh, clawed has verified to be accessible.
Now, that means it doesn't really have access to the internet.
So everyone, the first.
The reason it doesn't work is you didn't choose full. Choose full.
Well, I'm going Well, what's the right. Make sure you choose full.
Next thing you want to do is, you know, set your API keys.
Now, if you're using my agentic flow system,
you, you. You can use open router. So you're going to do something like
open router underscore API underscore key equals whatever.
And then. And you, if you want to use like some of my advanced
browning capabilities, you're probably going to use the Gemini Gemini API.
And you might use per,
you know, the perplex, perplex city API.
I p.i. underscore key.
Remember, you need it, you need to do that. Also note,
this is a quirk of their system. Anything that involves.
A comment, like, you know,
doesn't work. You'll see invalid format. So you get to strip out all these
lines. Like. like this. Like any comments that you might have in your ENV.
I don't know why they, why they do that. It's a little bit of
knowing, to be honest. But get rid of those. And that.
And that's how you do it. So once, once you've got that in place,
just take a screenshot of that if you want. Make sure,
full. And be alright.
Then once you have that, then you can go and I did this on
a demo this morning. You know, install the cloth.
So, MPX Alpha and the MPX Agentic DB,
research swarm, and find some new novel discovery in the medical field.
Literally, I did that an hour ago on,
uh, on one of my coaching calls. So,
let's see what, what came up here. So, we can see here that it
installed. It installed the version.
It returned with three, four. I'm actually pushing an update to three,
five. Maybe I'll do it right now. Actually,
that fixes a minor error in windows,
uh, that was causing a conflict.
But anyway, three, five's coming. I hope this happened to you.
Uh, here's the goal is the research swarm component that tells you how to
do the research swarm. Here, it's setting up the,
the. It's equal light database. It's doing the various,
uh, swarm research. Now,
now it's spawning seven specialized agents and.
Utilizing medical breakthroughs, let me continue monitoring the progress.
Excellent six agents have completed their research.
Alright, do blah, blah, blah, blah.
Here's what we've got. Alright, so it cr- Now here's a drawback of the
system I don't like. It- I'm going back. It has a really weird way
of dis- it- it displays the research summaries as a kind of GitHub,
uh, commit. it. But anyway,
you- if you want, you can copy the- like,
the quickest and easy way to see this if you don't want to open
up GitHub is grab this, go back.
Back to here,
and then we're gonna go- I'm back to this for a sec and then
we're- like, you could open up and get- you could open up and get
up as well, by the way, I'm just enjoying an alternative way to do
it umm- we're gonna go here and then we're gonna call it med.md
and I'll say uhh. You have various medical
discoveries. Alright. All right.
Good enough. I'm going to create that publicly so you guys can see it.
And let's see what we, let's see what it came up. I haven't looked
at this yet. So, It's basically,
it's spawned seven agents and keep in mind it's using,
it's actually not using, clod flow specifically for the agents.
It's, It's actually using my agentic flow system to do the agents on
E2B instances. But the benefit to that is I can spawn thousands of dollars.
And it's potentially millions of them, I guess.
True. Um, they
work
concurrently. Yeah, the question?
Just,
uh, quick part would be probably- ehm,
useful if you- when you- when you create a GIS,
right? To also capture the prompt that you use.
Like the- Thank
you. That would like- then, this- this goes back to like the discussion we
were having before. Like, how did you get from
this point to this really great resource like?
So, that- I think those of
us
that are learning journey. Sure.
Alright. Thank you.
We should be just capturing- I
mean, the stream- the stream of prompts that we're giving it.
I could- I
could ask it to include the original prompt as well.
Well. And. Here we go. This is- this is my prompt.
Super simple prompt. Like, vib- vibing prompt,
if you will. Umm, alright, so it creates- seven specialized agents,
research depth, four to nine variable by agent role.
Now, that's a cool thing about my research swarm.
It sort of figures that stuff out. . . for you using the goal
components. Here are the agents that were deployed.
So we had to explore broad and we had depth analysis.
So you got verifier, you know, this is,
you know, and this is how deep it goes.
Depending on the depth, like, the research.
You know, a can run basically forever. So I don't want it to run
forever. So you want to set sort of a depth and that basically tells
it how long it needs to run. Domain experts,
critics. Critics basically is like,
I making sure that it's not full of crap, uhm,
and, and ver, and verifies it as a, that exists. Alright,
knowledge cut off, limitation identified,
future recent discoveries. This is,
this is how it's thinking. Again. Anti, here in my anti hallucination protocol.
Again. The AI,
we had a discussion at the Toronto,
a, uh. But, Uh, it doesn't lie to you.
It doesn't lie in the same way that humans lie.
But it lies in the way that it so- it takes the least- the
path of least resistance sometimes to give you the answer.
So it's not- I don't know if it's lying to- I feel like you
are lying just to get to kind of reflect what you're saying back to
you in a way that's sort of what you'd expect it to say.
But regardless of whether it's lying purposely or lying because it's been programmed to
be sort of, you know, a sycophant,
the result is the same. This stops that from happening,
right? Protocol six, never generate speculative data or statistics.
That's in medical, right? So this is going to be particularly important.
Uh, only site sources you have verified and exist.
Never create fake citations or URLs.
Verify, you know, validation and impossibly assess- 9% of verification
threshold cannot be met because, uh,
recent discoveries may lack. So these are things that are- Legit-logical,
right? But I'm broadly saying,
find me new things without really telling it what.
If I was a- like this LSA at a genomic data set,
which is a project that I'm currently working on as well,
it would ground the information- on the basis of the DNA information and the
correlation between the DNA information for certain anonymous donors
of the DNA information. And, uh, and their sort of profile for their ailments
and other conditions, along with the,
uhh, PubMed, uh, uh, data structure that I'm sort of using for grounding for
research, as well as the research that exists within the ahh,
ahh, actual research organization, which in this case would be a cancer research organization
that, that are funded by university. And uh,
I think the U.S. got, government. Anyway,
the, so this is providing grounding. But in this case,
I didn't include any of that grounding. So it's essentially just searching the web.
So this is, It's actually meaningful because it's like,
I'm just searching a web. I can't say it's true beyond the fact that
it's publicly accessible data. Anyway.
Novel, scientific contributions,
self-aware research systems, form demonstrated recognition of capabilities.
So, let's go, researching integrity over results,
recommended alternative research approaches that it's doing various things.
So basically, in this case, it's it's giving me a technique.
It didn't tell me the exact, uh, data.
Okay. So what I need to do next,
this to me is basically told me how to- what did it. Alright.
So now I'm going to go back here and I'm going to say,
like, what the heck did you actually discover? Or maybe it did.
Uh, I'll task it. What happened?
Instead of fabricating medical discoveries, seven ages form demonstrated,
unprecedented research by something. Okay.
Fine. Okay. Let's find, uh,
find me some actual- This
is this. I think it's called pub med.
It may as a med- med pub, I don't know. Something like that.
Alright, let's do that.
Let's do it. Let me, let me search that quick. Yeah, Yeah,
pub med. Yeah. Yes. Alright. And there might be an API.
I, I should, you know, use pub med.
Um, and we're gonna let that continue.
Prove, are you running
clock flow on clock go web?
Yes, I
am. MPX, clock flow and MPX.
Agent DB and MPX research research.
So the con, so what I didn't do here,
because I'm running research swarm, I didn't tell.
I wanted to run agentic flow because essentially research swarm is my research implementation
of agentic flow. So I didn't bother doing it twice.
Nice, and it's built into a clod blow here.
So, yeah, I, it's,
it's using these tools. And this- This is, this is all I gave it.
So, all you need to do is basically the same basic prompt.
And it just kind of magically,
It works. And now I,
I'm, I'm, I'm, I'm early in the process,
so we're gonna let that run a bit. I'm gonna- Good I'm back for
a moment and see what's going on with the,
the robotics one. Back to,
oh, it's looks like- it's still running. No,
it's, it's done. Alright, let's see what happened here.
I've, a performance benchmark. This is real,
not simulated. I've created a comprehensive benchmark,
memory, serialization, 54 nanoseconds.
If this is true, I- we- this is the basis- and this is
why I think Martin was concerned. This is the basis of arguably the world's
fastest robotic- uh, operating system.
Like, this is orders of magnitude more capable than
the sort of previous. But- but I, I need to- I need to be
able to prove that. So,
performance, again, it's not giving me the docs directly because it's in here,
and that's- that's a drawback of- the system.
So, I could go and I could create a PR, or I could- and
I can take a look, which I think I had open here,
uh, right here.
And I can refresh. Because it- it did the commit.
See, one minute ago. So now I get- I can go and try to
find the files. Where the heck- to put those.
So we can go and take a look here.
It's in. I don't even know where it's at here.
here. I gotta, I gotta take a closer look.
Well, we'll, we'll, we'll surf around, see if we can find it.
Here's the performance report created a minute ago.
So there's. This is the performance report,
real measurements. Yeah, it's crazy.
Like, when you think nanoseconds,
microseconds, and this is just astronomically faster.
Like, you know, there's a thousand times a thousand to get
to one. One millisecond from a nanosecond.
So it's essentially a million, I don't even know,
it's a million times. It's a million something faster.
Then, then, then a millisecond.
So, and when you think that the humans think on the order of a
hundred milliseconds, so then it's a hundred million times faster,
I, uh, someone correct me if my math is off,
but I think that's, that's the, uh, the general,
uh, frame. For how much faster it is,
it's ridiculously faster. So,
oh, here we go. A million
iterations.
Yeah, so. For one nanofus.
Second, at speed of life, approximately 30 cent of the episode.
So, to edit a block in memory.
for me. Does it,
or I guess what is, how long does it take to edit or flip
a bit in memory? Cause my understanding is that it's still- .
Greater than the numbers. Yes,
you
are right. So the real question is how long is one cycle on a
CPU and it- And that's the basis for as fast as you can possibly
run, right? Now keep in mind this is running in a container somewhere,
so there's a couple of I'll be happy. Okay, so of abstraction, but you're,
you're, so what I'm attempting to do is get to the closest form of
the tick,
or the cycle.
In a CPU, and then run the sort of calculations,
and essentially many hyper,
many agents that are doing very particular.
Things, uh, very, very fast scales.
So you'll see here that this is actually running, uhm,
I think the lowest it got to was, was 30 nanoseconds.
Which is basically means that there's overhead between the CPU,
the memory, and other components in the computer,
which makes it, means I'm not going to be able to, get to in
the nanosecond, because that's the smallest increment of time that exists within a computer.
But, I'm getting pretty freaking close. Well, right,
so this would be the smallest increment.
Anyway, here's a- ehm, ehm,
ehm, ehm, ehm. Now,
ultimately, this is,
this is how we- how we prove- group.
8 that the unit to Martin's point is this real.
This is the step towards, you know, making- making this real.
So, example performance summary. summary. Hello robot.
Simple. 10 seconds. And so it's creating basically,
uh, uh, production robot examples.
Example. them. Example. Execution proof.
System architectures. Hub sub.
Tokyo is the sort of,
uh, hypers. We'll next week. Umm, uh,
event bus for Rust. I think is what,
what that is. So this is, you'll see a lilyness in what stuff I'm
building. Here's the comparison with Ross too.
So Ross 3 is,
is 540 nanoseconds for serialization.
This is running, and so running around 2 to.
10 times faster. Message overhead is 3 to 6 times faster.
And the allocation overhead is,
uh, according to this. Anyway, 50 to a hundred times faster.
So back to my original point, the Ross 2 system is essentially
If we believe this to be
true,
using- I'm random thing Martin asked me on a- on a random Tuesday afternoon
using a website and just a- a really brief,
uhh, sort of prompt and- and really in-depth,
umm, PRD,
we were able to create arguably,
I'm gonna use the word arguably. you believe? the world's fastest robotic system.
Do you
feel
that you
lose anything in- . . In regards to testing where the
system is testing virtualized hardware and when it actually-
Actually, wait. It comes on actual hardware.
There may be some degradation degradation or any loss.
Hard to say.
Umm, I'm gonna give you guys this.
So someone smarter than me can go and fool around with this here.
Let me pop this in. In the text chat.
And here you go. I'm sending you the hello robots.
So. I don't know. Like I said.
This is like, this is how I vibe code,
right? I don't know. This could be an elaborate- Robert.
It could be full of shit. I have absolutely no idea.
But what's cool about this is to,
in order to run this, because I did- the compilation of the- the Rust
to a TypeScript. All ye- if you want to invoke this robotics,
you don't need to go and use some convo- umm,
sort of Python meets C++ interface.
You can literally just define this using either my emcee- c p or some
type script, right? So you hear the swarm intelligence.
So this purpose. So let's say you wanna create.
I can see some really nasty. See you. This is for this, but let's
say you wanna create a swarm of,
uh, drones. This is,
this creates a self optimizing. Thank see you in the next swarm of drones.
You can see here it's using my agent DB.
It's creating a 2D vectors.
Here's, This is vision tracking. Uh, here's a robotic arm manipulation.
Back to home run hitting robot.
This is how you create a home run hitting robot. Now keep in mind,
TypeScript's going to give you overhead. Now,
I, I, I need, if you want to run this. you ultra fast,
skip the TypeScript and just use the raw,
uh, libraries, which you'll see in packages.
Uh, uhh, uhh, where's,
uh, crates, here it is.
So these crates, this is, this is the basis for the sort of core.
You're, intellectual capabilities of the system.
And we can see some of the code here. So if we go to
the core, we can see the messaging bus, the library,
Brace services. Lots of work to be done.
I-I'd have to dig, dig deeper, but for those of you- Peter,
but Any-any comments,
uh, guys? Any comments, uh, guys? So is this actually working,
uh, thing, or like, it is,
you have
tested- Uhh, timeframes. I know.
I
have no idea. You're looking at- I'm just looking at what,
I built the other day. Uh,
I don't- I need someone like Martin to go plug this into a robot.
And if- if it takes a- it's Martin's fault.
Yeah,
that's it.
Try one more thing.
Try to integrate, uh.
Like, rather than normal bits, right?
What if we try to integrate quantum bits,
quantum algorithms? So, it's like, You don't need to.
Yep. Must be enough.
Quantum isn't needed
for any of this stuff. So, uh, and it turns out that,
at least in my opinion. All in take it with a grain of salt.
But the, the, the
benefits of
quantum mostly have to do with speed or,
or the temporal dynamic. Of computing.
So, the, the idea of quantum essentially was this idea that you could,
you solve really complex problems by,
by, uhh, uhh, I sort of paralyzing them and,
and getting all kinds of answers to that problem all,
all at once. And for certain things, like, for certain things,
uhh, uhh, like
crypto or whatever,
you're going to get, uhm,
you have to use quantum. But for the things, that I'm doing,
I'm saying, well, you can get some of the benefits of a quantum-based environment
by, uh, by operating super fast. So,
when you look at, like, nanosca- I'm skip. I know are the Umm, yourheyoa
structures? The sort of be, what do you want to call?
Like, the causal loop between what's happening.
What's happening. What's the, what's happening.
I mean, I think quantum is trying to,
quantum computing is trying to simulate the
predictable They will need, nature of AI models.
Because it is, uh,
predictable in its
own sense, right? Yeah.
So,
speed trumps, um,
broad, expensive sort of brute force.
We'll see GPU's and quantum brute force the answer and
essentially temporal structures attempt to parallel.
Do a sort of concurrent parallelization of the problem.
Many, many really small targeted,
umm, sort of. and answers to questions that are happening beyond the,
the sort of our ability to see and understand very,
very fast. So for the things I'm doing,
uh. I wouldn't use Quantum here. It just doesn't seem like it would solve
my problem. So I'm trying to, I'm just trying to get better,
faster, uh. Compute.
Alright, have you tried by coding using what you say,
this, some browser model coming out, right?
Browser agents. So have it.
Try it. Like,
comment. Have you tried using comment for by coding using plot code?
So it's like an agent trying to, in the load,
it's just a prompting. Yeah, yeah,
exactly.
You're, you're, you're, you're thinking exactly how I'm thinking.
Yes. 100% I am. And then I'll show you how to do it.
All right. So, uh, again, before anyone complains,
yes, I know it's, it's like a beta or whatever.
Not everyone has access or whatever. But here's the,
uh, cloth. I'm not sure why it's taking so long
to load. room I have a question
about operation when,
when do you just ask Claude to generate PRD and when do you utilize
the swarm research for PRDs?
When do I ask Claude
to do the PRD, sorry, I think we'll say one more time.
time. ... ... I think in the robotic
example, I think you just asked Claude to,
to create the 20 years from now version.
But there's also a whole tool he created for swarm research.
So when do you ask us, Claude, and when do you actually utilize swarm?
I like, I
like the interface for
deep research. search. For Claude, um,
just because it's pretty and I can see these sources and it's,
it works. I basically kind of.
verse engineered this a little bit for my research swarm.
So, essentially in this particular scenario,
when I'm praying a PR. D and I'm vibing, and I'm totally vibing.
You can see the simplicity of my prompt.
You know, I didn't dig particularly And
it ran for an hour. And in this case, then what I might do
based on this PRD. You then the first step over here might
be to actually go and, uhm,
and use, do another,
I need to make sure that this stuff is grounded in,
in factual, you know, components.
What, what, uh, the clod system doesn't do potentially- Now,
it gives me a whole list of-
of- of things here,
but it's- it's not cryptographically signing them and verifying and showing me how,
where, and what. So, it's broad. God.
And when you, when you, when you see that, when you go back to
my, uhh, this, you know,
these documents here, they're not, you know, particularly well.
you I'll define. So then I might use my research swarm to basically go
and validate it. So that'll be the first step,
and then that would run for another hour or so. So before I get
to the point of implementation, um,
so it's usually a multi-step process. Now the other thing you can do here
to the question of. Can you get Claude to basically,
you know, manage the entire sort of structure?
Yes, you can. and SHELBY So check this out.
So now I'm using the Claude co, or the Claude,
uhh, whatever they call it,
browser extension. attention. Now you see here that I've got,
oh, I don't have this. This is a new computer. Let's see what we've
got here. Yeah, I don't have. So I'm gonna create a shortcut. Now we're
gonna call. All this. We're gonna call this goal.
Goal. Now what we're gonna do is we're gonna jump back into one of
my, uh, VS. codes for a second.
Where do I have that? I gotta get too much stuff going on here.
Uh, fidelity. I will see you video.
Actually, sorry guys. I got too many windows open.
Which one is it? No, no. Uh,
neural trader. I'm gonna show you guys neural trader too here in a minute.
Uhh, so I'm gonna start that. This'll,
this'll segue into the neural training stuff I'm doing,
which is, all the stuff you just saw,
apply to- And we'll next time. So,
let's, let's, uh, but before I do,
I'm gonna show you how I can get the claw due to manage clawed.
So that's it I'm gonna give this a second to start up.
And, so, you guys can do the same thing I'm about to do as
well. Hopefully it's, I tried the same thing
using Firebase. You know that Google's Firebase,
right? So, I'm using-
So, it is creating a full stack testable app.
Yeah, but Firebase has a- So the,
the problem with comment is it's, it's, and the problem with,
uh, Claude, which does pretty much exactly the same thing is it's just slow.
Now, I'm trying to get, uh,
erm, I'm gonna, actually I've got something else open,
I'm gonna show you guys instead. Umm, alright, so I'm going to- It's not
right It's this. I'm going to agents, and so now I've got my cloth
flow installed, I've got my different folders, I'm going to goal,
I'm grabbing the goal planner. better I'm going to copy this goal planner agent,
and then I'm going to go back here. So again,
just to recap, I've got the,
the, extension here, installed, then I click the settings.
Alright, now I'm going to go back here. Oh.
And, My computer is slow.
It's a brand new computer. Why are you, why are you bringing it slow?
Maybe I should, maybe I
should
slow some stuff down. Uh, what'd you buy?
Uhh,
Oh, I got the new ASIS
present book,
uh, dual-screen jobbie. I like lots of,
uh, uhh, I got lots of screen,
double screens, actually. Alright,
so now I, I, I, I go here, I'm gonna pop this in here.
So this, this is my goal. So what this is is a goal oriented
action planning system. You can,
it, it, it, it, it. It basically does dynamic planning.
It does effective prediction and various goal decomposition.
So it gives me the sort of secret brains.
I'm going to create that. Then I'm going to go back here.
And then I'm going to do, I'm going to do slat.
You know what? It's the, it's this extension that's slowing it down.
Anyway, I'm not going to run it. Maybe I will run it.
Oh, goal? Yeah, it's, it's totally slow.
Claudio. . . So if you had added that as a skill,
uh, versus
the shortcut.
Okay. Would you still have to come back and add the shortcut also?
The extension of the skills,
the school, the, that is a skill. That is a skill.
So you can add skills directly to Claude,
but the, um, the browser extension option doesn't use it.
You got it. Alright, so now I'm going to goal.
So
insert, it basically inserts the giant prompt.
And, and then I could, and then, you know, y'all.
But I'm just, I'm going to just say, um,
find new novel.
All right, we're Uhh, medical break,
break throughs. That's to see where we are
quickly. for tomorrow. Oh, this is, this is actually the robotics
one. one.
Okay, let's, let's do, uh,
optimize and pre,
and prepare the,
uuuh, ross,
pre, uuh,
greats. And- m-p-m for
publishing, using the- blood.
.ai, code, ui,
something like that. So, I've given it the ability to operate autonomously with that-
with my goal prompt. Well, that's a And now I'm going to go and
I'm just going to click Act Without,
Act Without Asking, which is probably dangerous and I might go- a little below
72, you know, 972, we'll see.
And now this will- this will organize and- and manage the cloud code
system. this day. So, if you want this thing to run for a really
long time, like days or something, this is how you're gonna do it.
Alright, so now it's doing its things. Thanks. I'm taking a screenshot.
It's gonna figure out what it needs to do.
And I'm just gonna let it run for a while. Okay, I'll run for
a while. I need a bit. Can you a unit test
also? Yes, yeah. So my,
uh, quad,
my, uh, agentic flow system includes the test.
Yes. It's a development London school where it does sort of a test driven
development framework. So that's already built in. And I saw that when I went
to the- Uh, vibe cast folder.
We went here. We went here. And there's one more
thing. The, the Lord browser which you're trying to- What do you use?
Will it know how to prompt engineer another AI model?
Will it have the base of- prompt engineering?
It's- it's- that's what my tools do.
It inherently no- it inherently knows how to do a kind of- a meta
prompt. So, it just- it just kind of magically works.
Alright, so this- this- this- this- this-- this we're- we're gonna let that- we're
gonna let that go for- while- alright,
I'm gonna jump to, uhh,
neural trader. Actually, before I do, any- guys,
any questions on what you've seen so far? I've been- Go fast and hopefully
it makes sense. Um,
the gold planner, um,
shortcut into the chat. That, just so we can drop in and create our
own slash goal. Yeah,
so the goal, the goal play, there's a couple of different
ways to handle it, so. If you want to copy and paste it,
you can, well, actually, you know what I'm going to do for you guys?
I'm just going to give you the, give you that. So let's go back
to. Alright,
let's just go to Clod,
Clod Flow. Hello. We'll go here,
and then we go to, we go to .clod, and we go to Agents.
There you go. I'm the next Well,
I Oh, no. Okay. Okay. Well, I know And you can copy any of
these agents. I'm going to pop this into the text area for you guys.
Oh, I got to find where that went.
Alright, there you go.
And just go into one of the folders. You'll see here goal.
Uh, what to do. Thank you.
And this is code oriented.
This, this is the one I use most frequently. Click the coffee button.
and And you,
and you're good to go. Just copy it right there. And you can.
Thank you. Pop that into.
You
go. Also make a skill out of this. If you save this,
d- so if you choose to download the raw file,
save that as a zip. Then you can go in the clod.
Where is it?
Uh,
and I think it's under settings.
Yeah. Yeah.
And you can go to... Keep availability. Yeah.
Yeah. And
you can, You can
upload, It skills. See,
see, I've got, What's the difference between this and
the research swarm, uh,
npx? The research npx
is
way more comp, is way more,
It, research, the research npx runs forever.
It's a research swarm. There we go.
So, if you're curious about that- essentially,
this will run indefinitely.
So, what happens with the cloud, umm, the cloud blows- blow.
Deep research is it run- it can run for hours. Like,
I've seen something run for more than two hours, but eventually it ends.
This, on the other hand, this research form This is We for a The
is warm! It is never ends. Like,
when you- if you set up with a stream of data,
let's say you're- I'm gonna show you guys my neurotrader here in a minute.
You know, the system will- will- will you can get a- let's say stock
market information or crypto or whatever you're looking to invest in and- or
even a fire hose from, like, X or some social media network.
It'll study that in real time, learning and adapting and getting some-
That can be expensive if you're using expensive models.
That's why I include the option to run local models that don't cost you
anything. So, y'all in that's- scenario, all you really need is a GPU,
or potentially even a CPU, depending on the level of fidelity you're looking for.
And it'll just run. And run. Until it makes the decision.
Then it'll say, oh, I've been running for two weeks,
and I just found the optimal stock trade.
It can. It can do that stock trade in under 100 milliseconds based on
two weeks of training. So it's always learning, always adapting,
and, and. And, and always getting better.
So you've got, and, and that's what the research swarm does.
Now, if you don't. If you, if you don't use the mid streamer,
then it's, it's gonna end. Mid streamer.
Uhh, mid stream,
I think, yeah, mid stream. Yeah, mid
streamer is the low latency streaming toolkit.
So. So, uhh, temporal analysis toolkit.
Well, you know, that sounds like giant mnemonic here. But the,
this is basically the, the tool in which I'm using to,
to sort of inspect the stream of data.
So, I'm, I'm looking at the data, finding bits and pieces.
I'm using that, also as the way I handle the AI defense,
AI defense system. So,
rather than learning about, you know,
cancer research, what the AI defense system's doing is inspecting the flow
of information in real time to figure out what,
private information is leaking,
what keys are potentially leaking, and then,
or even using a sort of, uhh, the,
the potential of,
sort of, psychological tactics,
it's learning how you potentially are being manipulated,
or your system is being manipulated. Yeah. So, it's attempting to hack itself with
a real-time stream of information. And,
you can see here, I can do detections, in this case,
under- 0.015 milliseconds.
So, we're talking hundreds of,
you know, microseconds, I guess, at this point.
So, you can do that- I can. And currently, blah, blah, blah. It's just
nuts. So, all these tools are built in as a kind of
Lego building blocks that- One tool connects the next tool,
connects the next tool to create each of my new tools.
So, when you go, if you want to see all the bits and- pieces
of this, which is actually the- I can even get to my jujitsu one
yet. But basically, these tools are all- Hawker.
I'm a so when you see you agenting jujitsu,
I'm- I'm combining all the things I'm showing you into new
and interesting new applications. We'll see of weeks. In this case,
this is a high-speed mechanism for thousands of potentially millions of agents to
concurrently work on the same information.
So I've got low latency for inner agent communication.
I've got the ability to see the information flowing to and from different agents.
to real time. I've got the ability to learn from that in real time.
I've got the ability to adapt based on the learnings of that in real
time. time. So I can take all these pieces and make new interesting
sort of components based on all my various- other components.
So now when you look at the- my recent updates,
this is the sneak peak into the stuff that I'm building.
. . So now we're gonna get into how am I gonna do the
stock stuff. So before I ever get to posting the MPX- or the MPX
and MPM, you'll see here I've actually posted a bunch of my components that
I need to do, you know, high-speed neural trading.
to break down. So, in this case, the, the NT Core,
which is basically my neural trader core,
it allows you to do zero-poppy stuff.
So, similar to what we saw in the robotic system,
I need the ability to basically figure out the options.
Right? And right now, the limitation for stock trading,
predominantly, is- is- is- is two parts.
The speed of light, you know, can I front load between New York and
London, basically, and- and me. Like the decision faster than somebody else.
The faster than somebody else part is essentially where the world of quantum trading
comes into play. Most of the people doing quantum trading right now are working
in tools like Julia. They're using C libraries.
They're, they're. We're trying to get as close to the sort of hardware as
possible. And some of the best traders are,
are doing an amazing job. And none of that is.
Made publicly available. So, if you happen to work at a large bank and
you're doing this and you're, you're a recent graduate from MIT,
this is how- they're doing it, but most people don't have access to it.
I'm crazy. And I said, let's give everyone access to it.
And, and, and this is what this. So,
we're talking the ability to do, you know,
financial calculations in nanoseconds or microseconds.
seconds. It's type safe, so it's easy to use.
You don't have to be a genius. Basically point your,
your, uhm, your favorite agent at this.
And, uh, But, So these are all the various parts of it, right?
So we've got, where else we got here? We've got my,
my, these are the extractions. This is the market data.
I need a, a component. Now, I haven't put this all together yet,
because I'm essentially giving you the,
the building blocks to sort of Lego.
It's, assemble all the various bits and pieces.
Umm, and what's,
what's guys sending me here? I,blap buff.
you uhh, first, here we go. We can add that to the mix. But
anyway, umm, back to my, back to my rant.
subscribe more videos! So, these are all the parts.
Right, so you can see I've got different,
you know, I'm using alpaca and all these different parts. I haven't,
I didn't bother with too much. Uh, read me because eventually what I'm going
to do is essentially make this available as a compiled,
uh, package, which is what we're going to I see now.
Alright. Which
of the components is
you built? Do you consider to be the
fun? on. Is it Agent DB?
Is it cloud flow? Uhm,
then you build and then whoever would build on top of it.
And use the other parts. If and- Yes,
you know- It's- It's- It's
right
now- No.
No. The part that's probably the most,
umm, valuable.
I don't know if that's the right word. The mo- The mo- It has
the most impact- and what I've been building is definitely Agent DB.
Agent, Agent DB is, is,
is, uh, evol- all the things I built recently is by far giving me
the most impact, right? This allows me to do reasoning.
Thank you, Google. This allows me to do- various types of learning plugins
based on self-selection of the best and optimal learning patterns,
and I can spin these up- across parallel agents that can try
all the possibilities of all the different ways to achieve or solve a problem.
them. . And I can do that in ridiculously fast periods of time.
Right? So I've got the quick sync, again, the UDP component,
no handshake. shake. Instantaneous communication.
I've got MCPs. I can plug it into cloud without a whole lot of
effort. And I deliver it as a universal.
for right. One time. So you don't have to worry about compiling.
All you need to type is MPX agent,
uh, agent DB and you suddenly get, you know, the system that's capable of.
Doing all these crazy things and, you know,
really, really quickly. So. If you want to start,
and you want to create something crazy, point.
Find agent DB and say, go,
go, learn how to do something.
And it's, it's kinda like, the matrix where,
you know. I hope you have a neo plugs in and suddenly knows how
to do jujitsu or something, right?
It's, it's got that kind of capability.
So, and I know, I'm . I, I probably should call it something,
the Agent DB. I think the DB does a disservice to it.
It is based on a vectorization,
but. It's more than that. It's basically this idea of a kind of vectorized
synaptic network that doesn't require,
uh, sort of neural structure in the way. That traditional neural networks operate.
So I get all the benefits without any of the overcast.
Maybe Asian baseline or something. Yeah,
it's like. The high speed
graph is what it is.
You know, you know what? We'll bring all this together is if we go
back to your
original prompt that you use. For the medical research swarm,
right, is actually using all these things together.
So you're basically installing clod flow.
Plus agent TV, plus research swarm to find it a novel medical
discovery. And so it's, it's using all these- ehm,
right? So it's, it's basically the research swarm is going out and doing that
research, but it's
using
agent DB to- store everything that it's learning to,
which makes it immensely faster,
correct? And better. Yes.
Yes. And yes.
Yeah. Exactly. It's hard to even describe.
Like, it sounds like science fiction, for the most part.
Uhm. And so,
so, back to, back to, uhh,
the before, before we got just,
uhh, because someone's raised, said.
I was like, what is your view on basically pectative
versus grabbing? The way I see it is that,
if you're exploring. You know, it's exploration over like repeatability or
traceability. I mean, in fact, the DB obviously is what we use.
But from production, like an enterprise where probably
explainability is more, there's some work we- down on graph,
uhh, from- graph work.
What is your view and like, where do you stand on?
On those two. Thank you. You're- I'm not sure if I quite understand what
you're asking me.
You're saying, like, much better. A knowledge graph.
So rather- So it's in there. Like
to DB for ex-
an
agent DB, for example, you've got patterns in the- in the w- you- you're
basically capturing the patterns effectively in- in the agent DB implementation.
That's how I have understood versus proper knowledge graphs,
which is, uhm, uhm,
I I'm using a hypergraph,
just to be
clear. So, most graphs,
and I'm, uh, graph experts probably gonna,
you know, call me out. you know what I'm about say. But most graphs
are basically bidirectional,
right? You've got an edge, and you've got sort of some data relates to
it. And so it's, it's, it's. It's a kind of one-to-one,
or potentially one-to-many, but it's still one thing connected to many other things.
Now, the, the. The part that I'm attempting to do
is a many-to-many multi-dimensional structure,
which I think sometimes- Okay. This is referred to as a hypergraph.
The hypergraph allows for the structure to-to exist within
both- Thank very much. Time and space.
Okay, time and space again. It sounds like a nut job describing it that
way, but that's what it's doing. So time.
The temporal, right, is what's happening over a period of time,
you know, and as time elapses,
you've got an- ehm, enthalpy is the accumulation of chaos,
right? So the- the faster you operate,
the less- and therapy you get,
less chaos. There's a,
uhh, there's an- there's essentially an algorithm that essentially measures- As you're,
That's called looping off. Uh,
I think it's what it's called. And what that does is essentially measures the
amount of empathy that- that- that- that's created over time.
So when we go back to the concepts of there's a,
uh, you know, accumulation of- of- of complexity.
Or chaos, the longer something runs,
the harder it is to sort of make predictions and understand that information.
So the shorter the period, the more- or tightly bound that is within the
structure of what you need to understand. That's why the nano and microseconds are
so important because uu- you can essentially understand cause and effect much more effectively
because it's such a short period of time. So within the structure of the
graph, the graph is, is defining not only that,
that temporal element, what's happening, how quickly it's happening,
and the accumulation of, of, of, of, of comple- complexity,
and then defining a structure to understand how that relates to everything
else that's happening. So in this case.
You've got multiple agents doing multiple things concurrently.
They're writing files, they're researching, they're figuring out what's good and what's bad.
I've applied the idea of reinforcement learning to that entire
crazy concept that I just described around time that says,
is it operates, not only is it understanding what it's doing,
how, what the ramifications are, cause and effect,
causal loops. I'll see you the next I'm also training the system to give
it a point structure, 20 plus negative 15 to a maximum of 0.095
or 95% or minute. I'm going to point 0.055 a percentage point until
you reach a coherence, meaning that it does the thing in which it's supposed
to do prediction. Effectively every time. That's all happening in
the structure of essentially the combination of Agent DB and all the other crazy
stuff I've been showing you guys. And,
and, and, and what are applying this reinforcement learning?
Come you, I'm. Yeah, it's machine learning. It's basically,
it's vectorized temporal hyper graph machine
learning. That's what it is.
So, uh, do you see this as an alternative to rag or
graph rag or playing, I'm tuning a model on private corporate data?
No, it's an ogment to it.
So, when you go to demo,
one of my demo, This here actually is a Grag self-learning.
So, the, the, the, and this is a rudimentary,
uh, implement, uhh, implementation of it. But if, if you go in and you
look at the inspector here, you'll, you'll be, you'll see kind of,
kind of what it's doing here. But basically,
what, what's happening is, Okay. . . . As the rag requests are being
made, so I'm, I'm making a retrieval-augmented generation.
I'm requesting information from some secondary source.
Generally, that's probably a, uh,
vector or something. Then, what I'm doing,
as part of that process, I'm using the,
I'm, I'm learning, based on the requests that are being made,
so that gets better as those requests are made.
Most RAG systems, uhh, don't get better because they're essentially,
you know, using an LLM that doesn't allow it to understand the,
the, again, the cause and effect. of what it's being requested.
It's just, we're getting the information, inserting it and giving it to the LLM
and the LLM and the say, okay, here's what you need to know.
We're starting the learning. I'm storing,
in
this example, I'm storing it in as
a sequel light database in the. We'll see you in the end users memory
on their computer. In this example,
I'm actually storing it in the memory.
Hurry. Holder here in memory DB.
So in memory DB,
you'll see here I've got a. . The pattern embeddings.
Each of these pattern embeddings has a binary that I can,
I can compile that concludes different bits of.
And that can, that can define different patterns that can be found.
It can define memory entry.
So this case. I got 379,
uh, pages. You know, there's how many per page here.
Yeah, this is, this is. That's it. And stop. It's fine. I'm going to
Stop. Stop. Yeah, there's 37,891
memory, uh, memory entries for me building.
building. my, uh, system. So as it builds,
it can, it's learning and tracking everything.
It's done. One. Now,
the important part here, this is right,
basically. Before I make a request to do something,
the system can- can understand everything that's happened to lead to where it's currently
at. So now, 37,892 entries- rez- later,
the system is, like, basically been pre-trained on what it needs to do
to effectively build the things at which it needs to do.
But because- because I'm able to request it in this really,
really fast structure, like milliseconds or microseconds,
it doesn't affect the speed of the overall system.
Basically, it acts as a kind of intermediary request that is made
before it goes and says, hey, LLM,
I need to know something. If I've already answered the question 37,000 times,
I don't need to go to the LLM. So,
back to the, a gen... Do I have a page for that?
Let's go to Rube.io for a second. I I hope this,
I'm rambling here, but hopefully this makes sense. Thank you very much. Back to
the agentic flow. I'm uh,
my projects. Agentic flow,
agentic flow. Hello.
Has a, yeah, here we go. This has a proxy. Oh,
I don't know if I- put it on this page, I'd probably have to
go to where I put that in GitHub,
possibly. So, the- the- the proxy- You I don't- I don't
know why I didn't include that in my documentation.
That's an important part of the- of the system. But anyway,
the proxy- I say. Eventually is a local proxy that everything flows through
in high speed. So, before the request to a given LLM
or- or third party is made, it flows through your local proxy.
Now, that local proxy can then say,
in real time, because of the things I was showing you earlier,
midstream- game and others, it can all, it can automatically say,
okay, I don't need to make the request to the LLM because I've already
know how to do the request because I've done it. I know that this
request is going to fail because I've already done this and the request resulted
in a bad piece of code that. It failed. Or whatever else it needs
to learn. And I'm not specifically telling it how to learn.
It just kind of magically learns. And,
and that's the self-learn. Learning capabilities. So the first time you use it,
it's going to be basically the same as just making the request of the
LLM. But the 38,700.
And whatever time, it's now got all this information that's learned,
and it can do that in an instantaneous fashion.
Thank you for attention. Room,
do you need to, how do you add it to the cloth code flow?
Or, cloth code? Yeah,
so, yep. You're just, you're going, oh,
this is still running, by the way.
Uh, but yeah, you're just, boom. Just tell it to do this.
M-p-s
use, use the MPX agent to flow. Now, and then,
and do something like, tell me about it. You've done this,
tell me, tell me how this works. Right?
And it was, uh, I sued. Yeah.
I'm gonna sorry back. It should help like, uh, you got my idea.
My dyslexia is showing. Um,
use MPX, egenic flow. Right?
And, uh, yeah. In a j- s works.
Now, what you're seeing right now, I'm totally jumping around,
but what we're seeing now is flawed managing quad.
Right? Which is cool. And this will run, this will run for a while
as well. So now what we're doing is letting it sort of optimize.
It's going to create a private repo. It's doing some stuff.
Whatever. I'm going to let that run for a bit. So back.
Let's go back. Back to this for a sec. Which database you are
using
for the embeddings?
This is a, this is a SQLite optimized
database and the trick to the,
and I also use Postgres. Thank having me. I'm asking Superbase and whatever.
I, uh, SQLite is really useful for just as a sort of rudimentary interface
between any database I want to use. But.
One of the things that's really interesting about,
about SQLite, if we jump back here for a moment,
or in this, in this case, we're going to go to Agent DB. B
Agent DB.
So, oh wait, no, it's not going to dedicate sight to that.
Agent DB is something- Okay.
It's called H-H-S, yeah. I think it's H-S-W.
Thank you. Thank you. Where? Oh, H-F-R-O,
I always forget the exact acronym.
Uhh, where did I put that?
That's it. H-N-N-E,
why is my brain not working today? Uhhh uhhh, uhhh, uhh,
I gotta find it. There's, I have a hyper optimization of,
of the actual, umm,
I gotta find where, where I put it. But that, it's,
it's the most important part of the whole story.
Why am I drawing a blank on his name? Sorry about that,
guys. Here it is. Uhh, uhh, uhh, uhh, there's
a lot happening here. Here it is.
H. each. H-N-S-W.
I just got my letters mixed up. Okay.
H-N-S-W. H-N-S-W.
H-W is what they call a hierarchical navigational
small world is a graph based approximate near- neighbor.
This is the magic that makes it actually work in the ridiculously
low latency. CQ. So it's designed for efficient similarity search in high
dimensional vector spaces. Remember I mentioned,
there's kind of high dimensional. Right? Let's talk about the multi-dimensional structure.
It's used in applications like vector databases and in other components.
So this is the comp- this is the part that basically makes them- this
is the magic. If you- if you want
to look at how- exactly I'm doing it,
this is what you need to look into. But what you need to know
is, I'm- I'm doing it. So it's- And
you can ask chat GPT or whatever to tell you more about H-N-S-W.
Um,
and it's, yeah. But. And then, you know, pinecone others are using it.
See what Wikipedia has to say here. Yeah,
same. Same. Same information. They're really trying to sell us here.
Alright. We should add,
uh, Agent DB to this list. I'll see Yeah,
you can use this with
PG vector,
by the way. And. and Oh my god,
it's
almost, it's worth the bomb the hour. The hour went,
a half went by pretty quick. Thank you. Uhm,
I, I, I, I get a hard stop today at 1.30. I got,
I got a call. Uhm,
any final comments, questions,
thoughts? much. I didn't get to get into my, uh- Yeah,
the neural trader part, we'd love to hear more next time.
Next week. All the stuff I showed you- is what I'm putting in the
neural trader. And I'm gonna make it open source because why not?
Live a thousand. Let's- Let's make- Let's level the operations,
the- the world for everybody here.
I'm gonna- I'm gonna aim to get a first version out problem- problem.
Probably next week.
I will release it. I'm gonna release it to the folks who,
uh, paid for my previous neural trading session- You
know, thanks for supporting me. You guys will get it first. And, uh,
then I'll probably give it to the tribe. Uhm, uhm,
I'm gonna- I'm gonna ask you is, is this neural training what you're talking
about?
Uh, what do you say? Fast-paced quant trading type of health?
What, uh, like, type of things which industries do?
Self-learning. It's a self-learning trading system.
So. Thank you. I've
got the high speed stuff. But to be honest, I'm working faster than most
trading, uh, APIs can respond to. So, uh, s- s
certain point, I'm just too fast for, basically,
any current modern trading system.
So, what I'm really doing- So,
there's this problem for sequential data that,
uhh, it doesn't depend upon the pass,
it only depends upon the
current and- you know, the next output.
So, it's basically like a Markov chain. Yeah,
kind of chain. Yeah, chain. I'm- I'm- I'm- I'm using Markov chains.
Uhm, yes,
100%. Yeah. So, what it's doing,
essentially,
and
is- it's really good- Good.
at doing really small wins.
So, the- the investment isn't- I'm gonna make 10% is- it's- I'm gonna
make .01% above my feet,
but I'm gonna do it a million times. Right?
So, when you- when you look at- I- I can- I can comfortably do
the same profitable, you know,
investment strategy across a whole variety of different,
uh, verticals. And I can- it just slightly more than it cost me to
make- to make that profit. But then I can get a swarm of agents
doing that concurrently, million- Really?
Millions and millions of times every minute. That- so,
you know, one-one-tenth of a million is actually a pretty good,
uh, in-in-in ret- We'll be right turn on investment.
So, have you tested your profit and,
like, loss? What is this pattern coming
out? I have, but I can't- .
I can't share that without my security
laws issues. So, that said,
use, use at your own risk. Don't, don't-
Don't
spend more than you can- you can
lose.
And I'm not a financial advisor.
This is not- I was just asking like, what is- the general behavior you
have observed. Yeah, it does general behavior.
You can- okay, long story short, you can take my neural trader,
pop in in the cloud code. I have and say
go, go, create me some investments. So,
uhm, you give the win rate on your site there.
there. Do you
know, like, what the risk reward return is on it?
Like, what return you have on it? Cause I don't think I saw that
there. It's an. I'm gonna lose that because I'm a little worried about securities,
uh,
you know, considerations there. All I can say is it to.
It depends on your strategy and what you're doing. Some people do really,
really well. Others can't figure out how to make a dollar.
And the only thing I can see. The difference between those that are doing
really well and those who don't is they,
the ones that do well seem to have a background in sort of finance
and trading. And they just basically take what they already know and,
and apply it to the system.
If you don't know what you're doing, you're not going to get any results.
help. . . . . . It's almost like garbage in, garbage out.
Oh, like, gambling. Rather than trading. It's gambling.
Yeah. So, you know, the folks that don't know
what they're doing, don't make any money.
It's, it doesn't change the nature of that.
And I'm at the end of my session here,
guys. I love this- As always, thanks everyone for tuning in.
Umm, we're gonna do the, uh,
AI Hacker Space tomorrow at 12 noon.
I share the zoom, unfortunately. Good morning of.
Uh, thanks dad for joining us today.
Um, until next time.
Thank you. Thank you.