rUv: How are you doing?
Mark Allen: Great.
Mark Allen: How are you?
rUv: Good.
rUv: Got some new tools and toys for you guys to play with today.
Mark Allen: Yeah, I was gonna ask you probably have Claude skills integrated.
rUv: Yeah, I got two things.
rUv: I got skills and I've got my new Vector Agent DB system which allows for self learning without any traditional machine learning components which would be perfect for what you guys are doing.
Mark Allen: Oh man, I'm excited.
Mark Allen: So the.
Mark Allen: Yeah, maybe you should start give us a little brief on those.
Mark Allen: It's so funny.
Stuart Kerr: I'm.
Mark Allen: I was diving in, I told Mac this weekend when I was diving into Claude skills.
Mark Allen: I like.
Mark Allen: I, I'll bet that RUV is working on getting Claude skills in there into Claude flow.
rUv: Yeah, well, I had previously done the commands and the agents and the challenge with the commands is they were invoked by the user, slash, whatever.
rUv: Right.
rUv: And so what I had to end up doing is basically stuff all these sort of intention, intents, whatever, into the agents, which I did a pretty good job of, you know, because then, so you're basically invoking an agent and then the agent kind of knows generally what it needs to do in that structure.
rUv: And now the benefit to the skills is you can sort of have more structured sort of contextual awareness that relates the skills that it might encounter as it does development.
rUv: So when you think of like declarative development, right.
rUv: I'm telling it in the entry point A and then I'm telling it what the optimal exit point is, Z and but everything in between, it's kind of figuring out as it goes.
rUv: So the benefit to skills is as it's going through the sort of process of building, learning, adapting, fixing, whatever it can say an hour in, oh, I need to do a very particular form of testing or whatever, and then it can invoke that skill as part of the agents doing the work where previously if it went outside of that sort of structure, it, it would essentially fail or take you down a rabbit hole.
rUv: That didn't, that wasn't adequate.
rUv: So now combine.
rUv: Oh, sorry, go on.
Mark Allen: So, so also seems for my reading that it's more, it's.
Mark Allen: It's more efficient use of context window to use a skill inside of a sub agent rather than design it to have all the MCPs by default on.
rUv: Exactly.
rUv: So what I was doing before was I guess what you would call context stuffing.
rUv: And I was basically saying here are all the conditions, variables, whatnot that you might encounter, which is confusing because a lot of those conditions aren't really needed until the condition is met.
rUv: Like I've got a problem that needs to be solved.
rUv: So in this particular scenario the system is now more intuitive and declarative and it's saying, oh, I've now, I now have a problem.
rUv: Don't worry, I have skills that can address that particular problem.
rUv: So if the problem never happens, I don't have to tell it what this, what how to address it.
rUv: It kind of self discovers those things.
rUv: Now the second part of the equation, this is something I was building before they came out with skills.
rUv: This was sort of the underlying part of my reasoning bank structure and the memory structure of cloud flow which I separated and I call Agent db.
rUv: Now what this does is allows you to learn to train the system in using reasoning.
rUv: So a reasoning bank that says how and why and what am I thinking about and why is it important?
rUv: Then I've got the ability for me to bypass the need to do explicit neural networks, which I was doing using a micro neural network, but now I'm applying that just on a vector that basically allows it to understand the interconnected relationship of what's happened, what's currently happening and what's likely going to happen.
rUv: And that is also embedded within the cloud flow system and the skill system.
rUv: So it's continually learning and optimizing.
rUv: Anyway, I use this H. Whatever graph based structure and anyway this combined allows you to make it way more smart.
rUv: And for you guys what's interesting is not only can it be better when you're, when it's building the app, but you can then take it and deploy it as a standalone agent that can run perpetually.
rUv: So think of like a trading bot that needs to understand the market dynamics and what your optimal trades are looking like that's going to run all the time.
rUv: Always looking for the optimal moment to do your trade, right?
rUv: Long, short, high frequency, whatever.
rUv: So it's and it's doing that, but it's using the vector to do that.
rUv: And I've created some demos to sort of help illustrate that a little bit.
rUv: This all runs by the way in your browser, so I don't have to pay for any of the compute.
rUv: I'm offloading it all to the end user and using and borrowing their computer GPUs to do that.
rUv: So if I want to create like a neural trading system, for example, I'm going to go in here and I can start the trading process.
rUv: And this is all actually running specifically in, you know, actually I got Gemini running here in this one, but it's essentially running in your browser versus you know, requiring explicit hosting or whatever.
rUv: Here's a marketing one that's probably so the.
Mark Allen: So, so you're not using an AI call, an API call to the AI in this.
Mark Allen: It's just logic.
rUv: This is, this is all, yeah, this is all happening client side in the browser because I'm cheap, right?
rUv: So you know, so this is actually calculating, this is actually doing the machine learning in the form of a memory based vector.
rUv: So I'm basically borrowing the memory from the person who's visiting the website, then compiling it using Rust based wasm, which is the compilation of the sort of complexity of the vectors and then basically using their system and I can borrow their gpu, their CPU and their memory.
Mark Allen: Wow.
Stuart Kerr: But we're looking at a demo here, right?
Stuart Kerr: This isn't a live trading system.
Stuart Kerr: Or is it?
rUv: This is, this is real.
rUv: This is, I'm using, I'm using, I'm generating the data through Gemini but the structure is real in the sense that I'm, it's using real data.
rUv: I'm just built, I'm feeding the data from, in a loop from Gemini.
rUv: So it's a real simulation, if that makes any sense.
Stuart Kerr: Have you launched this in reality?
Stuart Kerr: Does it work?
rUv: Yeah, yeah, I've got.
rUv: So we can see it here, operating here.
rUv: This is what's actually happening under the covers.
rUv: You know, a lot of my customers are creating marketing feedback and AI systems that will buy their ads, optimize a B, test their ads and then learn which ad patterns work best.
rUv: This is a representation of that.
rUv: So in this case, if I click run a B test, it'll run.
rUv: You can see the AB test running.
rUv: This is all real.
rUv: Now the difference between what I'm doing here is I haven't connected to meta ads directly.
rUv: I used Gemini to simulate what the data from meta ads would look like so that I'm running it through the neural system directly.
rUv: But it's basically replace the fake stream with the real stream and it's the same information RU is the peer to.
Mak Allen: Peer GPU and memory sharing, you know, while totally different from torrents and seating.
Mak Allen: But you know, as analogy, is it pretty similar to seating for.
rUv: No, a little bit different.
rUv: So.
rUv: Well, depends on the BitTorrent basically has multiple connected, sort of, I don't know how you describe it, but they're basically multiple parts of a file that you can concurrently download and then reassemble once it's done.
rUv: So I can get Pier 1 does like say one piece, Peer 2 does another piece and so on.
rUv: So that what that does is allows you to spread the sort of loading of larger files across multiple peers.
rUv: Now we could hypothetically do that for the delivery of the actual components themselves.
rUv: That's not what I'm doing here.
rUv: This is more for like client side, like intelligence or something like that.
rUv: So in this case you can see I've got different options for presets.
rUv: So if I want to choose like a wasm, this would be in the browser.
rUv: If I want native I might choose that and I can choose different vectors.
rUv: The vector basically are the style or structure in which you're defining your vector database.
rUv: So for example Anthropic uses a slightly different version than watching Anthropic I think use the same one as OpenAI.
rUv: But for example Google bert would use 768 where OpenAI uses 1536.
rUv: The larger the vector, the more dimensions, the slower it becomes.
rUv: So something like this is fast or much faster.
Stuart Kerr: And do you have folks using this in reality doing AB testing with their live ads working?
Stuart Kerr: I understand the conceptual part.
Stuart Kerr: Have folks taking this to production.
rUv: Well it depends what you mean by production.
rUv: Everyone's building stuff.
rUv: I don't really know what level of production they would be at.
rUv: But do I have people using it?
rUv: Yeah, tens of Thousands.
rUv: I did 36,000 downloads of the thing last week.
rUv: Now how many of those are production?
rUv: I have absolutely no idea.
rUv: But the, you know the real question is does it work?
rUv: Then the answer is yes.
Stuart Kerr: And then I guess the same question on the trading side, have you had anybody tell you, hey, I actually used this and hooked it up to Live Feed.
rUv: Oh yeah, real dollars in you're talking my neurotrader.
rUv: The Neurotrader is my most lucrative product by far.
rUv: You know I've got around 70 customers.
rUv: The biggest did it did a 50 million dollar test.
rUv: These guys are Dubai or whatever they get.
rUv: That's like a drop in the bucket for I guess these guys.
rUv: I just got off a nerve.
rUv: I just spent my morning doing neural trading seminars.
rUv: This by far is my most lucrative offering.
rUv: And so basically what I took is I took all the stuff I do for neural trader and then I just did a sort of light client side version of it.
rUv: But yeah, people pay me big bucks to do their you know, neuro trading components.
rUv: I yeah the finance space is definitely the most lucrative.
rUv: It's probably a no brainer on that one.
rUv: But sure, yeah, you can check it.
rUv: You can check out no trader.
rUv: Yeah, I get about 70 or so customers in about 30 countries and I launched this in July.
Stuart Kerr: Wow, that's great.
Stuart Kerr: Wonderful.
rUv: This.
rUv: Yeah, it's all mcp.
rUv: If you guys are interested I can give you access.
rUv: I don't, you know, it's just definitely.
Stuart Kerr: Interested and would love to explore more but that's outside the scope of this discussion.
rUv: Yeah, this is the, this is the hot thing.
rUv: I, I don't give this away because you know, it's rich bankers.
rUv: So I figured I could make a buck just to be honest with you guys.
rUv: But it's all built on the same general tech that you're seeing here.
rUv: You know that.
rUv: So this, the only difference is this would be client side and that the other, what I'm showing you would be server side but similar tech.
rUv: So there's, that's so cool.
rUv: This is the autonomous training system, that kind of stuff.
Mark Allen: I think we all have interest in playing with that neural trader at some point when we get our heads around everything else we're working on.
Mak Allen: It's.
rUv: Yeah, the neural, the neuro trading stuff is a whole, you know, is a whole thing.
rUv: Yeah, you know I use, I support sports betting.
rUv: I can do, you know, options based trading, forex.
rUv: I can do poly markets and prediction markets, all that stuff.
rUv: And then you can correlate all those things.
rUv: So you.
rUv: I can correlate the poly market to the social media to the random crazy things some president might have said and then see the, the inflection of crazy and how that affects other stocks relating to that.
rUv: And I can do baskets of, I think 128 stocks in less than 10 milliseconds.
rUv: So I can know, I can get with about 90%, you know, real, you know, prediction.
rUv: I can figure out what the correlation between some random statement on Truth Social and how that would reflect in the real market.
rUv: And the other thing I can do really quickly which is the most profitable is I can do mirror trading.
rUv: So turns out the most profitable trading strategy is actually just following some of the US senators, particularly one out of California and doing whatever she does.
rUv: I can actually do an exact mirror trade of whatever she trades in under 100 milliseconds.
rUv: Like it takes a heart milliseconds to blink.
Stuart Kerr: So discover exactly what she is buying, you know.
rUv: Well not just what she's buying.
rUv: That's actually.
rUv: Yeah, yeah.
rUv: So it's not.
rUv: Yeah, she's the greatest investor of all time basically.
rUv: But it's not what she's buying, it's what the other things that are affected by what she's buying slightly faster than anyone else can figure out how the, the influence of what she just bought would affect these sort of correlated stocks either positively or negatively.
rUv: So I'm not actually just copying her.
rUv: I'm copying the interconnected relationship.
Stuart Kerr: You become one of the flash boys doing high frequency trading based on related facts, based on your genius of what are the implications, fallouts and correlations of all the other the run with.
Stuart Kerr: And I can, that's amazing.
rUv: I can do that.
rUv: In as far as I can tell, I've got the fastest high speed trading system in the world right now.
rUv: I can, I can work in less than a microsecondition.
rUv: So just on the verge of nanoseconds using these loops.
rUv: Each of those loops use a form of algebraic sort of structure, a kind of causal loop sometimes or strange loop they call it.
rUv: So I'm not trying to detect everything, I'm detecting really small incremental mathematical equations, but I'm doing millions or billions of those in really tight secession, then putting it all together anyway, it's crazy.
rUv: All right, cool.
Stuart Kerr: Okay, we'll come back to that side interest in this and we probably need to have a whole section just on this mark.
Mark Allen: Absolutely.
Stuart Kerr: Because all of us would love to dive deeper.
rUv: For you guys, the most impactful thing other than actually getting your site working is the automated marketing and onboarding process.
rUv: So once you've got the site working, what we're going to do is we're going to create an autonomous kind of marketing AB testing component that allows you to hyper target your optimal onboard right where you're getting your customers from.
rUv: And then what you can do is you can basically target the most likely candidates or customers, dentists, whatever that are going to buy it.
rUv: And you can optimize based on certain demographics.
rUv: Maybe the dentist is older versus younger or male or female or east coast, west coast, whatever the, whatever works best.
rUv: And then you optimize the ad and the specific sort of positioning of that specifically to what you know will most likely convert for that user.
Stuart Kerr: Let me ask you, can you do the same thing, Rufe, if you've tried it for SEO?
Stuart Kerr: Because one of the things we're discovering is SEO is as you know, inherently local.
Stuart Kerr: Most local people's SEO is absolutely abysmal.
Stuart Kerr: So there's a great opportunity to stand out 100%.
Stuart Kerr: This is the kind of thing where a programmatic formulaic strategy to make you the baddest guy locally would have a very significant outsized impact or could a hundred you're directly.
rUv: So you almost stole exactly what I was about to say.
rUv: So basically one of my customers is a hyper targeted law firm that specializes insurance claims but they focus on insurance claims for sub $100,000 claims.
rUv: And it turns out it's more expensive to actually hire a lawyer for a you know than your.
rUv: It is cost you to get the $20,000 because your, your windshield got hit by hail.
rUv: So what, what we do is we hyper target where the hail came down in Oklahoma last week and then we can go and we deliver ads that say was your windshield destroyed?
rUv: And, and you need help sort of submitting your claim.
rUv: Because what these insurance companies do is basically if it's less than $100,000 they just blankly reject it because it's actually cheaper for them just to reject all the claims and say you're not going to get it and then some portion is going to fight it but it's actually more expensive to fight it.
rUv: So there's an arbitrage that they're doing.
rUv: So we can capitalize on arbitrage by doing hyper targeted marketing that follows essentially the weather patterns and gives you ads the people who are likely affected on a street level.
Stuart Kerr: That's awesome.
Stuart Kerr: Listen, that's the stuff that makes this stuff plutonium based.
Stuart Kerr: I mean you can do really, really clever things and none of the people that run these local businesses have any clue what's really happening beneath the surface of Google.
Stuart Kerr: The rest of the stuff, everything else.
Stuart Kerr: So to be able to attract that and implement it in a highly efficient and effective way is incredible.
Stuart Kerr: I guess one of the questions is how do you find the local folks or do you just put it on Facebook marketing or like how would you figure out how to get to the local people in that zip code?
Stuart Kerr: They got hit by it.
rUv: But that's a meta ads, Instagram, whatnot.
rUv: Yeah.
Stuart Kerr: All right.
Mark Allen: Okay, so let's shift over to Mac.
Mark Allen: One of the things that we thought ruv when Mac and I were talking is to give you an overview of the entire project here because I think we've made some assumptions about things because we really hadn't done this.
Mark Allen: That'll help us to understand.
Mark Allen: So let's just pass it to Mac.
Mark Allen: You can share.
rUv: Okay.
Mak Allen: So I know Rouvnet only has a certain context window and we had a misunderstanding about setting up Supabase last week, but I just want to make sure I ran you through a brief overview of both platforms and how they connect.
Mak Allen: Like we've gone over for the main platform, there's the admin dashboard, analytics, AI call management and various practice configuration features.
Mak Allen: And then the patient portal is the furthest downstream where they'll be able to do some appointment rescheduling.
Mak Allen: There'll also be scheduling in the main platform that's baked into practice configuration or AI call management, document signing, payments, insurance upload.
Mak Allen: And yeah, this is how they connect and these are the main features and the technology that comes along with it.
Mak Allen: So I think we ironed out a good amount of it last time, but where we left off was on starting on the main platform and I just wanted to make sure that I got it started with your presence, just to make sure that, you know, I had your blessing and we started it off right.
Mak Allen: We still need to do.
Mak Allen: I think the first step of Supabase for the main platform was rbac.
Mark Allen: Before we jump in the technical things, I want to make sure that this is fully understood.
Mark Allen: Okay.
Mark Allen: So the, the patient portal is.
Mark Allen: Is maybe even less sophisticated than the main application that the orthodontist are using.
Mark Allen: And so the orthodontist, their practice manager is a main user of that.
Mark Allen: So and then there's a separate AI components as well.
Mark Allen: So typically the very first start of a, of a patient user into this is they call on the phone, an AI agent answers the phone and schedules their appointment.
Mark Allen: And so that appointment scheduling, so in the orthodontist practice is a free appointment, free evaluation that they come in.
Mark Allen: And so it has to work through the main app where the practice manager will see here's all the appointments that are scheduled.
Mark Allen: And then through the main app it has to through the API go to the practice management system to say to first of all say what are the available appointments?
Mark Allen: And then once the AI agent talks through that with the patient, then it goes and updates through the main app, the accidental app.
Mark Allen: So we record, that's effectively the system of record.
Mark Allen: And then it also is going to update back to the practice management system because that is the system of record for the practice itself.
Mark Allen: So they'll effectively have two system of records where we're going to duplicate certain data.
Mark Allen: But inside of the nexidental you'll be able to see here's all of the patients that have been booked through the AI scheduling agent.
Mark Allen: And then those patients are also going to be uploaded into the practice management system.
Mark Allen: And the practice management system has its own calendar so if that makes sense.
Mark Allen: So there's effectively three different AI components in this app that we're building in.
Mark Allen: So first one is scheduling new appointments.
Mark Allen: The second one is insurance verification and that's a matter of calling out to the insurance companies.
Mark Allen: It's pretty simple.
Mark Allen: In the area of orthodontics is like, you know what, a lot of them don't have any coverage.
Mark Allen: To the degree they have coverage, what is your total lifetime benefit, how much of it's been used for the patient, that sort of thing.
Mark Allen: And then the third one is a follow up.
Mark Allen: So after the actual appointment, then an AI is going to follow up with the patient to get that contract signed.
Mark Allen: And so those are all three different areas that we're building AI into the system.
Mark Allen: So it's.
Mark Allen: So you think about it as there's multiple different ui.
Mark Allen: There's the patient portal and that's for the patient, but then there is the UI for the clinic itself.
Mark Allen: And the practice manager is the main user of that.
Mark Allen: Practice managers and a treatment coordinator as well as another role that we have and the treatment coordinator is typically the one that presents the fee.
Mark Allen: So one of the components that we have in this, we have some legacy technology and a feature set that our partner already built out with another traditional software programming group that does this payment slider.
Mark Allen: Here's how much you can do as a down payment, here's how much you can pay over time.
Mark Allen: And so we're rebuilding that in this new version.
Mark Allen: And then they also had an electronic signature technology for sending out the contract.
Mark Allen: So we're rebuilding all that.
Mark Allen: So you gave us some amazing ideas in the last appointment, the last meeting that I wasn't there last Wednesday where you had the ideas of using the Stripe Connect and today the orthodontist finance the payments over time.
Mark Allen: So to allow Stripe to finance that and them to get that cash up front is a huge value add.
Mark Allen: That's a huge new feature.
Mark Allen: So thank you for that.
Mark Allen: So the bottom line is, you know, when I listen to that, I'm like, we want Stripe Active for us to sell the software to the clinics and we want Stripe Active for the patients to be able to purchase their orthodontic plans.
Mark Allen: So hopefully that gives you a broader understanding.
Mark Allen: So there's quite a bit of functionality still to build out beyond the patient portal.
rUv: So keep it.
rUv: So keep it simple to start.
rUv: One of the challenges I think that you've been having is you're trying to do everything all at once and doing nothing in particularly well.
rUv: What we need to do is take a step back.
rUv: And the reason why I want you to start with the patient portal is it's like the end user of the end user.
rUv: It allowed us to start with something that we could achieve a functional completion on relatively quickly, which I think we've probably made it, I don't know, 80, 90% of the way there on that particular part.
rUv: Now the next part is probably going to be related to user authentication, user sign up, user validation, verification, whatever.
rUv: Right.
rUv: And without that the system won't work.
rUv: You need to have some mechanism to know who's who and what they have access to, which I think Mac was referring to with his RBAC comment.
rUv: So the next step probably is one, where are we in that sort of patient portal portion?
rUv: Like is that nearly done or functional enough that it could be.
Mak Allen: The last that we left off on the patient portal was this is good until we set up some other things upstream besides messaging.
rUv: Good.
rUv: Which way?
rUv: Sorry.
Mak Allen: So after you had looked at it and went through all browser debugging, the only errors were due to APIs.
rUv: Or you want to run that quick just to bring everybody up to speed.
rUv: NPM run dev in.
rUv: In that folder.
rUv: You probably need to go to the folder, I would guess.
rUv: I think we separate.
rUv: I think we separated it into two different folders.
Stuart Kerr: Yeah.
rUv: If you're gonna, if you're gonna run it that way.
rUv: Yeah.
rUv: Just tell it to run as background process.
rUv: You should also install my latest skills as well going.
rUv: And we.
rUv: I can show you how to create some skills or you can use.
rUv: Yeah.
Mark Allen: What does that mean to run it.
rUv: As a background process?
rUv: I mean.
rUv: Well, it.
rUv: Usually when you're going to run something, you're going to go and create a new terminal and then.
rUv: And run the command and.
rUv: But if you want to run it within Claude code, you need to run it so it doesn't block.
rUv: So it's a background process.
rUv: You can also hit Control B to put it as a background process.
Stuart Kerr: Sorry, what do you mean it doesn't block?
rUv: It doesn't block everything else.
rUv: So if you had just said run the npm, it would have ran it, but then it would have basically stopped it as soon as it was done running this runs it in the background.
rUv: So you can continue to use the Claude code system after it runs.
rUv: Normally what you would do here is probably wouldn't use Claude code to run it.
rUv: You just run it, you know, running the command.
rUv: But if you're going to do it this way, run it as background.
Stuart Kerr: That's a great tip.
rUv: All Right, So let's log out.
rUv: Let's go through the process here.
rUv: Quick.
rUv: And remind me, the sign up.
rUv: We did make the sign up work, right?
rUv: We, we could sign up with something other than test.com, right?
rUv: Yeah.
rUv: Oh, but so the, the.
Mak Allen: On the signup side of things, the clinic code right now allows anything because there's not a feature in the main platform to generate a unique code.
Stuart Kerr: Yeah.
rUv: Which is trivial to, I might add.
rUv: We just need to figure out what the signup code needs to look like.
rUv: Like my guess is the signup code probably should be like a.
rUv: You guys know those mnemonics they use for crypto?
rUv: It's like a word based approach versus a uid, which is a bunch of random characters.
rUv: I would say a mnemonic would probably better and easier for people to remember.
Mak Allen: Okay, so just a series of words with dashes.
rUv: Yeah.
Stuart Kerr: Okay.
rUv: Doesn't need to be a lot of words and dashes.
rUv: But probably the drawback to a mnemonic is there's potential conflicts if people start using simple mnemonics.
rUv: So, so you'll have to have some mechanism to avoid conflicts.
rUv: But generally what we could do is be the one that generate the mnemonic and that should be enough to solve that problem.
Stuart Kerr: Like GitHub does with CodeSpace names.
rUv: Yeah, exactly.
rUv: Yeah, that's exactly what the GitHub CodeSpace name is.
rUv: It's a mnemonic.
Stuart Kerr: Yeah.
rUv: All right, so yeah, this is looking pretty good.
rUv: You see that Mac added the debugging information in the right hand console, so that allows us to know exactly what's happening, data loaded, how long it took.
rUv: So we can see any choke points.
rUv: We can see that the appointments Data loaded in 664 milliseconds.
rUv: So half a second, basically.
rUv: So pretty quick we can see fetches.
rUv: So everything that's happening is now loading in a way that is visible both programmatically as well as in the UI itself.
rUv: And that helps us debug the system really nicely.
rUv: And Max is doing a great job here.
rUv: Looks spectacular.
rUv: Thank you, Rube.
Mak Allen: I also went over these and the reason why these aren't working is again, bold sign not having template documents just yet in the API.
Stuart Kerr: Meaning you just didn't build that part out yet, Mac.
Mak Allen: I, I need to get the templates from our design partner, Nick Kim.
Mak Allen: Like the.
Mak Allen: How the actual documents should look.
Mak Allen: Still waiting on those.
Stuart Kerr: Okay.
rUv: Yeah, but we can see the debugging information is working really well.
rUv: No download available for this record.
rUv: So yeah, it's Looking.
rUv: This looks, this looks spectacular.
rUv: And for this we'll end up using.
rUv: Oh, yeah, I don't think we did the treatment page.
Mak Allen: I did do the treatment page.
Mak Allen: I've not had an error yet on the treatment page.
rUv: Oh, you know, that's.
rUv: That.
rUv: The demo gods are smiling on us.
rUv: Okay, so, okay, so let's just quickly.
rUv: So there's two ways to solve this.
rUv: Let's.
rUv: Let's do it the right way.
rUv: So.
rUv: Yeah, DSP and what.
rUv: Whenever you find an error like that, you want it to be able to reference this error in the future.
rUv: So what you're going to do is you're going to use.
rUv: You're going to type something like create a GitHub issue using the CLI and outline and review the following error with suggestion fix or something.
rUv: Right.
rUv: And this is going to allow us, if we ever encounter the error in the future, to take it and then we take a step further.
rUv: You could say, using the reasoning bank, update the memory with the, you know, fix in final, you know, and that what that allows the system to do is understand if this problem ever happens again, the memory will then refer to it and it'll keep it from hopefully happening more than once.
Stuart Kerr: Can we do it in a more generic way, Ruben?
Stuart Kerr: Anyway, that says, hey, anything, right now you're doing it to capture this error.
Stuart Kerr: We understand that.
Stuart Kerr: Is there a way to do it in a more.
Stuart Kerr: Hey, I'm testing.
Stuart Kerr: I'm going to encounter a bunch of things I don't know what do it for.
rUv: That's what I've already done.
rUv: So the reasoning bank, my previous implementation, my memory system, was explicit.
rUv: It means that you had to know exactly what the problem was to refer to the previous version.
rUv: And my new version, what I did is I used a semantic reference to it that allowed for natural language querying that comes up with a semantic understanding.
rUv: So it doesn't have to be explicitly the same thing and it could be generally the same thing and it'll find out what the solution to the problem was if it's generally the same problem, which is a better and faster and more effective way to handle those types of problems.
rUv: All right, if you go back for seconds, this is going to take you.
rUv: This is going to take a minute because it's going to have to do the GitHub issue while we do this, pop open a new terminal.
rUv: I'm going to get you set up with the new capabilities for.
rUv: So close that up and type control C Go.
rUv: Yeah, you don't need control.
rUv: C that.
Mark Allen: Yeah.
rUv: Type in MPX CLAUDE flow dash.
rUv: Yeah.
rUv: Klepto at alpha Cloud flow.
rUv: Space init.
rUv: Yeah.
Mark Allen: Force.
rUv: And we're just going to manually update it.
rUv: All right, looks like you're already running the most recent version.
rUv: That looks good.
rUv: Now we're just instantiating.
rUv: My new memory system could not instantiate them.
rUv: Locate the bindings.
rUv: That's an interesting issue.
rUv: Okay, keep going.
rUv: All right, now let's go to the CLAUDE component at the top left hand side.
rUv: Go to Claude folder claude.
rUv: We're looking for script skills.
rUv: Okay, we got the skills now we got the skills.
rUv: Type dsp.
rUv: Remember, when you load new skills or agents or whatever, now just do a generic like tell me what skills you have.
rUv: I feel like I need to produce skills with a Z or something.
rUv: That's the skills.
Mak Allen: All right, this looks new right here.
Mak Allen: Ruv.
Mak Allen: I've not seen it is new.
rUv: Yeah.
rUv: I've given you my status line.
rUv: I can show you how to customize that here in a minute as well.
rUv: So the status line is telling me various sort of stats that I need to know.
rUv: If you don't know what the heck they mean, they're just a bunch of random numbers.
rUv: But you can ask the system to explain you the status line.
rUv: But before we do, we're going to tell me the skills you have.
rUv: So these are skills I've given you.
rUv: These are things that relate to the stuff that the system can now discover on its own.
rUv: So you've got.
rUv: So now if you want Swarm orchestration, before you had to sort of try to invoke it, now you can just say, use the swarm orchestration skill.
rUv: Skill and.
rUv: Or say, you know, just say swarm orchestration.
rUv: Yeah, just hit enter.
rUv: And now what we're looking for now when you see the gray text indicates that the.
rUv: The skill is being invoked.
rUv: So now when I was explaining that I had to sort of explicitly instruct all the different things through a big long claw MD file.
rUv: Now I don't have to do that now.
rUv: I can do that.
rUv: Now you can evoke the skills by basically sort of using natural language.
rUv: And more importantly, as your aI sort of goes through and does things, it'll discover and use those skills that are made available.
rUv: So you notice I've got GitHub, project management, workflow automation.
rUv: I've got Hivemind and Hooks and pair programming.
rUv: These are all the different sort of hooks.
rUv: And you can create your own because I created a skill builder.
rUv: Go down and say use skill builder.
Mark Allen: you created a skill builder on top of their skill build because they have a skill builder but your skill uses cloud flow.
rUv: Yeah, their skill builder sucks because it doesn't have memory, it doesn't have very good context.
rUv: So I, I took it and applied it using my agent DB and all my, all the stuff that I was showing you.
rUv: So my skill builder allows it to be intelligent and to learn and to adapt.
rUv: Their skill builder is just dumb.
rUv: So mine allows you to create new skills, validate existing skills, generate design, you know, and a bunch of other things.
rUv: So for example, let's say you wanted to create a skill that is optimized for the reasoning bank.
rUv: You might want to create a skill specifically that's tailored just for your repo.
rUv: So you could say something like create me a reasoning bank statement skill optimized for the particular requirements of this repo in both patient portal and next to dental portal or something.
Mak Allen: And it'll go.
rUv: And it'll tempt to do that.
Mark Allen: And so one of the cool use cases of this that I've seen is I was telling Mac about this is that you could, if you have a difficulty in addressing some particular issue and it's like kind of looping through and figuring it out.
Mark Allen: Once you figure it out, you can say now create a skill that'll allow you to do this right from the get go.
rUv: Exactly.
rUv: That's exactly what you're doing.
rUv: And so as Mac gets better, he might start broadly and say, just give me a skill that allows the system to learn what I'm doing and avoid redundancy and mistakes kind of thing.
rUv: And it'll go figure that out.
rUv: Right.
rUv: It'll say, okay, I can use the reasoning bank system or various other tools available to me or other skills and it'll go and build those things.
rUv: So most of what you're trying to do is make the system capable of self awareness and self improvement.
rUv: Wow.
rUv: Which is straight up, you know, remember I was saying mnemonics, it's like you literally Johnny Mnemonic from like a cyberpunk movie from the 90s.
Mark Allen: Yeah.
Stuart Kerr: William Gibson would be pleased.
rUv: Yeah, it's like all this stuff is totally sci fi, right?
rUv: It's like just insane.
rUv: And the fact we're creating self learning systems without that don't even require a neural network, which is even, it's.
rUv: Which is even crazier.
rUv: No GPU required.
rUv: So that Nvidia.
Stuart Kerr: What, what's a less ethereal version of a skill that a mere mortal new person coming into this would likely use.
rUv: This to build error fixing.
Stuart Kerr: Okay, so can we try that?
Stuart Kerr: Because that'd be an interesting Mac.
Stuart Kerr: Would that be useful to have?
Mark Allen: I just said, well, we have to.
Mak Allen: Experience the error or we're fixing or.
Stuart Kerr: But.
rUv: But we don't.
rUv: That's a real good thing.
rUv: Yes.
rUv: Yeah.
rUv: So click.
rUv: Click that for a sec.
rUv: Let's see that.
rUv: This was critical errors identified.
rUv: It didn't actually fix the error.
rUv: It doesn't look like.
rUv: All right, so now scroll down.
rUv: Enhance fixes.
rUv: Was it fixed?
rUv: I can't even tell.
Mak Allen: It was.
Mak Allen: It does not fit.
rUv: Okay, fix.
rUv: So now what you're going to say, now what we're going to do is we're going to fix it, but then what we're going to do after we're done, we're going to create a skill based on the fix that we can apply anytime there are errors, and we're going to use a similar approach to fix those errors.
rUv: So all you need to do next time is basically choose the skill that basically fixes accidental errors.
rUv: But before we do, we're going to fix this error and then use it as a basis for that skill.
rUv: So jump back into the other one and say, fix, you know, fix the issue and up.
rUv: You know, fix the error and update the issue with details once confirmed.
rUv: Something like that.
Stuart Kerr: And would we make that a skill so that it knows to always look for any open issues, go fix automatically?
rUv: Well, we can do that as well.
rUv: That uses a.
rUv: So right now we're using the cloud code components and cloud flow components, Right?
rUv: But we also have cl.
rUv: The.
rUv: The agentic flow system.
rUv: The agentic flow system allows you to basically build and run autonomous agents that are similar structurally as the.
rUv: As cloud flow, but run independently of cloud flow perpetually.
rUv: So you can then say, okay, I've built an agent or skill or whatever, and then I might want to have that run all the time.
rUv: So, for example, you have a customer onboarding experience, and that might kick off a phone call.
rUv: And that phone calls the customer and they spend a minute or two asking questions.
rUv: Once that's done, that creates a hook.
rUv: The hook saying, I finished.
rUv: Here's the transcript of the call.
rUv: Another agent says, okay, what do I need to know?
rUv: What's important from this call?
rUv: Then that updates a CRM, sends an email to a doctor somewhere and says, here's what you need to know, or updates a calendar.
rUv: So it's a series of things that can happen to model that you might use Claude Code to sort of figure out exactly how that works.
rUv: You're doing kind of what Mac's doing right now.
rUv: Once you, once you're confident in what it can do, then you're going to say something like create me a agent, flow agent that I can deploy to the cloud and run all the time whenever this happens.
Stuart Kerr: And would you do that on a more general way where you basically said, hey, the system's up and in production.
Stuart Kerr: Occasionally it's going to encounter a hiccup, something I didn't count on.
Stuart Kerr: When that happens, capture it, put in the GitHub issue, look for the GitHub issue, come back, fix it, verify it, and then, you know, clear out that GitHub issue to make sure that's eradicated and send me a one page email with a confirmation of what I found, what I fixed, where we're at.
rUv: Yeah, but you know, embarrass, that's why we keep Krista around.
rUv: But yes, anything Krista can do, we can automate in a better way with her and Mac as the kind of lead orchestrators.
rUv: Right.
rUv: So a lot of what you're doing right now is figuring out what those things are and that's going to be us, you know, encountering those problems and then saying, how can we automate these things?
rUv: So step one is just discovery, step two is instrumentation of that.
rUv: And step three is some form of sort of orchestrator, you know, human in the loop that keeps an eye on it and making sure that these things aren't going off into the wrong direction, which still happens, obviously.
rUv: So until we're, until we have the learning loop, which essentially is learning what works and what doesn't and getting better.
rUv: So there's a whole series of things that are recursive in nature, looping back upon itself, getting better, optimizing, informing us of what it's doing occasionally when it does it, or getting permission at least initially to do it.
Mark Allen: At what point should we recreate the regression system.
rUv: For your automation?
Mark Allen: Yeah, remember we built the regression system but then went back because we built a bunch of stuff that was wrong.
Mark Allen: And so we haven't rebuilt the regression system that you taught us how to build.
rUv: There's always going to be, we're going through a kind of learning stage.
rUv: So a lot of what we've been doing, Mac and Kristen and I, we've been sort of going through the process, just getting up to speed in what the, what's possible.
rUv: So, you know, that's why we sort of built that particular Portal first because we want to have a win, if you will.
rUv: And once we're confident in our abilities to build, then we start thinking about how we automate.
rUv: But right now we're mostly concerned about the builds back to.
rUv: So okay, so back to that.
rUv: You see that there's a SQL issue.
rUv: We needed to probably tell it to use the SQL based mcp, which you did.
rUv: Okay, looks good.
rUv: Jump back in.
rUv: Let's see if the error is fixed.
rUv: Remember, you might want to do a hard refresh sometimes on this stuff.
rUv: Right, Clicking on the refresh but continue.
rUv: Looking good, Looking good.
Stuart Kerr: Nice.
Mak Allen: Okay, no crash there.
rUv: Yeah, so that is a common issue that you're going to run into.
rUv: That was a SQL based issue.
rUv: That means that the Supabase likely didn't have the table or didn't have read write access to it and were getting a sort of dramatic error because we didn't have error handling for a kind of null value that was being.
rUv: Being returned frequent.
rUv: And that's the reason why we have so much stuff happening in the console window on the right is for us to see what's happening.
rUv: Okay, so now that we have, now we've fixed that issue, let's go Double check the GitHub issue for a moment and see that it replied.
rUv: So scroll down and summary.
rUv: All official errors have been fixed.
rUv: Okay, perfect.
rUv: Now go back into.
rUv: And then we're going to create a nexidental and create a, a new like, what do you want to call it?
rUv: I'm thinking like some sort of like error fixing skill.
rUv: You got to give it a nice name based on the previous sort of structure for fixing errors in the site or something that you're going to have to type something like that.
Mak Allen: Error learner.
rUv: Yeah, create a self fixing error.
rUv: It needs to post a GitHub issue.
rUv: It needs to fix and verify and then reply once verified.
Mark Allen: Do we have to tell it to use the skill builder or it knows.
rUv: Create a new sibling skill?
rUv: No, it should know.
rUv: We're going to keep an eye on it here in a sec.
rUv: It's still a little beta the.
Mark Allen: The.
rUv: So sometimes it kind of doesn't use the.
rUv: The skills which is normal for Claude.
rUv: Create a self fixing skill that posts a GitHub issue using the CLI.
rUv: Yeah, fixes the issue, posts the reply, uses the reasoning bank system to remember the.
rUv: You use these to remember the errors and refer to any previous fixes and is self learning.
rUv: Self improving.
rUv: Wow.
rUv: Yeah, I know, right?
rUv: Self learning, like how is that even a Thing.
rUv: But anyway, here we are, living in the future.
rUv: All right.
rUv: Yeah.
Stuart Kerr: Will that keep track of it?
Stuart Kerr: Well, will we get the listing of them?
Stuart Kerr: All right, these are nine that I found.
Stuart Kerr: These three are fixed.
rUv: These six are, you know, it happens automatically under the covers, but yeah, you could query the system and tell me, you know, has this error happened before and how did we fix it?
rUv: Because what I'm creating is a multidimensional vector structure that is connecting not only the similarity of the error, but how it interconnects to any time that error has ever been addressed in the.
rUv: In the past.
rUv: And I can do the vector lookup in milliseconds.
rUv: I can look up something like a hundred thousand vectors in less than.
rUv: Than like 50 milliseconds.
rUv: So I'm like hyper optimizing for speed back to neurotrader because I need to do things that are super fast because I, I need to be able to make decisions.
rUv: Now in this case, you don't care about super fast because it really makes no difference if it takes you know, 20 milliseconds or 5 seconds.
rUv: It's super fast.
rUv: Seen it's not going to make any real difference.
rUv: But for certain applications, it makes a difference.
Mark Allen: You note here it's putting it in.
Mark Allen: In docs self fixing skills instead of in skills.
rUv: Yeah, tell to use the.
rUv: Tell to use the skill builder.
rUv: Yeah, this is.
Stuart Kerr: And where will it put it if we tell it?
Mark Allen: Yeah, it'll put in skills.
rUv: Yeah, it's not putting.
rUv: It was creating a plan, which isn't necessarily the worst thing, but it's kind of redundant to create a plan.
rUv: Just do it again.
rUv: This is part of the problem.
rUv: When you're using skills, it sometimes needs to be invoked a little bit.
Stuart Kerr: While we're waiting R. Have you found an easy way to clean up some of the other things that it creates in the directory so that you don't have just lots of plans and everything constantly populated everywhere?
rUv: Yeah, Mac and I did that last week when we.
Stuart Kerr: I'm sorry, sick.
Stuart Kerr: Last week I missed that.
rUv: Pardon me.
rUv: Yeah, I think we claimed the docs folder, remember?
rUv: Take a look at the.
rUv: Let's look.
rUv: I think it was you guys that did.
Mark Allen: Yeah, we did.
Mak Allen: So you did an asynchronous fix at the time when we thought that they needed to be two separate supabases and you.
Mak Allen: Yeah.
Mak Allen: Did a major reorg of.
rUv: Yeah.
rUv: So go to the docs folder.
rUv: You'll see exactly what.
rUv: What we did.
rUv: Yeah, see.
rUv: See how nice and clean and organized that is Now Beautiful.
rUv: Yeah.
rUv: So occasionally you just need to clean things up, point it at the docs and say, or reorg.
Stuart Kerr: Why is it one of those skills to build I'll always keep my org clean, always go through the directory and make sure things.
rUv: That would be a, that would probably be a two part process.
rUv: What you're going to probably do is create a Claude, remember to clean up my docs folder.
rUv: And then you want to create a skill set that specifically says what that needs to look like.
rUv: Now if you really want to get, if you really want to clean stuff up, what you're going to do is you're going to move all those docs into a SQL like database and then you could use like my agent DB structure to create a vector style database that allows you to query it in real time.
rUv: So rather than having a folder full of files which is cumbersome and hard to track, you slap it all into docs DB and then you use semantic relationships and can query that in real time.
rUv: The benefit to that is you don't have to parse every single MD file and try to figure out what's what, which is going to overload the context of claude.
rUv: You're only searching for the things that are meaningful within the DB itself.
rUv: So if you really want to take it a step further, you're creating these DB files.
Stuart Kerr: So would it make sense then for Mac to create a skill that automatically took and converted all the docs into the SQL database?
Stuart Kerr: To do that.
rUv: Hit escape.
rUv: You're going down a weird path here.
rUv: Yeah, it's building a Supabase.
rUv: I don't know why it's wanted to do Supabase.
rUv: It's decided to try to do a Supabase database.
rUv: For some reason you don't need that.
Stuart Kerr: Because it says must.
Stuart Kerr: Oh, must use MCP Supabase MCP for the Supabase.
rUv: Oh, no.
rUv: Yeah, I don't know where that came from.
rUv: We definitely don't want to use Supabase mcp.
rUv: That's probably just bad instructions.
Mak Allen: Oh, I put that in there.
rUv: Yeah.
rUv: Should use Agent.
rUv: It should use the existing reasoning memory db, not Supabase.
Mak Allen: MCP for Supabase related options when it's implementing a fix.
rUv: Well, then you need to be clear that you need.
rUv: The reasoning system needs to use the.
rUv: Yeah, I don't know what it's building there.
rUv: I think it's gone down a weird rabbit hole.
rUv: But we'll, we can do that later.
Stuart Kerr: Okay.
rUv: It's.
rUv: Yeah.
rUv: What it's building now would just be way over arc engineered for what we needed.
rUv: We just needed a way to remember how to do a kind of multi step fix.
rUv: It would have figured out all the other stuff automatically.
Stuart Kerr: Okay.
rUv: Is that so.
rUv: So just use this.
rUv: Invoke the skill builder first before doing anything else.
rUv: So just delete everything else.
rUv: Just control C. Yeah, use this.
rUv: Use the skill builder.
Stuart Kerr: Yeah.
rUv: Okay, there you go.
rUv: It's confused with all the other stuff you've done.
rUv: Like it's got a whole.
rUv: Yeah, just, you just escape.
rUv: It's.
rUv: You're too, you're too far down a rabbit hole of something that's confused.
rUv: But generally speaking, start fresh.
rUv: When using the skill builder.
rUv: Having it start later in this case, it's just confusing.
rUv: It thinks it needs to do all kinds of stuff it doesn't need to do.
Mak Allen: Should I just point it at the issue in the comments?
rUv: No, you just want to make it, you want it generic.
rUv: Say something like use the skill builder.
rUv: Yeah, try that.
rUv: Start, start with that.
rUv: Once it sort of says here's what the skill builder can do, then post your other.
rUv: See, now you see it's invoking the skill builder, which it never did last time then.
rUv: And now once you have that invoked, then you give it that command.
rUv: Maybe hit up, you grab the previous command again.
rUv: There you go.
rUv: And fix.
rUv: Implement.
rUv: Use the Supabase.
rUv: Yeah, lose the Supabase mcp.
rUv: You don't need that level, you don't need that level of detail.
Stuart Kerr: You said you SQLite for most of the.
rUv: Yeah, I use SQLite and I hyper optimized it using a combination of vector enablement within, in it.
rUv: So yeah, I can run it in memory, I can run it locally and for.
rUv: And if I want to move to like a more robust database system, all I need is an orm and I'm good to go.
rUv: But for this sort of thing, SQLite was perfect.
rUv: There's no requirements.
rUv: It basically runs anywhere.
Mark Allen: Is that right?
rUv: Yeah, give that a spin.
rUv: See what happens.
rUv: So you see how you invoked.
rUv: You can try to do it both at the same time, but just if you doing it sort of step by step, just make sure you keep an eye on it.
rUv: Okay.
rUv: Yeah, we go.
rUv: Skills.
rUv: Perfect.
rUv: So it's in the right, it's the right location.
rUv: It's creating reason.
rUv: This is going to be a super advanced skill because it's creating templates and scripts, but in schemas and stuff.
Mark Allen: But.
rUv: The skills are, they're pretty cool.
rUv: And then later Once you create the skill, remember you have to restart Claude to use that skill.
rUv: And, and you're going to do the same sort of thing.
rUv: You're going to say, you know, start the self fixing skill and fix this problem with it and then if it doesn't quite work as expected, make a slight modification to the skill.
rUv: When it goes a little awry and after a few tries you should be good.
rUv: And it's learning.
rUv: Right.
rUv: So ultimately it's going to get better the more you use it.
Stuart Kerr: And is there a way to tell it whenever you start Claude, hey, always have that working in the background.
Stuart Kerr: So whenever it sees an error, bam, go to work.
rUv: Yep.
rUv: The Cloud MD file would do that.
rUv: So you'd edit your cloud MD to say whenever you encounter an error, use the self fixing skill to address the error.
rUv: And it'll just automatically do it at that point.
rUv: Yeah, I know, it's pretty cool.
rUv: It's, it's a kind of a cool feature.
rUv: I'm not gonna lie.
rUv: They did a good job on it.
Mark Allen: Do you think that this is as significant as like mcp?
rUv: MCP changed everything for us because it gave us common nomenclature for third party access.
rUv: So MCP is a little more revolutionary.
rUv: But this, you know, in the world of Claude, this is a pretty nice upgrade.
Mark Allen: Yeah.
rUv: You know the guys on LinkedIn and social media that are like, you know, is this bigger than mcp?
rUv: They're, they're, these guys don't build anything, so they're just talking out their ass.
Mark Allen: Yeah, that's why I'm asking you.
rUv: It's like it's like 90 of it.
rUv: Like, I love these like social media influencers.
rUv: You're like, this is the biggest thing since sliced bread.
rUv: I'm like, have you ever actually baked a loaf of bread?
rUv: Right.
Stuart Kerr: As a separate conversation?
Stuart Kerr: Mark, I know one of the challenges you have is a lot of these things don't have A, MCPS or B, even clean APIs you can get to underneath for some of the electronic medical records and things of that nature.
Stuart Kerr: Is that a separate conversation to talk about how to use this, to potentially graft onto that in some agent based fashion?
Mark Allen: Because at least the first version of this, we're using a bridge, an ap, a company that basically gives us one end and they take care of the integration with multiple different PMSs.
Mark Allen: You know, we might try to address that at a later point in time, but that just gives us out of the box tested integration with a bunch.
rUv: All right, click on the self fixing skill MD file above there and let's take a.
rUv: Just control.
rUv: Click it in the console.
Mark Allen: Yeah.
rUv: All right.
Mark Allen: Why did it create a folder out of it?
rUv: Because it needs a folder.
rUv: Yeah.
rUv: So let's take a look at what it's building here.
rUv: So an autonomous system that detects errors, creates GitHub issues, implements fixes using AI powered reasoning.
rUv: This is like someone's startup.
rUv: We're just building it just on a whim.
rUv: Skill.
rUv: Yeah, it's pretty cool.
rUv: It's creating its own bash.
Mark Allen: So.
Mark Allen: So why did it put it at the root cell fixing MD and then it also created us skill.
rUv: What?
Mark Allen: No, sorry.
Mark Allen: At the root of skills.
Mark Allen: You see that?
Mark Allen: The new file?
Mark Allen: The cell.
rUv: Yeah, that's.
rUv: That's the folder.
rUv: Oh, no, it just changed.
rUv: Scroll up.
rUv: You're in the wrong folder.
rUv: I gotta, I gotta jump to another call here in a minute.
rUv: But yeah, so you see.
Mark Allen: Yeah.
Mark Allen: So why did it create that as a MD and then it also created.
rUv: The don't know folder?
rUv: Because.
Mak Allen: Because these skills right here is talking about the architecture of it.
Mak Allen: Probably wants to put it.
rUv: Delete the.
rUv: It's.
rUv: The self fixing MD needs to be gone.
rUv: It.
rUv: I don't know what that is, but it's not confusing.
rUv: Yeah, lose it.
Mark Allen: Self roll ups.
rUv: Yeah, it needs to be Skill md.
rUv: I. I don't know.
Mark Allen: At the bottom of that list.
Mark Allen: The bottom of the skills list.
Mark Allen: Okay.
rUv: I think, I think the.
rUv: The time before we just.
rUv: I don't know.
rUv: Who knows?
Stuart Kerr: Should we.
rUv: Definitely.
rUv: Definitely not needed.
Mak Allen: Okay.
Mak Allen: Definitely not needed.
Mark Allen: Yeah, because it needs to be like that.
Mark Allen: It needs to be Skill MD inside the folder.
rUv: Gotta.
rUv: Gotta jump, guys.
rUv: And now to remember to try it.
Mark Allen: You could.
rUv: You could pretty much try it now.
rUv: You.
rUv: You would create a new.
rUv: You would.
rUv: You would create a new terminal and then say, you know, tell me about your skills or try the self fixing skill kind of thing and it'll tell you know, it's a little back and forth while you sort of optimize it and get it to where you like it.
rUv: But looks.
rUv: Looks like a really nice running start.
Mark Allen: So what.
Mark Allen: What is cool for Matt to continue working on right now safely?
rUv: Well, it seems like the website's in a pretty good spot.
rUv: You should start thinking about creating the same thing on the main portal.
rUv: Start with the user access parts login register and make sure that works.
rUv: Once you've got that, then you can start working on in the same way you did the other portal start.
rUv: Did you say you had a concern.
Mark Allen: That the database was.
Mak Allen: Well, I mentioned that at the beginning.
Mak Allen: It doesn't seem like it's a.
Mak Allen: It's a mess now.
rUv: We'll worry about that later.
rUv: Let's keep it all together and if we need to federate or create some kind of single sign on, we'll worry about that at a later point.
rUv: Right now we're mostly concerned about just getting this thing working.
rUv: And we've got a solid database with user structure in place.
rUv: We know it works based on the other.
rUv: And we're going to basically implement the same general structure in the doctor part rather than the patient part and make sure you have a user system that makes a clear separation between patient and doctor as a kind of, you know, tiered access structure.
Mak Allen: And one last thing.
rUv: How would you.
Mak Allen: Actually, I'll go over the transcript later.
rUv: We have.
Mark Allen: I'm going to request for Brenda to get some more time with you this week.
Mark Allen: So I'll just.
rUv: Okay, yeah, just ping her.
rUv: I'm.
rUv: She'll.
rUv: She'll find a spot for you.
rUv: I just got.
rUv: Mondays are crazy.
rUv: It's like non stop for me.
Mark Allen: Okay, thank you so much.
Stuart Kerr: Follow on for our group right now.
rUv: Yep.
rUv: Yeah, I'll send out.
Stuart Kerr: Great, thank you.
rUv: Okay, later.