I understand
that Raul is not
going to come
today. Was it today
or what day he
was going to be
with his daughter in, I
think they went
to Chicago?
I'm not sure where
he was going.
I didn't see him
noting that, but maybe.
I think it was some
kind of like a concert.
Not Oasis, but
some other band.
So I'm not sure
if today is
going to be the
session or not.
Yeah, Brad said
there's going to be a
guest speaker talking
about documentation.
Okay.
Where are you
based out of, Timu?
Sorry?
Where are you
based out of?
I'm in Finland.
so i am the uh i run the
the finnish
finnish chapter
awesome and it's uh
it's been crazy crazy
week uh for the finnish
chapter we last week
we did have the first
meeting and it was
fully booked three times
over overbooked and uh
a lot of people were
left outside and now
that we have we asked
if we could uh come up
with the community
in WhatsApp but that
would have been full
too fast so we had this
on our own WhatsApp
it's there 700 people in
Finland joining our
group it's crazy 700 and
there's the top CEOs
of top companies VCs
university professors
well-known keynotes
week or so it's it's
totally crazy crazy
you know that's great
news team but holy
but thanks to the
agents we've been like
spreading the word
does uh have you shared
those those numbers
with uh the other
guys actually joined
during this meeting to
tell this uh it's been
like a hectic week
so i i'm happy to
happy to share this
information with Rob and
Ruben and other people.
Brad and
that's spreading
like wildfire.
Yep.
Yeah, it's doing
it globally also.
Yeah.
I'm going to add you
on LinkedIn here.
I'd be curious to
see like a trend
line of growth
by registrations
and growth by
geographic region.
I have noticed, I
believe that every
other country also
might have this kind
of a similar situation,
because there
was a spike in Sweden.
There was a good
atmosphere in Sweden,
and there was in
London and Paris
and other countries.
You are in the
States, correct?
I'm in Toronto. Toronto
is my home chapter.
I'm just north of there.
So basically, same
chapter than Rue,
and I think Rob is
also... Brad, Rob,
Nick,
Ocean is in New
York, I think. Jed is
in New York. Jed is
in New York, yeah.
That's Brad.
Hi, everyone.
Hi, Brad.
Hi, can you hear me okay?
Yes.
I keep messing up my
default microphone.
I installed a
fancy one, and I
don't use it very
often, so it's all
messed up. How are
you guys doing?
it's been a busy
week had a couple
of keynotes and
stuff like that
Timu just shared
some stats
with me tell Brad
before he tell
all the other
guys but wild
actually we had
the first meeting
last week we were
talking about already
last week but there
was like three
times overbooked
and then emerging
how we can connect and
how we can
discuss between
this meeting and
we were offering
that we could bring
up the people into
Discord and they
told that it's too
technical and it's
not easy enough
for some of the
persons and people
to join that so
that could we get
that set up in a
WhatsApp group and
we did and one day
we had like 350
users in WhatsApp
and then it was so
full of discussions
that we had to cancel
the whole WhatsApp
and start a new
WhatsApp with a
community session in
Finland, in Finnish
and it's been like
four days and there's
750 people already
joined Oh my goodness
Yeah, it's crazy
It's totally crazy
And what kind
of group is it?
What is the context?
It's the agent, it's
Finland discussion
about AI how to
progress in AI
the finished chapter
and everyone is welcome
we have CEOs of the
top companies we have
professors we have
VCs we have keynote
speakers everyone who
is remarkable in AI in
Finland is already
joined practically and
a lot of enthusiastic
people who just want
to improve the society
and make AI matter
so me and Mikko
Alasaarela have been like
collaborating, I
just finished my call
with Mikko and how
to progress we are
planning hackathons
and assembly kind of
meeting, bringing
customers and clients
customers and the
developers together in
different situations
so it's pretty good
ongoing here oh wow,
that's incredible man
but it's thanks to
all the agentics stuff
that's enabled we're
trying to do our best
well i'm finding
there's a very large and
growing disconnect
between um people that are
either just starting
out vibe coding or
um ones that like i deal
a lot with uh recent
grads or university
students that they're
not allowed to use
ai and then like this
agentic stuff is just
rocket science so it's
it's like a horse
buggy versus a rocket
ship right now we're
trying to get the people
to the agent engineering
so so it's not
both there is a white
coding uh a community
in finland and we we
were discussing with
mika that we need to
get them a different
kind of uh impact in
a way that we need to
get the people who are
responsible for the
development teams head
of head of technology
ctos ceos of startups
and so forth so that
they will like choose
the agentic engineering
from the start or
change their way of
working into the agent
ways and and brad
yeah yeah no just on
on that that's a good
point so brad i uh i
connected with um jason
la barbera okay nvidia
is he Yeah, at NVIDIA.
He's a senior executive
search leader.
And I've been sort of
just poking around,
you know, connecting
with people. And I told
him I was interested
in connecting with
him. And we started
having an interesting back
and forth on voice
messages in LinkedIn
where he was saying
that he's getting, even
at NVIDIA, they don't
know this. but he's
getting he's working
with a lot of companies
who are struggling to
figure out how what
is the criteria to hire
an agentic engineer
it's this it's so
emergent and and and
changing so often that
there's no sort of like
you know job placement
kind of benchmark
which is which is really
really interesting
because i think
there's been a lot of
discussion sort of in
this group about like
certification and and and
and so on and so forth
but it seems like on
the other side like
on the hiring side that
they need assistance
as well they know
they need agentic
engineers yeah um but
they don't know know how
to hire so maybe
there's an opportunity i
told jason like let's
get together and talk
about that and i can
bring it back to the
agentics foundation
because i know some people
are sort of you know
looking at certification
and a few other
things but you know
he's he's posted a couple
posts recently about
his consultations
with with Reuven and
ocean and uh you know
he flat out said in one
of the message messages
messages that this
group is trailblazer
like they are the
trailblazers of agentics
i think we know that
But it's actually
nice to – it was
reassuring getting
feedback from
someone who's in
that position,
senior executive
search leader
at NVIDIA. Like,
that's wild.
Yeah, no, it's definitely
– no, it's great
to hear the, like,
end user feedback
because we've been
talking about this for a
little while, trying
to figure out how do
we do it and trying
to get teams together.
yeah you intuitively
know but it's different
when you actually
have someone in the
field saying we're
demanding this uh just uh
yeah some of some of
my thoughts where i
where i see where we're
going is it's really
two different routes
we just essentially
launched the the real
website for agentics org
uh so nick nick has
invited a whole bunch
of people and mad and
i hope you and you
and a whole bunch of
other people have been
helping out getting
the systems in place So
that's been kind of
priority one. And then
now we're looking at
creating the courses.
So the natural evolution
is if we have a
couple of more formal
courses on what is agentic
engineering, how to
get started, and then
working our way through
to more and more
advanced as one stream
to have these courses
where you can get micro
certified by us and have
some kind of stamp
of approval. And then
when we're looking at
really the top level,
like the black belt in
agentic engineering,
I'm talking to a
couple of accreditation
companies that would
accredit the agentics
foundation. So we have
some authority saying that
if we give out these
certificates, we're
actually recognized as
a learning institution.
So we can create
certificates all we want,
but it just helps to
have, hey, you know
what, as a foundation,
we're certified, which
helps for if anyone
on here wants to go
and apply for government
grants throughout
the world kind of thing.
At least the foundation
is an authorized
authority to say, yeah,
when we say that
you're an instructor or
you're a black belt in
agentic engineering,
we have a little bit
of weight behind us.
And so the last point
in that is, I think,
like what you're
mentioning with Jason and
others is, is there a
certificate that you
can say that you're a
black belt or whatever
color belt in agentic
engineering? so you're
officially recognized
by the agentics
foundation that you're
at this top tier or
whatever tier you are
so it's definitely
something that um love to
i think we have we have
to kind of light a
fire under our butts
and and get on it a
little bit a little bit
more there's a lot of
people creating the
courses and there's a
lot of discussion so
it's kind of that
scatterbrain approach right
now and we're almost
ready to get formalized
to actually have a
certification because
Like you said, if we're
kind of the leaders
and we're pushing
the development, the
ethics, the security, the
safety, best practices,
well, someone has to
have a certification
program and it makes
sense that we are.
Yep. Awesome.
Just regarding the
new community website,
have the email address
has been ported over
from the previous site?
So right now, people
are registering and
you just register from
scratch. We're
working on ways to get
everyone to come over.
But if you're on the
existing site, if you're
a subscriber, myself
and Nick are adding
you to make sure that
your subscription
continues. um so we're
doing that but right
now it's log on to the
new site start from scratch
we are we're meeting
with the the disco
which is the platform
people about how do
we migrate the other
2500 people um over uh
so we're working we're
working on it but
the easiest way is if
you want to go to the
agentix.org it brings
you to our new community
site you register
and sign up uh that
that's the easiest way
and then we're going
to be backfilling all
the people that haven't
haven't registered
okay sounds good yeah
welcome everyone um we
have uh i'm i'm the
substitute teacher today
rubens traveling so
um it's not going to
be quite the bycoding
uh that you're used to
i'm going through uh
i'll go through a process
but um i guess before
we get started i
know i'm not sure if
you would like to say
something timu you have
some amazing amazing
news not to put you on
the spot and if anyone
else wants wants wants
to to say something
and then that later on
we'll we'll also have
have some stuff no
hello everyone and just
uh good news from the
finland and the finnish
agent community last
week we had a really
successful event and
the house was full and
three times overbooked
and uh many people
watching on the stream
but after after the
streaming and event the
people were like crazy
that what's next what's
next and how how can
we participate and
so forth and so we we
put up on a whatsapp
group for the finnish in
in finnish so that is
a lower lower barrier
to discuss and the
first day it got 350
participants and we only
had one group so that
was full with different
kind of topics and
discussions and we
decided that if it's going
to be this successful
this fast we really
need to do this as a
community likewise is the
global community also
so so we did a whatsapp
community for the
agent in finland and a
couple of days and
it's 750 users everyone
top ceos professors
keynote speakers public
sector decision makers
We were aiming at the
level of head of ITs,
CTOs, decision makers
who can help organizations
to get into the
agenting, engineering
and utilize AI well.
And I can say, I need
to be humble, but I can
say that the first
week with this Finnish
chapter has been both
very, very interesting
discussions and finding
the willingness of
the participants, how
they want to alter and
do something good in
the society to help all
the public sector and
the organizations to
find momentum in
utilizing it. And the last
thing that I'd like
to say that we are
differenting ourselves
from the wide coding
society. So we are
elaborating the engineering.
I'd like to thank
everyone on the call
for the help earlier.
And by the way,
Iro on the call is one
of the participants
who was also in the
meeting and nice
to see Finnish people
also on this call
too. But yeah, it was
great. And there's
a lot of momentum
ongoing now in Finland,
but probably all
around the world.
Oh, incredible.
Yeah, I can't believe
the traffic growth
in such a short
period of time. It's a
hotbed of some smart
people over there.
It's Mikko Lassar,
I think it's a
big name in Finland.
And I think at
least he also is
helping the growth.
Awesome. um
does any anyone
else have anything
uh they would
like to share
now or we can
um we we can go we can
interrupt it
along the way
um so so yeah if if
there's any news or
anything feel free to
interrupt i'll yeah i can
carry on And what I
shared yesterday, Brad,
where we, you know,
speaking of certifications,
one of the things
that we are wanting
to do is get people's
roles and jobs, right?
So I'll just read
this post, but I won't
tell you his name
because he, I've already,
I've reached out to
him to kind of set up,
highlight him on the
website and set up
maybe a conversation,
but he really wants
to, he's inundated
with the new job. So he
wants to kind of
figure that out first.
So in respect of that,
I'll redact his name
in the company, but
I'll read the post.
He said, excited to
announce that I've joined
company as an agent
engineering lead.
I'm thrilled to take
on this new challenge
and contribute to
company's mission of
modernizing the enterprise.
This role represents
an incredible
opportunity to work on
innovative projects
and explore the jagged
frontier in agentic
engineering, and I'm
looking forward to
working with the talented
team. Thank you who
have supported my
journey, in particular,
Reuven Coyne, for
ongoing inspiration
in building incredible
tools and the whole
agentic foundation crew.
There you go. That's
awesome. Yeah. So I
didn't ask him if that
title existed before
he talked to the
company, but I'm curious
of how how they
landed on agent
engineering lead as a
title. But there you go.
Just to add something
to Matt, and then we'll
let you carry on,
Brad. In my discussion
with Jason, we were
talking about the roles
that might be analogous
to on some level.
And he brought up
the forward deployed
engineer role. role. And
Brad, I think you sort
of mentioned this
at one of the first
Toronto meetups where
you were talking about
how you're literally
just sitting with a
stakeholder who has a
vision in his head of
what he's trying to
build and you're building
alongside them. And
that's sort of the
role of a forward
deployed engineer so it's
it's i think you know
agentic engineer is
one uh one class
classification or or naming
convention but i
also think forward
deployed agentic engineer
is is almost more
relevant uh um to this
group in particular
absolutely absolutely
and uh yeah and Just
a recap for everyone
with regard to the
foundation, some of our
priorities right now.
We finally just got
the, not just Scott,
but through a lot of
help with Matt, Nick,
all kinds of different
people in our group
have our community site.
So we've updated from
our old website to a
new website that is
more learning centric
and research centric.
So just sent out emails
to people. if you can
come on board register
and we're creating
there's a couple of
courses right there now
where that people can
do and we're going to
be providing more and
more courses for different
levels of subscribers
and active members
making sure that they
have access to some
of the leading edge stuff
so we're just migrating
and creating the
courses now with the
goal that once we have
a couple of courses
we're going to go through
and really focus on
there's a big need and
we're talking about
this just before the
meeting um where people
people we need some kind
of formal recognition
and there's people
working in london like
mondweep bentz and and
others and and a lot
of people trying to
figure out how do how do
we become more of an
authority where we have
courses and certificates
to have available
for people so we're
working through that
process right now won't
bog us down with the
details but there's
been a lot of hard work
being done and it is
something that we're
seeing demand and i think
we're now the largest
um agentics for sure
organization the largest
not-for-profit and
we're expanding pretty
pretty rapidly so i have
a personal personally
i feel almost
obligated that we we we
have this um we have
this community so now is
the time to be become
a little bit more
formalized so thanks
to everyone that's been
helping out and uh
enough of me talking i'll
i'll get on with uh the
the office hours uh as
i mentioned before my
style is a little bit
different than roofs
i'm not going to vibe
coding i'm not not that
fast and not uh that
fast what i'm going
to go through is my
process for more of the
agentic engineering so
i think top line
everyone seems to have a
different idea if you
have if you have a better
description pipe up but
i look at vibe coding
as you're playing
so even if you're if
you're brand new and
you've never done coding
before to a lot of
people in this group vibe
coding is you know
what you're going down
a rabbit hole and you're
just creating stuff
i do a lot of teaching
and i use a company
called lovable.dev i
used to be gpt engineer
for playing around with
the front end i like
to see things i'm a
visual learner so i like
to see things before
I go deeper this
process that I'm going
through is I already know
what I want right now
just to give you some
context I'm going
through my final final
classes at school and
I have to do a capstone
project and what I'm
doing is I'm looking
at creating gold standard
for documentation
so being able to have
agents that take messy
user feedback take all
the ****** stuff to
be honest with you if
it's uh if it's i'm
recording a call with
a client and taking a
transcript and putting
it in i i want to take
all that and create
what i consider gold
standard um that that's
what i'm doing for a
capstone project what
i'm doing on the personal
side and i'm going
to try and push the
the boundaries for it
is i actually want to
go through and i i
have a more of a neuro
symbolic language uh
that i'm working with to
essentially almost
take the documentation
and turn it into more of
a proof-based programming
so where you have
gold standard
documentation that's been
validated even to the
point of mathematical
proof if you can and then
from there essentially
software design
becomes create the gold
standard document and
it's essentially put
the lego pieces together
or and and with the my
mental images rather
than building the
lego which is the code
you're actually just
creating the instruction
manual that comes with
the box of lego if
you can create the
instruction box with all
the lego pieces and you
know they fit together
perfectly then that
documentation now
becomes gold standard or
proof based documentation
and to go from that
to actually building
the lego set you can
give to any child
that's between the ages
of 8 and 80 and they
can actually build it
so that that's my long
-term vision um so where
i'm focusing now and
what i'll go through
is one thing that i
find for documentation
is it is the key if
you're doing agentic
engineering everything
else is you create the
documentation everything
else is correcting
mistakes or creating
the better agents to
follow the documentation
but in my view I spend
between 50 sometimes
70 percent of the time
when I create stuff
creating the documentation
and then if I have
good documentation it
makes it really easy
to to go through to
actually create any
kind of software tool so
some call it the boring
stuff i call it the
the money maker because
it's the stuff that
takes all all your
time and if you mess
up on the documentation
there's absolutely no
chance you can actually
vibe code your way
into making something
good you have to
essentially backtrack hit
the redo button on on
get commits a whole bunch
of times and start
from scratch or you
have to do refactoring
which i can't stand
refactoring because it's
a pain in the butt for
me so i'm i'm going
to go through here i
haven't played around
with um cli agents or
agents that are um
natural language based for
a little while so i
might struggle through
here i've been working
with uh uh this the
more symbolic agents
but i'm going going go
go through and show
how i how i create uh
documentation this is
the first one that will
that I've done.
So just to bring some
context, when I go
through for Golden
Docs, I've identified
really, as much as
you might want to have
50 or 100 documents,
and you can see my
stuff gets messy, I
have to clean it up.
I really found you
only need three. And
these are the three
that I'm focusing on.
If your projects are
a little bit more
complex, you may have
a couple of others. But
what i find is these
three are the the main
ones so the first one
is a philosophy document
philosophy and
architecture i like to
use the i like to use
metaphors and analogies
so this is the soul
so this is the whole
reason of being so
why why are you even
creating the software
uh this is a i found a
very abstract and i
just kind of went down a
couple of different
rabbit holes and they
all came to the same
place but the soul or
that constitution
whatever term you want to
have I haven't really
seen it very often,
but it really, really
does help, especially
if you're doing agentic
-based programming.
And just as a slight
tangent, when you're
doing this, I actually
now include the
sole in all of my agents.
And what I'm finding
is near 100% needle
and haystack retrieval
when I have sole,
that they don't drift.
Because that's one
of my problems with
using very symbolic
languages is you get
drift because Because
it's not natural for
an LLM to follow a
symbolic language. The
process is absolutely,
the process of
symbolic languages is
absolutely how LLMs
follow. And they're
naturally, with very
little hints, they
follow a natural process.
But the actual syntax,
they forget. Where
if you add a soul
and the purpose, I'm
finding that the
drift is very minimal.
You'll still have it,
but it's very minimal.
So the first document,
and this is the
one that I want to
create today, is the
philosophy, or I like
to call the soul.
The second one is
SAD or specifications
document. There's
other terms that you
use out there, but I
look at it, it's the
technical specifications
in your design.
So it's kind of,
you've got the reason
why you're in being,
and then this is the
blueprint of what
you actually create.
Some people, a lot
of people actually
break this out into
multiple documents,
5, 10, 15 different
documents that
all have different
components of this.
The way that I program
is I like small because
my brain can
understand small. I can
understand three major
documents. I can't
understand 20. And I
generally, when I do agentic
coding, I only do
things that I know how
to code myself. And
it's just I get the
agents to do my work
for me. And the last one
that I find is the
implementation plan. So
it's not the detailed
step-by-step phases.
That's when you're
actually implementing,
but to have your plan
of what steps are you
doing when, how are you
doing it, how do you
monitor, what are you
going through. so all
really what this is
is the master master
implementation how are
you actually doing it so
quick summary i'll go
a little bit faster
but this this is the
the core so it's why
are you doing something
what are you doing
and then how are you
doing it all these
other documents is
ad hoc as needed
generally i do do them
based on a feature set
or when i'm creating
github epics or something
through my agents,
these get done on
the fly or for that
specific feature for
that specific module.
But sometimes I find
you might need these
other documents like
your data architecture,
API, endpoints,
any kind of integration
protocols. So this
would be more your API
quality and validation
frameworks. And you
have others that are
ad hoc based on the
client needs so this is
this is the golden
docs that i want to use
and uh i've also i
just i was just playing
around just before
the call um for this
first one that i want
to have which is soul i
know i'm breaking the
rule of cloud code of
more than 500 lines
but um it seems seems
oh actually i didn't
break it it's only 250
lines but this is my
my first attempt on
what what the first
pillar is the reason why
you're going through
so to start i just um
started up cloud code
uh dangerously skipped
permissions and then
now i'm just going to
what i like to call
uh ground information
and uh as jed jed
mentions the 500
lines might have
been something that
was uh state-of
-the-art back in the
day and it's it's
now more of a
guide a guideline
rather than a rule
so i'm going through
usually when i start
a new session like
i just started now
just start start
applaud you
do the installation
process
dangerously skip
permissions because i don't
like to click yes yes
yes all the time and
then i i typically start
by grounding i always
like to go through
um i haven't really
touched this for a while
but i i like to update
my clod md file so
this is your master
master file with the
master instructions it
essentially tells me
tells clod everything that
it needs to know within
this dot clod file
i leveraged a lot of
um what what roof did
in clod flow uh for
this it's just i've i've
tailored it to my own
coding style um so
quickly what what i've
done is i've created my
own more more elaborate
or or bigger picture
agents and i'll show
that in just a second
and uh i i did
leverage a couple
other sections
what i'm working on
today is the the
golden documents here
so i'm going to
go through and go
and go through my
agents and really
just execute
something here so um
just a quick one
brad um what changes
did you make to
cloud.md in this
particular case like
what would you what
would be the things
that you look for
in the out of the
box cloud.md file
uh yeah take a look
what i normally do is i
i actually just ground
i i make a copy of
the the original um
so whatever whatever i
found to start with
um usually make a copy
then i then i do grounding
so i say go through
research my dot clod
file to understand
what's going on a lot
of the time i have
specific documents and
guides such as in here
i have a developer
cheat sheet so this this
provides all the all
the more specialized
things that i do what
how i want to be done
so i first say send
the agents to identify
and research what's
in this file to get it
into the context memory
and then i say based
on based on the
structure of the existing
backup copy of clod
update with with my
information now i know
jed and other people
are more sophisticated
so they might have
better comments that's
just the way I do it.
So it looks like yeah
Jed uses personas
which I love personas
and then there's
there's other other
repos but that's
the way I do it
as I just I do
grounding first and
then say update update
cloud yourself based
on these files.
Brad it's just part
of your bar forge repo
uh yeah this is just
my repo it's just my
working working version
right now uh i'm i i
just have to finish a
couple of courses and and
i'll be taking all
the agents that i have
and open sourcing them
i just haven't got
around to it um so the
bar bar forge is is just
my working repo it's
really messy so it's
not something that i
would share with people
So create a swarm
of three agents
running in parallel
to evaluate.
I'm
just going to
say which file.
Just type and then
I can explain.
So what I did was create
a swarm of three agents.
I forgot to tell it,
but hopefully through
the CloudMD, it knows
to go through my agents
to identify which ones
are going to analyze
and then what I'm
saying is take a look
at this folder there's
only two documents
what the main thing is
to update the one that
I have for pillar
one which is the sole
document so it's going
through let's see which
agents are are going
through I don't see
them running in parallel
here but hopefully
they will soon so
what is pulling is my
favorite agent which is
my brutal honest agent
uh and well while it's
going through this
is this is what i'll
be open sourcing this
one i actually did
open source uh i can
provide a link um but
this this i like to give
personas to my agents
again for grounding
uh that if you ground
and give it an idea
it actually seems
to carry all the way
through um it knows
the personality and the
purpose or again why
things need to be done
so in this case the
one main agent that's
being called that i
can see is the brutal
honest agent so this
is one that is is going
through and it you're
giving it its tasks
giving it the constraints
and the persona
is dr house um it's
just a fun name easy
for me to remember and
it goes through and
knows okay don't don't
believe any false
claims never put false
claims in there anything
that you do make sure
you validate and i
think it says who its
friends are so these
these are just all
all different criteria
on how you go through
so get the evidence
claim the test
analysis how to test
and then this
is the key one
the documentation
versus reality
and this is an older
version but you can
write this in pure prose
you don't have to write
it in code or anything
like that and then
it then one tip that i
found that for all my
teaching classes that
i always always always
do is create a rubric
so in this case rather
than just saying yeah
it's good because
you know a clod especially
lies and if you've
ever worked with the
biggest the biggest
one that thinks it does
better than it should
is google google pro
it will always say that
you got an a a plus
or whatever factor so
if you're asking any ai
especially if something's
safety memory i'm
finding you know what
it'll always give you
the mum effect where
where something's not
as good as it should
be but mum will always
say hey you know what
you're doing well keep
going I'm encouraging
you if you create
something called it like
a rubric if you remember
back in elementary
school or if your
kids are in elementary
school they get rubrics
explicitly say this is
here's the different
categories and here's
a score to use so I find
this rubric approach
really helps with
grounding and making sure
rubrics are still a
thing Jed I use them
all the time every one
of the classes that I
teach it's been very
long since i was that
old yeah well i'm old
enough that we actually
didn't use rubrics when
i went to school it's
a it's a term that i
learned from my kids
but if but if you have
a rubric it has points
on what what it needs
and depending on
the agent that you're
doing the more complex
you can have for the
rubric so rather than
just scoring itself
it's going through and
this is taking forever
i don't know why it's
um taking so long but
you go through and it
should be should be
bringing his friends so
that so you got the
brutal honest which is
the assessor and then
i i only have a few
other agents if i need
to create an agent um
i have i have this
one which actually it
gives instructions on
how to create an agent
so it goes through
i think this one
is called professor
x from from x
-men so that's the
soul or the reason
why and then you go
through and where's
my guides for
the gold standard
so it goes goes through
you have an agent
creator and then when
i want to create a
new agent it goes
goes through this i've
evaluated it through
dr house he validated
it cli only took
me a whole bunch of
iterations but i again
like to spend a lot of
time on documentation
making sure that I
get documentation right
it still lies it's
not 95 percent out
of 100 but you know
what it's better than
my first approach in
all reality when I
manually went through
I would score maybe a
20 percent and without
the doctor house
it was saying yeah
this is production
ready and so it's like
plot just lies all
the time so I like to
iterate and go through
this rubric process.
So this, this, this
really gives tasks.
This one was a little
bit focused when I
wrote the CLI, a little
bit code, code heavy
for Python, but I do
find that cloud code
and a lot of the
other ones do like to
have code. They understand
code quite well.
So if I ever want to
create a new agent
that that's how i
do it is i i create
my gold standard
agent which i consider
perfect heavily
manually authored to
make sure human in
the loop is there so
everything that's on
there i understand
and i agree to
once i have a gold
standard once i have
a gold standard agent
then then the next
step is now create a
template so i want to
create a template on
here's how to create
other gold standard again
i do heavy heavy human
in the loop at that
stage as well i i now
you and then from there
once i have one as a
template one template
and one that's already
been done now it
makes it easy that i
can just have the agents
create themselves so
for time to create
these agents took me
about five hours uh to
create the first agent
about two hours to
create a template and
then the other 20 took
me about 15 minutes
and and they created
themselves and the same
thing when i used the
neurosymbolic agents
uh same same kind of
process but now i have
existing agents that
are creating other
ones so you get what's
called a flywheel effect
that the next time
through rather than
spending five hours to
create that gold standard
it took me an hour
to do and then to create
all the neurosymbolic
language agents
really it was a matter
of click a button and
uh while claude would
would take its time
for some reason it's
not going in parallel
here um that's why
it's taking taking a
little bit of time is that
gold standard agents
open source brad i
i will provide it yeah
uh michael right now
the only one i have
on a repo is the the
doctor house just uh
because it was one that
i presented it's almost
like a month ago but
these other ones
these are the ones and
i'm doing i just i just
have a little bit of
day job stuff to
do in the next
couple of days and
then I'm getting back
and I'll be posting
all of them.
So it says it's doing
in parallel, but I
don't actually see it
running in parallel.
If I was doing this not
live with the
demo guides,
I would cancel
and restart.
But in this case, I'm
just going to hope
it works. In terms of
running in parallel,
I find I have to
explicitly tell it to
launch multiple sub
-regions simultaneously.
Cloud code appears
to be resisting
multiple agents using
batch tool. I think
this is an attempt by
Anthropic speculating.
It's an attempt
by Anthropic to
reduce token consumption
on the max times.
That makes a lot of
sense because this exact
prompt is what I've
used a hundred other
times and I just haven't
used it as much. just
saying spawn three agents
in parallel sometimes
i say batch agents
but it goes through
so uh i can i can while
i go through i can
just show for some of
the other agents what i
have so i have um i
creep trying to find the
uh the directory i do
have these different
agents so they're all
special specialized
and they my my finding
was if you have a gold
standard document on
how to create agents
it makes it really easy
for these agents to
create sub-agents on
the fly so if you have
something that is a
front-end specialist so
here's my front-end
expert i guess it's called
jarvis it goes goes
through it's grounded
uh core mission so it
has set kind of different
tones which actually
might seem flaky but
it actually does work
if you if you ground
it and then talking
about what the what what
it actually does but
what i find is as you
go through here's all
the different patterns
that it would check
to make sure it's okay
how to save stuff into
memory the performance
matrix and then some
somewhere down the
line i have how to
create its own sub-agents
so um my approach is
you have these these
i call them gold
standard agents and then
they actually call
and create their own
agents on the fly based
on the gold standard
documents so rather
than me having 100
or 400 or whatever
number of agents i keep
to these 20 and then
if they need to they'll
spawn their own sub
agents on the fly so
lesson learned when i
present i double check
that cloud is not
***** and going through
brad did you create
the initial agent by
hand or you the gold
gold standard agent
um by hand is a
relative term uh yeah
i i said create
one based on verbal
diarrhea to be honest
i was like this these
are these are things
that i want to see
so the way that
i i i did it i
I said here's here's
what I want and then I
just iterate through I
once I have one agent
in the past one agent
was good enough that
it could help me create
something and then
once I had a couple
of agents even in
horrible format those
agents actually provided
the better the better
code and then once I
have better code then
it's kind of a recursive
process I had the
agents go through and
look at themselves and
improve themselves.
Another tip is if you ask
Claude to create
shortcuts,
I have one that
when I type in
CC, it means Claude code,
dangerously skip
permissions. Do
you have any
other tips here,
Jed, to make sure
it runs in parallel?
That using batch
tool doesn't work?
Batch tool sometimes
works, sometimes
doesn't. The first
thing I do is I don't
try to edit the
prompt in that field.
because strolling
back and forth without
being able to click
to the specific token
or character I need
to change is a pain.
So I usually open
an empty file or
a blank file into
which I'll write
and edit the prompt
and then copy
and paste the prompt
into plot code.
So the biggest
thing here that I'm
seeing is spawn
agents in parallel
simultaneously so
they run concurrently
using the available
NCP spot. You know
what? Let me just
type that all in.
why would you not just
um have a file and
have it have numbers
in it so you add so
you have a list of
everything you you
have told it and then
just tell it to um
execute the fifth line
or the sixth line or
the seventh line so
that you've got a
record and if you need
to repeat the whole
process you is a file
that you can check
in yeah yes um so i
find for for memory
systems um two different
things one one is
memory like you said
it's perfect for most
of the time uh so
it'll remember what
you're doing i do
have i do have like um
like we've had the
full full memory system
uh but that's it
remembering things i'm
thinking more like
rather than in the
interaction cli typing
the instruction there
in your instruction
you just say refer
to file yeah line five
yeah that yeah that
yeah so you saw i just
copy copied the path
and actually sorry i
wasn't watching where
you copied the where
you copied the plan oh
uh so you go in here
if i want to include
uh say this document
i just uh go to copy
path yeah but i'm saying
um okay so show me
again what you so i
understand you do that
but you're still
writing the instruction
in the command line
right yeah yeah whereas
i was saying don't
put the instruction in
the command line only
the only thing to
write in the command line
say execute the fifth
line of my oh if
you're if you have the
full plan i don't i'm
creating the plan right
now so i'm create i'm
so i'm yeah if you
have a plan so if you're
doing an implementation
plan uh the way
that i do coding is
um i have my agents
they actually um i have
a github agent i should
have a github agent
uh implementation
plan agent somewhere.
Oh, Epic Planner.
So Gandalf, I didn't
create all this stuff,
but what this agent
does is it gives it
some information, but
the way that I do when
I'm doing implementation
is read through
everything and actually
create a GitHub Epic
or GitHub issue. So
it's connecting through
GitHub CLI to actually
go through. I have
a proper gold standard
on how to create an
issue or an epic.
And it'll go through,
analyze the instructions
and post it onto GitHub
as step one. And then
step two is I use
a separate swarm of
agents to go and actually
solve the feature
set or the issue you
have on GitHub. So I
do a two step process.
I just for me, I can't
click go and have
have cloud code run
for an hour by itself.
It always messes up
on me. So I have these
stop breaks where you
have human in the loop
and I find the GitHub
one is very good.
Going back to the
memory and remembering
what you have. So
that's if you do
the step. I find the
memory works except
for if you want to
validate something.
If Claude or any other
system has written
the test, I find it
very difficult. It
can't actually correct
it and run its own
test. It will lie to
you and or not lie, but
it thinks it ran the
test where a lot of
the times it hasn't.
So some of the tips
find is open up a
new terminal and when
you want to run tests
run them separately.
I think Jed and
others use MCP. I use
GitHub to be able to
have it as a separate
thing so it's not in
memory. So when it's
evaluating a test
it's not looking back
on something that
is already written.
And so this tip
that Jed had
got the agents
to run in Swarm.
Yeah, so you
use the CLI for
GitHub as well,
not the MCP too?
Yeah, the CLI is
well established. And
most importantly,
when you put the wrong
command, it instructs
you to use help or
offers solutions, which
the LLM is usually
able to follow off
of versus the MCP,
which, in my experience,
does not do that.
So there's some
questions about how I
created. So what I did
was to create the agent
is I had really the
soul, so the reason
of being for a brutal,
honest assessor.
So I had that
foundation, very high
level. This is
what I want to do
is create a
foundational level
assessment. So I
created this one first.
I went through, asked
Claude to, based on
this, based on the
requirements of Claude
code, get grounded.
So understand what my
purpose and the reason
why I want to have
an agent, and also what
is the capabilities
of Claude code,
including any kind of
memory systems, any
kind of hooks, any
kind of guides, MCP,
but get the grounding.
Then from there,
I went back and
forth and did
testing. I said, okay,
based on this,
create an agent.
So I created one that
wasn't very good, but
you know what? It was
better than no agent.
Step two was, based on
this not very good agent,
create a template for
all the other agents.
So that's where I
created the template.
I think it's in here.
gold standard agents.
So I created a template
for all other agents.
Step three, so this
was based on the
one agent that I
liked, which you can
see the Dr. House
principle, it created
all the other
ones. So here's all
things that you
should be including.
The next step that I
did to create all of
them is really now you're
starting to get into
agents that can
create agents that can
create agents is now
that I have one one good
one I have the gold
standard here's the
agent creator was the
third one that third file
I created which is
your professor x and
you're based on this
gold standard you can
now create other agents
so that that's the
way that I created all
the different agents
and then once you have
it done once now I have
a rubric scoring
mechanism I just go
through recursively
until each agent was at a
standard that I understood
as a human and also
uh was good enough
and then my last step
before i went into
what i call production
but it's just my own
use is making sure that
um these agents actually
worked so if i had
if i had a ****** file
run it through say
these agents swarm create
a create a scorecard
of it if i know i
already knew what the
errors were if it came
back with the same
errors you know what
that was good enough test
for me, I didn't have
to go any further.
So this presentation
today was supposed to
be all about showing
the code and for some
reason my cloud's just
not liking me today.
This is really helpful.
Brad, there was
a question on
the chat from, I
think, Dimitri,
who asked about
the cloud code
templates, right?
So whether did you
create these
agents by yourself
without using cloud
code templates.
So I hadn't come
across this before, so
I'm having a look.
So obviously this
website has a load of
agents and templates.
Did you, you know?
Oh, that's slick.
Thanks for bringing that
up. I haven't actually
looked at this.
I'll check it out.
Have you used it?
How do you find
the templates?
Dimitri?
Yes, I found
it very useful.
because for me, it
was easier to, you
know, find the
template for my task
and adapt it a bit
for my requirements.
Oh, that's cool.
Instead of creating
it from zero.
Yeah.
I'm definitely going
to check that out.
Thanks, Dimitri. I
had a look at one
of them. Like, this
seems to be, like,
this is what you are
showing, but it's
very detailed, lots
of information.
Like, I was looking
at the front-end
developer in these
templates. They are very
high level. So I'm
just wondering, like,
even if you have
something as a starter,
how would you go about
and probably get it
to a state where you
have been, you have?
So I'll give you a
link on the chat just
to, you can bring it
up on your window.
But if you, for example,
go open this link.
The front end developer?
Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah.
Then if you then go
down and click on
the markdown, so at
the bottom of the
screen, there is a
component code section.
Yeah, 28 lines of
code. Yeah, it's very,
I think, high level,
right? So if, for
example, someone were
to just start with
this, how would they
go about and get it
to probably the state
that you are in?
um so yeah this is
this is now an opinion
of mine i haven't
verified it it
works for me is um
that this the smaller
agents um just are
not the way that i
code um i i like
dealing with only 20
again ones that i can
understand so every
every agent i fully
understand what
a security expert would
do a front-end developer
agent would do so
i i it's just my my
brain can only handle so
many so i i personally
like to have longer
agents that are very
explicit on what you do
um so if the way that
i would do is i i just
brainstorm what what
is needed for for an
agent this is a good
template um to do it's
just my my style i
like to have a lot more
information maybe that's
why it's taking so
long here but i find
if i have if i have one
such as my front end
expert here it's quite
a bit more detailed
so jarvis goes through
and it's just says all
the different specializations
it has uh this
i just had um clod
clod create what the
specializations were but
i just brainstorm and
once for me it was more
of a snowball effect
once i have one, then
it made it easier to
do more and more. So
I find for my style of
coding, I like to be
explicit, such as, oh,
here, this is where
it's explicit. So rather
than just creating
agents on the fly, in
this case, it's saying,
here, this is, you're
creating an analyzer,
an optimizer, an
accessibility guardian.
So what this agent would
do is rather than needing
these smaller agents
to be saved it creates
them on the fly so
it's not a lot of code
but it it essentially
will create it create
the philosophy about
the same um i would
go through so if i was
to create from scratch
again this is the best
way to do it you have
a template like this
and then i like to say
this is the way that
i code these are things
that i look for uh
so a front end i only
use i really only use
certain programs. Backend,
I only use certain
things. So as much as
I love Laravel, I'm
not going to put Laravel
or PHP in a backend
development agent
because I don't use that
anymore. I love it,
wish I could use it, but
it's not something that
I use anymore. So to
create the agents, I
just keep going through
iteratively back and
forth. And then when
you do have one or two
that look good, you
just have them improve
themselves. So to create
the CLI agents, I had
them go through in
some cases they recursively
improve themselves
once sometimes it
took five or six times
to get it to a state
and then i i'm a big
human in the loop fan uh
for this kind of stuff
because i'm focusing
on documentation so
that that's the way
that i create the agents
and the good thing
is once i had
those then i can
create more of
my uh special
specialty agents
uh so when we go
through um okay this
it's not really
updated it's using it's
not using the
neural symbolic here
how would you know
if it was uh because
yeah neural symbolic
is all it's all
weird symbols and
and you do that just
so it reduces the
number of tokens oh
uh i'm working on oh
this okay here yeah this
this is my
neurosymbolic so it's my
neurosymbolic is actually
made for um ai it's not
made for it's human
readable to a point if
you know what you're
talking about it's kind
of like if you program
it's like writing in
in the language c or
even python python's
not english so yeah um
it's a hybrid between
and this this is one
where I'm really really
focusing a lot of my
research right now is
this neurosymbolic to
become an abstraction
layer between human
understanding and machine
learning so it follows
the machine processes
and it's and when I
write documentation
it's explicitly written
for AI and it's written
to include proof-based
coding it's included
for the personas to
include all the stuff
for agent coordination
it so it's more i just
found the symbolic is
um one token saving
but it's more uh reducing
ambiguity i can't
get any language to
yeah how i would have
said it the second time
i symbolic the what
confused me was when you
called it neuro symbolic
like oh is that
something different it's
like no it's a symbolic
language okay that's
yeah no it's just to
make me sound smart.
No, it's just a
symbolic language that I
just found for, again,
my way of coding,
this is the way that
I'm creating documents.
So I probably have
the worst demo ever
created, because for
some reason I can't get
Cloud to actually
create anything for me.
So also, Brad,
you are using
Cloud only here,
right? Cloud Code,
not Cloud Flow
at the moment.
So I took Cloud
Code as the base,
and then I took
the learnings from
what Roof created
in Cloud Flow
and adapted it
for my own style.
So just I like the
longer agents for, For
and then because I'm
a documentation first
person, I like a
process where it creates
the document. So there's
a human in the loop
to review documents
before I go into the
next step. So rather
than I'm not someone
that can I can't do
what what Roof or Jed or
Ocean do where you
click a button and Cloud
Code will run for for
an hour. Except for
today, I'm one where,
you know, I go through
and create an epic
and it has one task.
And then I like to
review it to make sure
and then go from an
Epic to implement your
Epic.
So I've taken a lot
of the learnings from
what Claude-flow does,
but I've adapted it
to myself. So I've
created my own agents.
Memory system is fairly
similar to what Roof did.
One of the big things
that I'm looking at is
templates. So similar
to what Dimitri was
talking about, where
rather than creating
something from scratch i
have this gold standard
in this case like a
agent template which
is supposed to be
gold standard and to
create new agents you
just review the template
and you're just
essentially changing the
wording so rather and
i'm focusing on that that
style of coding so
rather than creating
even say a website i'm
not saying create create
a chatbot from scratch
i'm saying here's
here's the here's the
different components
that are already what i
consider gold standard
on being able to
connect to an llm here's
another one how to
create the component
for the prompt area so
here's all the different
templates that i
know are are perfect
take the template rather
than starting from
scratch just modify
the template so that's
more my my coding style
which is again quite
different than a lot of
people in the community
but it's just the
way that works for me
i would assume that
there are a bunch of
people who would prefer
to operate the same
way as you do and
therefore a function of
the foundation might
be to help you find
those other people so
that progressively you
know you can build up
that approach between
you so it's not you
know you're benefiting
from the community
yeah and uh yeah i do
i do quite a bit of
teaching i'm creating
a course right now on
documentation first
for uh programmers so
it's just my style is
always i like to push
the boundaries for
myself but i always
try and um work through
something to what
makes sense and and
typically if i i merge
what i really want to
do the ambitious side
and how i would explain
it as a teacher
somewhere in the middle
is actually the best
practice is is what i
found so that's that's
where even creating
these documents which
was supposed to be
we're supposed to create
all three documents
today and can't even
get one working but
that's where i find
this is like this is
your school of thought
and i think it's great
yeah and you know
you've pretty much said
that ruth has a different
school of thought
and i'm i'm sure
that there's you know
markedly a third because
as soon as this yeah
there's often end so
what i'm really saying
is you know maybe we
can find those little
sub conveniences
that want to work on
the schools of thought
yeah yeah i'm i'm yeah
i'm i admittedly I'm
not as advanced as
Rue or Jett and others.
I'm a straightforward,
I've done 25 years of
coding. I'm finishing
off masters and
teaching it. I have a
certain way and I'm
old enough that I can't
really change. I
have to know what the
agents are doing. I
can't just blindly trust.
Yeah, that's
great. That's
just what I thought.
It's cool.
So it's the way I do
it. And this is, so
this is my technique
where we're getting to
the end, but um just in
um i guess big picture
the way that i do it
is documentation i
don't like 20 docs i
like three which is your
philosophy which i
like to call soul i
find the grounding is
incredible if you include
that and you can
get as theatrical or
false claims as you want
it actually does help
and then um um the
next one is so that's
your why then you get
into your traditional
what what you want
to do which is your
technical and specs and
then your how which is
am I in the right
thing oh I'm
in the wrong one
so why how or
why what and how
and very rarely
do I I'll have research
documents but very
rarely do I want the
code to go through
these again I'm working
on symbolic languages
so as much as my
agents are very long
here like 800 800 lines
of code when i convert
it into symbolic
language still working
on it now it gets down
to about 200 or 300
lines so it's pretty
condensed and my style
is a lot of very
precise and descriptive
agents again it's just
a different way of
coding it's the way
that i know how to do
and it just works for
me i encourage you
to look at others you
have your pillar one
document and this
initial research document
right um but you talk
about three um core
documents in your
initial research document
yeah the output that
you're generating
was it to create the
other two pillars or
well the first thing
i was doing is i just
wanted to go through and
improve this document
it's this was my first
stab of doing this
right before the call
um what i created
this document just before
the call and everything
worked perfectly
but demo gods didn't
didn't agree with me
uh and what i wanted to
do was it's good but
it's not great so
rather than just having
it it good i wanted to
go through and have
the agents improve on
this to get it to a
gold standard and the
reason why is this is
in my opinion the the
reason why the
constitution the soul is by
far the most important
document that i need
so i need this to be 100
gold standard whatever
terminology theatrical
term you want to
use i need it to be
there and that's what i
we're supposed to do
in the call is upgrade
this to gold standard
and then the the what
and the how i see you're
doing the refinement
of pillar one right
now and then you
would move on to the
second two yeah i'm i'm
a do once in a ******
way do a second or
third time recursively
until it's a great way
cool hey brad are
you are you tweaking
your cloud.md yourself
or are you just letting
it naturally
organically happen yeah
i just uh i take every
tip that rube and
the rest of you guys
have for how to improve
cloud md and i i
just put a document
there saying here's
tips here's here's the
here's what i have
in my agent set as
grounding and then say
have at it and create
update the cloud code
by yourself kind of
thing and then i i do
human in the loop i
double check to make
sure the links all
work but i find that
works for me so the
cloud code ends up being
fairly straightforward
it's basic instructions
with um very
prescriptive that if
you need to use agents
this is the folder
and here's the exact
agents to use but it
won't i find it works
generally fast that
it'll go it won't
actually read those
files unless you need to
and then are you are you
are you like spinning
up swarms or are you
just doing everything
sort of just just
serially uh usually um
in my agents they um
the the soul of it is
they know um how big
of a swarm size and and
which ones to do for
which tasks um so if i
wanted a normal task is
three typically three
one is doing research
one is doing validation
one is actually doing
the work and then
for more complicated or
or brainstorming it'll
it'll go up to say
seven different agents
for different things
that are completely
different and that that's
what that's where my
style is very few agents
that are very clear
boundaries that it's
very rare that you would
ever have a back-end
agent interfering with
a front-end agent
because they're they're
so different and and
that that's one of the
reasons why i kept very
few agents is because
when i have swarms
they don't they don't
copy each other and i
don't get those race
rate race conditions or
conflicts right right
and then you said that
you you developed your
own memory system so
can you talk a little
bit about that uh that
one i just took what
um i just kept with
what what roof what roof
did and just adapted
it for myself so i i
just said um add different
fields when you've
learned something so
when you've learned
something and then i had
another one that says
when we've identified
and i confirm that
it's gold standard um
make sure you put it in
memory so you only look
up the gold standard
fields um rather than
looking through my
garbage because i i do
so much iteration uh
that that i found memory
sometimes you don't
want to pollute your
memory with your garbage
yeah so it's like i get
it yeah so it's like
yeah you know what
when you want something
good go through yeah
um yeah and then yeah
dimitri mentioned
another thing um prd um i
just i i a lot of
clients use prds and
implementation plans
and different
different documents
i find for me those
three documents i
can create anything from
them so if i have if
i have to make something
client friendly uh
here's the documents i
have i just i can put
it literally into
cloud cloud desktop or
even chat gpt here's
the three documents i
want and then i just i
don't even use swarms or
anything in that i just
manually gpt it and
say you know what
take from these three
documents turn it into
the client wants a prd
the client wants whatever
a timetable and it
just takes takes that
and it's easy to do
i'm coding i'll do it
with cloud code yeah and
that's a you know
there's a lot of desktop
tools right that you
can use to develop
prds i'm a product
strategy product
management guy myself
And I spent a lot
of time figuring,
watching all the
developments in the,
what I call the first
mile, which is the
PM crafting a spec.
And so there's so
many tools. You
can use Claude
Code, Claude Flow,
you know,
Nexus. You can use all
those tools to generate
a parity. Or you can
actually use, you
know, Perplexity and
OpenAI and all the other
tools just on the
desktop and web services.
And I don't know if
you've been following,
but there's a new
tool that GitHub just
released and it's focused
around spec-driven
development. And their
tool is the spec kit,
right? And that's, you
know, we talk a lot
here about test-driven
development. Well,
now finally, people
have started saying,
yeah, the POD, the
spec is really the gold
standard thing that
you should be spending
all your time on at
the beginning before
you write a line of
code. So now there's
spec kit, right? And
spec, it's all about spec
-driven development
and getting your PRD
right, getting your
spec right, and having
everything mapped back
to the spec and the
PRD as you process
and as you build out.
And the PRD is the
thing. Spec is the
actual thing that
you're really
curating on and that
drives everything.
Oh, that's awesome.
Yeah.
That's exactly what
my capstone project
is. i'm trying to
do this and um well
i'll have to read
through this because
this might i might have
to change my project
now i was just two
days ago i think
it just came out two
days ago summarize
david are you a
practitioner respect it uh
no you know i'm i'm
reading as much as i can
of it in the last 18
hours and i i really
like it because this
is the methodology that
as a as a lifelong product
manager i i believe
in the value of a
prd right and and i
believe that something
like this was i had a
shot at building something
similar to this but
i think this is definitely
the way to go or
very valuable in the
world of agentic ai and
using using agentic
ai to build products
how did you get around
the need to pivot or
adapt mid-flight in
the after the spec is
driven or built you mean
as it starts building
it's using the speak
as your according to
the article on the
blog post when github
announced it expects that
you know the complete
destination the final
picture it doesn't appear
to leave room for
course correction or
adapting to problems
mid-flight and that's
been my experience
actually using it so i'm
curious how you course
correct without having
to start over so i
actually for me personally
i'm a super technical
product manager i can
write code myself hand
write code like brand
i i've been writing
code since i was 12,
but I'm a product
manager. And what I
do is when I define
a product and I
actually do a ton of
research around the
architecture and
the infrastructure.
And so I actually,
I'm very brutal in my
spec and I say, I've
done all this research
and this is how I want
you to do it. I don't
leave a lot of leeway
to the system to
make too many big,
broad, sweeping changes.
I don't particularly
like that because it
gets you in the
situation where halfway
through your build out,
the system diverges
off, and now you have
to course correct.
And course corrections
basically result
in, if you do that,
it results in a
completely new spec
being built that means
you've got to go back
and figure out how
different and how
much you've diverged
from the original.
And either you're
old school and you
want to control that
or you're modern and
you say, just go for
it. And however
you're diverging off,
just accept it. So
it comes down to that
methodology. Either
you live by the sword,
you die by the sword,
man you accept it and
you let it go or you
say no and you go back
and you rework the
spec man that's a lot
of manual product um
product management work
to figure it out there's
no like is to the
special you're leaning
on the specifications
and you're thinking
you're saying that
the specifications are
right and those are
the guardrails yes
it also feels very
waterfallish because you
know because if they're
as what jed said if
they're how do you what
happens if you need
to course correct make
any changes and
you're leaning on the
gospel of that specification
then how so what
i so what i tend to
do like i said i do a
lot of research up
front like for example,
say there's a key value
data store and there's
like three different
key value stores that
it's going to use.
And I'll do all that
research up front. And
then when the build
process comes to this
phase, it'll say, yeah, I
want to use this
alternative key value store
that your research
never covered. I don't
want to get into that
situation, right? I want
to know that I did
enough really good
research to know which
was the best key value
store, which was the
highest performing one,
the lowest memory
resource, the most global.
I want to know, I want
to do that research
up front. It takes
no time. Hypothetical
situation, David. In the
course of your research,
a key value store,
let's say SQLite versus
Redis versus PG Vector,
some other technology,
you settle on one.
you realize in the
course of building the
perform the realized
performance does not
match the spec performance
then what so then i
like i guess i'll i'll
take the the information
i get back right
and i'll be like ****
i missed something i
absolutely missed this
and i'll then you make
a decision like okay
um yes let's go with
that and let's rewrite
the spec but you like
Brad said, you've got
to have the human in
the loop. The product
manager is the decision
making point. Either
you be the person, you
be the decision making
point, or you let the
system just, you let
the agentic system
just make the decision
for you and let it go.
For me personally,
I like to, I don't
like to make every
decision, but I like
to try to figure
out what the big
impactful ones are
before I get started.
Because there's so many
decisions that have
to be made would that
then be b2 maybe yeah
yeah so i i have this
rule and it's a kind
of a weird rule but for
me it works i end up
doing like when i get
to version 12 of my
prd i know that i've
done enough work and i
know that i've really
my spec is mature before
version 12 and it's
just a weird number
that for me over the
last two decades if i
get to version 12 i
know i'm good right but
anything before version
12 uh is it's kind of
fair game and i wasn't
talking about just
the spec i was also
mentioning what jet talked
about v2 meaning of
the architecture so if
you need to change yeah
yes yeah no i don't
like to see very big
changes in my architecture
once i commit to
the build jump in
really quick guys and
just uh uh just i just
because the demo gods
finally came through
after the fact um of
course after probably the
recording ended and
all this kind of stuff
but yeah i went went
through just from that
that prompt uh again
i don't believe any of
this. It's even though
I have my brutal,
brutal assessor, I
don't believe this until
like, like David, I need
to put human eyeballs
on this to actually
verify. But you can see
it initially said that
the first wave was
what I normally get,
which is not very good.
31 out of 100. Don't
know what that means.
There is a rubric to
say, and then it, I think
it overestimated,
but it said, you know
what it went from 31
to 95 based on all the
gold standards that i have
in this case sometimes
actually if i provide
enough documentation
the right documentation
it's it's able to
do it and then this
this is where we're
talking about uh for for
the artifacts for the
memory memory system it
created um uh different
parts of the memory
and very quickly this
is this is what the
um the document came
out to uh i haven't
gone through it but it's
been analyzed saying
what's been done here's
the common names and
it's really just saying
that these are the
different systems which
which you need so um
what is actually required
then from this i would
i would actually go
through uh i'm not
sure if this even works
and i don't know
if it worked but oh
here this makes more
sense the others
were just validations
for being able
to do something but
this is more how
do you actually
create the document
um so just wanted to
show that something did
work in this in this
thing and um if i'd
like to talk to david
and a few others in the
group because i'm looking
at rather than just
having here's the
spec document it's how
do you create the
lego pieces for a spec
document so if you do
have to change on the fly
it's a matter of
taking out a lego piece
putting in a new lego
piece and making sure
nothing else breaks so how
do you have more before
going down that
particular rabbit hole my
understanding after
having a deeper researcher
go through the purpose
of having these
specs and PRDs is the
cost of writing code
was tremendous. All
the engineer hours that
were consumed that SCC
draws assumptions off
of. Because the cost of
writing code has come
down precipitously with
these LLMs, is writing
a fully mature spec
still necessary? What
I've been doing, and
admittedly I haven't
properly formalized
this, is allowing font
code and its multiple
invocations to act in a
distributed sense. So
suppose I'm building
a full stack application.
I have three or four
different backends
that match the same
process or rules or that
go down different paths
that are being built
concurrently. And I
similarly have maybe one
or two frontends that
are being built to
experiment with different
user experiences that
are all interoperable
with the different
backends being built.
So I effectively
have multiple
forms of agents that
are collaborating
with each
other, trying to
decide independent
of me, the human,
on the communication
protocol or the interface
layer, for lack
of a better term,
between the front end
and the back end. and i
effectively have a a
poor man's diffusion
model into which or from
which an application
emerges does that
all make sense yeah
that's a cool that's
a cool way to to to
play use use your
resources right is you can
um you can build like
a hundred different
implementations of the
same spec and figure
out and have them
if you have the
resources to do that
that's a good way to do it
because your cost of
building is cheaper
right or the spec
evolves with the
learnings from
what didn't work
so you're A-B testing
during the build
and then whatever
you'll test the
output of A-B and
whatever the best
it's multivariate
it's certainly not
A-B yeah it's more
than A-B yeah yeah
yeah just as a
descriptor but yeah
A practical
example is the
stuff I've been
experimenting with
in the U.S.
options market.
There are hundreds
of trading ideas,
different ways to
calculate Greeks, different
variables that are
used, different patterns
and data sets, all of
which are dimensions
against which some
algorithmic trading
system can be tested.
so instead of trying
to plan all of that
ahead of time i simply
set up a sandbox and
said here's the data
here's the output
these are the business
rules that **** cannot
be broken now optimize
for whatever my goal
is yeah you know it's
a good way to do it
i don't know if you
know you still have
to spend the time to
figure out which one
which one you want to go
with right if you have
if you don't that's
kind of the point
i gave it a goal to
optimize toward There was
a VP at Netta, or back
then it was called
Facebook, who gave a
talk at Stanford, and
how multiple teams
were aligned because
of a North Star metric.
So it didn't require
central authority
to approve or
reject a project.
All projects were
approved, provided you
can justify how
it affected or was
intended to affect
that North Star metric.
So taking that same
principle and reapplying
it here seems
to be, it's not
consistent, I admit.
but seems to allow me to
be more productive
than having to manually
vet and curate a
spec, for example.
Yeah, I do understand
your methodology
because you believe
that you don't want
to be in the loop,
right? You don't
want to give your
cycles to be having to
figure out which
one is the best and
look at the spec. I'm
also a bottleneck.
Yes, yeah. Humans
are slower, right?
I'm a meatbag compared
to these silicon beasts.
You've done this
multi-parlough,
right? You've run all
these permutations.
You've seen which
ones maximize
the reward function
of, you know.
It's unclear how many
of the permutations
in the problem space
are being tested.
I'm not curating this.
Yeah, no, that's right.
You're just letting
them all run. um i
think that the point
though is that there
are pieces in there that
are really problem
space so again i don't
know the coverage of the
problem space yes there
are multiple instances
running but i don't
so like hypothetical
mountain range i don't
know if every single
coordinate is being
tested for a local
maximum or local minimum
i assume there's some
sort of inferential
learning happening so
that if there's a slope
and there is no peak
it is probably not a
maximum or minimum
search somewhere else you
should be able to
gleam the components
either those those you
know maybe they all pick
the same um memory
system i should be able
to gleam those parts
that should that would
win in the in the
golden spec right if you
consider all right
we did it ran it 20
different ways and
repeatedly the the elements
that one were to compile
it to a wasm right
okay there's there's
your gem that you've
discovered and then if
you were to write from
scratch right you
should be able to derive
the golden speck as a
an outcome of the month
of the monte carlo run
does that make sense
so in that paradigm
if there are multiple
in-flight experiments
running if let's say
a new way was
discovered or a new way
was invalidated
does that then mean
the in-flight runs
that are adjacent
to that new way
should also be
stopped well as you
say it's a question
local versus global
maxima so possibly but
you know you can you
could run it depends
on the parameters
you're trying to run if
you're trying to
minimize the overall cost
well quite possibly
and you could eliminate
some runs if you know
that they are they have
some bad spec elements
to them like you
just go okay we know
that we're never going
to accept anything
I know written in c
because it's not memory
safe or something right
so whatever the
learnings were yes you
could go and identify
the ones that are in
flying and kill those
but really my point was
can we derive the spec
elements that would
be reliable so that
they become pillars and
of course it also depends
on what is in that
set of things selected
so some things will
be more compatible
with other things that
are also selected at
the same time yeah yeah
yeah do you have all
the uh back ends in the
same code space so you
you need degrees of
separation in any way
or i'm not explicitly
separating them but
this environment is
capable of spawning
child containers and they
are explicitly instructed
to only test in
child containers instead
of in virtual environments
so i assume although
admittedly i'm
not verifying this that
there is legitimate
separation between runs
or between invocations
but then jed i mean
do you how do you are
you the question to
you is it are you a
practitioner of of a
master spec and if and then
how how how detailed
is your master spec?
The spec for me is as
detailed as cloud code
thinks it needs to
be. So for those who
are unfamiliar, I
published a repo on GitHub
for pose detection.
And the first prompt
was to conduct deep
research on the different
components needed to
build a web browser,
a browser-based application
that can leverage
local GPU and local
cameras to conduct
pose detection on a
subject visually it was
able to assemble that
spec that uh corpus
of information which
represented in aggregate
probably 40 000
tokens worth of stuff
and then i didn't read
any of it to be clear
so i i'm not really
sure what's in it i just
know that when i
validated the output i
was able to look at
myself in a web browser
running offline and
see the overlay was
following my movements
it wasn't my that's what
you were referring
to earlier about the
how not the what
correct yeah okay i i i
promise the what what
i know not how to want
yeah nice and that is
definitely one way a
contemporary way to
do it like for me as a
kind of a lifelong
product manager like i've
i've pre-ai right
i've just defined and
brought to market many
many products in my
career and i had to
manually write a 50 page
spec and then sit down
in front of in a team
of 50 engineers and
defend every line of
my spec over a full
one week interrogation
right and so i've
i've gone through that
pain but that's how
The distinction, David,
is those engineers were
way more expensive.
Yeah, they were, right?
So the cost of being
wrong is much higher.
Yes, absolutely,
dude. I've spent
$10 million over
the course of a year
building a product
that was killed
because our
assumptions were wrong.
And I would have loved
to be able to know
that in one month, but
we couldn't code fast
enough because we
didn't have AI. So I
totally get it and I
love it. I just haven't
got myself and my
traditional ******** product
management methodology
to a point where I
can step out of the
loop and fully, fully
give an agentic system
much more decision
-making influence over
the spec. I'm just not
there yet. I want to
be there. And that's
why I was kind of
excited at this GitHub
special kit. focus that
energy on defining what
the outcome is because
then once you say
this is what i want
it to this is what it
should accomplish in
the end then you're sort
of you get the benefit
of the the serendipity
and whatever the ai
can sort of present
to you for options of
getting there instead
you're sort of trying
to think of everything
waterfall beforehand
saying well i gotta
think through everything
because i've got
to defend it there's
no one to defend it to
anymore i know focus
on your outcome define
that as clearly and
as specifically as
possible and then you
know let let the ai riff
on what your options
are anybody have any
insight on when you know
you have the correct
out the amount of
outcome because that
seems like that's where
the key is in the prompt
to getting what the
outcome i.e. jed the
right description of
what it is you want.
How do you know
when you derive
and you got into
that proper place?
Yeah, it's tough,
right? But I do like
the outcomes,
right? I've had some
moments where I'm
like, oh, this is the
right way to do it.
I need to step back
and let it have more
control and me just
describe the outcome,
the experience.
I have had some
moments where that I'm
curating a new product
management methodology
where I'm definitely,
I realize, one
of my moments was
this, like you said,
Michael, I realize
that I don't have to
defend every line of
my PRD spec anymore.
I'm not going to be
interrogated for a week
by 50 engineers. And
I don't have to be
sensitive about the
language that I write
my PRD in because a
human engineer, here,
50 human engineers
aren't going to be
reading it. And I'm
not going to **** them
off because they
say, tell me what you
want. Don't tell me
what the implementation
should be. And I
realize that now, right?
I'm like, oh, this is
the outcome and the
experience I want
for the user and the
system. And just do
that, right? And so I've
had these moments
where I'm actually
involving my product
management methodology.
some getting there as
a pm as an ai and as a
gentic pm it's uh
it it's been a very
interesting journey to
to we're inventing this
these new concepts someone
like jed who's like
you know what just you
you make this you do
100 iterations build
100 versions or and and
uh let's see which one
wins that's awesome
i i love that but i
haven't got myself there
yet well and it also
depends on how many
people you have to
answer to because i think
that you know seriously
because you know if
you have to explain it
because it's not even
it's not just explaining
it to the developers
that are going to
have to do it but it's
to all these people that
are in theory spending
money on what you're
doing you know so
the more bureaucracy
exists above you the more
that you probably have
to focus on a waterfall
approach because
management wants to know
where we're going and
how long it's going
to take and yada yada
yada so i think that's
where a lot of these
larger more bureaucratic
companies are just
going to fall by the
wayside because they
carry with them that
overhead of explanation
and and and sort of
muscle memory of this
is how you get a project
funded etc yada yada
yada whereas you look at
someone like jed who's
basically saying okay
there's this thing
that i want to do let
me shorten the distance
between you know uh
knowing that i want that
thing to be done and
getting it done you
know in multiple ways
trying multiple ways of
getting to that point
independent of having
to explain it or
justify it to anybody
because all i want is the
outcome so what you know
so i think what jess
talking about is sort
the essence of our
capability here the
question is how much do
we need to sort of
entertain or or or kind of
uh support the
bureaucracy that that has
historically um you
know guided and and kind
of constrained how we
do what we do yeah i
agree there's so much
you know you know there's
so much bureaucracy
above because everybody's
these people are like
writing checks or
allocating headcount,
you know, they're
allocating resources.
They're like, want one stuff
to be delivered and
launched and you've
got program managers
and project managers and
engineers and the
engineering managers and,
you know, all the stuff
like I'm, you know,
Yes.
So, you know,
that's the stuff that
I have to deal with.
I'm here in Silicon
Valley at, you know,
salesforce.com doing
Agent Force, where we're
building out, you know,
this $10 million system,
I can't just say,
you know, we're going
to run 13 experiments
in the next 48 hours.
But in the end,
if you think about
all of that effort
is spent towards
solving a
particular problem.
And, you know, at
what point does all of
that overhead, you
know, become a burden
to solving that problem
and at what point
does a sort of ai first
organization come in
and say well i can
solve that problem for
you and you know i didn't
have to have a sales
staff or a you know
a whole you know
program management yada
yada yada like here's
the solution to the
problem right you know
in particular when
you start to have a
delegation of even more
of the kind of structure
of the organization
in agentics as well
because then you know
you don't have to there's
fewer gatekeepers and
more things start to
happen and really when
it comes down to it
is how quickly did
you get the thing that
needed to be done done
all of those other
sort of justifications
and rationales for uh